<bill session="103" type="h" number="101" updated="2010-04-18T23:15:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Action Now Health Care Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve access to health insurance and contain health care costs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407676"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400398" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="404705" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="402657" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400571" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400596" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="410529" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400156" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400091" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="404296" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="404723" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407899" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400307" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400534" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400028" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400226" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="411247" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400567" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="407558" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="401383" joined="1993-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400329" joined="1993-02-04" withdrawn="1993-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="408092" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="404401" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400188" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="407400" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="409423" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400504" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400205" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400590" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400560" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="1993-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400586" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="410084" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400568" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300097" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400544" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400012" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="409219" joined="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400369" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="405033" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="1993-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400583" joined="1993-01-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-15"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.R.3600.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3600" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Accidents"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Antitrust actions"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Antitrust policy"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Data transmission systems"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical services"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Homeless"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Insurance rates"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Malpractice"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical associations"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medical ethics"/>
		<term name="Medical laboratories"/>
		<term name="Medical malpractice insurance"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medical tests"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Migrant labor"/>
		<term name="Negligence"/>
		<term name="Obstetrics"/>
		<term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
		<term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Reinsurance"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Risk management"/>
		<term name="Rural hospitals"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Surveys"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Trauma care"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Improved Access to Affordable Health Care Coverage Subtitle A: Increased Affordability and Availability for Employees Subtitle B: Improved Small Employer Purchasing Power of Affordable Health Insurance Subtitle C: Health Deduction Fairness Subtitle D: Improved Access to Community Health Services Subtitle E: Improved Access to Rural Health Services Title II: Health Care Cost Containment and Quality Enhancement Subtitle A: Medical Malpractice Liability Reform Subtitle B: Administrative Cost Savings Subtitle C: Medical Savings Accounts (Medisave) Subtitle D: Medicaid Program Flexibility Subtitle E: Limitations on Physician Self-Referrals Subtitle F: Removing Restrictions on Managed Care Subtitle G: Medicare Payment Changes Subtitle H: Limitation of Antitrust Recovery for Certain Hospital Joint Ventures Subtitle I: Encouraging Enforcement Activities of Medical Self-Regulatory Entities Action Now Health Care Reform Act of 1993 - Title I: Improved Access to Affordable Health Care Coverage - (Sec. 102) Preempts inconsistent State laws. (Sec. 103) Requires small employer health insurance carriers to offer a MedAccess basic plan (providing only benefits for essential preventive and medical services and having an actuarial value not over 60 percent of a MedAccess standard plan) and a MedAccess standard plan (providing benefits typical of the small employer market). Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to tax the failure of a carrier or plan to comply with related standards. Mandates: (1) acceptance of every small employer and full-time employee; or (2) in States that so provide, allocation of risk. (Sec. 104) Regulates pre-existing condition requirements, premiums, rating practices disclosure, minimum participation requirements, and renewability. (Sec. 108) Mandates development of models for reinsurance or allocation of risk mechanisms. Requires State (or Federal) establishment of at least one mechanism in each State. Amends the IRC to impose a tax in any such Federal reinsurance State. (Sec. 110) Establishes the Office of Private Health Care Coverage and a related advisory committee. (Sec. 111) Authorizes research and demonstration projects on the impact of these provisions on the availability of affordable small employer coverage. Requires: (1) methods for measuring the relative health risks of eligible individuals; and (2) a model for equitably distributing health risks among small employer carriers. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 121) Preempts State laws: (1) requiring the offering of health plans providing certain services; and (2) prohibiting employer groups from purchasing health insurance. (Sec. 131) Amends the IRC to increase and make permanent deductions for the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals. (Sec. 141) Amends the Public Health Service Act (PHSA) to provide for grants to: (1) migrant and community health centers and to entities providing health services for the homeless to promote primary health services for underserved individuals; and (2) increase access to outpatient primary services in certain geographic areas. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 171) Changes the heading of title XII (Trauma Care) of the PHSA to &quot;Emergency Medical Services&quot; and makes similar changes to references within the title. (Sec. 172) Authorizes grants to States for State offices of emergency medical services. (Sec. 173) Requires projects under existing provisions to include demonstrations on telecommunications between rural medical facilities and other medical facilities with useful expertise or equipment. (Sec. 174) Authorizes appropriations to carry out specified provisions of title XII. (Sec. 181) Mandates grants to States for rural air medical transport systems. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 191) Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to extend special payments for the inpatient services of small, rural Medicare-dependent hospitals. Title II: Health Care Cost Containment and Quality Enhancement - (Sec. 211) Reforms medical malpractice regarding: (1) a statute of limitations; (2) use of alternative dispute resolution systems (ADRs), including for claims against the United States; (3) settlement offers and conferences; (4) noneconomic and punitive damages; (5) periodic payment for future damages; (6) mandatory offsets for collateral source payments; (7) contingent attorney's fees; (8) several and joint liability; (9) findings of negligence; (10) practice guidelines sanctioned as affirmative defenses; (11) the standard of proof regarding certain labor and delivery circumstances; (12) supersedure of certain State laws; and (13) establishment and certification of State ADRs. (Sec. 241) Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to authorize appropriations for sanctioning guidelines as affirmative defenses. Mandates: (1) research and demonstrations on the use of data on malpractice actions; and (2) development of a standard reporting form for State ADRs in transmitting information on disputes resolved. (Sec. 242) Authorizes State professional disciplinary agencies to make agreements with professional societies to allow the societies to: (1) participate in licensing; and (2) review malpractice allegations or other information on the practice patterns of a practitioner. (Sec. 243) Requires each health professional and provider to participate in a risk management program. (Sec. 244) Mandates grants: (1) for basic research on malpractice prevention and compensation and outcomes research; (2) to States to improve licensing and discipline; and (3) for public education on appropriate health care use and realistic expectations, public education on the resources and role of licensing and disciplinary boards, and development of faculty training and curricula regarding quality assurance, risk management, and medical injury protection. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 245) Mandates a study on factors preventing or discouraging physicians from volunteering in medically underserved areas. (Sec. 251) Regulates: (1) data elements, uniform claims forms, and uniform electronic transmission of data elements; (2) provider claims submission; and (3) hospital and non-hospital electronic medical data. (Sec. 262) Requires hospitals, in order to participate in Medicare, to maintain and electronically transmit clinical data on patients in a set of electronic comprehensive data elements. (Sec. 263) Provides for electronic transmission of data elements to Federal agencies. (Sec. 264) Prohibits plans from requiring that a provider provide any data element not in the set or transmit any data element in a manner inconsistent with standards. (Sec. 265) Establishes an advisory commission. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 271) Provides for a comparative health care value program in each State. Authorizes grants and appropriations. (Sec. 273) Requires each Federal agency concerned with health insurance or care to develop comparative value information. (Sec. 274) Mandates model systems for the gathering and analysis of data on health care cost, quality, and outcome. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 281) Provides for standards regarding Medicare and Medicaid identification cards. Establishes a Medicare and Medicaid system to provide information on primary payors. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 282) Nullifies any State law requiring that medical or health insurance records be maintained in written rather than electronic form. (Sec. 283) Provides for standards regarding: (1) beneficiary and provider identification numbers; and (2) coordination of benefits. (Sec. 285) Mandates grants to demonstrate the application of comprehensive information systems in continuously monitoring patient care and improving patient care. Authorizes appropriations from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund. Authorizes grants for: (1) communication links between plan and provider information systems; (2) regional or community-based clinical information systems; and (3) developing and testing, for physicians and non-hospital entities, the definition of a comprehensive data set and the specification and presentation of individual data elements. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 291) Amends the IRC to exclude from an employee's gross income any amount contributed by the employer to a trust created exclusively to pay an individual's medical expenses (medical savings account). Sets contribution limits. Subjects the employee to taxation as owner of the account. (Sec. 301) Amends Medicaid provisions to modify contracting requirements for coordinated care services. (Sec. 311) Amends Medicare provisions to extend physician self-referral limitations to all payors and certain additional services. Revises exceptions. (Sec. 314) Mandates a study to estimate the changes in aggregate costs that will result from the amendments made by these provisions. (Sec. 321) Preempts managed care restrictions under State law. Mandates a study of managed care benefits and cost effectiveness. (Sec. 331) Amends Medicare provisions to revise the method for determining prospective payment updates to hospitals. (Sec. 332) Lowers the limitation amount and suspends certain annual adjustments regarding clinical diagnostic laboratory tests. (Sec. 343) Limits antitrust recovery to actual damages if certain requirements are met, including the filing and publication of information regarding hospital joint ventures. (Sec. 345) Establishes the Interagency Committee on Competition, Antitrust Policy, and Health Care. (Sec. 351) Prohibits, subject to exception, damages and other recovery under the Clayton Act or similar State laws from a medical self-regulatory entity engaging in standard setting or enforcement activities designed to promote the quality of health care and not conducted for financial gain.

	</summary>
</bill>
