<bill session="103" type="h" number="1052" updated="2010-05-20T22:11:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">States Solid Waste Regulatory Authority Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize States to regulate the treatment, disposal, and other disposition of solid waste.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400578"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404213" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="1993-02-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E423)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Compost"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Interstate compacts"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste reduction"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/23/1993--Introduced.
States Solid Waste Regulatory Authority Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize each State to enact and enforce laws: (1) imposing fees on the treatment, disposal, and other disposition of solid waste; and (2) banning the importation of solid waste beginning five years after enactment of this Act if the State has an approved solid waste management plan. Requires State solid waste management plans to require that the State: (1) identify the amount of solid wastes by waste type that are reasonably expected to be generated within the State or accepted from another State during the ten-year period following enactment of this Act; (2) identify the amount of solid waste to be reduced during such ten-year period through source reduction, recycling, and resource recovery; and (3) assure the availability of solid waste treatment, storage, and disposal facilities. Requires that a State solid waste management plan: (1) require laws, regulations, and ordinances for the development of new and expanded solid waste management facilities; (2) describe solid waste management practices that promote source reduction and recycling; (3) identify existing State and regional markets for recyclable materials and actions that the State will take to develop recycling markets; (4) provide that all solid waste management facilities shall register with the State and that only registered facilities may manage solid waste identified in the plan; (5) provide for technical and financial assistance to local communities to meet plan requirements; and (6) specify the conditions under which the State will authorize a person to accept solid waste from other States. Sets forth additional plan requirements, unless the State demonstrates that their inclusion is impracticable, including: (1) a policy requiring the procurement of recycled products; (2) a program to encourage composting; (3) a system for curbside pickup or separation of recyclable materials; and (4) a policy requiring the separation of recyclable materials prior to treatment or disposal and requiring a surcharge on tipping fees for solid waste from commercial establishments or office buildings that is not source-separated before delivery to waste facilities. Requires States to submit plans for approval.

	</summary>
</bill>
