<bill session="103" type="h" number="1057" updated="2010-04-19T01:52:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Small Business Promotion and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect and promote small business concerns.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407669"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="409219" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1993-06-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-10"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>See H.R.2264.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2264" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Cabinet officers"/>
		<term name="Community property"/>
		<term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employment tax credits"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Farms"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government securities"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Home labor"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Internal revenue law"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Research and development tax credit"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="Stockholders"/>
		<term name="Student aid"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Women in business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/23/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Small Business Tax Incentives Title II: Increase of Number of Permitted S Corporation Shareholders Title III: Women-Owned Small Business Concerns Title IV: Prepayment of Development Company Debentures Title V: Cabinet Level Status for SBA Administrator Title VI: Assistant United States Trade Representative for Small Business Title VII: Judicial Review Under Regulatory Flexibility Act Title VIII: Congressional Budget Office Small Business Legislative Cost Analysis Title IX: Relief From Retroactive Application of Treasury Department Regulations and Rulings Title X: Study of Impact of Regulatory Analysis Upon Small Business Title XI: Fair Labor Standards Act Title XII: Independent Contractors Omnibus Small Business Promotion and Protection Act of 1993 -Title I: Small Business Tax Incentives - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend permanently: (1) the income tax credit for increasing research activities and the targeted jobs credit; (2) the authority to issue bonds for which 95 percent or more of the proceeds are used to provide any manufacturing facility or farm land or property; (3) the exclusion from gross income of payments to an educational assistance program; and (4) an increased deduction (from 25 to 100 percent of such insurance costs) for health insurance costs of self-employed individuals. Title II: Increase of Number of Permitted S Corporation Shareholders - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase from 35 to 50 the maximum number of shareholders of a &quot;small business corporation.&quot; Title III: Women-Owned Small Business Concerns - Amends the Small Business Act to: (1) include as socially disadvantaged small business concerns those which have been subjected to gender-based prejudice; (2) include women under the definition of socially and economically disadvantaged individuals for contracting purposes; and (3) prohibit the application of community property laws in determining whether a small business meets certain ownership and control requirements. Title IV: Prepayment of Development Company Debentures - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to allow the issuer of a debenture purchased by the Federal Financing Bank and guaranteed by the Small Business Administration (SBA), at the election of the borrower whose loan secures the debenture, to prepay such debenture by payment to the Federal Financing Bank of the unpaid principal balance and any required prepayment penalty. Title V: Cabinet Level Status for SBA Administrator - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the SBA Administrator should be designated by the President as a full-fledged member of the Cabinet. Increases the Administrator's pay to an executive level commensurate with Cabinet status. Title VI: Assistant United States Trade Representative for Small Business - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the U.S. Trade Representative should establish the position of Assistant United States Trade Representative for Small Business to promote small business exports and remove foreign impediments to such exports. Title VII: Judicial Review Under Regulatory Flexibility Act - Amends the Regulatory Flexibility Act to repeal the proscription against judicial review of agency determinations regarding regulatory flexibility. Title VIII: Congressional Budget Office Small Business Legislative Cost Analysis - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to prepare for each public bill or resolution reported by a congressional committee an estimate of the costs incurred in carrying out such bill or resolution and costs to small businesses in complying with such legislation. Title IX: Relief from Retroactive Application of Treasury Department Regulations and Rulings - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide that all final, temporary, or proposed regulations and rulings issued by the Secretary of the Treasury shall apply prospectively from the date of their publication in the Federal Register. Title X: Study of Impact of Regulatory Analysis Upon Small Business - Requires the SBA's Chief Counsel for Advocacy to study the impact of Federal regulatory paperwork and tax requirements upon small business. Title XI: Fair Labor Standards Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 with respect to minimum wage and maximum hours to include within its purview workers engaged in industrial homework. Title XII: Independent Contractors - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Internal Revenue Service should adopt objective, reasonable standards to determine independent contractor status.

	</summary>
</bill>
