<bill session="103" type="h" number="1075" updated="2010-04-19T01:55:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To allow an item veto in appropriation Acts for fiscal years 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, and 1998 by the President to reduce spending to levels necessary to achieve a balanced budget by fiscal year 1998, and to establish select committees on congressional budget and appropriation process reform in the House of Representatives and in the Senate.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411247"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>See H.R.1578.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1578" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Balanced budgets"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal budget process"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Item veto"/>
		<term name="Presidential powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/23/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Item Veto to Achieve Balanced Budget by Fiscal Year 1998 Title II: Changing Budgeting and Appropriating by Eliminating the Committees on Appropriations Title I: Item Veto to Achieve Balanced Budget by Fiscal Year 1998 - Requires the President to submit budgets for FY 1995 through 1997 to achieve a balanced budget by FY 1998. Requires the FY 1998 budget to be balanced. Grants the President an item veto authority for appropriations for FY 1994 through 1998. Title II: Changing Budgeting and Appropriating by Eliminating the Committees on Appropriations - Establishes a select committee in the House of Representatives and a select committee in the Senate to report to their respective Houses in January 1994 resolutions amending their respective Rules to: (1) eliminate the Committees on Appropriations; (2) modify the membership and jurisdiction of the Committees on the Budget; and (3) modify the jurisdiction of each standing committee to authorize it to make appropriations with respect to its subject matter jurisdiction.

	</summary>
</bill>
