<bill session="103" type="h" number="1116" updated="2010-04-19T02:02:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Water Act Research Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Federal Water Pollution Control Act with respect to research and development activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400524"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="1993-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="407672" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1993-11-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-01"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-08"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1059-1060)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-23"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Sedimentation"/>
		<term name="Soil pollution"/>
		<term name="Surveys"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetland ecology"/>
		<term name="Wetlands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/24/1993--Introduced.
Clean Water Act Research Amendments of 1993 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to revise the authorized activities of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency with respect to water pollution control and investigations. Establishes a National Water Quality Research Committee to advise the Administrator on research activities. Requires the Committee to report annually to the Congress on: (1) research conducted in the preceding year; (2) highest priority research needs for the following five-year period; (3) planned research activities; and (4) opportunities to coordinate Federal and State research. Establishes a Water Quality Monitoring Council to ensure the coordination of Federal and State surface and groundwater quality monitoring programs. Directs the Administrator to conduct a program of research and development of methods for the control of nonpoint sources of pollution. Requires the Administrator to: (1) conduct a national survey of data regarding bottom sediment contamination; and (2) conduct a program of research and development of methods for improved remediation and control of pollution problems resulting from contaminated sediments. Directs the Administrator to conduct a program of research and investigation concerning groundwater quality. Requires the Administrator to: (1) conduct a program of research and development to improve understanding of the status and trends of ecosystems and to develop improved predictive models upon which to base standardized protocols; and (2) issue protocols based on such program for use by States in conducting water quality assessments. Directs the Administrator to conduct a research technology development and demonstration program to identify and demonstrate cost-effective preventive measures for sources of pollution in complex watersheds having a mix of land use types. Requires the Adminstrator to conduct a basic research, development, and demonstration program for wetlands. Revises provisions concerning grants for research and development to require the Administrator to establish a grant program to demonstrate practices for the prevention and control of industrial and municipal sources of water pollution. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
