<bill session="103" type="h" number="1112" updated="2010-04-19T02:01:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Apprenticeship Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish youth apprenticeship demonstration programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407399"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="408109" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400537" joined="1993-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E446)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1396" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Employment"/>
		<term name="Apprenticeship"/>
		<term name="Business and social problems"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Employment subsidies"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Grievance procedures"/>
		<term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
		<term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Labor mobility"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Nondiscrimination provisions"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Secondary school students"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/24/1993--Introduced.
Youth Apprenticeship Act of 1993 - Establishes an Institute for Youth Apprenticeship as an independent establishment to administer youth apprenticeship demonstration programs set up under this Act. Directs the Institute Board Chairperson to establish guidelines, criteria, and procedures for such programs. Directs the Institute Executive Director to enter into contracts with public and nonprofit private organizations to develop and evaluate youth apprenticeship demonstration programs. Requires each eligible entity entering into such a contract with the Institute Board to establish partnerships among secondary and postsecondary schools and employers, labor organizations, and community and civic leaders to provide apprenticeship training to students. Requires at least: (1) one secondary school wage incentive demonstration program under which the Institute shall pay 50 percent of the apprenticeship wage; and (2) one secondary school disadvantaged youth demonstration program. Authorizes two postsecondary school demonstration programs. Requires training for various levels of secondary school students. Requires employers to pay: (1) 100 percent of the apprentice wage rate in secondary school programs (but 50 percent in the wage incentive program); (2) 100 percent of the apprentice wage rate and costs of continuing basic skills courses in postsecondary programs; and (3) costs of on-the-job training. Does not require employers to hire apprentices upon completion of the apprenticeships. Requires program coordination and assistance by the Institute, including operating a clearinghouse for the partnerships and gathering information on labor mobility of apprentices. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Board, Institute, and these programs within 69 months.

	</summary>
</bill>
