<bill session="103" type="h" number="1166" updated="2010-04-19T02:10:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Middle Class Tax Relief Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax relief for middle-income taxpayers by increasing the personal exemption amount and to provide additional revenues by increasing the taxes paid by high-income individuals and corporations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-10"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>See H.R.2264.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2264" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exemption"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Wealth tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/2/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Relief for Middle-Income Taxpayers Title II: Revenue Provisions Middle Class Tax Relief Act of 1993 - Title I: Tax Relief for Middle-Income Taxpayers - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide an additional exemption amount ($1,000) to the regular personal exemption ($2,000) for middle-income taxpayers. Specifies the maximum gross income amounts for such taxpayers. Provides a formula for reducing the additional exemption amount for middle-income taxpayers whose incomes exceed certain transitional dollar amounts. Provides for inflation adjustments of amounts under this title. Title II: Revenue Provisions - Increases the individual income tax rates for certain high-income taxpayers. Imposes a surtax on the individual tax rate or the alternative minimum tax rate for individuals whose incomes exceed $225,000. Increases the rates of corporate income tax and of alternative minimum tax.

	</summary>
</bill>
