<bill session="103" type="h" number="1186" updated="2010-04-19T02:13:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Environmental Technologies Agency Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Environmental Technologies Agency.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401383"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400239" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1993-03-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1019)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Growth and Credit Formation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-16"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Growth and Credit Formation" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Business intelligence"/>
		<term name="Communication in science"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid programs"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Privatization"/>
		<term name="Product development"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
National Environmental Technologies Agency Act - Establishes the National Environmental Technologies Agency to: (1) coordinate Federal environmental restoration and protection planning; (2) identify areas that need technical solutions to maintain environmental security, are not receiving product-oriented research necessary to meet those needs, and exhibit the greatest promise for the development of solutions; (3) support the development of technology having future application in environmental restoration and protection; (4) coordinate the exchange of technological information relating to environmental restoration and protection between Federal agencies and the private sector; (5) support continuing research and development of advanced technologies; (6) monitor research and development being conducted on advanced technologies by private industry; and (7) promote continuing development of a technological industrial base in the United States. Establishes the Industry and Academia Advisory Council to make recommendations regarding general policy for the Agency. Permits the Agency Administrator to transfer to the domestic private sector technology developed with the support of the Agency if the technology may have potential application in private activities relating to environmental restoration and protection. Provides for dissemination of the results of Agency research. Directs the Administrator, in determining whether to make an award to a joint venture, to consider whether the joint venture has provided for appropriate participation of U.S. small businesses. Entitles the United States to a share of licensing fees and royalty payments made to a joint venture in an amount proportionate to the Federal share of costs incurred. Provides for the return of unspent Federal funds to the Agency if it appears that the recipient is not making satisfactory progress toward successful completion of the project. Entitles the United States, upon dissolution of a joint venture that receives funding under this Act, to a share of the residual assets proportionate to the Federal share of costs. Establishes the Environmental Advanced Research Projects Revolving Fund. Authorizes the use of the Fund to provide financial assistance to entities that serve long-term environmental security needs. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
