<bill session="103" type="h" number="1193" updated="2010-04-19T02:14:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">National Service bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Voluntary Service and Educational Opportunity Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program of voluntary national service for young people and senior citizens.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406284"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E486)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-12"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Forces and Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-12"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education, Training and Employment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-20"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Executive Comment Received from Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Executive Comment Received from Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Forces and Personnel" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Education, Training and Employment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Employment"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Compensatory education"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Dropouts"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employment subsidies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Grievance procedures"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Housing subsidies"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Military pay"/>
		<term name="Military personnel"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="National service"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Officer personnel"/>
		<term name="Older workers"/>
		<term name="Peace Corps"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
		<term name="Student aid"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Establishment of the Citizens Corps Title II: Administration of the Citizens Corps Subtitle A: Administration of the Civilian Service and Senior Service Subtitle B: Provision of National Service Positions for Members of the Civilian Service and Senior Service Subtitle C: Deferred Placement of Members of the Civilian Service Subtitle D: Administration of the Citizens Corps With Regard to Service in the Armed Forces Title III: Benefits for Participating in the Citizens Corps Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions National Voluntary Service and Educational Opportunity Act of 1993 - Title I: Establishment of the Citizens Corps - Establishes a Citizens Corps to provide the following voluntary national service options: (1) Civilian Service; (2) Service in the Armed Forces; and (3) Senior Service. Sets forth requirements for individual eligibility, terms of service, types of national and community service, applications, and placements. Title II: Administration of the Citizens Corps - Subtitle A: Administration of the Civilian Service and Senior Service - Makes the Commission on National and Community Service responsible for administering the Civilian Service and Senior Service of the Citizen Corps. Directs the Commission to make general grants to States for: (1) paying stipends and wages for Civilian and Senior Services members; (2) providing and administering national service opportunities in each State for such members; and (3) making grants to national service councils in each State. Authorizes supplemental grants to a State or to a Federal agency under certain conditions. Subtitle B: Provision of National Service Positions for Members of the Civilian Service and Senior Service - Directs each State Governor to prepare a national service plan specifying priorities in the State for providing national service opportunities for Civilian and Senior Services members. Requires designation, and allows redesignation after the first two years, of volunteer service areas for the State. Requires establishment of a national service council for each volunteer service area. Requires each council to: (1) recruit and place volunteers; (2) prepare and implement a volunteer recruitment and placement plan (subject to public review and the Governor's approval); (3) select service sponsors (public agencies or public or nonprofit organizations); and (4) prevent displacement of workers. Requires each State to establish a grievance procedure for resolving complaints of worker displacement by Corps members. Authorizes the Commission to require a private nonprofit organization to pay a limited amount for each Corps member placed in a national service position with that organization. Subtitle C: Deferred Placement of Members of the Civilian Service - Provides for a deferred placement program under which individuals eligible to serve in the Civilian Service may receive financial assistance for an education or training program at an educational institution or training establishment, if they have received a high school diploma or equivalent and are accepted or enrolled as a full-time student. Makes the Government's financial obligation (and any participant obligation conditioned thereon) contingent upon appropriations for assistance under this subtitle. Subtitle D: Administration of the Citizen Corps with Regard to Service in the Armed Forces - Makes the Secretary of Defense responsible for administering Citizens Corps members' service in the Armed Forces. Provides for a deferred enlistment program under which a certain number of individuals eligible to enlist for service in the Armed Forces as Citizens Corps members may receive financial assistance for an education or training program at an educational institution or training establishment. Directs the Secretary concerned to expand the Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps program to accommodate such number of individuals. Title III: Benefits for Participating in the Citizens Corps - Requires the State (or the Federal agency where a member is placed) to provide specified weekly stipends to Civilian Service members and hourly wages to Senior Service members. Requires the Commission to provide other assistance for Civilian and Senior Services members, as well as health insurance for each Civilian Service member. Sets compensation for Citizens Corps members serving in the Armed Forces at 66 percent of the basic rates for other comparable members of the Armed Forces. Makes such Citizen Corps members ineligible for specified benefits. Provides for the following educational or housing benefits, as the participant elects, for the following types of Citizens Corps service: (1) up to $10,000 for each year of Civilian Service; (2) up to $24,000 for two years of active duty in the Armed Forces; and (3) up to $12,000 for one year of service in a Selected Reserve of the Armed Forces. Allows a prorated benefit in certain cases of partial service. Directs the Commission and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, as appropriate, to administer such financial assistance. Sets a ten-year limit on use of such assistance, with exceptions. Excludes such assistance from gross income for Internal Revenue Code purposes. Includes such assistance in determination of family contribution for student assistance need analysis under the Higher Education Act of 1965. Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Entitles Peace Corps and VISTA volunteers who successfully complete their service after the effective date of this Act to the same education or housing assistance benefits as Civilian Service members, but reduces such benefits to reflect any compensation that is more than the Civilian Service stipend. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
