<bill session="103" type="h" number="1202" updated="2010-04-19T02:16:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Urban Schools of America (USA) Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide financial assistance to eligible local educational agencies to improve urban education, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400312"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1993-03-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Academic performance"/>
		<term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
		<term name="Asbestos abatement"/>
		<term name="Building laws"/>
		<term name="Child welfare"/>
		<term name="Community and school"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Desegregation in education"/>
		<term name="Dropout prevention"/>
		<term name="Dropouts"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugs and youth"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational innovations"/>
		<term name="Educational planning"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Educational statistics"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Homeless"/>
		<term name="Homeless children"/>
		<term name="Immigrants"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Lead"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Migrant education"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Minority teachers"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Radon"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Regulatory reform"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="School health programs"/>
		<term name="School violence"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Teachers"/>
		<term name="Urban education"/>
		<term name="White House conferences"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Urban School Improvement Title II: School Building Repair And Renovation Title III: Urban School Research Title IV: General Provisions Urban Schools of America (USA) Act of 1993 - Title I: Urban School Improvement - Authorizes appropriations and sets forth funds allocation factors. Requires LEAs to use funds under this title to meet national education goals through programs designed to: (1) increase the academic achievement and graduation rates of urban school children to at least the national average; (2) prepare urban school graduates to enter higher education, pursue careers, and exercise their responsibilities as citizens; (3) recruit and retain qualified teachers; and (4) decrease the use of drugs and alcohol by urban students, and enhance their physical and emotional health. Sets forth program accountability requirements. Authorizes the Secretary to make competitive incentive awards to individual participating schools that demonstrate exemplary progress in meeting specified program requirements. Directs the Secretary to report on the impact of Federal regulations, guidelines, and policies on urban public schools. Requires LEAs desiring to receive an allotment to establish (or designate) a local advisory group. Sets forth special rules relating to ranking of schools to determine relative need, in general, on the basis of achievement, poverty, and racial isolation. Requires each LEA receiving a grant to serve between ten and 20 percent of its schools. Requires eligible LEAs to have flexibility to serve homeless children, desegregating students, immigrants, migrants, or other highly mobile populations, within the program assisted under this title. Title II: School Building Repair and Renovation - Authorizes appropriations to assist eligible LEAs in repairing and renovating instructional facilities in city schools and for programs for school environmental concerns and safety improvement. Limits the period covered by a grant application to three years, and requires annual review by the Secretary. Title III: Urban School Research - Authorizes appropriations for the National Institute for Urban Education (the Institute), established in the Department of Education by this title. Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to create an Assistant Secretary for Urban Education (the Assistant Secretary), who is to establish the Institute in the Department. Requires the Institute and allows LEAs to use funds for specified functions involving research, information, and evaluation relating to urban education and title I programs. Title IV: General Provisions - Establishes the Interagency Council on Urban Schools to: (1) review Federal programs to determine effects on urban schools' ability to meet national education goals; (2) track school progress toward such goals; (3) solicit advice and information from urban education experts and urban school representatives on improvement of Federal programs; (4) review Federal regulations for duplication or contradiction; (5) report annually to the Congress and the President on urban school progress; (6) review and recommend improvement or streamlinig of Federal data collection in urban schools; and (7) conduct research to help urban school practitioners improve school performance. Directs the President to conduct a White House Conference on Urban Education. Authorizes appropriations. Establishes a National Commission on Urban Education, which shall: (1) study specified issues relating to urban schools; and (2) report, and recommend changes in Federal legislation, to the President and appropriate congressional committees. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
