<bill session="103" type="h" number="1214" updated="2010-04-19T02:19:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Consolidation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the regulation of banks and savings associations by a single Federal independent regulatory commission, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404634"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400612" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="406277" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="407672" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="404139" joined="1993-03-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E509-510)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1084)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1140)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1242-1243)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1314-1318)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank holding companies"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Community development banking"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Deposit insurance"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
		<term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="International banking"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
		<term name="Savings banks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/4/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Federal Banking Commission Title II: Abolition of Federal Banking Agencies Regulatory Consolidation Act of 1993 - Title I: Federal Banking Commission - Establishes the Federal Banking Commission (the Commission). Transfers to the Commisssion all regulatory functions of: (1) the Comptroller of the Currency with respect to national banks; (2) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (and any Federal Reserve Bank) with respect to member banks, bank holding companies and affiliates, and certain international banking entities; (3) the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision with respect to savings associations and savings and loan holding companies; and (4) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation with respect to State nonmember banks and certain savings and foreign banks. Establishes within the Commission a Consumer Division to: (1) conduct consumer examinations to determine the Compliance of each insured depository institution with respect to consumer protection and community reinvestment laws; and (2) implement prescribed consumer protection and information programs. Title II: Abolition of Federal Banking Agencies - Abolishes the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency and the Office of Thrift Supervision. Authorizes the President to establish a transition commission to facilitate the transfer of functions with the least disruption to the regulatory environment. Declares that the individuals serving as Comptroller of the Currency and the Director of Thrift Supervision are eligible to be detailed to the transition commission.

	</summary>
</bill>
