<bill session="103" type="h" number="1235" updated="2010-04-19T02:22:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Campaign and Administrative Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for voluntary expenditure limitations, to restrict the practice of &quot;bundling&quot; of contributions, to provide for tax credit and deduction for contributions to candidates for Congress, to require full disclosure of independent expenditures, to eliminate PAC contributions to individual candidates, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400334"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Campaign contributors"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Congressional candidates"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
		<term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
		<term name="Political advertising"/>
		<term name="Political parties"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Primaries"/>
		<term name="Radio in politics"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Television in politics"/>
		<term name="Voter registration"/>
		<term name="Voting"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/4/1993--Introduced.
Congressional Campaign and Administrative Reform Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act (Act) of 1971 to limit multicandidate political committee (PAC) contribution authority. Delineates specified circumstances where an expenditure shall constitute an expenditure in coordination with a candidate rather than an independent expenditure. Amends the Internal Revenue Code with regard to congressional contributions to allow: (1) a credit of up to $100 for an individual and $200 for a joint return; and (2) a deduction of up to $500 for an individual and $1,000 for a joint return. Amends the Act to provide for voluntary expenditure limitations for House of Representatives elections. Subjects to certain limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements any amount (&quot;soft money&quot;) paid by the national committee of a political party or a State committee of a political party with respect to an activity (such as voter registration or a get-out-the vote effort) which is intended both to influence a Federal election and achieve another purpose. Limits contributions from persons other than local individual residents for House of Representatives elections. Requires members of the House of Representatives to account for franked mail (with specified exceptions).

	</summary>
</bill>
