<bill session="103" type="h" number="1246" updated="2010-04-19T02:24:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tobacco Health Tax Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase excise taxes on cigarettes and other tobacco and tobacco-related products and to use the increased revenues to expand Medicaid eligibility and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400882"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="410589" joined="1993-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1993-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="405758" joined="1993-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400417" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="1993-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="1993-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-04-22" withdrawn="1993-11-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E530)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-12"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
		<term name="Agricultural credit"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Cigarettes"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Lead poisoning"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
		<term name="Smoking"/>
		<term name="Smoking and youth"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Tobacco tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/1993--Introduced.
Tobacco Health Tax Act of 1993 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the excise tax on the following tobaccos and tobacco-related products: (1) cigars; (2) cigarettes (including an additional tax on packs containing fewer than 20 cigarettes); (3) cigarette papers and tubes; and (4) smokeless and pipe tobacco. Imposes a new tax on cigarette tobacco. Provides, for each calendar year after 1993, an inflation adjustment of the tobacco tax rates. Provides a floor stock tax on the following tobaccos and tobacco products manufactured in or imported into the United States which are removed from stocks before January 1, 1994: (1) cigars; (2) cigarettes (including packs containing fewer than 20 cigarettes); (3) cigarette papers and tubes; (4) snuff; and (5) chewing, pipe, and cigarette tobacco. Establishes in the Treasury the Tobacco Health Tax Trust Fund which shall consist of funds resulting from tobacco tax increases under this Act. Outlines authorized expenditures from the Fund, including the use of 80 percent of such proceeds for Medicaid (title XIX of the Social Security Act) eligibility and payment expansions. Outlines actions authorized to be taken by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in connection with such expansions, including the authority to require an increase in Medicaid payment rates to hospitals and physicians. Provides conforming provisions imposing a floor on Medicaid payment levels for inpatient hospital services and physicians' services. Authorizes expenditures from the Fund for: (1) grants to State and local governments to compensate for any reduction in revenues to such governments caused by the Federal tobacco tax increase under this Act; (2) specified health promotion and illness prevention programs; and (3) public education and other activities to discourage the use of tobacco products, especially among youths. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to make certain offset payments to tobacco producers if the domestic consumption of tobacco declines by at least five percent of that calculated in 1993. Directs the Secretary to encourage such producers to convert their operations to alternative crops. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to States submitting alternative crop conversion plans. Provides funding for such alternative crop program through the Fund.

	</summary>
</bill>
