<bill session="103" type="h" number="1262" updated="2010-04-19T02:27:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Explosives Fingerprinting Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require explosive materials to contain taggants which enable law enforcement authorities to trace the source of the explosive material, whether before or after detonation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407141"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400553" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="407306" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="407817" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="402152" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400906" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1993-03-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/1993--Introduced.
Explosives Fingerprinting Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit, with respect to any explosive material which does not contain an identification and a detection taggant: (1) its manufacture; (2) its transport, shipment, distribution, or receipt in interstate or foreign commerce; (3) its importation; and (4) its resale or other disposition as surplus by a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States. Makes such provisions inapplicable to any such material designated by the President for use by the Department of Defense or another Government agency for national defense or international security purposes. Sets penalties for violations. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) defer one or more of specified effective dates provided for in this Act one year at a time until the Secretary is satisfied that identification and detection taggants are available in sufficient quantity for commercial purposes, will not impair the quality of explosive materials for their intended use, and will not adversely affect the environment; and (2) inform the Congress before making any such deferrals.

	</summary>
</bill>
