<bill session="103" type="h" number="1267" updated="2010-04-19T02:28:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To grant state status to Indian tribes for purposes of enforcement of the Solid Waste Disposal Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409205"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E540-541)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-22"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Indians"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
		<term name="Underground storage"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) treat Indian tribes as States under such Act; (2) delegate primary enforcement authority for programs under such Act to Indian tribes; and (3) provide grant and contract assistance to tribes to carry out such Act. Sets forth conditions under which Indian tribes may be treated as States. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress on: (1) recommendations for addressing hazardous and solid wastes and underground storage tanks within Indian country; (2) methods to maximize Indian participation in, and administration of, programs under such Act; and (3) the amount of assistance required and how the Administrator intends to provide such assistance to Indian tribes for the administration of such programs. Requires the Administrator to establish an inventory of: (1) sites within Indian country at which hazardous waste has been stored or disposed; and (2) open dumps within Indian country at which solid waste has been disposed. Directs the Administrator to assist Indian tribes in upgrading open dumps to comply with applicable requirements.

	</summary>
</bill>
