<bill session="103" type="h" number="1272" updated="2010-04-19T02:28:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Multiple Employer Health Benefits Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to set standards under such title for multiple employer welfare arrangements providing health plan benefits.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400318"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="404723" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400307" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407817" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400083" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400586" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400568" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400595" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400610" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404009" joined="1993-03-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E567-569)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2122)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Capital"/>
		<term name="Cash management"/>
		<term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
		<term name="Corporate finance"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Delegation of powers"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Financial statements"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1993--Introduced.
Multiple Employer Health Benefits Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to establish certification standards under title I (Protection of Employee Benefit Rights) for multiple employer welfare arrangements (MEWAs) providing health benefits. Treats as employee welfare benefits plans, and exempts from certain restrictions on preemption, a MEWA which provides benefits consisting solely of specified medical care, which is not fully insured, and which applies for and receives a specified exemption. Sets forth exemption procedures, as well as additional requirements applicable to exempted arrangements. Requires certain disclosures to participating employees. Requires exempted MEWAs which are not fully insured to maintain specified types of reserves. Sets forth corrective actions which such MEWAs' operating committees must take: (1) to avoid depletion of reserves; or (2) in connection with termination of the MEWA. Provides for review of actions by the Secretary of Labor with respect to denials of applications for, or suspensions or revocations of, such exemptions. Revises ERISA with respect to: (1) a specified exemption from preemption; (2) treatment of single employer arrangements; and (3) treatment of certain collectively bargained arrangements. Sets forth ERISA requirements relating to employee leasing health care arrangements (ELHAs). Provides for treatment of ELHAs as MEWAs, with certain exceptions. Sets forth special rules under which an ELHA may receive a MEWA exemption. Includes under such exemption requirements: (1) a minimum three-year lessor tenure; (2) solicitation restrictions; (3) creation of an employment relationship, involving disclosure statements, informed consent, and informed recruitment of the lessee's employees; and (4) a requisite employer-employee relationship under the ELHA. Allows delegation to a State of some or all of the Secretary's enforcement authority with respect to MEWAs with exemptions. Directs the Secretary to provide enforcement and technical assistance to the States with respect to MEWAs.

	</summary>
</bill>
