<bill session="103" type="h" number="1301" updated="2010-04-19T02:33:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorism Prevention and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Preinspection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To combat terrorism.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="1993-03-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Air piracy"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Assault"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Biological weapons"/>
		<term name="Bombings"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Chemical weapons"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Counterintelligence"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Forgery"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government property"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Hostages"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Mass destruction weapons"/>
		<term name="Money"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Navigation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Offshore structures"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Presidential protection"/>
		<term name="Protection of officials"/>
		<term name="Security measures"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Ships"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Territorial waters"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Torture"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Domestic Terrorism Title II: Explosives Title III: Illegal Immigration Title IV: International Terrorism Title V: Authorizations to Expand Counter-Terrorist Operations Terrorism Prevention and Protection Act of 1993 - Title I: Domestic Terrorism - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for imposition of the death penalty if death results from: (1) the commission of terrorist acts; and (2) using, or attempting or conspiring to use, weapons of mass destruction under specified circumstances. (Sec. 102) Enhances penalties for specified violations of the International Economic Emergency Powers Act and passport and visa provisions of the Federal criminal code. (Sec. 104) Extends the statute of limitations for specified terrorism offenses. (Sec. 105) Revises provisions regarding Federal Bureau of Investigation access to telephone subscriber information to increase such access under specified circumstances involving counterintelligence investigations and international terrorism. (Sec. 106) Sets penalties for: (1) violence at airports serving international civil aviation; and (2) violation of Federal aviation security regulations. (Sec. 108) Establishes an Economic Terrorism Task Force. (Sec. 109) Revises the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) concerning alien witness cooperation with Federal or State law enforcement authorities or courts. (Sec. 110) Sets penalties regarding: (1) providing material support to terrorists; (2) homicides and attempted homicides involving firearms in Federal facilities; and (3) specified explosives offenses. (Sec. 113) Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to amend sentencing guidelines to increase the base offense level for a felony that involves international terrorism. Title II: Explosives - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the: (1) manufacture of explosive material which does not contain an identification taggant and a detection taggant which meet standards to be promulgated by the Secretary of the Treasury; and (2) transport, shipment, distribution, receipt, or other disposition or importation of explosive materials not containing such taggants. Title III: Illegal Immigration - Immigration Preinspection Act of 1993 - Amends the INA to: (1) require the Attorney General to establish and maintain preinspection stations in at least three of the ten foreign airports which the Attorney General identifies as serving as last points of departure for the greatest number of passengers who arrive from abroad by air at ports of entry within the United States; and (2) convert the visa waiver pilot program for certain visitors into a permanent program, subject to specified revisions. (Sec. 304) Revises INA provisions regarding passenger manifests (including authorizing the use of electronic manifests), inspection by immigration officers, and immigration inspection and preinspection services to expedite airport immigration processing. Directs the Attorney General to implement an expedited process for the inspection of U.S. citizens upon arrival from abroad by air at ports of entry within the United States. Title IV: International Terrorism - Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act to provide that whenever an alien furnishes information leading to the conviction of an international terrorist, or the prevention, frustration, or favorable resolution of an international terrorist act, and the Secretary of State and the Attorney General jointly determine that the protection of such alien or the alien's immediate family requires admission, such alien and immediate relatives may be issued visas and admitted for permanent residence, subjects to specified limitations. (Sec. 402) Amends the Federal criminal code to: (1) increase penalties for international terrorist acts; and (2) prohibit specified offenses of violence against maritime navigation or fixed platforms. (Sec. 406) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) extension of the territorial sea and assimilated crimes in such areas; and (2) jurisdiction over crimes against U.S. nationals on foreign ships. (Sec. 409) Sets penalties for: (1) torture; (2) counterfeiting U.S. currency abroad; and (3) foreign murders of U.S. nationals. Provides for the imposition of the death penalty for terrorists under specified circumstances. Title V: Authorizations to Expand Counter-Terrorist Operations - Authorizes appropriations to specified departments and agencies for counter-terrorist operations and programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
