<bill session="103" type="h" number="1315" updated="2010-04-19T02:35:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-11">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-11"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Franchise Disclosure and Consumer Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen current Federal law and regulation to protect consumers in connection with the representation and sale of franchise businesses; to facilitate increased public disclosure regarding franchise opportunities, to enhance common law remedies for purchasers of franchises, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400537"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E593-596)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-19"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-22"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2596" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Contracts"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Financial statements"/>
		<term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/11/1993--Introduced.
Federal Franchise Disclosure and Consumer Protection Act - Makes it unlawful for any person, partnership, or corporation, in connection with the advertising, offering, licensing, contracting, sale, or other promotion in or affecting commerce of any franchise, to: (1) employ a device or artifice to defraud; (2) engage in any act or practice which operates or is intended to defraud; (3) obtain money or property by means of untrue statements or intentional omissions of material facts; or (4) discriminate among prospective franchisees on the basis of race, sex, religion, disability, or national origin. Outlines similar provisions with respect to the acts or omissions of a franchisor in presenting false or misleading information with respect to the franchise to a prospective franchisee. Specifies information to be furnished within prescribed time periods to a prospective franchisee by a franchisor or franchise broker, as required by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) under the Franchise Rule. Requires the franchisor to keep and maintain adequate records for purposes of substantiation of all information required to be presented to a prospective franchisee. Authorizes the FTC to enforce the provisions of this Act. Authorizes any person injured by a violation of this Act to bring an action in Federal district court within prescribed time periods and for specified relief, including injunctive relief. Prohibits a franchisor from requiring franchisees to agree to provisions in franchise agreements which would: (1) violate prohibitions of, or rights granted under, this Act; or (2) relieve parties from appropriate liability. Provides for the use of arbitration to resolve disputes arising under a franchise agreement. Directs the FTC to conduct an ongoing study of the need for additional provisions to strengthen franchise disclosure requirements and protect prospective franchisees.

	</summary>
</bill>
