<bill session="103" type="h" number="132" updated="2010-04-18T23:20:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Care Insurance Standards and Consumer Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to protect consumers through the establishment of standards for long-term care insurance policies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402763"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer complaints"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Insurance agents"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Sales promotion"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Long-Term Care Insurance Standards and Consumer Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the Social Security Act to require the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC), or if NAIC does not, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to establish minimum Federal standards for long-term care insurance policies that incorporate specified requirements. Prohibits the offering of a long-term care insurance policy in a State unless the State has an approved regulatory program, or the policy has been certified by the State. Requires NAIC to: (1) issue guidelines governing endorsements for long-term care insurance policies; (2) establish requirements for long-term insurance agent training and certification; and (3) establish a Steering Committee on Long-Term Care Insurance Standards in order to make recommendations concerning such minimum Federal standards. Provides for enforcement of standards. Sets forth conditions for the approval of State regulatory programs by the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to study, develop, and report to the appropriate congressional committees on a standard measure of value for long-term care policies.

	</summary>
</bill>
