<bill session="103" type="h" number="1348" updated="2012-07-17T06:06:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-11-02">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1994-11-02" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Cane River Creole National Historical Park and National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Weir Farm National Historic Site Expansion Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Cane River Creole National Historical Park and National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Weir Farm National Historic Site Expansion Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor in the State of Connecticut, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400585"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406284" joined="1993-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400205" joined="1993-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="1993-03-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E649-651)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-08-04"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-09T16:29:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 103-233.</text></action>
		<calendar number="127" datetime="1993-09-09T16:29:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 127.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-13T12:52:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Vento moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-13T12:53:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6608-6610"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-13T12:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-09-13T12:57:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-09-13T12:58:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-14"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-15" ><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-07"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston under the authority of the order of Jun 27, 94 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-305. Minority views filed.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="511" datetime="1994-07-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 511.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14409"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Amendment SP 2630 proposed by Senator Ford for Senator Wallop.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Amendment SP 2630 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1994-10-06" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T02:47:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 575 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of Senate amendment to H.R. 1348. The Senate amendment and the motion to concur shall be considered as read. The motion shall be debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be ordered without intervening motion.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:24:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Vento asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment.</text></action>
		<vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="1994-10-07T16:26:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11272"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:26:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1994-10-07" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident datetime="1994-10-25" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1994-11-02" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-449" type="public" datetime="1994-11-02"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-449.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="575" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4746" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Connecticut"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Ethnology"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Farms"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Louisiana"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Painting"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Regional economic development"/>
		<term name="Regional planning"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s2630"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Passed Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Title II: Weir Farm National Historic Site Additions Title III: Cane River Creole National Historical Park Title IV: Cane River National Heritage Area Title I: Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor - Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 - Establishes the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor in Connecticut. (Sec. 104) Sets forth the boundaries of the Corridor. (Sec. 105) Encourages the Governor of Connecticut to develop a Cultural Heritage and Corridor Management Plan, based on existing Federal, State, and local plans but coordinating such plans and presenting a comprehensive historic preservation, interpretation and recreational plan for the Corridor. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) plan preparation; (2) public involvement in plan development; (3) plan implementation; and (4) duties of the Secretary of the Interior and other Federal entities. (Sec. 109) Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Weir Farm National Historic Site Additions - Weir Farm National Historic Site Expansion Act of 1994 - Amends the Weir Farm National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1990 to expand the boundary of the Weir Farm National Historic Site in Connecticut to include specified lands. Title III: Cane River Creole National Historical Park - Cane River Creole National Historical Park and National Heritage Area Act - Establishes the Cane River Creole National Historical Park in Louisiana. (Sec. 304) Directs the Secretary to: (1) manage the Park in a manner that will preserve resources and cultural landscapes relating to the Creole culture of the Cane River and enhance public understanding of the important cultural heritage of the Cane River region; and (2) coordinate a comprehensive research program on the history of the Cane River region. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) construct, operate, and maintain an interpretive center on lands within the Park to provide for the general information and orientation needs of the Park and the National Heritage Area established by this Act; and (2) acquire lands within Park boundaries. (Sec. 306) Requires the National Park Service to prepare a general management plan for the Park. Title IV: Cane River National Heritage Area - Establishes: (1) the Cane River National Heritage Area to complement the Park and to provide for a culturally sensitive approach to the preservation of the heritage of the Cane River region; and (2) the Cane River National Heritage Area Commission to assist in implementing the purposes of this Act and to provide guidance for the management of the Area. (Sec. 403) Requires the Commission to prepare and submit a management plan for the Area to the Governor of Louisiana for approval or disapproval. (Sec. 404) Provides for termination of the Commission and continuation of national heritage area status for the Cane River region. (Sec. 406) Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
