<bill session="103" type="h" number="1356" updated="2010-04-19T02:42:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Black Canyon Conservation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To redesignate the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Monument as a national park, to create the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Conservation Area, to include the Gunnison River in the Nation's Wild and Scenic River System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400265"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="National monuments"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/16/1993--Introduced.
Black Canyon Conservation Act of 1993 - Redesignates the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Monument in Colorado as the Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Park. Establishes the Gunnison Gorge National Conservation Area (conservation area). Designates the Gunnison Gorge Wilderness (located within the conservation area) as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate the Gunnison River, Colorado, as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transmit to specified congressional committees a comprehensive plan for the long-range protection and management of the conservation area. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
