<bill session="103" type="h" number="1373" updated="2010-04-19T02:45:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, to require merchant mariners' documents for certain seamen.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E656)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-22"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Navigation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-22"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Navigation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1915" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Marine transportation"/>
		<term name="Barges"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="Merchant seamen"/>
		<term name="Passenger ships"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/16/1993--Introduced.
Amends Federal law relating to unlicensed shipping personnel to require merchant mariner's documents for individuals serving on a vessel of at least five gross tons (currently, at least 100 gross tons), subject to certain exceptions, including small passenger vessels (currently, including vessels operating only on rivers and lakes, except the Great Lakes). Replaces provisions excepting barges with provisions excepting offshore supply vessels under 100 gross tons. Prohibits the Secretary of Transportation from: (1) collecting a fee under provisions of Federal shipping law for any service related to a merchant mariner's document required to be obtained under this Act; or (2) making available to the public any personal information concerning an individual required to obtain such a document.

	</summary>
</bill>
