<bill session="103" type="h" number="1392" updated="2010-04-19T02:48:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Porkbusters III bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Spending Priority Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To rescind unauthorized appropriations for fiscal year 1993.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400398" joined="1993-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="410529" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="406431" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400156" joined="1993-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400085" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400885" joined="1993-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400389" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="401547" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404296" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="1994-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400192" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="411247" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="408364" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="405758" joined="1993-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400225" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400504" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="408553" joined="1993-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="408618" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400560" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400083" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400604" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="405560" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400079" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="410887" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="405033" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1993-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="1993-03-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E683-684)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Aeronautics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural research"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Army procurement"/>
		<term name="Astronautics"/>
		<term name="Atmospheric research"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="College sports"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commercial aviation"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Cultural relations"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Earth sciences"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational exchanges"/>
		<term name="Electric vehicles"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Energy supplies"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="General Services Administration"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Harbors"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Highway maintenance"/>
		<term name="Highway research"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Meteorology"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Oceanographic research"/>
		<term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
		<term name="Office of Science and Technology Policy"/>
		<term name="Olympic games"/>
		<term name="Pest control"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Public buildings"/>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
		<term name="Public works"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Reptiles"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Space programs"/>
		<term name="Space sciences"/>
		<term name="Sports"/>
		<term name="Transportation planning"/>
		<term name="Transportation research"/>
		<term name="Volcanoes"/>
		<term name="Weather forecasting"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
		<term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/17/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Agriculture Appropriations Title II: Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Subtitle A: Department of Commerce Subtitle B: Related Agencies Subtitle C: Department of State Title III: Defense Appropriations Subtitle A: Research, Development, Test and Evaluation Subtitle B: Other Department of Defense Programs Subtitle C: Operations and Maintenance Title IV: Energy and Water Appropriations Subtitle A: Corps of Engineers Subtitle B: Department of Energy Title V: Interior Appropriations Title VI: Transportation Appropriations Title VII: Treasury, Postal Service, and General Government Appropriations Title VIII: Veterans Affairs, Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Subtitle A: Department of Veterans Affairs Subtitle B: Independent Agencies Subtitle C: Department of Housing and Urban Development Title IX: Blue Smoke and Mirrors Spending Priority Reform Act of 1993 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that any money returned to the Treasury as a result of this Act should be deposited in the General Fund to be applied against the Federal budget deficit. Title I: Agriculture Appropriations - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to the Department of Agriculture for certain special research grants and for the construction of buildings and facilities of the Cooperative State Research Service which were not authorized, not awarded on a competitive basis, or not subjected to congressional hearings (&quot;unauthorized&quot;). Title II: Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies Appropriations - Subtitle A: Department of Commerce - Rescinds FY 1993 specified appropriations to: (1) the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and (2) the International Trade Administration. Subtitle B: Related Agencies - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to the Small Business Administration for unauthorized grants for specified miscellaneous projects. Subtitle C: Department of State - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to the Department of State for an unauthorized grant for the North/South Center at the University of Miami, Miami, Florida, and certain educational and cultural exchange programs. Title III: Defense Appropriations - Subtitle A: Research, Development, Test and Evaluation - Rescinds unauthorized FY 1993 appropriations made to the Department of Defense for: (1) university grants; (2) electrical vehicle demonstration projects; (3) Army industrial preparedness and manufacturing technology development programs; (4) medical research; (5) naval research, development, testing, and evaluation; and (5) the Space Surveillance Network Improvement Program. Subtitle B: Other Department of Defense Programs - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations for efforts to prevent brown tree snakes from entering Hawaii from Guam. Subtitle C: Operations and Maintenance - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations for the following projects: (1) self-powered locks; (2) grants for World University and 1996 Summer Olympics games and World Cup 1994; (3) Army procurement of extended cold weather clothing systems; (4) study of nuclear disposal by the former Soviet Union and for Project Peace; and (5) the Hawaiian Volcano Observatory. Title IV: Energy and Water Appropriations - Subtitle A: Corps of Engineers - Rescinds unauthorized FY 1993 appropriations for funding of surveys and planning activities and construction of water resource projects. Subtitle B: Department of Energy - Rescinds unauthorized FY 1993 appropriations made under the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1993, for funding certain energy supply, research, and development activities. Title V: Interior Appropriations - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations for unauthorized funding of: (1) certain National Park System projects; (2) certain construction projects of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service; and (3) certain National Forest Service projects. Title VI: Transportation Appropriations - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to the Department of Transportation for unauthorized funding of: (1) certain airway science programs; (2) a certain highway research, development, and technology project; (3) certain construction and maintenance projects; (4) certain Federal Highway Administration demonstration projects; and (5) transit planning and research. Title VII: Treasury, Postal Service and General Government Appropriations - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to the General Services Administration for certain unauthorized grants for projects funded through the Federal Buildings Fund. Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to the Office of Personnel Management for the establishment of health promotion and disease prevention programs. Title VIII: Veterans Affairs, Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations - Subtitle A: Department of Veterans Affairs - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to be Department of Veterans Affairs for unauthorized construction projects. Subtitle B: Independent Agencies - Rescinds 1993 appropriations to: (1) the Environmental Protection Agency for certain unauthorized projects; (2) the Consortium for International Earth Science Information Network; and (3) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for certain unauthorized research and development projects and construction projects. Subtitle C: Department of Housing and Urban Development - Rescinds FY 1993 appropriations to the Department of Housing and Urban Development for unauthorized funding of certain housing projects and assistance programs. Title IX: Blue Smoke and Mirrors - Expresses the sense of the Congress that, with regard to the appropriations process, &quot;forward funding&quot; tactics should no longer be utilized and Congress should operate within the funding limits prescribed for each fiscal year.

	</summary>
</bill>
