<bill session="103" type="h" number="1403" updated="2010-04-19T02:49:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Caribbean Basin Free Trade Agreements Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that the Caribbean Basin Initiative is not adversely affected by the implementation of the North American Free Trade Agreement and to apply &quot;fast track&quot; approval procedures to free trade agreements entered into between the United States and certain Caribbean Basin countries.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404520"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408725" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400085" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300151" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400106" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="403308" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="407672" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1993-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E698-699)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-19"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Caribbean area"/>
		<term name="Clothing industry"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
		<term name="Customs administration"/>
		<term name="Customs unions"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="Free trade"/>
		<term name="Handicraft"/>
		<term name="Import quotas"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Labor unions"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="North America"/>
		<term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
		<term name="Tariff"/>
		<term name="Tariff preferences"/>
		<term name="Textile industry and fabrics"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/18/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Relationship of NAFTA Implementation to the Operation of the Caribbean Basin Initiative Title II: Caribbean Basin Free Trade Agreements Caribbean Basin Free Trade Agreements Act - Title I: Relationship of NAFTA Implementation to the Operation of the Caribbean Basin Initiative - Amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act (the Act) to accord certain textile and apparel articles and certain other articles from Caribbean beneficiary countries the same tariff and quota treatment accorded any such articles imported from Mexico under the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA). Directs the President to: (1) monitor the effects, if any, that implementation of NAFTA has on the access of beneficiary countries to U.S. markets for sugars, syrups, and molasses; and (2) take or propose, after consulting with interested parties and appropriate congressional committees, any actions necessary to ameliorate any adverse effects such implementation may have on them. Title II: Caribbean Basin Free Trade Agreements - Directs the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to determine the feasibility of any beneficiary countries either: (1) acceding to NAFTA and any supplemental agreements pertaining to environmental, labor, and import issues; or (2) entering into bilateral or multilateral agreements with the United States that contain provisions comparable to those contained in NAFTA, or which will achieve the objectives of the Act or the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988. Authorizes the President to enter into trade agreements with beneficiary countries to provide for the elimination or reduction of any duty or trade barrier to, or other distortions to, trade with the United States. Requires the President to consult with the Congress before entering into such agreements. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to make congressional &quot;fast track&quot; procedures applicable to implementing bills submitted with respect to such trade agreements.

	</summary>
</bill>
