<bill session="103" type="h" number="1441" updated="2010-04-19T02:56:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement with the William O. Douglas Outdoor Classroom, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400025"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.1584.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Cultural property"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Mountains"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/24/1993--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to enter into cooperative agreements relating to Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area: (1) with appropriate organizations or groups (on a matching grant basis) to promote education concerning the natural and cultural resources of the Area and adjacent lands; and (2) in which the Secretary agrees to maintain the facilities at 2600 Franklin Canyon Drive, Beverly Hills, California, for eight fiscal years and to provide funding for programs of the William O. Douglas Outdoor Classroom that utilize those facilities (in return for which the Classroom agrees that at the end of the term of such agreement, all right, title, and interest in and to such facilities will be donated to the United States for addition to the Area). Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
