<bill session="103" type="h" number="1477" updated="2010-04-19T03:01:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Canyon Ferry Recreation, Tourism, and Economic Development Management Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the management of lands and recreational resources at Canyon Ferry Recreation Area, Montana, and other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411677"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E765)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-23"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Reclamation of land"/>
		<term name="Reservoirs"/>
		<term name="Tourist trade"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	
3/24/1993--Introduced.
Canyon Ferry Recreation, Tourism, and Economic Development Management Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation and the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to enter into cooperative management agreements necessary to manage the Canyon Ferry Recreation Area, Montana. Directs that such management agreement provide that the management responsibilities given to the BLM for lands withdrawn or acquired for reclamation purposes shall be accomplished in accordance with the statutory authority generally exercised by BLM in the management of public lands. Directs the Secretary to manage all lands and facilities in the Area associated with recreation, tourism, and related economic development pursuant to the Canyon Ferry Resources Management Plan of 1993. Provides that provisions of the Federal Water Project Recreation Act that limit or prescribe costs that may be incurred by Federal and non-Federal entities for recreation, planning, management, or facilities or that require non-Federal management of recreation facilities or programs shall not apply to the Area. Requires all recreation user fees collected from the Area to be retained by the managing agencies and used exclusively to fund the operation, maintenance, and development of the Area for recreation, tourism, and economic development.

	</summary>
</bill>
