<bill session="103" type="h" number="1498" updated="2010-04-19T03:05:05-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to provide for findings of presumptive disability under title II of such Act in the same manner and to the same extent as is currently applicable under title XVI of such Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E774)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/25/1993--Introduced.
Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for findings of presumptive disability under such title in the same manner and to the same extent as are currently applicable under SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income). Amends SSA title XVI to provide that any individual who receives a benefit under SSA title II on the basis of presumptive disability shall be deemed for purposes of SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to be a recipient of a benefit under SSA title XVI in any case in which he or she would be eligible for such benefit under SSA title XVI if the amount of such benefit under SSA title II were disregarded.

	</summary>
</bill>
