<bill session="103" type="h" number="1501" updated="2010-04-19T03:05:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Handgun Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the importation, manufacture, sale, purchase, transfer, receipt, or transportation of handguns, in any manner affecting interstate or foreign commerce, except for or by members of the Armed Forces, law enforcement officials, and, as authorized by the Secretary of the Treasury, licensed importers, manufacturers, dealers, and pistol clubs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411947"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403776" joined="1994-04-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-05"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Private police"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/25/1993--Introduced.
Handgun Control Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to make it unlawful to import, manufacture, sell, buy, transfer, receive, or transport any handgun. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to exempt from such prohibition such activities involving handguns by licensed importers, manufacturers, or dealers or licensed pistol clubs as required for the operation of such clubs, for the use of Federal or State agencies, or for curio, museum, or collection purposes. Sets forth requirements for the licensing of pistol clubs. Prescribes civil and criminal penalties for violation of licensing and recordkeeping requirements. Authorizes voluntary delivery of handguns to Federal, State, or local law enforcement agencies and provides for compensation to persons who establish proof of lawful acquisition and ownership. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
