<bill session="103" type="h" number="1502" updated="2010-04-19T03:05:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Timber Management Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to conduct a yield and cost study of timber management investment opportunities on Federal timberlands in California, Oregon, and Washington, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="1993-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="410567" joined="1993-04-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Forests and forestry"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Endangered animals"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Forest management"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Lumber trade"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Oregon"/>
		<term name="Owls"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Reforestation"/>
		<term name="Timber sales"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/1993--Introduced.
Timber Management Improvement Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture and of the Interior, acting through the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management, respectively, to prepare a report displaying the yields and costs (financial and environmental) of timber management investment opportunities for Federal lands in the States of California, Oregon, and Washington. Requires both Secretaries to establish advisory boards to review and comment on the investments examined. Amends the Cooperative Forest Assistance Act of 1978 to allocate appropriations for private forest lands in the States of California, Oregon, and Washington to further second growth management of timber resources to offset the expected decline in timber harvests from Federal lands as a result of listing the northern spotted owl as a threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973. Requires financial assistance to be concentrated in those counties containing Federal lands designated as habitat conservation areas for the purposes of the protection and recovery of the northern spotted owl. Amends specified Federal law (the Knutson-Vandenberg Act) to assure that amounts from the fund established by such Act are available for timber management investments on Federal lands consistent with the Act's original intent.

	</summary>
</bill>
