<bill session="103" type="h" number="1508" updated="2010-04-19T03:06:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Park System Reformation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the reformation of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400174"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400552" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="1993-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="1993-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400569" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1993-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1993-05-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E791-792)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-19"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.4476.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3709" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4476" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4476" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cultural property"/>
		<term name="Delegation of powers"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Real property"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Development of a Comprehensive Plan for the Future of the National Park System Title II: New Area Establishment Title III: Enhanced National Park Service Technical Assistance Program for Protection and Management of Natural, Cultural, and Recreation Sites National Park System Reformation Act - Title I: Development of a Comprehensive Plan for the Future of the National Park System - Establishes the National Park System Strategic Planning Commission to develop a long-term plan for the direction of the National Park System. Requires the plan to guide the System for the next ten to 20 years and to address criteria for determining inclusion or exclusion of a site within the System. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to terminate National Park Service management at all park areas as recommended by the Commission. Applies the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to all actions of the Secretary during the termination process. Directs the Administrator of General Services to delegate to the Secretary, with respect to excess and surplus real property and facilities located at such park areas, the authority to: (1) dispose of surplus property; and (2) grant certain approvals under the Surplus Property Act of 1944. Directs the Secretary, as part of each annual budget request, to transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a schedule of actions to be carried out under this title and an estimate of the total expenditures required and cost savings to be achieved by each closure, along with environmental assessments of such actions. Prohibits the Secretary from establishing new units of the System until the Commission transmits a report to the Congress. Title II: New Area Establishment - Directs the Secretary to submit reports of new area studies to the appropriate congressional committees for purposes of determining the suitability of adding such areas to the System. Requires the National Park Service to maintain a list of units in order of their numerical priority for potential addition to the System. Repeals provisions of existing law concerning inclusion of additional areas to the System. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Enhanced National Park Service Technical Assistance Program for Protection and Management of Natural, Cultural, and Recreation Sites - Establishes the American Heritage System to better protect natural, cultural, and recreational resources which do not belong in the System. Provides for administration of such sites by State and local governments and private entities with Federal technical assistance. Requires the National Park Service to establish a grant program to conduct studies for potential designations of American Heritage sites. Provides for Federal technical and financial assistance for designated sites for periods of up to ten years.

	</summary>
</bill>
