<bill session="103" type="h" number="1527" updated="2010-04-19T03:09:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a grant program to provide coordinated and comprehensive services to elementary and secondary students and families.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400586"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400205" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="1994-04-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E805)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-16"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Community and school"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Elementary school students"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
		<term name="School health programs"/>
		<term name="Secondary school students"/>
		<term name="Social work"/>
		<term name="Socially handicapped children"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/30/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a model grant program to provide coordinated social, health, and education services to elementary and secondary school students and their families (under the chapter 1 title I programs for educationally disadvantaged children). Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make such grants to selected local educational agencies (LEAs) to conduct model programs in schools where at least 30 percent of families meet poverty criteria and in such schools in partnership with community-based organizations if the LEA is responsible for fiscal administration. Sets forth program elements, Federal share, application, selection, and reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
