<bill session="103" type="h" number="1547" updated="2010-04-19T03:12:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-31">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Citizen Representative Reform Act Use a Stamp Provision</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate the franking privilege for the House of Representatives, to establish a spending allowance for postage for official mail of the House of Representatives and to limit the amount and type of mail sent by Members of the House of Representatives.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400298"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="1993-03-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congressional allowances"/>
		<term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/1993--Introduced.
Citizen Representative Reform Act Use a Stamp Provision - Abolishes the franking privilege in the House of Representatives. Establishes a spending allowance, in lieu of the Official Mail Allowance, for postage for official mail of the House. Makes such allowance available to Members in the same manner and to the same extent as the Official Mail Allowance with specified exceptions. Directs the Postmaster of the House to take necessary actions to provide for use of postage meters to record the cost and volume of mail paid for from such spending allowance for postage. Transfers all amounts that, but for the enactment of this Act, would have been available to pay for franked mail of the House to the spending allowance for postage.

	</summary>
</bill>
