<bill session="103" type="h" number="1544" updated="2010-04-19T03:12:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Community Environmental Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to reauthorize the State water pollution control revolving loan program, to provide assistance to economically distressed rural communities in the construction of wastewater treatment works and public water systems, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400331"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="402657" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="411677" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="408052" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="407351" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400578" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400534" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="408556" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="409578" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400609" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="401153" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400614" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400591" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400390" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="409633" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400611" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="404067" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400526" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="1993-03-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E827)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-12"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>See H.R.3948.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3948" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/30/1993--Introduced.
Rural Community Environmental Assistance Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to extend the authorization of appropriations for State water pollution control revolving funds through FY 2000. Requires each State to establish a rural community environmental assistance account in such fund to be used only for the construction of wastewater treatment works and public water systems in economically distressed rural communities, subject to certain loan and grant conditions. Requires States to establish grant eligibility criteria. Permits assistance to be provided only if: (1) the wastewater treatment works is consistent with planning requirements under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act; and (2) the public water system is approved by the State agency with primary enforcement authority under the Safe Drinking Water Act. Requires States, in providing such assistance, to give priority to an economically distressed rural community in which: (1) there is a need for collector sewers and interceptors to improve access to wastewater treatment facilities; (2) residents rely on inadequate wastewater treatment facilities or drinking water systems that are determined by public health officials to be a hazard; or (3) residents rely on public water systems which do not meet requirements of the Safe Drinking Water Act. Requires States to submit plans for the intended uses of amounts in rural community environmental assistance accounts to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for approval. Permits the submission of a plan only if it has been approved by a State Rural Environmental Infrastructure Advisory Panel. Withholds payments from States that fail to comply with requirements for rural community environmental assistance accounts. Directs the Administrator to: (1) make grants to regional, State, and local agencies and not-for-profit organizations to assist economically distressed rural communities by providing technical assistance for the financing, operation, and maintenance of wastewater treatment works and public water systems; and (2) set aside appropriations for such grants.

	</summary>
</bill>
