<bill session="103" type="h" number="1579" updated="2010-04-19T03:17:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Free Trade in Ideas Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To restrict the authorities of the President with respect to regulating the exchange of information with, travel to or from, and educational and cultural exchanges with, foreign countries.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400580" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="407351" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400885" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="404634" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="404013" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400585" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400539" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="409793" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400314" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1993-04-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-14"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from State.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-16"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Art objects"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Cultural relations"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational exchanges"/>
		<term name="Exhibitions"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign correspondents"/>
		<term name="Foreign news"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Freedom of speech"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Magnetic tapes"/>
		<term name="Microforms"/>
		<term name="Motion pictures"/>
		<term name="Phonorecords"/>
		<term name="Photography"/>
		<term name="Presidential powers"/>
		<term name="Press organizations"/>
		<term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
		<term name="Right to travel"/>
		<term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Trading with the enemy"/>
		<term name="Video tape recording"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
Free Trade in Ideas Act of 1993 - Amends the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, the Export Administration Act of 1979, the Trading With the Enemy Act, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, and the United Nations Participation Act of 1945 to declare that the authority granted the President under such Acts does not include the authority to regulate or prohibit: (1) the importation from or exportation to any country, or the communication or telecommunication or other form of transmission to any country, of publications, films, posters, phonograph records, photographs, microfilms, microfiche, audiotapes and video tapes, artworks, telephone conversations, other voice or data communications, telecasts, and news wire feeds; (2) other forms of telecommunications; (3) other materials which in the United States would be protected by the First Amendment to the U.S. Constitution; (4) information that is not otherwise controlled under the Export Administration Act of 1979; (5) travel related to importation, exportation, communication, telecommunication, or transmission; (6) transactions for the creation or circulation of such information, or rights to such information, whether commercial or otherwise; (7) other transactions incidental to the above-mentioned activities or transactions; (8) any transactions ordinarily incident to travel to and from any country; (9) any transactions ordinarily incident to travel and maintenance within any country; (10) any transactions incident to the arrangement, promotion, or facilitation of travel to, from, or within a country; (11) any transactions incident to nonscheduled flights or voyages to and from any country; (12) normal banking transactions incident to travel to and from any country; (13) the importation or exportation of publications or other informational materials from any country; (14) financial or other transactions, or travel, incident to activities of scholars, other educational or academic activities, cultural activities and exchanges, or public exhibitions by nationals of one country in another country; or (15) financial or other transactions related to the establishment of U.S. news bureaus in foreign countries, or the establishment of foreign news bureaus in the United States.

	</summary>
</bill>
