<bill session="103" type="h" number="1570" updated="2010-04-19T03:16:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-31">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Idaho Wilderness, Sustainable Forests and Communities Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain lands in the State of Idaho as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406605"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-07"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1890-1893)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-03"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E22-23)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.3732.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3732" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3732" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Forests and forestry"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Diversification in industry"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Forest management"/>
		<term name="Forest roads"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Lumber trade"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Timber sales"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Idaho Wilderness Title II: Idaho Forest Management Title III: Release to Multiple Use Title IV: Idaho Rural Economic Development Idaho Wilderness, Sustainable Forests and Communities Act of 1993 - Title I: Idaho Wilderness - Designates specified lands in the following Idaho national forests as wilderness and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: (1) Panhandle National Forest; (2) Clearwater National Forest; (3) Nez Perce National Forest; (4) Payette National Forest; (5) Boise National Forest; (6) Salmon National Forest; (7) Sawtooth National Forest; (8) Challis National Forest; (9) Targhee National Forest; and (10) Caribou National Forest. Amends the Endangered American Wilderness Act of 1978 to revise the boundary of the Gospel-Hump Planning Unit. Title II: Idaho Forest Management - Designates specified lands in the same Idaho national forests as management areas, wildlife corridors, a historic area, and a recreation area. Outlines management directives and emphasis for such lands. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct a project on St. Joe National Forest to demonstrate the change in timber volume resulting from investing in good sites on lands already roaded. Leaves the Jackson Bar Airstrip (known as the Wilson Bar Airstrip) open for use by recreation aviators. Directs the Secretary to modify the existing land and resource management plans for the national forests affected by this Act. Sets forth provisions concerning water quality on the Panhandle National Forest and monitoring of the areas and corridors designated by this Act. Title III: Release to Multiple Use - Releases those National Forest System lands in Idaho which were not designated as wilderness, management areas, wildlife corridors, or a historic or recreation area from certain management provisions relating to wilderness study areas to allow them to be managed for multiple use and not necessarily for the purpose of protecting their suitability for wilderness designation. Title IV: Idaho Rural Economic Development - Requires the Secretary to promote ecosystem restoration, rehabilitation programs, and projects through technical assistance, grants, and cooperative agreements with Idaho agencies, local governments, private corporations, and landowners. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
