<bill session="103" type="h" number="1578" updated="2012-07-17T06:06:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-29T15:42:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-04-29T15:42:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="150"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Expedited Rescissions Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Expedited Rescissions Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for the expedited consideration of certain proposed rescissions of budget authority.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400386"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404602" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="411725" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400882" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400520" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="409966" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="407124" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="408618" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="408556" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400548" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="409627" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="408364" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400118" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406024" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400389" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400112" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400106" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="402890" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="405507" joined="1993-04-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01T22:46:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 149 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1578 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for consideration of the bill in the Committee of theWhole. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part 1 of the report accompanying this resolution. Only those amendments printed in part 2 of the report shall be in order, to be offered and debatable in the manner specified and not subject to amendment except as specified. All points of order against the amendments shall be waived.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Committee on Government Operations Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T17:02:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 149 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T17:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 149.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2084-2104"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T17:04:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1578 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part 1 of the report accompanying this resolution. Only those amendments printed in part 2 of the report shall be in order, to be offered and debatable in the manner specified and not subject to amendment except as specified. All points of order against the amendments shall be waived.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T17:05:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 149 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T17:05:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Al Swift to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T17:05:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 149, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with two hours of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T19:32:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1578 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T11:51:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2138-2163"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T11:52:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T11:54:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 149, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Castle amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T12:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 149, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with thirty minutes of debate on the Michel amendment to the Castle substitute amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T13:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed debate on the Castle amendment, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T14:40:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1578.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T14:41:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T15:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Clinger moved to recommit with instructions to Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T15:05:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit the bill to the Committee on Rules with instructions that the Committee report the bill back forthwith with an amendment to prohibit either House from waiving, changing or suspending any provision of the Act except by statutory enactment or by a vote of 3/5 of the Members of the House involved. The amendment would also prohibit the House from considering any rescission bill introduced pursuant to the provisions of the Act under a suspension of the rules or under a special rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T15:25:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 233 (Roll no. 149).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2161-2162"/></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="150" datetime="1993-04-29T15:42:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 258 - 157 (Roll no. 150).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29T15:42:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Budget; Governmental Affairs pursuant to the order of August 4, 1977 that if one Committee reports the other Committee have thirty days to report or be discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Rules"/><text>Committee on Budget. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hr" number="149" />
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="149" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="24" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="159" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="222" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="223" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="354" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="565" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="666" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="998" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1013" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1075" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1138" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1253" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1597" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1636" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1642" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4600" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Constitutional law"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative amendments"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Presidential messages"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Supreme Court"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h31"/>
		<amendment number="h32"/>
		<amendment number="h33"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/1993--Passed House amended. Expedited Rescissions Act of 1993 - Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to allow the President to transmit to both Houses of the Congress, for expedited consideration, one special message proposing to rescind all or part of any item of budget authority provided in an appropriation bill. Requires that such special message be transmitted not later than three days after the President approves the appropriation bill and be accompanied by a draft bill or joint resolution that would, if enacted, rescind the budget authority proposed to be rescinded. Sets forth House and Senate procedures for the expedited consideration of such a proposal. Terminates the President's authority two years following enactment. Provides a special transition rule for messages of the 104th Congress proposing to rescind certain budget authority of the 103d Congress. Provides judicial review of congressional actions under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
