<bill session="103" type="h" number="1584" updated="2010-04-19T03:18:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">West Virginia Rivers Conservation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the further conservation of certain unique and nationally significant river segments in the State of West Virginia.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400331"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-03"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.3252.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3252" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3252" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="West Virginia"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Boundary Modifications Title II: Upper New National Wild and Scenic River Title III: Elk River Title IV: General Provisions West Virginia Rivers Conservation Act of 1993 - Title I: Boundary Modifications - Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978, the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987, and the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to modify boundaries of the: (1) New River Gorge National River; (2) Gauley River National Recreation Area; and (3) Bluestone National Scenic River. Title II: Upper New National Wild and Scenic River - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a segment of the Upper New River, West Virginia, as a component of the National Wild and Scenic River System. Title III: Elk River - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to study and report to specified congressional committees on the eligibility and suitability of designating a specified segment of the Elk River, West Virginia, as either a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System or a unit of the National Park System (NPS) as a national river or recreation area. Title IV: General Provisions - Calls for consolidated management between offices and personnel administering the segment of the Upper New River designated by this Act and offices and personnel administering the New River Gorge National River, the Gauley River National Recreation Area, and the Bluestone National Scenic River. Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 to make provisions of the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987 (the Act) relating to cooperative agreements and remnant lands in the Gauley River National Recreation Area applicable to the New River Gorge National River. Amends the Act to set forth provisions relating to access of the Gauley River National Recreation Area by certain noncommercial entities. Authorizes the Secretary to construct a visitor center in the vicinity of the confluence of the New and Gauley Rivers at Gauley Bridge, West Virginia. Extends certain provisions of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act with respect to segements of the Bluestone and Meadow Rivers that were found eligible in studies completed by NPS in 1983 but that were not designated as part of the Bluestone National Scenic River or the Gauley River National Recreation Area under the Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
