<bill session="103" type="h" number="1603" updated="2010-04-19T03:21:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for programs, functions, and activities of the Bureau of Land Management for fiscal years 1994 through 1997; to improve the management of the public lands; and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400612"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E886)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-03"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1626)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.2530.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2530" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2530" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional veto"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Electric power transmission"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Horses"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Protection of animals"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Reforestation"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Salt"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
		<term name="Utah"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
Authorizes appropriations for the programs, functions, and activities of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior for FY 1994 through 1997. Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (the Act) to add riparian areas as a priority for the Secretary of the Interior's inventory of all public lands and their resource and other values. Provides for congressional disapproval of the Secretary's decision to implement land use plans by the enactment of a joint (currently concurrent) resolution. Requires that land use plans be developed for all public lands outside Alaska no later than January 1, 1998, and for all public lands by January 1, 2000. Requires the Secretary to make certain evaluations and establish certain priorities with respect to the development and revision of land use plans. Changes the title of the Associate Director of BLM to Deputy Director and adds positions of BLM State Directors. Amends the Act to increase from $1,000 to $10,000 the maximum fine for violations of regulations with respect to public land management and use and for causing the death of free-roaming horses or burros on public lands. Requires the Secretary to minimize adverse environmental impacts on such lands. Adds certain environmental and outdoor recreation policies to the concerns to be represented through appointments to the Secretary's advisory councils. Changes the Secretary's submission date for a request of authorizations for programs, functions, and activities of BLM. Prohibits a regulation from imposing liability without fault with respect to a right-of-way granted, issued, or renewed under the Act to certain entities. Authorizes the sale of public lands in excess of 2,500 acres unless the Congress enacts a joint (currently concurrent) resolution disapproving such sale. Provides for judicial review of any agency actions or failure to implement the Act. Requires claimants to certain highway rights-of-way granted across public lands to file notice of their intent to maintain or abandon such claims with BLM. Provides for claim investigations and appeals for claims found to be invalid. Prohibits the Secretary from removing any wild free-roaming horses or burros from sanctuary public lands operated as such on May 22, 1991, or altering existing arrangements for the care and maintenance of such animals. Directs the Secretary to: (1) study and report to the Congress on the nature and extent of the salt loss at Bonneville Salt Flats, Utah, and on how best to preserve the resources threatened by such loss; (2) take no action to diminish the long-term sustainability of the biological resources and productive capacity of public lands; and (3) identify any portion of the public lands suitable for designation as one or more national conservation areas.

	</summary>
</bill>
