<bill session="103" type="h" number="1616" updated="2010-04-19T03:23:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Handgun Registration Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the mandatory registration of handguns.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402763"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-08"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/8/1993--Introduced.
Handgun Registration Act of 1993 - Directs the Attorney General to establish a Federal handgun registration system, to include penalties of fines and imprisonment, which shall apply in any State during a period in which the Attorney General finds that the State does not require: (1) an individual who owns, possesses, or controls a handgun to register with either a State law enforcement agency (in the case of handguns so controlled before the effective date of such a State law) or with a licensed dealer (in the case of handguns so controlled after that date); (2) imposition of specified penalties for registration requirement violations; and (3) maintenance of easily retrievable records identifying both (a) each individual residing or regularly appearing in the State who possesses, owns, or controls a handgun; and (b) the handgun. Requires the Attorney General to terminate specified law enforcement assistance under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to each State, and each recipient in the State, during a period in which the system established by this Act applies to the State.

	</summary>
</bill>
