<bill session="103" type="h" number="1633" updated="2010-04-19T03:26:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-09">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-06-09" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Judicial Reorganization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">District of Columbia Judicial Reorganization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To create a Supreme Court for the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E888)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-15"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Judiciary and Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia" subcommittee="Judiciary and Education"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-09"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 7 - 4.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Subcommittee on Judiciary and Education Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13T18:24:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on District of Columbia. H. Rept. 103-176.</text></action>
		<calendar number="99" datetime="1993-07-13T18:25:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 99.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House District of Columbia" subcommittee="Judiciary and Education" activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Courts"/>
		<term name="Administration of justice"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Child welfare"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Custody of children"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Magistrates"/>
		<term name="Paternity"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Probate law and practice"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State courts"/>
		<term name="Tax administration"/>
		<term name="Tax courts"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/13/1993--Reported to House amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Supreme Court of the District of Columbia Title II: Judges of the District of Columbia Courts District of Columbia Judicial Reorganization Act of 1993 - Title I: Supreme Court of the District of Columbia - Amends the District of Columbia Code to establish the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia (Court) consisting of a chief justice and six associate justices with jurisdiction over appeals from final decisions of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals that meet specified criteria. Allows the Court, at its discretion, to certify a case or class of cases for review before it has been determined by the D.C. Court of Appeals, but only under limited circumstances. Allows the Court to: (1) answer questions of law certified to it by the U.S. Supreme Court, a Court of Appeals of the United States, or the highest court of any State, if a question of D.C. law may be determinative of the case pending in the certifying court; and (2) order the certification of a question of law of another State to the highest court of such State. Provides for the temporary assignment of Court judges to and from other D.C. courts. Directs the chief justice of the Court to annually summon the active judges of the D.C. courts to a Judicial Conference of the District of Columbia for the purpose of advising as to the means of improving the administration of justice within the District of Columbia. Title II: Judges of the District of Columbia Courts - Makes the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission, rather than the President, responsible for designating the chief justice or chief judge of a D.C. court. Redesignates hearing commissioners as judicial magistrates. Expands the duties of such magistrates to include cases involving the establishment of paternity, certain probate and tax matters, and child delinquency and neglect. Directs the Chief Judge of the Superior Court to conduct such studies on the utilization of judicial magistrates as the Board of Judges deem expedient. Directs the Executive Officer of the District of Columbia courts to study and report to the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration in the District of Columbia, for forwarding with any comments and recommendations to the Congress, on the feasibility of establishing a District of Columbia Night Court as a division of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia.

	</summary>
</bill>
