<bill session="103" type="h" number="1678" updated="2010-04-19T03:33:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Every Fifth Child Appropriations Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations to begin a phase-in toward full funding of the special supplemental food program for women, infants, and children (WIC) and of Head Start programs, to expand the Job Corps program for the year ending September 30, 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400216"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403864" joined="1993-04-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E903-904)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Child nutrition"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
		<term name="Food relief"/>
		<term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/2/1993--Introduced.
Every Fifth Child Appropriations Act - Appropriates funds to carry out the special supplemental food program for women, infants, and children (WIC program) authorized in the Child Nutrition Act of 1966. Declares that, in order to achieve full funding for the program, there should be specified amounts appropriated in certain fiscal years. Appropriates funds to carry out the Head Start programs authorized in the Head Start Act. Declares that, in order to achieve full funding for the programs, there should be specified amounts appropriated in certain fiscal years. Appropriates funds to carry out the Job Corps program authorized in the Job Training Partnership Act. Declares that, in order to establish a minimum number of additional centers, serve a minimum additional number of youths, and achieve full funding for the program, there should be specified amounts appropriated in certain fiscal years.

	</summary>
</bill>
