<bill session="103" type="h" number="1687" updated="2010-04-19T03:34:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Schools of America (RSA) Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide financial assistance to eligible local educational agencies to improve rural education, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411677"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400580" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="408839" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="408052" joined="1993-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="411166" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="404013" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401033" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400527" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="409578" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400377" joined="1993-11-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400112" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="403308" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="408618" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="406920" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400614" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403875" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="402454" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400595" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403403" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="1994-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400554" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="409400" joined="1993-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="403873" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="404067" joined="1993-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="1994-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E911-912)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Regional educational laboratories"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Rural schools"/>
		<term name="Schools"/>
		<term name="White House conferences"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	
4/2/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Rural School Improvement Title II: School Building Repair and Renovation Title III: Evaluation of Results Subtitle A: Assistant Secretary Subtitle B: Rural School Research and Evaluation Title IV: General Provisions Rural Schools of America (RSA) Act of 1993 - Title I: Rural School Improvement - (Sec. 101) Establishes, and authorizes appropriations for, a rural school improvement (RSI) grants program to help meet national educational goals. (Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary of Education, under such program, to: (1) reserve specified funds for competitive grant awards to exemplary school programs; and (2) make allotments to State educational agencies (SEAs), for suballotment to local educational agencies (LEAs), based on relative Chapter 1 funding (for educationally disadvantaged students under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965). Requires recipient LEAs to make subgrants to community-based organizations or nonprofit partnerships between the LEA, local colleges or universities, or area-wide collaboratives of private sector businesses. (Secs. 103-106, 109, and 110) Sets forth: (1) requirements for applications, local planning, uses of funds, accountability, and local advisory groups; and (2) special rules for ranking schools within an LEA by need, flexibility, and coordination with Chapter 1 planning. (Sec. 107) Authorizes incentive awards to individual schools that demonstrate exemplary progress. (Sec. 108) Directs the Secretary to report on the impact of Federal regulations, guidelines, and policies on rural public schools. Title II: School Building Repair and Renovation - (Sec. 201) Establishes, and authorizes appropriations for, a program of assistance for rural school building repair and renovation. (Sec. 202) Allots program funds to SEAs based on relative Chapter 1 funding, with suballotments to LEAs based on number of: (1) children from families below the poverty line; (2) school buildings used for instructional purposes; and (3) school buildings more than 25 years old used for instructional purposes. (Secs. 204-207) Requires eligible LEAs to use half of their suballotment for programs for school building repair and renovation, and half for programs for school environmental concerns and safety improvements. Authorizes SEA waivers of such requirement. Applies Davis-Bacon Act requirements to such programs. Title III: Evaluation of Results - Subtitle A: Assistant Secretary - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to establish an Assistant Secretary for Rural Education in the Department of Education. Subtitle B: Rural School Research and Evaluation - (Sec. 311) Establishes, and authorizes appropriations for, a program of rural school research and evaluation. (Sec. 312) Directs the Secretary to establish for each region a National Rural Regional Education Research Center, to be operated by the appropriate regional educational laboratory. (Sec. 313) Requires each Center to make direct grants to rural LEAs in its region participating in a program assisted under title I of this Act, to conduct local schoool district research and evaluation of efforts toward meeting the national education goals. Title IV: General Provisions - (Sec. 401) Establishes the Interagency Council on Rural Schools. (Sec. 402) Directs the President to conduct a White House Conference on Rural Education. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 403) Requires eligible LEAs to use Federal funds received under this Act only to supplement but not supplant non-Federal funds.

	</summary>
</bill>
