<bill session="103" type="h" number="1698" updated="2010-04-19T03:36:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit Members of the House of Representatives from using official funds for the production or mailing of newsletters; to reduce by 50 percent the amount which may be made available for the Official Mail Allowance of any such Member; and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408839"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405939" joined="1993-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Congressional allowances"/>
		<term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/5/1993--Introduced.
Prohibits a Member of the House of Representatives from using any official funds for the production or mailing of a newsletter. Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to change the Official Mail Allowance for Members of the House of Representatives to not more than the product of: (1) one and one-half times the single-piece rate applicable to first class mail (currently three times such rate); and (2) the number of addresses in the congressional district. Requires any unobligated funds remaining in the Official Mail Allowance of a Member of the House at the end of a session of Congress to be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury and applied toward the reduction of the Federal budget deficit.

	</summary>
</bill>
