<bill session="103" type="h" number="1749" updated="2010-04-19T03:44:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Enhancement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to increase the ability of State and local governments to protect and enhance open spaces, enhance the capability of State and local governments to provide recreational opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400380"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400161" joined="1993-10-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="405758" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400117" joined="1993-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="1993-10-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300156" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="406605" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400615" joined="1993-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400554" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1993-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1993-04-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1997)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-02"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cultural property"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Limited access highways"/>
		<term name="Natural monuments"/>
		<term name="Open space lands"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Urban areas"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
		<term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1993--Introduced.
Community Enhancement Act of 1993 - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to require specified percentages of appropriations from the Land and Water Conservation Fund to be made available for assistance to States for outdoor recreation programs. Provides that payments to States for outdoor recreation may not cover more than 75 percent of: (1) the cost of acquisition of specified lands, waters, and interests; or (2) the cost of revising comprehensive State outdoor recreation plans to conform to specified requirements. Permits counties or political subdivisions to receive funds allocated to States for land acquisition purposes to cover up to 50 percent of the cost of developing or revising local plans to retain land for recreation and open space preservation purposes. Authorizes counties or other governmental entities to receive funds to cover up to 60 percent of the cost of acquiring lands, waters, or interests, following adoption of a plan and through September 30, 1997. Treats Indian tribes and Alaska Native Village Corporations collectively as one State for purposes of receiving outdoor recreation assistance and provides for a competitive grant program for the receipt of such assistance. Requires statewide outdoor recreation plans to contain: (1) a description of Federal and State activities that adversely affect open space and recreational resources; and (2) an evaluation of the extent to which local zoning or the lack of zoning contributes to degradation of State and local projects funded with outdoor recreation assistance. Establishes a program to provide Federal assistance to States, local and interstate entities, and private nonprofit organizations for the protection or establishment of: (1) Greenways (linear parks or open spaces linking natural and cultural features within or near metropolitan areas); and (2) Urban Open Space Preserves (open spaces with natural, rural, or agricultural character within large metropolitan areas). Requires the Secretary of the Interior to conduct studies and report to the Congress on Federal assistance to protect open space areas. Authorizes appropriations from the Fund for loans to State, local, or interstate entities if recreational resources are of vital significance and are in imminent danger of damage or when an opportunity to address a severe recreation deficiency will be foregone. Establishes an advisory board to assist in the selection of projects to receive such assistance.

	</summary>
</bill>
