<bill session="103" type="h" number="1740" updated="2010-04-19T03:43:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to prohibit the use of solid waste as fuel for any incinerator being used for the destruction of polychlorinated biphenyls or other hazardous substances and to require the Environmental Protection Agency to review and research methods of disposal and storage of polychlorinated biphenyls.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407351"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-30"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
		<term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to prohibit solid waste from being used as fuel in any incinerator being used for: (1) the destruction of polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) or other hazardous substances from a facility subject to a response action under CERCLA; or (2) the implementation of a response action under CERCLA. Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) review methods for disposal and long-term storage of PCBs; and (2) establish a research program on additional methods for disposal, long-term storage, and other means of containing and preventing PCB contamination. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
