<bill session="103" type="h" number="1743" updated="2010-04-19T03:43:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women's Educational Equity Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Educational Organizational Act to establish an Office of Women's Equity and to amend part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to encourage gender equity throughout the education system in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400554"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
		<term name="Women's education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to establish an Office of Women's Equity as an organizational entity in the Department of Education. Requires the Director of such Office to report annually on the programs and activities assisted under the Women's Educational Equity Act. Women's Educational Equity Act of 1993 - Amends the Women's Educational Equity Act (part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965) to reauthorize and revise grant programs to encourage gender equity throughout the educational system, including grants for model equity programs, local implementation, and research and development. Gives the Director of the Office of Women's Equity specified responsibilities under such Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
