<bill session="103" type="h" number="1786" updated="2010-04-19T03:50:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food-borne Illness Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to require the inspection of meat and poultry to determine the presence of microbial contamination that can cause food poisoning or infection in humans, to require the Secretary of Agriculture to develop appropriate labeling to warn purchasers of meat and poultry of potential microbial contamination and give proper handling and cooking instructions to destroy microbial contaminants, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406482"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="1993-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="1993-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1993-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400117" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="410567" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="411350" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1993-10-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-23"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-23"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations and Nutrition.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1021-1022)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAG-03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Department Operations and Nutrition" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural research"/>
		<term name="Animal diseases"/>
		<term name="Bacteria"/>
		<term name="Biological research"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Food contamination"/>
		<term name="Food poisoning"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Livestock"/>
		<term name="Livestock industry"/>
		<term name="Meat inspection"/>
		<term name="Meat packing industry"/>
		<term name="Poultry"/>
		<term name="Poultry industry"/>
		<term name="Poultry inspection"/>
		<term name="Vaccination"/>
		<term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/21/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendments to Federal Meat Inspection Act Title II: Amendments to Poultry Products Inspection Act Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions Food-borne Illness Prevention Act of 1993 - Title I: Amendments to Federal Meat Inspection Act - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to include in the definition of &quot;adulterated&quot; meat containing excess levels of pathogens (as defined by this Act). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish: (1) standards of animal cleanliness at inspected facilities; (2) microbial pathogen level testing of carcasses and parts, and meat articles; and (3) pathogen levels for live animals, carcasses, and raw meat and meat food products. Subjects imported meat articles to pathogen inspection. Requires raw meat labels to provide pathogen warnings as well as handling and cooking instructions. Considers an article misbranded if not so labeled. Title II: Amendments to Poultry Products Inspection Act - Amends the Poultry Products Inspection Act similarly with respect to poultry. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) programs of pathogen contamination research and animal identification; and (2) an advisory council on meat and poultry pathogen control.

	</summary>
</bill>
