<bill session="103" type="h" number="1791" updated="2010-04-19T03:51:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To restore reductions in veterans benefits made by the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400357"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411677" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="1993-04-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Compensation, Pension and Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education, Training and Employment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Memorial Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Compensation, Pension and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Education, Training and Employment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Housing and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Alcoholism"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Divorce"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Military cemeteries and funerals"/>
		<term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Remarriage"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/21/1993--Introduced.
Presumes a veteran to be totally disabled for purposes of pension determination provisions if such person is 65 or older or becomes unemployable after such age. Restores the full permitted monthly pension (currently $90) for veterans having neither spouse nor child and receiving Medicaid-covered nursing home care. Provides that the remarriage of a veteran's surviving spouse shall not eliminate the right of such former spouse to survivors' benefits if the remarriage is terminated or dissolved unless the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines that the divorce was secured through fraud or collusion by the surviving spouse. Provides similar benefits protection for a veteran's child whose marriage is dissolved without fraud or collusion. Repeals a Federal provision requiring a minimum copayment for medication received for a nonservice-connected disability by a veteran with a service-connected disability rated at 50 percent or less. Authorizes the Secretary to furnish hospital and nursing home care for the nonservice-connected disability of a veteran whose income falls below a specified level. Allows such care to be furnished to other ineligible veterans if a minimum amount is paid by such veteran. Prohibits a veteran from being required to pay for certain outpatient services furnished during any 90-day period. Revises certain income thresholds used in determining whether such payment is required. Entitles all veterans with a service-connected disability (currently, only those whose rating is 20 percent or more) to the basic veterans' educational assistance entitlement. Authorizes the Secretary, in lieu of furnishing a headstone or grave marker, to reimburse a person for the cost of such in any cemetery other than a national cemetery in the case of a veteran's burial. Allows a veteran's abuse of alcohol or drugs to be considered an injury incurred in the line of duty for purposes of eligibility for veterans' benefits and misconduct determinations.

	</summary>
</bill>
