<bill session="103" type="h" number="1808" updated="2010-04-19T03:53:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lead Battery Recycling Incentives Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to provide management standards and recycling requirements for spent lead-acid batteries.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410889"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="402763" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="408839" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403314" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400612" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400527" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="410589" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="406729" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401446" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401947" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="402152" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400572" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400314" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="403776" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1993-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1016)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Electric batteries"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Lead"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
Lead Battery Recycling Incentives Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate regulations for persons who generate, transport, store, recycle, or dispose of spent lead-acid batteries. Sets forth required elements of such regulations, including specific requirements for battery storage and transfers and recordkeeping and management practices. Directs battery retailers to accept from customers spent lead-acid batteries of the same type and quantity as the batteries sold. Requires the Administrator to implement education activities to inform the public about the environmental and safety hazards associated with improper handling and disposal of spent lead-acid batteries. Authorizes appropriations. Applies such requirements to batteries which are transported to or managed by a lead-acid battery recycling facility, a secondary lead smelter, or any facility that prepares batteries for recycling. Requires producers or importers of lead-acid batteries to recycle, for the ten-year period beginning 24 months after this Act's enactment, an amount of spent lead equal to at least the amount determined by multiplying the amount of lead in the batteries produced or imported by such persons by the recycling percentage established by the Administrator. Authorizes compliance with such requirement by: (1) reclaiming lead and using it in the production of new batteries; (2) purchasing reclaimed lead from secondary lead smelters to produce new batteries or shielding; or (3) purchasing recycling credits. Sets the recycling percentage at 80 percent. Increases such percentage by two points annually. Authorizes the Administrator to reduce or waive the two percent increase if the rate exceeds 95 percent. Directs the Administrator to allow: (1) producers of lead-acid batteries to create credits for recycling an amount of batteries greater than required; and (2) producers of new batteries to purchase such credits for purposes of complying with this Act. Applies battery recycling requirements to persons who produce or import more than 10,000 pounds of new lead-acid batteries annually. Sets the recycling percentage at 90 percent if the Administrator fails to promulgate recycling regulations.

	</summary>
</bill>
