<bill session="103" type="h" number="1824" updated="2010-04-19T03:56:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bicycle and Pedestrian Transportation Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide a minimum level of funding for bicycle transportation facilities and pedestrian walkways, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406277"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400256" joined="1994-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1993-07-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1024-1025)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Bikeways"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Forest roads"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Motorcycles"/>
		<term name="Pedestrians"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Transportation planning"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
Bicycle and Pedestrian Transportation Improvement Act of 1993 - Requires each State to obligate for bicycle transportation and pedestrian walkways not less than three percent of the funds: (1) apportioned to the State under the Congestion Mitigation and Air Quality Improvement Program and the Surface Transportation Program; (2) apportioned to the State for the National Highway System; and (3) made available for forest development roads and trails, public lands development roads and trails, park roads, parkways, Indian reservation roads, and public lands highways. Allows the Secretary of Transportation to require States to acquire right-of-ways reasonably necessary for bicycle and pedestrian facilities. Prohibits the Secretary from approving Federal-aid system projects, including bridge projects, that will result in the severance, reduction, or destruction of an existing or potential route for nonmotorized transportation traffic and light motorcycles, unless such project provides a reasonable alternative route or such route exists. Requires States to survey all public roads to identify hazardous locations which may constitute a danger to bicyclists and to correct such locations. Permits the use of electric golf carts on trails and walkways, when State and local regulations allow. Requires appointed members of the National Highway Safety Advisory Committee of the Department of Transportation to be selected from, among others, organizations representative of bicyclists and pedestrians.

	</summary>
</bill>
