<bill session="103" type="h" number="1822" updated="2010-04-19T03:56:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Counter-Terrorism Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Death Penalty Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent and punish domestic and international terrorist acts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400211"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Air piracy"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Assassination"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Bombings"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Treason"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Youth"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Punishing Domestic and International Terrorist Act Subtitle A: Terrorist Death Penalty Act of 1993 Subtitle B: Terrorist Acts Committed in the United States Subtitle C: Increasing Penalties for International Terrorist Acts Title II: Authorizations to Expand Counter-Terrorist Operations Comprehensive Counter-Terrorism Act of 1993 - Title I: Punishing Domestic and International Terrorist Acts - Subtitle A: Terrorist Death Penalty Act of 1993 - Terrorist Death Penalty Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to: (1) make it a Federal offense, punishable by up to life imprisonment, to commit terrorist acts against U.S. nationals abroad; and (2) authorize the imposition of the death penalty where terrorist acts against U.S. nationals result in first degree murder. Sets forth procedures for the imposition of the death penalty, including notice by the Government that it intends to seek the death penalty if the defendant is convicted, the conduct of the sentencing hearing, a list of mitigating and aggravating factors to be considered, proof of such factors, the return of findings, and procedures for appeal and review of a sentence of death. Prohibits sentencing to death individuals who were under age 18 at the time of the offense, or carrying out a death sentence upon a woman while she is pregnant, a person who is mentally retarded, or specified other persons under a mental disability. Subtitle B: Terrorist Acts Committed in the United States - Authorizes the imposition of the death penalty for domestic terrorist acts that involve an individual acting as an agent of a foreign power and that result in first degree murder, and up to life imprisonment for acts that result in death that does not constitute first degree murder. Sets forth penalties for: (1) attempts or conspiracy to kill; and (2) engaging in physical violence that results in serious bodily injury. Specifies that, for purposes of this Act, a person possesses an intent to commit a terrorist act if such person intends to: (1) intimidate or coerce a civilian population; (2) influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion; or (3) affect the conduct of a government by assassination, kidnapping, or other violent act. Subtitle C: Increasing Penalties for International Terrorist Acts - Increases the penalties for terrorist acts committed against U.S. nationals abroad. Title II: Authorizations to Expand Counter-Terrorist Operations - Authorizes appropriations for counter-terrorist operations and programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
