<bill session="103" type="h" number="1833" updated="2010-04-19T03:57:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the private transfer of a handgun or ammunition to any person who does not have a State permit to possess the handgun or ammunition.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1993-07-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1006-1007)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7040-7041)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit an individual not licensed to deal in firearms or ammunition under Federal law (unlicensed individual) from transferring a handgun or ammunition to another unlicensed individual unless: (1) the transferee has presented to the transferor a valid permit, issued by the State in which the transfer occurs, which allows the transferee to possess the handgun or ammunition; and (2) the transferor has made a record containing specified information. Prohibits an unlicensed individual who engages in such a transfer from failing to transmit such record to the chief law enforcement officer of the transferee's place of residence within seven days after the transfer. Prescribes penalties.

	</summary>
</bill>
