<bill session="103" type="h" number="1830" updated="2010-04-19T03:57:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Global Environmental Cleanup Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage foreign governments to adopt and enforce environmental pollution control standards to safeguard local environments from damaging industrial practices.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400273"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406768" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400389" joined="1993-05-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-30"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control equipment"/>
		<term name="Air quality"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Environmental law and legislation"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Export credit"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Industrial pollution"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="International environmental law"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
Global Environmental Cleanup Act - Directs the Secretary of State to prepare an annual report regarding the environmental protection requirements of each foreign country with respect to air and water quality and hazardous and solid waste disposal. Directs the President to use 20 percent of the aggregate amount of foreign assistance allocated each fiscal year for a foreign country to make loans to enable the country to purchase U.S. pollution control products and services and for administrative expenses. Makes such requirement inapplicable if a country assures compliance with pollution control standards and promotes protection of the local environment from damaging industrial practices. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. executive directors of each international financial institution to oppose proposed lending unless the Secretary of State determines that: (1) the borrowing country assures compliance with pollution control standards that will protect local environments from damaging industrial practices; or (2) the lending will support an industrial program that has the potential to adversely affect air or water quality or involves hazardous or solid wastes but is designed to protect the environment from damaging industrial practices.

	</summary>
</bill>
