<bill session="103" type="h" number="1850" updated="2010-04-19T04:00:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">University-Industry Technology Development Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide incentives for universities to develop effective technology development and technology transfer programs, and to enter into partnership with businesses, in coordination with State and local governments, to develop technologies and processes critical to meeting specific national goals and promoting the long-term vitality of local communities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-30"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Science"/>
		<term name="Antitrust actions"/>
		<term name="Bank accounts"/>
		<term name="Capital gains tax"/>
		<term name="Commercialization"/>
		<term name="Community and college"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="High technology industries"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Industry-university relations"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="Investment tax credit"/>
		<term name="Investments"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology policy"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/1993--Introduced.
University-Industry Technology Development Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish programs for the selection of: (1) University Technology Development Programs to provide incentives and assistance to universities seeking to develop programs to foster commercially promising basic research; and (2) University-Industry Technology Partnerships to provide incentives and assistance for businesses and universities to enter into partnerships to develop commercial applications for new technologies and processes. Sets forth application requirements and selection criteria. Directs the Secretary to select between ten and 25 meritorious proposals as University Technology Development Programs or University-Industry Technology Partnerships annually and to provide financial and technical assistance to such programs. Requires private business participants to contribute at least 50 percent of the capital requirements of the partnership and universities to contribute at least 25 percent of the capital requirements of the technology development program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to authorize partnerships to establish technology partnership accounts. Establishes a ceiling on deposits into such accounts. Permits amounts in such accounts to be invested only in interest-bearing securities or in the stock of domestic corporations (subject to the Secretary of the Treasury's approval and a percentage limitation). Provides for the nontaxability of deposits. Requires capital, capital gain, and ordinary income subaccounts to be established in such accounts. Sets forth the tax treatment of qualified and nonqualified withdrawals from accounts. Treats amounts not withdrawn from the account after a period of ten taxable years as nonqualified withdrawals subject to taxation. Establishes a technology partnership investment tax credit. Excludes the applicable percentage of any long-term capital gain recognized on the sale or exchange of a technology program investment held for more than five years from gross income. Requires all cooperative activities and joint ventures in furtherance of the goals of a University Technology Development Program or a University-Industry Technology Partnership to be judged by the rule of reason in any Federal or State antitrust action. Limits damages in such actions to actual damages and attorney's fees. Authorizes programs or partnerships to seek antitrust rulings by the Secretary of Commerce on proposed activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
