<bill session="103" type="h" number="1867" updated="2010-04-19T04:03:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Pesticides Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act with respect to public health pesticides.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400112"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400509" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400505" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="404013" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400574" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="406729" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="406920" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="410084" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400572" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="403864" joined="1993-04-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1041)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations and Nutrition.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from EPA, USDA, HHS.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Department Operations and Nutrition" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Insect control"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Pest control"/>
		<term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
		<term name="Public health"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Rodenticides"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/27/1993--Introduced.
Public Health Pesticides Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to consider the risks and benefits of public health pesticides separately from the risks and benefits of other pesticides. Requires the Administrator, in weighing any regulatory action concerning a public health pesticide, to weigh any risks of the pesticide against the health risks to be controlled by the pesticide. Defines: (1) a &quot;public health pesticide&quot; as a minor use pesticide registered for use and used predominantly in public health programs for vector control or other health protection uses; and (2) &quot;vector&quot; as any animal capable of transmitting the causative agent of human disease or of producing human discomfort or injury. Exempts from reregistration fees public health pesticides of which more than 50 percent of usage (or at least 50 percent in the case of certain end use products) is devoted to the promotion of public health. Provides for expedited processing and review of pesticide applications that propose the initial or amended registration of an end use pesticide that, if registered as proposed, would be used as a public health pesticide. Provides for review by the Secretary of Health and Human Services of registrations of public health pesticides proposed for cancellation. Directs the Administrator to identify pests of significant public health importance and to implement programs to improve and facilitate the safe use of methods to combat such pests.

	</summary>
</bill>
