<bill session="103" type="h" number="1884" updated="2010-04-19T04:05:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Fraud and Abuse Commission Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Fraud Prosecution Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a Federal response to fraud in connection with the provision of or receipt of payment for health care services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400553" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="401014" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="401417" joined="1993-11-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicare fraud"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public prosecutors"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/28/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Health Care Fraud Prosecution Act of 1993 Title II: Health Care Fraud and Abuse Commission Act of 1993 Title I: Health Care Fraud Prosecution Act of 1993 - Health Care Fraud Prosecution Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide penalties for fraud by health care providers in connection with the provision of, or payments or reimbursement for, health care services or supplies, when: (1) the loss caused by the fraudulent conduct exceeds $10,000; or (2) the offender has previously been convicted of fraud in Federal or State court. Limits such penalties to ten years' imprisonment, unless the offense caused serious physical injury to, or endangered the life of, a patient (up to 20 years' imprisonment) or caused the death of a patient (up to life imprisonment). Specifies that the sentencing court shall order a person convicted of an offense under this title to pay restitution to the patient and any payor for losses sustained as a result of the offense. Provides for criminal forfeiture of the proceeds of health care fraud. Authorizes the Attorney General to make payments of up to $10,000 to persons who furnish information unknown to the Government relating to a possible prosecution for health care fraud, with exceptions. Authorizes appropriations for the Federal Bureau of Investigation, U.S. Attorneys, and the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to hire, equip, and train personnel in connection with the investigation and prosecution of health care fraud cases. Includes within the scope of the mail fraud statute cases involving matter to be sent or delivered by any private or commercial interstate carrier. Title II: Health Care Fraud and Abuse Commission Act of 1993 - Health Care Fraud and Abuse Commission Act of 1993 - Establishes the Health Care Fraud and Abuse Commission to investigate the nature, magnitude, and cost of health care fraud and abuse and develop methods for its prevention, detection, and prosecution or litigation. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
