<bill session="103" type="h" number="1880" updated="2010-04-19T04:05:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Workers Economic Reinvestment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To mitigate the adverse effects on defense contractors and defense workers of reductions in defense spending.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401014"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400509" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="405855" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1993-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-30"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-30"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-30"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Growth and Credit Formation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15"><committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on SBA Legislation and the General Economy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-24"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Executive Comment Received from Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Growth and Credit Formation" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="SBA Legislation and the General Economy" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Apprenticeship"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Commercialization"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conversion of industries"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense contracts"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Defense industries"/>
		<term name="Defense procurement"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Industrial parks"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Occupational retraining"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/28/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Defense Procurement Specifications Title II: Retraining Defense Workers for New Employment Title III: Commercialization and Dual-Use Research Opportunities for Defense Contractors and Small Business Title IV: Fast Response State Technological Competitiveness Grants Defense Workers Economic Reinvestment Act of 1993 - Title I: Defense Procurement Specifications - Directs the Secretary of Defense to examine and report to the Congress on all existing Department of Defense (DOD) procurement contracts to determine whether those which apply to dual-use technologies (having both military and commercial applications) contain overly restrictive specifications on systems, supplies, and services that are also available commercially. Requires defense procurement specifications to encourage the use of commercially available systems, supplies, and services. Title II: Retraining Defense Workers for New Employment - Directs the Secretary to establish an Office of Training Oversight and Administration to coordinate and oversee retraining, placement, and other transition assistance for former employees of qualified defense contractors or former civilian DOD employees. Directs the Office to disseminate retraining and placement assistance information. Authorizes the Office to: (1) carry out a skills development program for retraining eligible defense workers in skills determined to be in short supply; and (2) award one- and two-year scholarships to assist such eligible defense workers to attend educational institutions. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Commercialization and Dual-Use Research Opportunities for Defense Contractors and Small Business - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program to assist qualified defense contractors to participate in the Advanced Technology Program of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and other appropriate programs of the Department of Commerce to commercialize significant new scientific discoveries and technologies. Directs the Secretaries of Defense and Energy to encourage research proposals involving dual-use applications and proposals involving military to civilian conversion. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to make loans to qualified defense contractors to carry out commercialization projects. Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) encourage the creation of industrial parks or technology incubator centers to transfer technology from defense contractors to small businesses; and (2) create and administer an awards program for redirection efforts by qualified defense contractors in the area of commercialization. Title IV: Fast Response State Technological Competitiveness Grants - Provides Federal grants to States for defense reinvestment programs which stress economic development, quality job growth, education and retraining, technology transfer and infrastructure, and enhanced competitiveness. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
