<bill session="103" type="h" number="1957" updated="2010-04-19T04:17:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the base closure laws to require the Secretary of Defense to transfer real property and facilities at military installations being closed or realigned to States and other entities that agree to convert the property and facilities into correctional facilities for youthful offenders to be operated as military-style boot camps and to require the Secretary to develop a program to promote the expanded use of such correctional facilities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400055"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400428" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404503" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1993-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1994-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="406431" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400502" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="408618" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="403190" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400107" joined="1994-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1993-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="403864" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="405507" joined="1993-05-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1190)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Correctional institutions"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="Military training camps"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
		<term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 and the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act to require the Secretary of Defense, before any action is taken with respect to the disposal or transfer of real property at a military facility being closed or realigned, to notify the State and each local government in which the facility is located, as well as other interested persons, of the suitability of the property or facility for conversion and use as a youthful offender boot camp. Requires the State, local government, or interested party to whom such real property is so transferred to certify that the property or facilities will be promptly converted and used for such purpose. Directs the Secretary to develop a model program intended to incorporate military basic training, instruction, and disciplinary procedures into the design and operation of youthful offender boot camps at the Federal, State, and local levels. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to reallocate between public agencies and private nonprofit organizations the percentage of grant funds authorized under such Act for correctional options that provide alternatives to traditional modes of incarceration and offender release programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
