<bill session="103" type="h" number="1965" updated="2010-04-19T04:18:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Universal Coordinated Care Act of 1992</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals a deduction from gross income for contributions to health services savings account; to amend the Social Security Act to provide for universal coverage of basic health needs for all Americans; to expand Medicare to include preventive and long-term care services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400334"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-10"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Balance of payments"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Cancer"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Free trade"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medical tests"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Mental health services"/>
		<term name="National health insurance"/>
		<term name="Nutrition"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Surveys"/>
		<term name="Tariff"/>
		<term name="Tax administration"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exemption"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1993--Introduced.
Universal Coordinated Care Act of 1992 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual a tax credit for certain amounts paid by or on behalf of such individual to a health services account for the payment of qualified health expenses. Provides for the certification of a health services supplemental policy as a health insurance policy or other health benefit plan offered by a private entity to an individual which provided reimbursement for expenses incurred, or services for catastrophic and long-term care. Requires any amount distributed out of a health services account to be included in the taxable income of the distributee. Imposes a penalty on distributions not used to pay qualified health expenses. Declares such accounts exempt from tax, unless the distributee engages in prohibited transactions or the account is pledged as security for a loan. Terminates such accounts on the death of the distributee. Requires a Health and Human Services report to the Congress on minimum standards for health services supplemental policies. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide coverage of home care services for qualified patients. Amends the Social Security Act to set forth the conditions a home health agency must meet in order to receive Federal funding for the provision of home care services. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Social Security Act to establish the national care voucher program under which U.S. citizens, resident aliens, and certain officers and employees of international organizations or foreign governments, are eligible for benefit coverage through the purchase of insurance through a national care voucher. Sets forth guidelines governing annual deposits to employee voucher accounts by employers and the United States. Exempts certain small employers from the requirements of new title XXII, including those participating in a small employer health plan. Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) minimum standards and requirements for the certification of health care insurance policies eligible to be purchased under this new title; and (2) a procedure for certifying such policies. Sets forth procedures for health insurance enrollment under the national care voucher program. Requires each carrier of small employer health insurance to register with the Secretary. Requires such a carrier to offer the same health plan to any small employer located in the same community. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a trade or business expense deduction for expenses paid or incurred by a small employer for a certified health care insurance policy. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require the Trade Representative to identify a foreign country as a high cost priority foreign country if the trade deficit between the United States and such country exceeds 15 percent of the total U.S. trade deficit and such country has entered into a free trade agreement with the United States. Imposes an equity tax of one percent of the value of the merchandise entered by high cost priority foreign countries. Establishes an Equity Health Insurance Trust Fund. Transfers to such Fund the equity taxes. Makes amounts in such fund available to provide payments to national voucher accounts.

	</summary>
</bill>
