<bill session="103" type="h" number="1967" updated="2010-04-19T04:18:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tire Recycling and Recovery Act of 1991</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to provide for a scrap tire management and recovery program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409966"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1993-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400527" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407558" joined="1993-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400417" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400539" joined="1993-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="401774" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1993-07-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1126)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Automobile tires"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fire prevention"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
		<term name="Insect control"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
		<term name="Rubber industry"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Tire industry"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1993--Introduced.
Tire Recycling and Recovery Act of 1991 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require States to submit scrap tire management plans to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for approval. Requires the Administrator to: (1) distribute guidelines and a model plan to States; (2) review and audit plans periodically; and (3) promulgate plans for States that fail to do so. Sets forth plan requirements and declares that plans must: (1) address the reduction and elimination of existing scrap tire piles that contain more than 3,000 scrap tires; (2) address current and future disposal, recycling, recovery, and reuse of scrap tires; and (3) provide for the issuance of permits to owners or operators of scrap tire collection sites and others who handle scrap tires. Authorizes the Administrator to provide financial assistance to States for conducting surveys of scrap tire piles and for developing and implementing tire plans. Prohibits: (1) the disposal of scrap tires in a landfill, monocell, or monofill; (2) the operation of collection sites, except in compliance with specified regulations; (3) the storage of more than 3,000 scrap tires for more than 60 days at collection sites, unless necessary for further reuse, recovery, or recycling; (4) the commingling of new scrap tires with existing scrap tire piles; (5) the transfer of control over scrap tires for transportation to a collection site to a transporter without a permit; and (6) the operation and maintenance of a pile or collection site, or the delivery or receipt of scrap tires for storage or disposal at a collection site, except in compliance with a permit. Exempts specified persons from such prohibitions if no threat of an adverse health or environmental effect will result from the exemption. Authorizes civil or criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Directs the Administrator to prepare guidelines for the Federal procurement of items that make use of rubber from scrap or used tires. Requires the Administrator to implement a plan for, and report to the Congress on, the abatement of scrap tire piles on Federal land. Repeals a provision concerning grants for discarded tire disposal.

	</summary>
</bill>
