<bill session="103" type="h" number="1992" updated="2010-04-19T04:22:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Endangered Species Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to ensure that listing of species is in the public interest, that species are listed only on basis of actual threats, not speculative future threats to their existence, that listing of species and designation of their critical habitat will be subject to blind peer review, that persons conducting listing processes do not benefit economically from a listing decision, that emergency listing without full public and scientific community participation will occur only in emergency situations, that incidental take prosecutions will occur only after a recovery plan has been prepared which provides guidance as to what constitutes a take, and that the Act does not encourage suits between private citizens, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400398" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400552" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400534" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400504" joined="1993-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400601" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="411178" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="405033" joined="1993-05-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Eminent domain"/>
		<term name="Endangered species"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/5/1993--Introduced.
Endangered Species Improvement Act of 1993 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Secretary of the Interior (or of Commerce or Agriculture, under specified circumstances) to determine that a species is endangered or threatened if the Secretary determines that: (1) the species warrants listing as an endangered or threatened species because of natural or manmade factors affecting its continued existence; and (2) such listing is in the public interest (after considering specified factors, including any beneficial or adverse effects which may result from the application of or the protections of the Act to such species). Directs the Secretary, prior to making any such determination, to submit for peer review all information on and analyses of the species or habitat upon which such determination will be made to a panel of experts who are not employed by, under contract to, or recipients of grants from the department of the Secretary. Bars any person who participates formally in such determination from receiving any funding pursuant to the Act or any other authority of the Secretary to study, conduct research on, undertake conservation activities for, or otherwise address the species involved. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) estimating the number of a species subject to a proposed rule; (2) applying the emergency listing process to situations involving &quot;an immediate threat of extinction&quot; (currently, &quot;a significant risk to the well-being&quot; of a species); (3) limiting application of the taking prohibition prior to completion of a recovery plan; and (4) eliminating citizen suits against private parties. Directs the head of any Federal agency who takes an action under the Act to compensate the owner of private property for any diminution in value caused by the action.

	</summary>
</bill>
