<bill session="103" type="h" number="1994" updated="2012-07-17T05:02:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20T13:04:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-11-20T13:04:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for environmental research, development, and demonstration for fiscal years 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="406420" joined="1993-07-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="REFERRED"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation Prior to Introduction.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-10"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-30"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18T19:44:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space and Technology. H. Rept. 103-376.</text></action>
		<calendar number="207" datetime="1993-11-18T19:44:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 207.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20T12:44:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Valentine moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20T12:44:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10343-10349"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20T12:44:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-11-20T13:04:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20T13:04:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20T13:04:00-05:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-23"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Toxic Substances and Research. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Toxic Substances, Research and Development" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1419" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1545" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conversion of industries"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Lead"/>
		<term name="Management audit"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research and development contracts"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Statistics"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Water purification"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Passed House amended. Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1993 - Authorizes appropriations to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for FY 1994 for the Office of Research and Development for environmental research, development, and demonstration activities and for program management and support. (Sec. 2) Prohibits the Administrator from closing Office field stations, laboratories, or other research centers or permitting Office reductions-in-force unless congressional committees have received advance notice. (Sec. 3) Directs the Administrator to establish in the Office separately identified core research programs consisting of fundamental research on ecology and environmental science and on exposure to, and effects of, environmental contamination. Requires such research to support efforts to assess and mitigate serious environmental risks. (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator to establish an Environmental Monitoring and Assessment Program to conduct environmental research and development to design a long-term environmental monitoring program to determine the current condition of, and trends in, U.S. ecological resources. Requires the Administrator to make available to the public and the Congress statistical data summaries and interpretive reports on ecological status and trends. (Sec. 5) Directs the Administrator to: (1) establish a modernization program for Office laboratories to identify, acquire, and maintain modern buildings, facilities, supplies, and equipment needed to conduct high quality research; and (2) conduct studies and make assessments of the adequacy of the equipment and facilities to meet the needs of EPA and to attract well-qualified scientists, engineers, and other appropriate personnel. (Sec. 6) Repeals a required annual report from the Administrator of a five-year plan for environmental research, development, and demonstration. (Sec. 10) Directs the Administrator to: (1) carry out a program of environmental technology transfer and exchange of scientific information to make full use of the Office's research, development, and demonstration efforts; and (2) establish a separately identified research program to improve EPA's capability to identify and assess risks resulting from environmental contamination. (Sec. 12) Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish a program to conduct research on lead; (2) carry out a research program within the Office to reduce scientific uncertainties with respect to risk assessment; and (3) report to the Congress on opportunities for the technology transfer of defense-related research for environmental applications. (Sec. 15) Authorizes the Administrator to enter into a cooperative agreement with a non-Government research foundation to conduct research on the disinfection of drinking water, subject to matching funding requirements. (Sec. 16) Directs the Administrator to enter into an arrangement with a private entity to study and make recommendations regarding the Office's acquisition and assistance management practices. Allocates funding for the lead and drinking water research programs and for the private study concerning the Office's acquisition practices. (Sec. 17) Expresses the sense of the Congress that any recipient of a grant under this Act should purchase, when available and cost-effective, American-made equipment and products when expending grant monies.

	</summary>
</bill>
