<bill session="103" type="h" number="2026" updated="2010-04-19T04:28:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Renewables and Energy Efficiency Incentives Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage energy efficiency and the production and use of renewable energy.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400262"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1993-06-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1182-1183)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Revenue Measures.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means" subcommittee="Select Revenue Measures"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-05" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Select Revenue Measures" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Accounting"/>
		<term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
		<term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
		<term name="Business losses"/>
		<term name="Coal"/>
		<term name="Depletion allowances"/>
		<term name="Electric power production"/>
		<term name="Electric utilities"/>
		<term name="Electric vehicles"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy tax credits"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Gas companies"/>
		<term name="Gasoline tax"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Motor buses"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
		<term name="Natural gas"/>
		<term name="Nuclear energy"/>
		<term name="Petroleum"/>
		<term name="Public utilities"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
		<term name="Trucks"/>
		<term name="Wind power"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/6/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Incentives for Production and Use of Renewable Energy Sources Title II: Incentives to Promote Energy Efficiency Title III: Revenue Increases Renewables and Energy Efficiency Incentives Act of 1993 - Title I: Incentives for Production and Use of Renewable Energy Sources - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow energy tax credits to offset 25 percent of tentative minimum tax. Includes certain small wind turbine equipment as energy property for purposes of the energy credit. Makes lessees of electric facilities eligible for the credit for producing electricity from renewable resources. Title II: Incentives to Promote Energy Efficiency - Makes certain trucks, vans, and buses eligible for the deduction for clean-fuel vehicles. Denies any credit for which such deduction is allowable. Allows electric or gas utilities a deduction for energy conservation expenditures. Removes the limitation on the exclusion from gross income for nonresidential property for energy conservation subsidies provided by public utilities. Title III: Revenue Increases - Reduces the credit for ethanol blenders. Increases the Highway Trust Fund financing rate for determining the tax on gasoline mixed with alcohol at a refinery. Reduces such financing rate for methanol and ethanol fuels. Prohibits an exemption from tax for interest on any bond used to finance certain electric generating facilities. Repeals the tax-exempt status of electric companies. Imposes a security rate tax on petroleum. Limits the deduction for percentage depletion for oil and gas wells to their adjusted basis. Repeals the exception from passive loss limitations for working interests in oil and gas properties.

	</summary>
</bill>
