<bill session="103" type="h" number="205" updated="2010-04-18T23:31:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Prohibiting the manufacture, sale, delivery, or importation of certain motor vehicles and rail cars that do not have seat belts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405939"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-15"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Motor buses"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
		<term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
		<term name="Railroad safety"/>
		<term name="School buses"/>
		<term name="Seat belts"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Prohibits the manufacture, sale, delivery, or importation of certain motor vehicles or rail cars unless they are equipped with seat belts, with particular emphasis on the use of a flight attendant double shoulder harness mechanism. Declares that such prohibition shall apply to: (1) any motor or rail carrier; and (2) any Federal, State, or local entity, school district, charitable organization, church, or other public or private entity providing transportation to passengers by motor vehicle or by rail. Requires persons who own or operate a motor vehicle or rail car constructed before enactment of this Act and used to provide passenger transportation for compensation, or to transport children under the age of 18, to equip such vehicle or rail car with seat belts or flight attendant double shoulder harness mechanisms. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of such prohibition.

	</summary>
</bill>
