<bill session="103" type="h" number="206" updated="2010-04-18T23:32:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require that passenger vans shall be subject to the same Federal motor vehicle safety standards as are applicable to passenger motor vehicles and to require manufacturers of motor vehicles to provide for dissemination to the public all vehicle warranty and repair information provided dealers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405939"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Automobile repair"/>
		<term name="Automobile safety standards"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
		<term name="Recreational vehicles"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Warranties"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Subjects passenger vans to the same safety standards applicable to passenger motor vehicles under the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1966. Amends the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1966 to require vehicle manufacturers to provide the Secretary of Transportation with motor vehicle warranty and repair information the manufacturer provides its dealers. Directs the Secretary, through the Auto Safety Hotline of the National Traffic Safety Administration, to make such information available to the public. Imposes civil penalties upon manufacturers that fail to provide such information.

	</summary>
</bill>
