<bill session="103" type="h" number="2089" updated="2010-04-19T04:37:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Health Insurance Purchasing Cooperatives Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the use of State-coordinated health insurance buying programs and assist States in establishing Health Insurance Purchasing Cooperatives, through which small employers may purchase health insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400572"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1224)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-14"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.R.3600.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3600" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Cooperative societies"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1993--Introduced.
Health Insurance Purchasing Cooperatives Act - Mandates grants to States for the administrative costs of planning and implementing coordinated buying programs through which small employers may purchase employee health insurance. Requires that the programs be the sole mechanism for small employers to purchase such insurance. Requires that a State program provide each small employer in the State access to health insurance for its employees and their dependents through one or more Health Insurance Purchasing Cooperatives. Waives Federal and State antitrust laws. Authorizes appropriations. Establishes the National Health Board. Requires the Board to establish Coordinated Buying Program Precepts setting forth certain criteria, including regarding a uniform data system, collection of outcomes data, and determining minimum benefit requirements. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Board to establish minimum benefit requirements for plans offered through Cooperatives. Amends provisions of the Public Health Service Act relating to health maintenance organizations (HMOs) to exempt from those provisions HMOs that provide services meeting the requirements under this Act. Establishes the National Health Insurance Data System, consisting of: (1) a National Data Base for Health Insurance and Health Outcomes Information; (2) no more than five Regional Health Insurance Data Centers; and (3) an electronic health insurance and outcomes data processing mechanism. Requires the Board to: (1) establish uniform billing and claims forms and mandatory reporting requirements; and (2) require carriers to issue to each participant an electronic processing card containing certain information on financial, administrative, and health outcomes matters. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction to self-employed individuals of 100 percent of the amount paid for health insurance purchased through a Cooperative. Retains current provisions allowing a deduction of 25 percent of the amount paid for health insurance not purchased through a Cooperative. Removes provisions ending, on a specified date, deductibility of health insurance payments by self-employed individuals.

	</summary>
</bill>
