<bill session="103" type="h" number="2080" updated="2010-04-19T04:36:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-11">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-11"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Land Reform and Reassessment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the management of public lands used for military purposes, to require assessments of future needs for withdrawals of public lands for such uses, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400612"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409954" joined="1994-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1204)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-29"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Received from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Air routes"/>
		<term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Fire prevention"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
		<term name="Military aviation"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="National Guard"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/11/1993--Introduced.
Military Land Reform and Reassessment Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to permit: (1) the military department of any State (currently, limited to Federal departments and agencies) to use, occupy, and develop public lands, subject to specified requirements; and (2) the use of public lands within the State by the military department of one or more States for military training, equipment testing, or other authorized military activities. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) issue a general authorization for the military department of one or more States to use public lands for activities the Secretary finds are not likely to result in a significant degree of residual contamination of affected lands; (2) permit such use for activities that would result in a significant degree of residual contamination under specified circumstances; and (3) waive rental charges for the use of public land by a State military department for military training, equipment testing, and other authorized military activities. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) reporting requirements; and (2) reimbursement by the Secretary of Defense of a State military department for costs to such department incident to the use of lands by a State National Guard or by U.S. armed forces for specified purposes. Revises provisions with respect to authority over the interchange of lands. Sets forth provisions regarding the monitoring of, effect of, and restrictions on military aircraft overflights over nonmilitary public lands and lands managed by the Secretary of Agriculture. Directs the Secretaries of the Interior and Defense to submit to the Congress an inventory of all public lands withdrawn for military purposes. Requires each future-years defense plan to include an identification of public lands whose withdrawal under the Engle Act is expected to be requested during the years covered by such plan. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the termination of military uses of withdrawn public lands; and (2) restrictions on use for military purposes of lands in the Orchard training area, Idaho.

	</summary>
</bill>
