<bill session="103" type="h" number="2127" updated="2010-04-19T04:43:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Child Welfare Services Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IV of the Social Security Act to establish a new comprehensive child welfare services program under part E, to make other amendments to the programs under parts B and E, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400428"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400509" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400161" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1993-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="1993-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400390" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="402152" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1993-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2469)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="Child welfare"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Foster home care"/>
		<term name="National service"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Student aid"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/13/1993--Introduced.
Comprehensive Child Welfare Services Reform Act of 1993 - Amends title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish a new comprehensive child welfare services program under part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance). Authorizes appropriations. Amends SSA title IV part B (Child-Welfare Services) to provide for coordination with other programs providing services to children and families. Amends SSA title XI to revise demonstration waiver provisions. Amends SSA title IV parts B and E to provide for recovery of training costs. Amends SSA title IV part E to make permanent the independent living program and to maintain basic and additional ceiling amounts at the latter amounts authorized under current law. Provides that in determining the eligibility of an individual aged 16 for foster care maintenance payments under such part, the State agency shall disregard from the resources of the individual an amount not exceeding what the agency determines to be reasonable for the purpose of achieving self-sufficiency. Amends the Adoption Assistance and Child Welfare Act of 1980 to repeal provisions respecting the annual report on voluntary placement.

	</summary>
</bill>
