<bill session="103" type="h" number="2134" updated="2012-07-17T05:47:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-02T14:01:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-08-02T14:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the conservation and management of interjurisdictional fisheries along the Atlantic coast by providing for greater cooperation among the States in implementing conservation and management programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1993-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="407141" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="1993-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="401383" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="1993-07-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1259)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Management.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Fisheries Management"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-30"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Management Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02T12:01:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries. H. Rept. 103-202.</text></action>
		<calendar number="113" datetime="1993-08-02T12:02:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 113.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02T13:55:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Studds moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02T13:55:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5576-5578"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02T13:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-08-02T14:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02T14:02:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Fisheries Management" activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" />
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1126" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
		<term name="Aquaculture"/>
		<term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Interstate compacts"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Seizure of vessels and cargoes"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Territorial waters"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/1993--Passed House amended. Atlantic Coastal Fisheries Cooperative Management Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior to develop and implement a program to support the fisheries management programs of the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission, including elements to support and enhance State cooperation in: (1) collection, management, and analysis of fisheries data; (2) law enforcement; (3) habitat conservation; (4) fisheries research; and (5) fishery management planning. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to prescribe regulations to govern fishing in the Exclusive Economic Zone that are necessary to support the effective implementation of the interstate fishery management plan adopted for a fishery for which no Federal fishery management plan is in effect. Makes specified enforcement and penalty provisions of the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act apply with respect to the regulations. Directs the Commission to prepare and adopt fishery management plans or amendments to provide for the conservation and management of coastal fishery resources. Regulates: (1) plan and amendment contents; and (2) the time frame for State implementation and enforcement. Requires the Commission to: (1) establish standards and procedures for the preparation of interstate fishery management plans under this Act; and (2) annually monitor State implementation and enforcement. Establishes procedures with respect to State noncompliance with interstate fishery management plans. Provides for review by the Secretary of Commerce of Commission determinations of noncompliance. Requires the Secretary, upon determining that a State has failed to implement and enforce an interstate fishery management plan, to declare a moratorium on fishing for the species covered by the plan within the waters of that State. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) termination of any such moratorium upon notification by the Commission of its withdrawal of a determination of noncompliance by a State; and (2) prohibited acts during any such moratorium. Imposes civil and criminal penalties, including civil forfeiture of vessels and fish, for violations. Directs that any such moratorium be enforced by the Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
