<bill session="103" type="h" number="2133" updated="2010-04-19T04:44:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Nonproliferation Safeguards Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the effectiveness of international nonproliferation safeguards.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1260)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Operations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Fissionable materials"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="Nuclear exports"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/1993--Introduced.
International Nonproliferation Safeguards Reform Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of State, during FY 1994 and 1995, to provide additional assistance to the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) for: (1) the implementation by the IAEA of reforms to strengthen the effectiveness of IAEA safeguards; and (2) contributions to the IAEA Technical Assistance and Cooperation Fund. Conditions such assistance on the President's certification to the Congress that the IAEA is taking steps to implement such reforms. Requires the President to direct the U.S. representatives to the IAEA to work toward the early adoption of reforms, including: (1) improving access to nuclear facilities within non-nuclear weapon states; (2) increasing the transparency of internaional nuclear commerce; (3) improving access to information about nuclear activities of IAEA member states; and (4) examining the advisability of conducting less frequent inspections at nuclear facilities in member states which consent to short notice, unrestricted inspections and which accept construction or modification safeguards and agree not to place certain limitations on inspectors. Authorizes additional appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
