<bill session="103" type="h" number="2132" updated="2010-04-19T04:44:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Recreational Camp Safety Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require recreational camps to report information concerning deaths and certain injuries and illnesses to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, to direct the Secretary to collect the information in a central data system, to establish a President's Advisory Council on Recreational Camps, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400370"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1993-11-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400322" joined="1993-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400502" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="406277" joined="1994-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="411947" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400590" joined="1994-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400595" joined="1994-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1260-1261)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Accidents"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Camping"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Child molesting"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Diseases"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Presidential commissions"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="Statistics"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Recreational Camp Reporting Requirements and Data Base Title II: President's Advisory Council on Recreational Camps Recreational Camp Safety Act - Title I: Recreational Camp Reporting Requirements and Data Base - Requires a recreational camp in a State to report to the Secretary of Health and Human Services on: (1) each medical incident that occurs at the camp; and (2) each incident of sexual abuse that is alleged to have occurred at the camp involving a camper or staff member as a victim and that has previously been reported to another governmental agency. Directs the Secretary to: (1) collect such information in a central data system in a manner that will enable compilation of separate statistics concerning incidents that involve campers, staff members, recreational camp operators and directors; and (2) report to the President, the Congress, the National Association of Governors, and the National Association of State Legislatures on a comprehensive analysis of the information. Authorizes the Secretary to issue advisories to assist States in the prevention of deaths, injuries, and illnesses at recreational camps. Requires a recreational camp to record information in a medical log concerning an incident that is required to be reported and such other illnesses and injuries that occur at the camp as the Secretary may prescribe. Requires the Secretary to advise each State agency that has legal responsibility for public health and each State agency that issues a license to a recreational camp of any failure by a camp to comply with any requirements of this Act. Title II: President's Advisory Council on Recreational Camps - Establishes the President's Advisory Council on Recreational Camps to develop model safety guidelines for recreational camps.

	</summary>
</bill>
