<bill session="103" type="h" number="2146" updated="2010-04-19T04:46:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Park Service Concessions Policy Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the concessions policies of the National Park Service, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400388"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400161" joined="1993-07-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4519)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See S.208.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="743" />
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1493" />
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="208" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="208" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Concessions"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Public utilities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/18/1993--Introduced.
National Park Service Concessions Policy Reform Act of 1993 - Repeals the Concessions Policy Act of 1965. Provides that such repeal shall not affect the validity of any contract entered into under such Act. Applies the provisions of this Act to such contract to the extent such provisions are inconsistent with the express terms and conditions of it. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to authorize, under specified conditions, private persons, corporations, or other entities to provide and operate such facilities and services in the National Park System. Requires a concessions contract to be awarded only through competitive bid procedures. Allows waiver of such procedures and award of a temporary contract to avoid interruption of services. Prohibits the Secretary from granting a preferential right to a concessioner to: (1) renew concessions contracts under this Act, with exceptions or; (2) provide new or additional services at a park. Sets forth a formula for determining franchise fees. Establishes a maximum: (1) ten-year duration for a concessions contract; and (2) two-year duration for a temporary one. Requires the approval of the Secretary before a concessions contract can be transferred, assigned, sold, or conveyed. Protects certain possessory interest of concessioners who have commenced acquisition or construction of any structure on Federal land within a park before the enactment of this Act. Requires all concessions contracts to make concessioners responsible for utility costs. Amends Federal law that authorizes the Secretary to provide utility services to concessioners on a reimbursement of appropriation basis. Places limitations on a concessioner's rates and charges to the public. Exempts contracts awarded by the Secretary under this Act from certain provisions of Federal law with respect to leasing of U.S. buildings and properties. Amends the Historical Sites, Buildings and Antiquities Act to repeal provisions authorizing the Secretary to grant concessioner contracts, leases, or permits without advertising and securing competitive bids.

	</summary>
</bill>
