<bill session="103" type="h" number="2151" updated="2012-07-17T05:13:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-04T17:03:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-11-04T17:03:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="547"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Security and Competitiveness Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Maritime Security and Competitiveness Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Maritime Security and Competitiveness Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, to establish the Maritime Security Fleet program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405524" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400189" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400569" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400428" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400603" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400291" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1993-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409627" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="407817" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="401153" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="410887" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400542" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400585" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="407141" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400302" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="406554" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="411725" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400500" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400156" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="401383" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400314" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="407351" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="411488" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400397" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="405855" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404068" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400885" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400107" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400417" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400583" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="401014" joined="1993-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-05-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1288-1289)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-24"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee On Merchant Marine.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-24"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-08-05"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22T17:47:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries. H. Rept. 103-251.</text></action>
		<calendar number="141" datetime="1993-09-22T17:47:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 141.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28T15:07:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 289 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2151 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T17:22:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 289 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T18:26:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 289.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8754-8763"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T18:26:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2151 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T18:26:00-05:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 289 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T18:26:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Leslie L. Byrne to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T18:27:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T19:34:00-05:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2151 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T14:07:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8810-8834"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T14:08:00-05:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T15:02:00-05:00"><text>LIMITATION ON DEBATE - Mr. Studds asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Penny amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed 90 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T15:04:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the preceeding agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 90 minutes of debate on the Penny amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T16:43:00-05:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2151.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T16:43:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T16:43:00-05:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="547" datetime="1993-11-04T17:03:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 347 - 65 (Roll no. 547).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T17:03:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Merchant Marine" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="289" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Marine transportation"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Barges"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Cargo preference"/>
		<term name="Citizenship"/>
		<term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
		<term name="Collective bargaining unit"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Export subsidies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Foreclosure"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Harbors"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Inland water transportation"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Labor unions"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Marine insurance"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="Merchant seamen"/>
		<term name="Merchant ships"/>
		<term name="Military sealift"/>
		<term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="Mortgages"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution control"/>
		<term name="Parties to actions"/>
		<term name="Puerto Rico"/>
		<term name="Shipbuilding"/>
		<term name="Shipbuilding subsidies"/>
		<term name="Shipping agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Tugboats"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h377"/>
		<amendment number="h378"/>
		<amendment number="h379"/>
		<amendment number="h380"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/4/1993--Passed House amended. Maritime Security and Competitiveness Act of 1993 - Amends the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 to modify the Act's purposes, including ensuring the existence of a U.S.-documented fleet of the best-equipped, safest, and most modern vessels (currently, the best-equipped, safest, and most suitable type of vessels, constructed in the United States). (Sec. 3) Establishes the Maritime Security Fleet of active commercial vessels to enhance sea lift capabilities and maintain a presence in international commercial shipping of U.S.-documented vessels. Conditions Fleet enrollment on the vessel owner or operator (the contractor) having an operating agreement with the Secretary of Transportation and on other requirements, including regarding the country in which vessels are built (or rebuilt) and documented and foreign shipbuilding subsidies. Ends eligibility for any vessel that carries goods fraudulently labeled as made in America. Requires: (1) annual payments by the Secretary to each contractor; and (2) that the vessel be made available in time of war or national emergency or for national security, to be compensated at commercial rates. Restricts noncontiguous trade. Prohibits, subject to exception, contractors from owning, chartering, or operating a competing foreign vessel. Authorizes appropriations for operating agreements. Makes amounts available but unneeded for ODSs available for operating agreement payments. (Sec. 4) Continues current ODS contracts until they terminate by their terms. Mandates age acceleration for bulk cargo vessels for which construction-differential subsidies (CDSs) have been paid and for which ODSs are required to be paid. Relieves a contractor, under specified circumstances, from the application of provisions relating to: (1) ODS operating restrictions; (2) operation of competing foreign-flag vessels; and (3) ODS essential service requirements. Exempts the agreements from provisions requiring contracts under the Act to equitably serve all U.S. port ranges. (Sec. 5) Terminates, 25 years after original delivery of a liner vessel constructed, reconstructed, or reconditioned with a CDS, all restrictions under specified provisions relating to documentation, operation solely in foreign trade, and purchase or requisition of the vessel by the United States. (Sec. 6) Revises various definitions, including &quot;foreign commerce,&quot; &quot;foreign trade,&quot; and &quot;citizen of the United States&quot; as they apply to the Act. (Sec. 7) Revises the definition of &quot;privately owned United States-flag commercial vessel&quot; as it applies to cargo preference provisions. (Sec. 8) Removes restrictions regarding mortgages from provisions setting forth requirements for a vessel mortgage to qualify as a preferred mortgage. Removes restrictions regarding parties serving as trustees of mortgaged vessel interests. Amends the Shipping Act, 1916 to remove restrictions on mortgaging of a documented vessel to a non-U.S. citizen. Allows leased vessels to receive coastwise endorsements if the lessor is primarily engaged in leasing or financing transactions, the vessel is under a demise charter to a U.S. citizen, and other requirements are met. Deems such a leased vessel and certain oil spill response vessels to be owned exclusively by U.S. citizens for purposes of provisions relating to: (1) reacquisition of coastwise rights; and (2) documentation eligibility. (Sec. 9) Allows a documented vessel to be placed under foreign registry if its owner documents at least one replacement vessel and if a Maritime Security Fleet agreement has not been awarded to the replacement vessel due to the unavailability of funds. Replaces provisions regarding court sales of documented vessels with provisions requiring that, when a documented vessel is sold by court order to a mortgagee not eligible to own a documented vessel: (1) the sale is not a sale foreign for purposes of provisions relating to reacquisition of coastwise rights; and (2) unless the vessel is transferred to a foreign registry, the vessel may be operated only with the approval of the Secretary of Transportation. (Sec. 10) Authorizes payments to a shipyard located in the United States for construction of a series of vessels if: (1) payment will contribute to essential national vessel construction capabilities; (2) the vessels are commercially internationally marketable; (3) upon completion of construction of the vessels, the shipyard will be capable of constructing additional vessels for an internationally competitive price; and (4) other requirements are met. Limits payments to a percentage of the construction cost. Allows the construction contracts to be contingent on the making of Federal ship mortgage insurance guarantees. Sets the payments at the cost of construction minus the cost of constructing a similar vessel in a foreign shipyard. provides for termination of the payment agreement, if the shipyard fails to make contracts for the construction of all vessels in the series, without affecting payments for vessels already under contract. Makes the agreements binding obligations of the United States to the extent that construction contracts are in effect. Authorizes an award to a U.S. shipyard for the cost of vessel designs and document and bid preparation. (Sec. 13) Amends the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 to declare that the collective bargaining representative for officers or crew is an interested party in, and has standing to challenge, any proposed or final order, action, or rule of the Secretary under the Act or provisions of the Shipping Act, 1916 relating to placing a vessel under foreign registry. (Sec. 14) Mandates a study on the international competitiveness of U.S.-documented vessels. (Sec. 15) Requires that: (1) a U.S.-flag commercial vessel transporting equipment, materials, or commodities under cargo preference provisions or provisions relating to shipping requirements for Department of Agriculture exports be engaged under terms no less favorable than the most favorable terms offered to any foreign flag vessel under such provisions; (2) the contracts be based on contracts used for commercial shipments; and (3) the Secretary participate in negotiations regarding agreements with recipient countries. Mandates administrative waivers and exemption of cargo preference requirements to ensure and maintain a significant increase of Government-impelled cargo through Great Lakes ports. (Sec. 16) Specifies that preferred maritime liens may be established for crew or master's wages, including funds relating to certain benefits, scholarships or legal services, or labor management committees. Allows a mortgagor, after executing a preferred mortgage and before the mortgagee has had time to file the mortgage, to incur obligations establishing such a lien. (Sec. 17) Requires entities expending assistance under this Act to comply with the Buy American Act. (Sec. 18) Declares that it is the sense of the Congress that entities receiving assistance under this Act should, in expending the assistance for equipment or products, purchase only American-made equipment and products.

	</summary>
</bill>
