<bill session="103" type="h" number="2155" updated="2010-04-19T04:48:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the negotiation and implementation of arms control treaties.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="1993-05-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from State, Arms Control + Disarm Agcy, National Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1329-1330)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Ambassadors"/>
		<term name="Arms Control and Disarmament Agency"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Nuclear exports"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/19/1993--Introduced.
Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to grant the Director of the U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency membership on the National Security Council. Amends the Arms Control and Disarmament Act to grant the Director primary responsibility for the preparation and management of U.S. participation in all international negotiations and implementation forums in arms control, disarmament, and nonproliferation. Amends the Arms Export Control Act to provide for the participation of the Director in specified arms export and licensing activities. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to provide for consideration of the Director's judgment in specified nuclear export activities. Requires all determinations under such Act to remove data from the Restricted Data category to be made only after consultation with the Director. Amends the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978 to require the Department of Commerce to maintain controls over all export items, other than those licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, which could be, if used for purposes other than those for which the export is intended, of significance for nuclear explosive purposes. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish procedures for establishing a list of such items, permitting automated access to all license applications, and for interagency referral of applications for the export of items on the list.

	</summary>
</bill>
