<bill session="103" type="h" number="2176" updated="2010-04-19T04:51:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Stadium Act of 1957 Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the District of Columbia Stadium Act of 1957 to authorize the construction, maintenance, and operation of a new stadium in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-26"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Operations and Metropolitan Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-05"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House District of Columbia" subcommittee="Government Operations and Metropolitan Affairs" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1951" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2702" />
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="976" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Parking facilities"/>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Real property"/>
		<term name="Stadiums"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/19/1993--Introduced.
District of Columbia Stadium Act of 1957 Amendments of 1993 - Amends the District of Columbia Stadium Act of 1957 to authorize the District of Columbia to use the specified portion of lands adjacent to the Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Stadium to construct, maintain, and operate a new stadium or any replacement thereof for not to exceed 99 years. Prohibits use of the new stadium from being limited by the seating capacity, cost, and other provisions in such Act. States that nothing in such Act, in any lease or deed executed pursuant to it, or in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority or ability of the District to sublease or otherwise encumber such lands to a third party, either public or private, for any use consistent with the use and term authorized by this Act. Provides that, with the exception of those lands used by the District for the new stadium, use of the lands leased to the District for stadium and stadium parking lots purposes shall continue. Extends the term of such authorized use for not to exceed 99 years. Leases specified lands to the District for overflow parking for not more than 2,000 automobiles only when all other stadium striped parking spaces are filled to capacity. Requires the use of such lands under reasonable terms and conditions necessary to ensure that they are maintained as grassed park land suitable for public recreational uses. Vests responsibility and authority exclusively in the District for construction, maintenance, naming, and operation of the new stadium and parking lots. Authorizes the District to assign such responsibility and authority to a third party, either public or private. Prohibits the National Park Service from being responsible for construction, maintenance, naming, or operation of the new stadium or parking lots or any costs arising therefrom. Authorizes construction of such stadium if its design has been reviewed by the Commission of Fine Arts and reviewed and approved by the National Capital Planning Commission.

	</summary>
</bill>
