<bill session="103" type="h" number="2192" updated="2010-04-19T04:53:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the FREEDOM Support Act to establish a program to provide loans for joint ventures between United States small businesses and small businesses or entrepreneurs in the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400611"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401014" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-07-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1325-1326)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Free enterprise"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/19/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Freedom for Russia and Emerging Eurasian Democracies and Open Markets Support Act of 1992 to direct the Secretary of State to support the establishment by U.S. small businesses and independent state small businesses or entrepreneurs of joint ventures to engage in business activity in the independent states of the former Soviet Union. Authorizes the Secretary to make loans for joint ventures. Establishes loan preference criteria, limitations, and repayment terms. Prohibits: (1) loans to a joint venture if, as a result of the joint venture, a U.S. small business would transfer any business activity that it has been carrying out to a location outside the United States; and (2) goods produced pursuant to a joint venture that receives a loan from being imported into the United States. Provides for a contract with a private entity for the establishment of a data base to facilitate joint ventures between U.S. and independent state small businesses. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
