<bill session="103" type="h" number="2199" updated="2010-04-19T04:54:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Polluter Pays Clean Water Funding Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to reauthorize and modify the State water pollution control revolving loan program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400885" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400612" joined="1994-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="1993-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="406277" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1994-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1994-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="405524" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="409627" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="410887" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1994-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1319-1320)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from EPA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1356-1359)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-01"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>See H.R.3948.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2255" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3948" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Chemicals"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Feeds"/>
		<term name="Fertilizers"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
		<term name="Pesticides"/>
		<term name="Pollution taxes"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Water use"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: State Water Pollution Control Revolving Funds Title II: Excise Taxes on Substances Contributing to Water Pollution, Etc. Polluter Pays Clean Water Funding Act - Title I: State Water Pollution Control Revolving Funds - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to add to the list of projects eligible for State water pollution control revolving fund assistance: (1) coastal nonpoint pollution control programs; (2) wetlands protection, remediation, and restoration; (3) watershed planning and management; (4) public water conservation and reuse; and (5) low-income water and sewer assurance programs. Establishes conditions on a State's authority to make grants from such funds. Makes eligible for grant assistance projects: (1) to be carried out in political subdivisions with 5,000 people or fewer or in communities where water and sewer bills exceed a specified percent of median family income; (2) for control of nonpoint source pollution; and (3) to establish a low-income water and sewer assurance program. Revises allotment provisions concerning State revolving funds to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to publish an allotment formula based on State populations. Directs the Administrator to establish minimum standards for low-income water and sewer assurance programs eligible for assistance under this Act. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Excise Taxes on Substances Contributing to Water Pollution, Etc. - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a tax on the discharge of any taxable chemical pollutant to water or any publicly owned treatment works. Exempts from such tax discharges of chemical pollutants used exclusively for any residential or farming use or any use by any Federal, State, or local agency. Imposes a tax on any fertilizer, pesticide, or animal feed which is: (1) manufactured or produced in the United States or entered into the United States for consumption use or warehousing; and (2) sold or used by the manufacturer, producer, or importer. Exempts articles which are to be exported or sold for export from such tax. Imposes a tax of 1.95 cents on each thousand gallons of water sold for use or used by the ultimate consumer in a taxable use. Makes persons using the water liable for the tax. Establishes the Clean Water Trust Fund to make expenditures to carry out State water pollution control revolving fund activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
