<bill session="103" type="h" number="2218" updated="2010-04-19T04:57:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Concentration Grant Targeting and Improvements Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to ensure that students are counted by using data from local educational agencies when available.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400586"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404220" joined="1993-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-06-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1312)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational statistics"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
Concentration Grant Targeting and Improvements Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to target chapter 1 concentration grants on local educational agencies (LEAS) with especially high concentrations of children from low-income families. (Current law targets these to LEAs in counties with such concentrations.) Requires the State educational agency, in States which receive the minimum concentration grant amount, to allocate such funds among LEAs in rank order of their respective concentration and numbers of children from low-income families and in amounts consistent with the degree of concentration of poverty. Allows only those LEAs with concentrations of poverty exceeding the statewide average to receive such funds. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to use data on counties or equivalent local government units if satisfactory data regarding LEAs are not available to calculate grant amounts.

	</summary>
</bill>
