<bill session="103" type="h" number="2215" updated="2010-04-19T04:57:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Law Enforcement Officers Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide a death penalty for the murder of Federal law enforcement officers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404296"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400398" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400329" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-10-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400056" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="410887" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-08-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Civil and Constitutional Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Appellate procedure"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Correctional personnel"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugs and youth"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Protection of officials"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
Federal Law Enforcement Officers Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for imposition of the death penalty for the murder of Federal law enforcement officials. Sets forth procedures for determining whether a death sentence is justified. Lists mitigating factors (which include impaired capacity, duress, minor participation, and lack of foreseeability) and aggravating factors (which include death during commission of another crime, involvement of a firearm or previous conviction of violent felony involving a firearm, previous conviction of specified serious offenses, and continuing criminal enterprise involving drug sales to minors). Provides for the conduct of a special hearing. Directs the court to instruct the jury that it shall not consider the race, color, religious beliefs, national origin, or sex of the defendant or any victim in making its determination. Sets forth provisions regarding review and implementation (including the use of State facilities) of a death sentence. Prohibits such sentence from being carried out upon a pregnant woman or a person who is mentally retarded or lacks the mental capacity to understand the death penalty and why it was imposed. Prohibits any employee of a State department of corrections, the U.S. Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Prisons, or the U.S. Marshals Service from being required to attend or participate in any prosecution or execution if it is contrary to the employee's moral or religious convictions.

	</summary>
</bill>
