<bill session="103" type="h" number="2225" updated="2010-04-19T04:58:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Highway Construction Private Investment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to require States to enter into contracts with private persons to finance construction of toll facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406343"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2605, H2663)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-01"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Highway finance"/>
		<term name="Interstate highway system"/>
		<term name="Toll roads"/>
		<term name="Tunnels"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
Highway Construction Private Investment Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to permit Federal participation in initial construction of any toll highway, bridge, or tunnel on the Interstate System and in the reconstruction of a toll-free Federal-aid highway on the Interstate System and its conversion to a toll facility. Requires each State, to avoid having specified Federal highway funds withheld from apportionment, to enter into contracts with private persons to finance construction of toll facilities which require such persons to obligate under such contracts, in the aggregate, an amount equal to or exceeding the State's aggregate apportionment amount for the fiscal year. Sets forth provisions regarding the reapportionment of withheld funds.

	</summary>
</bill>
