<bill session="103" type="h" number="2220" updated="2010-04-19T04:58:05-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom of Speech on Campus Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Education Amendments of 1972 to ensure that students attending institutions of higher education that receive Federal funds are able to exercise the right to freedom of speech, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400174"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400104" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400534" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="409618" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="403864" joined="1993-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="College discipline"/>
		<term name="College students"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Freedom of speech"/>
		<term name="Students' rights"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
Freedom of Speech on Campus Act of 1993 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that students attending universities or other institutions of higher education that receive Federal funds should be able to exercise full rights to freedom of speech on campus free from official intrusion. Amends the Education Amendments of 1972 to prohibit discrimination by an institution of higher education against a student based on protected speech in any education program or activity receiving Federal financial assistance under the Higher Education Act of 1965. Makes such prohibition inapplicable to religious or military institutions. Provides that such prohibition shall not be construed to prevent: (1) imposition of an official sanction on a student determined to have willfully participated in the disruption or attempted disruption of a lecture, class, speech, presentation, or performance made or scheduled to be made under the auspices of the institution of higher education; or (2) actions by such institution that are necessary to ensure the safety of individuals, protection of property, and continuation of the academic and administrative process without interference.

	</summary>
</bill>
