<bill session="103" type="h" number="2232" updated="2010-04-19T04:59:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Refugee Women and Children Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish standards and guidelines for providing overseas assistance to refugees and displaced persons.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="410974" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="1993-05-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Insurgency"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International relief"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Refugee policy"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Rights of women"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women's education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
Refugee Women and Children Protection Act - Directs the U.S. Government, in providing for overseas assistance and protection of refugees and displaced persons, to address the protection and basic needs of refugee women and children. Requires the Secretary of State to take certain steps concerning such refugees as called for in the 1991 United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) Guidelines on the Protection of Refugee Women. Directs the Secretary to ensure that all recipients of U.S. Government refugee and migration assistance implement such steps. Requires the Secretary, in providing such assistance, to raise at the highest levels of government the issue of abuses against refugee women and children by governments or insurgent groups that engage in or permit: (1) gross violations of internationally recognized human rights; (2) the blockage of humanitarian relief assistance; (3) gender-specific persecution; and (4) continuing violations of the integrity of the person against refugee women and children on the part of armed insurgents, local security forces, or camp guards. Declares that the Secretary should immediately investigate credible reports of abuses and identify remedial measures. Requires the U.S. Government to use its vote in the United Nations and participation in other multilateral organizations to promote policies which protect human rights and needs of refugee women and children. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the President should enter into negotiations to encourage other governments that provide refugee assistance to adopt refugee assistance policies to encourage full implementation of the UNHCR's 1991 Guidelines.

	</summary>
</bill>
