<bill session="103" type="h" number="2246" updated="2010-04-19T05:02:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax incentives to encourage development in certain border areas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400882"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402750" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="410695" joined="1993-06-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="College costs"/>
		<term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational finance"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Employment subsidies"/>
		<term name="Employment tax credits"/>
		<term name="Enterprise zones"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Housing finance"/>
		<term name="Indian economic development"/>
		<term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Low-income housing"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Poverty"/>
		<term name="Real estate business"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
		<term name="Urban economic development"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the designation of one border empowerment zone and five border enterprise communities: (1) by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in the case of an urban area; (2) by the Secretary of Agriculture, in the case of a rural area; and (3) the Secretary of the Interior for an Indian reservation. Describes a border area as one located in one or more counties each of which is located adjacent to an international border. Sets forth the eligibility criteria for such designations. Makes buildings in such areas eligible for the low-income housing credit applicable to buildings in high-cost areas. Provides for the issuance of enterprise zone facility bonds in border enterprise communities and empowerment zones in a manner similar to exempt facility bonds. Excludes enterprise zone facility bonds from the interest deduction limitations on financial institutions. Allows an empowerment zone employment credit to employers for a percentage of qualified zone wages paid during calendar years 1994 through 2004. Limits the amount of such credit. Allows a zone resident empowerment savings credit to employers as a general business credit of 50 percent of the qualified savings contributions made to a defined contribution plan on behalf of an employee. Limits the amounts of such contributions. Increases the limitation on expensing certain depreciable business assets. Increases the volume cap applicable to enterprise zone facility bonds if the business owners meet specified ownership requirements with regard to abiding in such zones. Allows the use of the targeted jobs credit for hiring economically disadvantaged border empowerment zone residents. Excludes from the penalty on early distributions from retirement plan distributions for first home purchases, higher educational expenses, or investment in an enterprise zone business.

	</summary>
</bill>
