<bill session="103" type="h" number="2242" updated="2010-04-19T05:01:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Voluntary Environmental Cleanup Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to encourage voluntary environmental cleanup of facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410567"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Real estate development"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/1993--Introduced.
Voluntary Environmental Cleanup Act of 1993 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide grants to: (1) States that establish voluntary environmental cleanup programs meeting specified requirements; and (2) local governments to conduct site characterizations for affected sites at which voluntary cleanups are being conducted or are proposed under State voluntary cleanup programs. Directs the Administrator to provide loans for the cleanup of affected sites to owners or prospective purchasers of affected sites at which voluntary cleanups are being conducted or are proposed. Sets forth loan application and approval procedures, as well as maximum loan amounts and loan agreement requirements. Grants the United States a lien on contaminated property subject to a loan until the loan agreement has been satisfied. Authorizes appropriations. Limits the amount of grants or loans that may be used for administrative costs.

	</summary>
</bill>
