<bill session="103" type="h" number="2244" updated="2012-07-17T04:15:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-26T23:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-05-26T23:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="193"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Second Supplemental Appropriations Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Second Supplemental Appropriations Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making supplemental appropriations, transfers, and rescissions for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1993, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408103"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-24T17:36:00-04:00" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Mr. Natcher asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Appropriations have until midnight on May 24 to file a report on H.R. 2244, making a Supplemental Approprtions for FY 1993. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-24T19:38:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-105, by Mr. Natcher.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-05-24T19:39:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 54.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25T19:00:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 183 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2118 and H.R. 2244 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Upon adoption of this resolution the Speaker may declare the House in the Committee of the Whole for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 2244) and all points against consideration shall be waved. All points of order against the bill H.R. 2118 shall be waived. Bill is open to amendments. The amendments printed in in the report accompanying this resolution relating to H.R. 2244 shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole, and the bill as amended shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment under the five-minute rule. The amendment printed in section two of this resolution relating to H.R. 2118 shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the W...</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T12:07:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 183 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T17:59:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 183.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2881-2916"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T18:00:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2118 and H.R. 2244 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Upon adoption of this resolution the Speaker may declare the House in the Committee of the Whole for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 2244) and all points against consideration shall be waived. All points of order against the bill H.R. 2118 shall be waived. Bill is open to amendments. The amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution relating to H.R. 2244 shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole, and the bill as amended shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment under the five-minute rule. The amendment printed in section two of this resolution relating to H.R. 2118 shall be considered as adopted in the House</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T18:00:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 183 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T18:00:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jim McDermott to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T18:01:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 183, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T19:49:00-04:00"><text>LIMITATION ON TIME FOR DEBATE - Mr. Natcher asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Burton amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed ten minutes, equally divided and controlled by Mr. Burton and Ms. Waters. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T20:41:00-04:00"><text>LIMITATION OF DEBATE TIME - Mr. Natcher asked unanimous consent that debate on all amendments offered to the bill for the remainder of the evening be limited to not to exceed twenty minutes, equally divided and controlled, except for the amendment to be offered by Mr. Kolbe which will be debated for not to exceed thirty minutes, equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T23:17:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2244.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T23:17:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T23:18:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to H. Res. 183, the sundry amendments adopted by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union are deemed to have been adopted in the House.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="193" datetime="1993-05-26T23:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 287 - 140 (Roll no. 193).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26T23:37:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="183" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Agricultural credit"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
		<term name="Apartment houses"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Astronautics"/>
		<term name="Atmospheric research"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Coast guard"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Credit insurance"/>
		<term name="Customs administration"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Educational statistics"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Federal office buildings"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="General Services Administration"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Impacted area programs"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
		<term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Naval bases"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Nutrition"/>
		<term name="Oceanographic research"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Sewerage"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Student aid"/>
		<term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Transportation research"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h74"/>
		<amendment number="h75"/>
		<amendment number="h76"/>
		<amendment number="h77"/>
		<amendment number="h78"/>
		<amendment number="h79"/>
		<amendment number="h80"/>
		<amendment number="h81"/>
		<amendment number="h82"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/26/1993--Passed House amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Supplemental Appropriations Title II: Rescissions Title III: General Provisions Second Supplemental Appropriations Act of 1993 - Title I: Supplemental Appropriations - Makes supplemental appropriations available to: (1) the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor; (2) the Environmental Protection Agency for construction grants; (3) the Farmers Home Administration of the Department of Agriculture; (4) the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice; (5) the Federal Railroad Administration of the Department of Transportation; and (6) the Small Business Administration through a fund transfer. Title II: Rescissions - Rescinds specified appropriations made to: (1) the Department of Agriculture for the Farmers Home Administration; (2) the Department of Commerce for the Economic Development Administration and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; (3) the Department of Justice for Office of Justice Programs and the Thomas Jefferson Commemoration Commission; (4) the Department of the Interior for the Bureau of Land Management, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the National Park Service, and the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation; (5) the Department of Labor for the Employment and Training Administration and departmental management; (6) the Department of Education for certain programs; (7) the Department of Transportation for the Coast Guard, the Federal Aviation Administration, and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration; (8) the Department of the Treasury for the U.S. Customs Administration, the Bureau of the Public Debt, and the Internal Revenue Service; (9) the General Services Administration for the Federal Buildings Fund; (10) the Department of Veterans Affairs for departmental administration; (11) the Department of Housing and Urban Development for certain housing programs; (12) the Environmental Protection Agency for the Hazardous Substance Superfund; and (13) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for research and development. Title III: General Provisions - Prohibits appropriations in this Act from remaining available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided. Restricts the availability of funds for the Community Investment Program until September 30, 1993. Prohibits the use of any funds to pay for the relocation of the Human Nutrition Information Service. Amends the Job Training Partnership Act to change the age eligibility requirements for the Youth Fair Chance Program. Allows the provision of stipends to youth in such program. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1993 through 1997.

	</summary>
</bill>
