<bill session="103" type="h" number="2260" updated="2010-04-19T05:04:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Peacekeeping Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling for reduction in the United States share of assessed contributions to international peacekeeping operations, restricting the use of the United States Peacekeeping Emergency Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406431" joined="1993-11-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="United Nations finances"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1993--Introduced.
International Peacekeeping Reform Act of 1993 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the United States should not be assessed a greater share for any international peacekeeping operation than the current U.S. share of the regular assessed budget for the international organization with jurisdiction over the operation; (2) all U.S. military assistance, logistical support, and in-kind contributions for an international peacekeeping operation should be fully counted toward the U.S. assessment for the operation or fully reimbursed; and (3) regional countries that would receive disproportionate benefit from the establishment of such operation should voluntarily provide a higher proportionate share of the operation costs. Prohibits funds authorized to be appropriated to the Contributions for International Peacekeeping Activities Account at the Department of State for the United States Peacekeeping Emergency Fund or which are not specifically designated for an existing peacekeeping operation from being made available for any peacekeeping operation of an international organization in which the United States assessed share exceeds its assessed share for the regular budget for such organization.

	</summary>
</bill>
