<bill session="103" type="h" number="2296" updated="2010-04-19T05:09:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to exempt pesticide rinse water degradation systems from subtitle C permit requirements.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400028"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400509" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1993-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-05-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Biodegradation"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Pesticide pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/27/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to exempt owners or operators of pesticide rinse water degradation systems from obtaining a permit for the treatment or disposal of pesticide rinse water if the system: (1) uses evaporation and biological degradation to treat or dispose of such water; (2) contains an above-ground tank or double-walled tank that can be inspected for leaks; (3) includes a secondary containment system capable of collecting and containing any leaks from the tank; (4) does not discharge fluid; (5) is protected from rainfall; and (6) when it is dismantled or any matrix or media used in the tank is replaced, if the matrix or media contains any hazardous waste, the matrix or media is treated, stored, or disposed of in accordance with hazardous waste management requirements. Applies this Act to systems in operation as of January 1, 1987.

	</summary>
</bill>
