<bill session="103" type="h" number="230" updated="2010-04-18T23:35:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to enhance the authority of States and Indian tribes to disapprove the provision by the Secretary of Energy of interim storage capacity for civilian spent nuclear fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406605"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF-03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy and Power" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Nuclear energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act with respect to storage of civilian spent nuclear fuel to: (1) require the Secretary of Energy to notify the affected State and Indian tribe of any decision to provide storage capacity at any site located within their respective jurisdiction; and (2) authorize such entities to disapprove that decision. (Currently, such notification and disapproval guidelines apply only to storage capacity of specified minimum tonnage.) Expedites from three years to one year mandatory removal of such fuel from the interim storage facility. Applies the notice and disapproval guidelines to contracts or obligations in effect before January 7, 1983.

	</summary>
</bill>
