<bill session="103" type="h" number="2312" updated="2010-04-19T05:12:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reform House of Representatives campaign finance laws, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400156"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408839" joined="1993-10-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3349)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Campaign contributors"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional allowances"/>
		<term name="Congressional candidates"/>
		<term name="Congressional districts"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
		<term name="Congressional privileges and immunities"/>
		<term name="Congressional terms of office"/>
		<term name="Congressional travel"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
		<term name="Political advertising"/>
		<term name="Political parties"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Radio in politics"/>
		<term name="Residence requirements"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
		<term name="Television in politics"/>
		<term name="Term limits"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
		<term name="Voter registration"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/27/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to limit contributions to House of Representatives (House) elections from persons other than local individual residents. Reduces maximum House contribution amounts from multicandidate political committees (PACs). Sets forth limitations and reporting requirements for amounts paid for mixed political activities (&quot;soft money&quot;). Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to reduce the House mail allowance formula. Amends Federal law to prohibit newsletter mailings under the congressional franking privilege. Lengthens the nonmailing period for mass mailings by House members. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a broadcast station to make broadcast time available to all House and Senate candidates in the last 30 (currently 45) days before a primary and the last 45 (currently 60) days before a general election, at the lowest unit charge of the station for the same amount of time (currently, the same class and amount of time) for the same period on the same date. Prohibits broadcasters from preempting advertisements sold to political candidates at the lowest unit rate, unless the preemption is beyond the broadcaster's control. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to deny, with certain exceptions, a deduction for specified lobbying and political expenditures. Establishes membership and dues reporting requirements for related political organizations. Prohibits lobbyist-paid travel by House members, officers, or employees. Expresses the sense of the Congress with respect to: (1) term limitations; and (2) the application of generally applicable laws to the Congress.

	</summary>
</bill>
