<bill session="103" type="h" number="2328" updated="2010-04-19T05:14:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Lands Corps Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Public Lands Corps, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400612"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411677" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1993-05-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1398-1399)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-02"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Credit and Rural Development.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-02"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-06"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-07"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>See H.R.2010.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Environment, Credit and Rural Development" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2010" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="College students"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Government internships"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="National service"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Student aid"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/27/1993--Introduced.
Public Lands Corps Act of 1993 - Establishes a Public Lands Corps in the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture to carry out authorized conservation, restoration, and rehabilitation projects on public lands or Indian lands. Requires the Corps to consist of men and women between the ages of 16 and 25 with high school diplomas or the equivalent. Authorizes the Secretaries to enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with any qualified youth or conservation corps to perform the projects. Sets forth provisions relating to: (1) preferred project characteristics; and (2) provision of facilities, services, and supplies and establishment of conservation centers for project programs. Authorizes the Secretaries to provide for the placement of qualified college students or recent college graduates as Resource Assistants in Federal land managing agencies to carry out research or other technical functions. Declares that the purposes of the Resource Assistant Program are: (1) to augment the work force of the Federal land managing agencies through more extensive use of college students and recent college graduates; and (2) to enhance exposure to the conservation agency work place as a potential career. Directs the agency to implement the Program through existing nonprofit organizations if they can provide an appropriate level and quality of program. Requires participating nonprofit organizations to contribute 25 percent of the total costs of each Program participant recruited and placed through that organization. Applies provisions of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (the Act) relating to living allowances, terms of service, educational benefits or awards, and nondisplacement to participants in the Public Lands Corps and Resource Assistant Program. Authorizes the Secretaries to pay up to 75 percent of the costs of any project carried out on public lands by a qualified youth or conservation corps. Permits the remaining 25 percent of such costs to be provided from nonfederal sources in the form of funds, services, materials, or equipment. Prohibits cost sharing in the case of such project carried out on Indian lands. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
