<bill session="103" type="h" number="232" updated="2010-04-18T23:36:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 and title 10, United States Code, to require as a term in each contract for property or services made by an executive agency that the contractor (and any subcontractors under that contract) shall comply with the workmen's compensation law of each State in which the contract is performed.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406605"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-19"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-06" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Defense procurement"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Workers' compensation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 and specified defense procurement provisions to require each contract for the purchase of property or services made by an executive agency to provide: (1) that the prime contractor and any subcontractor thereof shall guarantee to comply with State workers' compensation laws; and (2) for the termination of the right of the offending contractor or subcontractor to proceed with the work being carried out in a State in which compliance with such a law is not demonstrated, subject to specified requirements. Makes specified exceptions to such provisions under the Defense Base Act and the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act. Authorizes the President to suspend operation of this Act in the event of a national emergency.

	</summary>
</bill>
