<bill session="103" type="h" number="2334" updated="2010-04-19T05:15:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Domestic Employment bill</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Zoe Baird bill</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify the collection of employment taxes on domestic services.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400188"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>See H.R.4278.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4278" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Household workers"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="Tax administration"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
		<term name="Workers' compensation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/8/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to set forth rules for filing returns with respect to domestic service employment taxes and requires such returns to be made on a calendar year basis. Subjects such taxes to estimated tax provisions. Makes filing requirements inapplicable to any employer liable for tax concerning remuneration for services other than domestic service in a private home. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into agreements with States to collect the State unemployment tax imposed on remuneration for domestic service and transfers such amounts to a State's account in the Unemployment Trust Fund. Treats such taxes as domestic service employment taxes. Requires the Secretary to inform domestic service employers in private homes of their tax obligations. Adjusts the threshold (from $50 a calendar quarter to $800 a year) for paying and withholding social security taxes on wages paid for domestic service in a private home.

	</summary>
</bill>
