<bill session="103" type="h" number="2354" updated="2010-04-19T05:18:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prison Litigation Relief Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To limit judicial interference in the management of the Nation's prisons and jails and permit incarceration of greater numbers of dangerous offenders, without restricting the legitimate constitutional rights of inmates.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400574"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400596" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1994-02-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3346-3347)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Courts"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Civil procedure"/>
		<term name="Consent decrees"/>
		<term name="Constitutional law"/>
		<term name="Correctional institutions"/>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
		<term name="Prison administration"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/9/1993--Introduced.
Prison Litigation Relief Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal judicial code to require a district court, in any action challenging the constitutionality of conditions of confinement in any correctional instituion, that finds that a condition of confinement violates the Constitution, to narrowly tailor any relief to fit the nature and extent of the violation and to make an order no more intrusive than necessary to remedy the violation. Denies the court jurisdiction to: (1) impose a ceiling on the population of any institution or to require any adjustment of the release dates of inmates; or (2) prohibit the use of tents or prefabricated structures for housing inmates. Specifies that: (1) no consent decree in any such action shall provide relief greater than the minimum required to bring conditions of confinement into substantial compliance with the Constitution; and (2) in entering a consent decree, the court shall make a written finding to that effect (permits the court to recommend changes if it appears that the relief provided is greater than the minimum required). Permits the court, upon motion of a defendant at any time, to conduct a hearing on whether such an order or decree should be modified in light of: (1) changed factual circumstances; (2) a change or clarification of the governing law; (3) a succession in office of an official responsible for having consented to a decree; (4) the Government's financial constraints or any other matter affecting public safety or the public interest; or (5) specified grounds under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. Directs the court: (1) to conduct such a hearing if the motion was filed more than one year after the date of the order or decree or the date on which the last previous modification hearing was conducted, whichever is later; and (2) if the court denies a motion to modify such an order or consent decree, to make a written finding that the relief provided is no greater than the minimum required.

	</summary>
</bill>
