<bill session="103" type="h" number="2357" updated="2010-04-19T05:19:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women's Business Procurement Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to assist the development of small business concerns owned and controlled by women, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400537"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="1993-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="1993-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1993-06-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1439)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="Women in business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/9/1993--Introduced.
Women's Business Procurement Assistance Act of 1993 - Amends the Small Business Act to require the President and the head of each Federal agency to include small business concerns owned and controlled by women within the Federal procurement contract process. Declares that it is the policy of the United States that such business concerns should have the maximum opportunity to participate in the Federal procurement contract process. Requires the Director of the Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization section in each Federal agency to designate a &quot;women-in-business&quot; specialist responsible for the execution of programs designed to assist small business concerns owned and controlled by women. Requires that each such specialist: (1) possess the appropriate knowledge, qualifications, and training for such position; and (2) work full-time in such position. Establishes in the Small Business Administration the Office of Women's Business Ownership. Directs the Comptroller General to report to the Congress on the number of small businesses owned and controlled by women procuring Federal contracts. Expresses the sense of the Congress that if the number of such businesses procuring such contracts does not rise significantly, then further legislative steps should be taken.

	</summary>
</bill>
