<bill session="103" type="h" number="2358" updated="2010-04-19T05:19:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Nuclear Proliferation Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions against any foreign person or United States person that assists a foreign country in acquiring a nuclear explosive device or unsafeguarded nuclear material, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1054" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Defense procurement"/>
		<term name="Diplomacy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Export credit"/>
		<term name="Export finance"/>
		<term name="Financial institutions"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government securities"/>
		<term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Nuclear exports"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Pakistan"/>
		<term name="Presidential powers"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="Uranium"/>
		<term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/9/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Reporting on Nuclear Exports Title II: Sanctions for Nuclear Proliferation Title III: International Atomic Energy Agency Omnibus Nuclear Proliferation Control Act of 1993 - Title I: Reporting on Nuclear Exports - (Sec. 101) Amends the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978 to revise requirements of the President's annual report on Government efforts to prevent nuclear proliferation. Title II: Sanctions for Nuclear Proliferation - (Sec. 201) Requires the President to prohibit the procurement of goods or services from any foreign or U.S. person who has materially and with requisite knowledge contributed, through the exports of goods or technology, to the efforts by any individual, group, or non-nuclear weapon state to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material or to use, develop, stockpile, or acquire any nuclear explosive device. Requires the President to impose sanctions unless he certifies to the Congress that a government has taken actions to terminate the involvement of a foreign person in such activities. Exempts certain products or services from sanctions, including essential defense articles and services, products and services provided under existing contracts, essential technology or information, and humanitarian items. Applies sanctions for at least 12 months and terminates sanctions only if the President certifies to the Congress that a person has ceased to, and will not in the future, aid in such prohibited activities. Grants the President waiver authority with respect to such sanctions. (Sec. 202) Amends the Arms Export Control Act to prohibit sales or leases of defense articles or services to any country that is in breach of its commitments to the United States under international agreements concerning nuclear nonproliferation. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to waive a prohibition on assistance to countries engaging in certain nuclear enrichment transfers with respect to Pakistan if to do so is in the national interest. (Sec. 203) Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. executive directors of specified international institutions to oppose any use of funds to promote the acquisition of unsafeguarded special nuclear material or the development, stockpiling, or use of nuclear explosive devices by non-nuclear weapon states. (Sec. 205) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 to impose specified prohibitions on financial institutions that the President has determined have materially and with requisite knowledge contributed to the efforts by any individual, group, or non-nuclear weapon state to acquire unsafeguarded nuclear material or to use, develop, stockpile, or acquire any nuclear explosive device. Authorizes the President to waive a prohibition under certain circumstances. (Sec. 206) Amends the Export-Import Bank Act to prohibit Export-Import Bank assistance to any country that has aided or abetted a non-nuclear weapon state in acquiring a nuclear explosive device or unsafeguarded nuclear material. (Sec. 207) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to include within the list of activities that makes a country subject to sanctions the transfer or receipt (by a non-nuclear weapon state) of design information or components important for the development of a nuclear explosive device. Lists such sanctions. Title III: International Atomic Energy Agency - (Sec. 301) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should negotiate with other nations to achieve specified nuclear nonproliferation and safeguard objectives to enhance confidence in International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) safeguards and halt nuclear proliferation. (Sec. 302) Urges the President to negotiate with other nations to promote the early adoption of reforms in the implementation of IAEA safeguards.

	</summary>
</bill>
