<bill session="103" type="h" number="2351" updated="2010-04-19T05:18:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-14T15:39:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-10-14T15:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="503"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Authorization bill FY94, Nat. Found. on Arts and Humanities</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">National Foundation on Arts FY94 Authorization bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Arts, Humanities, and Museums Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Arts, Humanities, and Museums Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1994 and 1995 to carry out the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965, and the Museum Services Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411677"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1441)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Institute on Museum Services, Natl Endow Arts, Natl Endow Humanities.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Executive Comment Received from Institute on Museum Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Executive Comment Received from Natl Endow Humanities.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Executive Comment Received from Natl Endow Arts.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-29"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Ordered to be Reported.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21T13:47:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Education and Labor. H. Rept. 103-186.</text></action>
		<calendar number="106" datetime="1993-07-21T13:47:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 106.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T19:19:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 264 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2351 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T12:12:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 264 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T12:12:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 264.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7841-7862"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T12:12:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2351 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T12:12:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 264 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T12:12:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jose E. Serrano to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T12:13:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T12:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 264, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T13:50:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 264, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Dornan amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T14:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 264, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Gunderson amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T14:49:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2351.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T14:50:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T14:50:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Cunningham moved to recommit with instructions to Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T14:51:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit the bill back to the Committee on Education with instructions that the committee report the bill back to the House with an amendment which would prohibit the distribution of funds to individuals who are not lawfully residing in the U.S.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T15:23:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 210 - 214 (Roll no. 502).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7861"/></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="503" datetime="1993-10-14T15:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 304 - 119 (Roll no. 503).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T15:39:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="239" datetime="1993-10-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 239.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="264" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1218" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1218" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Culture"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
		<term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h359"/>
		<amendment number="h360"/>
		<amendment number="h361"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	
10/14/1993--Passed House amended. Arts, Humanities, and Museums Amendments of 1993 - Amends the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 to extend through FY 1995 the authorization of appropriations to carry out such Act, including funds for: (1) program grants and other assistance by the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA) and the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH); (2) matching non-Federal funds received; and (3) administration of NEA and NEH programs. Sets limitations on total appropriations authorized for the NEA and the NEH in FY 1994. Limits a State's current NEA allotment to not more than the preceding year's level if: (1) the State's current year funding for the arts is less than the average annual amount expended by the State during the most recent preceding period of three fiscal years; and (2) the rate of reduction in its arts spending exceeds that for the aggregate of the State's general fund reductions for the current fiscal year. Amends the Museum Services Act to extend through FY 1995 the authorization of appropriations, including funds for: (1) grants to museums to increase and improve services; and (2) functions of the Institute of Museum Services (which is within the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities).

	</summary>
</bill>
