<bill session="103" type="h" number="2381" updated="2010-04-19T05:22:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reimbursement for Assistance to the Former Soviet Union Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the President to encourage the independent states of the former Soviet Union to provide reimbursement to the United States for economic and development assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407669"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407676" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400192" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400188" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400115" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400536" joined="1993-06-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Barter"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="Debt agreements"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/10/1993--Introduced.
Reimbursement for Assistance to the Former Soviet Union Act - Directs the President to encourage those independent states of the former Soviet Union capable of providing eventual reimbursement to the United States for economic and development assistance to enter into negotiations to reach agreements outlining reimbursement. Requires the President, in carrying out development and economic assistance provisions of the Foreign Assistance Act, to conduct a study of: (1) the resources in each of the independent states and the prospective revenue from such resources; (2) the possible use of barter or exchange of such resources as methods of reimbursement; and (3) the collateralization of loan and investment guarantees provided by the U.S. Government for project financing in such states using such resources or prospective revenues.

	</summary>
</bill>
