<bill session="103" type="h" number="2407" updated="2010-04-19T05:26:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Partnership for Long-Term Care Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to improve coverage of nursing facility services under the medicaid program and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify the tax treatment of long-term care insurance.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406284"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402152" joined="1993-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1494)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-21"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Accident insurance"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/14/1993--Introduced.
Partnership for Long-Term Care Act of 1993 - Title I: Medicaid Program Improvements - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require States to cover certain primary care for pregnant women and children, and nursing facility services for other individuals, whose incomes are below the Federal poverty level. Requires States to establish a subsidy program to assist individuals whose incomes are no less than the Federal poverty level and no more than twice such level in paying long-term care insurance premiums. Provides larger subsidies as individuals' incomes approach the Federal poverty level. Prohibits States from establishing a subsidy resource eligibility limit at less than twice the resource limit under (SSA) title XVI (Supplemental Security Income). Title II: Medicaid Amendments Relating to Treatment of Payments Under Qualified Long-Term Care Insurance Policies - Subtracts long-term care insurance payments from an individual's assets in determining his or her Medicaid eligibility. Title III: Tax Treatment of Long-Term Care Insurance - Requires that, for the purpose of determining the income tax liability of life insurance companies, qualified long-term care insurance be treated as accident or health insurance. Applies this provision to policies which provide coverage for at least 12 consecutive months of diagnostic, preventive, therapeutic, rehabilitative, maintenance, or personal care services provided in a setting other than the acute care unit of a hospital and for an individual's loss of functional capacity. Provides that for the purpose of determining whether a tax exclusion applies to employer contributions to, or an employee's receipt of benefits from, qualified long-term care insurance, such contributions and benefits shall be considered to be for coverage under an accident or health plan. Makes the penalty tax on early distributions from qualified retirement plans inapplicable when such distributions are used to pay for qualified long-term care insurance. Treats an individual's qualified long-term care expenses as deductible medical care expenditures. Provides for the deduction of employer contributions to a reserve fund providing employees with post-retirement qualified long-term care benefits. Permits inclusion of qualified long-term care insurance in cafeteria plans. Excludes it from a cafeteria plan participant's gross income.

	</summary>
</bill>
