<bill session="103" type="h" number="2400" updated="2010-04-19T05:25:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Statistical Information and Analysis Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 13, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Commerce to prepare annual assessments of the progress being made by the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the Baltic states in establishing a free market economy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400539"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1488-1489)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16"><committee name="House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Census, Statistics and Postal Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" subcommittee="Census, Statistics and Postal Personnel" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American technical assistance"/>
		<term name="Baltic States"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economic statistics"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Estonia"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Free enterprise"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="Latvia"/>
		<term name="Lithuania"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/10/1993--Introduced.
International Statistical Information and Analysis Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to prepare and submit to the Congress an annual report analyzing the progress being made by the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the Baltic states in establishing a free market economy. Requires the President to establish an interagency committee to be known as the International Statistical Assistance Coordinating Committee to: (1) determine priorities for providing training and other technical assistance to monitor economic performance in such countries through the collection and analysis of economic statistical data; (2) coordinate such assistance with assistance provided by international or multilateral organizations; and (3) provide for analysis by its constituent agencies of economic statistical data regarding such countries and for the dissemination of such analysis to U.S. businesses and other interested parties. Requires U.S. assistance that is provided to encourage the development of a free-market economic system in the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the Baltic states to include training and other technical assistance to develop capabilities to monitor economic performance through the collection and analysis of economic statistical data. Expresses the sense of the Congress that a specified amount of funds allocated for U.S. assistance to encourage the development of free market systems in such countries be used for such training and assistance.

	</summary>
</bill>
