<bill session="103" type="h" number="2413" updated="2010-04-19T05:27:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide additional authority for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide health care for veterans of the Persian Gulf War.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400548"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1512-1513)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-21"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="War casualties"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1993--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide hospital care, and authorizes the Secretary to provide nursing home care, to a veteran exposed to an environmental hazard. Makes a veteran exposed to a toxic substance or an environmental hazard during the Persian Gulf War eligible for hospital and nursing home care for any disability for which a need for treatment is determined by the Secretary before October 1, 1994, notwithstanding whether it is medically evident that such disability is associated with such exposure. Extends the provision of such care through FY 1996. Makes such veterans eligible through such period for outpatient care for any disability for which a need for treatment is determined before October 1, 1994.

	</summary>
</bill>
