<bill session="103" type="h" number="2416" updated="2010-04-19T05:28:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Partnership System of Heritage Areas Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the preservation, interpretation, development and beneficial use of natural, cultural, historic and scenic resources that are a source of values important to the people of the United States through a national partnership system of heritage areas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400178"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-06"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-22"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.3707.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3707" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3707" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Culture"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Landscape protection"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="New York State"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Urban life"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1993--Introduced.
National Partnership System of Heritage Areas Act - Establishes the National Partnership Heritage Area Advisory Commission to advise the Secretary of the Interior in the creation and administration of the National Partnership System of Heritage Areas, including matters relating to partnership studies, recommendations for national designation by the Congress, and mechanisms for coordinating Federal activities which affect National Heritage Areas or Parks and for coordinating Federal, State, local, and private interests in each such area or park. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to assist in studies that identify and plan for heritage areas or State systems or programs for such areas. Requires that such studies provide a means for evaluating candidate areas and systems for further Federal involvement upon congressional authorization. Limits such a grant to 50 percent of the cost of conducting the study. Sets forth provisions regarding application procedures, review criteria, study content, technical assistance, and recommendations for national designation. Establishes the National Partnership System of Heritage Areas. Designates as components thereof: (1) National Heritage Areas or Parks; (2) National Heritage Corridors established by law; and (3) the New York State Urban Cultural Park System. Requires the Secretary to request the Governor of the State in which the designated area or system is located to submit a management plan to the Secretary for review and approval. Permits the Secretary, upon request of a Governor, to provide technical assistance in the preparation and implementation of the plan. Sets forth provisions regarding the role and contents, approval, and implementation of the plans, as well as reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
