<bill session="103" type="h" number="242" updated="2010-04-18T23:37:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Infrastructure Now for America's-Tomorrow Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide financial assistance for the repair, reconstruction, and rehabilitation of highways, bridges, transit facilities, airports, and wastewater treatment works.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400243"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402763" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="410974" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="1993-02-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-19"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-19"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-19"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW-05" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public works"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Aviation fuels"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Diesel motor"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Fuel"/>
		<term name="Gasoline tax"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
		<term name="Occupational therapy"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Infrastructure Repair Title II: Funding for Infrastructure Repair and Deficit Reduction Infrastructure Now For America's-Tomorrow Act of 1993 - Title I: Infrastructure Repair - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration to make grants to State and local governments for projects for: (1) the repair, reconstruction, and rehabilitation of highways and bridges; and (2) the construction of highway lanes for high occupancy vehicles. Sets forth application requirements and the Federal share (80 percent). Authorizes the Administrator to make loans to governments receiving grants for such projects to assist them in covering the non-Federal share of the cost of the project. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Administrator of: (1) the Federal Transit Administration to make grants to governments for projects for the repair, reconstruction, and rehabilitation of transit facilities; (2) the Federal Aviation Administration to make grants to sponsors, owners, and operators of public-use airports for the repairs, reconstruction, and rehabilitation; and (3) the Environmental Protection Agency to make grants to governments for environmental improvement projects, including projects for the construction, reconstruction, repair, and rehabilitation of wastewater treatment works. Sets forth limitations on the use of grant funds regarding: (1) land acquisition; (2) payment of maintenance costs; (3) the non-Federal share; (4) Buy American requirements; and (5) minority participation. Title II: Funding for Infrastructure Repair and Deficit Reduction - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the rate of excise taxes and the rates on motor fuels for deficit reduction to fund the Infrastructure Now For America's-Tomorrow Trust Fund. Establishes such trust fund to finance the grant program for infrastructure repair. Imposes a floor stocks tax on such motor fuels, with exceptions. Requires the transfer of such revenue to the trust fund.

	</summary>
</bill>
