<bill session="103" type="h" number="2445" updated="2012-07-17T05:40:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1993-10-28" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Appropriations bill FY94, Energy and Water Development</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Energy FY94 Appropriations bill</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Water Development FY94 Appropriations bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for energy and water development for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401417"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17T17:39:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-135, by Mr. Bevill.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-17"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Ordered to be Reported.</text></calendar>
		<calendar number="74" datetime="1993-06-17T17:40:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 74.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22T17:09:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 203 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2445. Waiving cetain points of order against the bill. No amendment affecting the subject of the Super Collider shall be in order, except as part of general reduction of amounts provided in the bill, the exception of one amendment offered by Rep Slattery of Kansas. Said amendment shall be debateabl for one hour equally divided, and not subject to further amendmetn or division in the House or in the Committee of the Whole</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T17:10:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 203 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T17:10:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3981-3989"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T17:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved to resolve into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T17:11:00-04:00"><text>Pending the foregoing motion, Mr. Bevill asked unanimous consent that the time for general debate on the bill be limited to not to exceed one hour. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T17:12:00-04:00"><text>On motion to resolve into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T17:12:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable William J. Hughes to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T17:12:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement previously agreed to, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T18:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T18:19:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23T18:19:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2445 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T10:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4019-4076"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T10:04:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved to resolve into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T10:04:00-04:00"><text>On motion to resolve into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T10:05:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable William J. Hughes to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T13:30:00-04:00"><text>LIMITATION ON DEBATE - Mr. Bevill asked unanimous that the time for debate on the Coopersmith amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed 30 minutes, equally divided between Mr. Coppersmith and Mr. Mineta. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T13:30:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of additional debate on the Coopersmith amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T14:25:00-04:00"><text>LIMITATION ON DEBATE - Mr. Markey asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Markey amendment be limited to not to exceed 30 minutes, equally divided between himself and Mr. Myers. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T14:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T15:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 203, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Slattery amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T17:12:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Dingell raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Dingell stated that the provisions of the bill beginning on page 35, line 17 through line 25, inclusive, requiring the transfer of a maximum of $10 million in fees collected by the United States Enrichment Corporation from foreign customers to the Department of Energy, constituted legislation on an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T17:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T17:19:00-04:00"><text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T17:19:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2445.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T17:20:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4019-4076"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T17:22:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the remaining amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:00:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Wolf moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:01:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:01:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by voice vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4075"/></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="273" datetime="1993-06-24T18:18:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 350 - 73 (Roll no. 273).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:18:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-09-23" ><text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-23"><text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. With written report No. 103-147.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="208" datetime="1993-09-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 208.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Measure laid before Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S12674-12728"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Amendment SP 981 proposed by Senator Hatfield.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Amendment SP 981 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Amendment SP 982 proposed by Senator Brown.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Amendment SP 982 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Amendment SP 983 proposed by Senator Bumpers.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S12760-12796, S12800-12815, S12817-12826"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Motion to table SP 983 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57-42. Record Vote No: 296.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 987 proposed by Senator Kerry.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Motion to table SP 987 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53-45. Record Vote No: 298.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 988 proposed by Senator Bingaman.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 988 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 989 proposed by Senator Bradley.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 990 proposed by Senator Bradley.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 991 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Chafee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 992 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Metzenbaum.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 992 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 991 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 993 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Wallop.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 993 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 994 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Danforth.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 994 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 995 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Moynihan.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 995 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 996 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Hatfield.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 996 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 997 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Warner.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 997 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 998 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Bumpers.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 998 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 999 proposed by Senator Johnston.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 999 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 1000 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Gramm.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 1000 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 1001 proposed by Senator Johnston.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 1001 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 1002 proposed by Senator Johnston for Senator Burns.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 1002 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Motion to table SP 989 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 41-58. Record Vote No: 299.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Amendment SP 989 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Motion to table SP 990 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 81-18. Record Vote No: 300.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="301" datetime="1993-09-30" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 89-10. Record Vote No: 301.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Senate insists on its amendments asks for a conference, appoints conferees Johnston; Byrd; Hollings; Sasser; DeConcini; Reid; Kerrey; Hatfield; Cochran; Domenici; Nickles; Gorton; McConnell.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:03:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:03:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:04:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Livingston moved that the House instruct conferees.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:04:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Livingston motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion require the managers on the part of the House to insist upon the House's termination of the Superconducting Super Collider.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:05:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:05:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:05:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7702"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T16:05:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Bevill, Fazio, Chapman, Peterson (FL), Pastor, Meek, Natcher, Myers, Gallo, Rogers, and McDade.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T15:40:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Natcher asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on Oct. 14 to file a conference report on H.R. 2445. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14"><text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T19:32:00-04:00"><text>Conference report H. Rept. 103-292 filed with 15 amendments in disagreement.</text><reference label="text of conference report" ref="CR H7906-7968"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T12:13:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill brought up conference report H. Rept. 103-292 for consideration as a privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8108"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T12:15:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T13:35:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on agreeing to the conference report was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8125-8126"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T13:36:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Myers moved to recommit to the conference committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:00:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit to Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 159 - 264 (Roll no. 510).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:02:00-04:00"><text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:03:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Slattery moved to amend the motion to recommit the conference report to the conference committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:03:00-04:00"><text>The Slattery amendment to the motion to recommit the conference report requires the managers on the part of the House to insist on the House position regarding elimination of funding of the Superconducting Super Collider.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:06:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the amendment to the motion to recommit the conference report was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:18:00-04:00"><text>On agreeing to the amendment to the motion to recommit the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 282 - 143 (Roll no. 511).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:20:00-04:00"><text>On agreeing to the Myers motion to recommit the conference report, as amended. Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T14:21:00-04:00"><text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-22T10:03:00-04:00"><text>Conference report H. Rept. 103-305 filed with 16 amendments in disagreement.</text><reference label="text of conference report" ref="CR H8364-8429"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T12:56:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill brought up conference report H. Rept. 103-305 by previously agreed to special order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T12:56:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T13:41:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="526" datetime="1993-10-26T14:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 332 - 81 (Roll no. 526).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8442-8452"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:05:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 2.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:05:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 2 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:05:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 3.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 4.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:07:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 3 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:09:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 4 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:09:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 12.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:09:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 14.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:09:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 12 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 14 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 15.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 15 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 17.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 20.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 17 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 20 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 22.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 22 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 29.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 30.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 29 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 30 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 31.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 32.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:11:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 31 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:12:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 32 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:12:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 33.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:12:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Bevill motion to recede and concur in Senate amendment No. 33 with an amendment. Senate amendment No. 33 provides funding for the Superconducting Super Collider. The proposed House amendment provides $640,000,000 for the orderly termination of the Superconducting Super Collider instead of providing $1.1 billion for continuation of the SSC project.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:21:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:45:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 33 Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 190 (Roll No. 527).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:46:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 36.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:47:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 36 Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8453-8460"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:47:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bevill moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 39.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:47:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 39 Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8453-8460"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26T14:47:00-04:00"><text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="333" datetime="1993-10-27" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 89-11. Record Vote No: 333.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14484"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Senate agreed to the House amendments to the Senate amendment nos. 2, 3, 4, 17, 33, and 36 by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14471"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1993-10-27" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident datetime="1993-10-28" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1993-10-28" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-126" type="public" datetime="1993-10-28"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-126.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup" />
		<committee code="HSAP-10" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" />
		<committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development" activity="Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="203" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public works"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Arkansas"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Beach erosion"/>
		<term name="Beaches"/>
		<term name="Breeder reactors"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Canals"/>
		<term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
		<term name="Civil engineering"/>
		<term name="Colorado River development"/>
		<term name="Columbia River development"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Computer software"/>
		<term name="Computers"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
		<term name="Delaware River Basin Commission"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Dredging"/>
		<term name="Easements"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Electric power"/>
		<term name="Electric power distribution"/>
		<term name="Electric power transmission"/>
		<term name="Electric utilities"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Energy supplies"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Flood control"/>
		<term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Geothermal resources"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Government vehicles"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Harbors"/>
		<term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
		<term name="Helium"/>
		<term name="Hurricanes"/>
		<term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
		<term name="Hydrogen"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Indian claims"/>
		<term name="Indian water rights"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Inland water transportation"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin"/>
		<term name="Islands"/>
		<term name="Kentucky"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Lakes"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Louisiana"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Missouri"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="National monuments"/>
		<term name="Navigation"/>
		<term name="Nevada"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="New York City"/>
		<term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
		<term name="Nuclear energy research facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
		<term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
		<term name="Nuclear research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Ohio"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution control"/>
		<term name="Plants"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Radioisotopes"/>
		<term name="Reclamation of land"/>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Rhode Island"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="River basin commissions"/>
		<term name="River regulation"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Sewage disposal"/>
		<term name="Shore protection"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Soil conservation"/>
		<term name="Space activities"/>
		<term name="Sports and recreation"/>
		<term name="Storm drains"/>
		<term name="Superconductivity"/>
		<term name="Surveying"/>
		<term name="Susquehanna River Basin Commission"/>
		<term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
		<term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Uranium"/>
		<term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Water storage"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetlands"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women in business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h135"/>
		<amendment number="h136"/>
		<amendment number="h137"/>
		<amendment number="h138"/>
		<amendment number="h139"/>
		<amendment number="h140"/>
		<amendment number="h141"/>
		<amendment number="h142"/>
		<amendment number="h143"/>
		<amendment number="h144"/>
		<amendment number="h145"/>
		<amendment number="h146"/>
		<amendment number="h147"/>
		<amendment number="h148"/>
		<amendment number="s981"/>
		<amendment number="s982"/>
		<amendment number="s983"/>
		<amendment number="s984"/>
		<amendment number="s985"/>
		<amendment number="s987"/>
		<amendment number="s988"/>
		<amendment number="s989"/>
		<amendment number="s990"/>
		<amendment number="s991"/>
		<amendment number="s992"/>
		<amendment number="s993"/>
		<amendment number="s994"/>
		<amendment number="s995"/>
		<amendment number="s996"/>
		<amendment number="s997"/>
		<amendment number="s998"/>
		<amendment number="s999"/>
		<amendment number="s1000"/>
		<amendment number="s1001"/>
		<amendment number="s1002"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/26/1993--House receded and concurred with amendment. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Defense-Civil Title II: Department of the Interior Title III: Department of Energy Title IV: Independent Agencies Title V: General Provision Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1994 - Title I: Department of Defense-Civil - Makes appropriations for FY 1994 for: (1) authorized civil functions of the Department of the Army relating to rivers and harbors, flood control, beach erosion, and related purposes; (2) expenses necessary for the collection and study of information related to such purposes; (3) the prosecution of authorized water development and related projects; (4) certain flood control projects on the Mississippi River and its related tributaries; (5) water development projects operation and maintenance; (6) regulatory programs; (7) flood control and coastal emergencies; (8) oil spill research; and (9) general expenses. Specifies miscellaneous authorized and prohibited uses of funds appropriated by this Act. Requires the Secretary of the Army in FY 1994 to provide for competitive bidding for a specified amount of dredge volume to be accomplished with Government-owned dredges. Authorizes the Secretary to reprogram funds as necessary to continue any prior water resources project which may be terminated. Authorizes the Secretary to convey to Galveston, Texas, the San Jacinto Disposal Area for fair market value, including a parcel of land on Pelican Island, Texas. Title II: Department of the Interior - Makes appropriations for FY 1994 for: (1) carrying out the Central Utah Project Completion Act; (2) the Bureau of Reclamation; (3) general investigation of proposed Federal reclamation projects; (4) project construction and rehabilitation; (5) project operation and maintenance; (6) the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund; and (7) general, special, and emergency funds. Title III: Department of Energy - Makes appropriations for FY 1994 to the Department of Energy (DOE) for: (1) energy supply, research and development activities; (2) uranium supply and enrichment activities; (3) the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund; (4) general DOE science and research activities, including specified funds to terminate the Superconducting Super Collider project according to prescribed terms and conditions; (5) the Nuclear Waste Disposal Fund; (6) the Isotope Production and Distribution Program Fund; (7) atomic energy defense weapons activities; (8) defense environmental restoration and waste management; (9) DOE materials support and other DOE defense programs; (10) defense nuclear waste disposal; (11) DOE administration expenses; (12) operation, maintenance, construction, rehabilitation, and funding expenses of the various geographical power administrations of DOE; and (13) salaries and expenses of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. Title IV: Independent Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 1994 for: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission; (2) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board; (3) the Delaware River Basin Commission; (4) the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin; (5) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission; (6) the Office of the Inspector General; (7) the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board and the Nuclear Waste Negotiator; (8) the Susquehanna River Basin Commission; and (9) the Tennessee Valley Authority. Title V: General Provision - Amends the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1993 to make eligible for participation in the Superconducting Super Collider Project small business concerns owned or controlled by women. Sets forth certification requirements for small businesses participating in the Project and requirements for certain records, reports, and audits by the Secretary of Energy in connection with such Project. Prohibits any entity from expending funds appropriated under this Act unless such entity agrees to comply with all applicable requirements of the Buy American Act. Provides that if a court or Federal agency determines that any person intentionally affixed a &quot;Made in America&quot; label on any product sold in or shipped to the United States that was not made in America, such person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract made with funds provided under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
