<bill session="103" type="h" number="2447" updated="2010-04-19T05:33:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Population Stabilization and Reproductive Health Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to establish and strengthen policies and programs for the early stabilization of world population through the global expansion of reproductive choice, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401310"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400885" joined="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="402890" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="1993-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="411725" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="406482" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400417" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400539" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400205" joined="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="411065" joined="1994-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400035" joined="1993-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="409650" joined="1994-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1994-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="401947" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400536" joined="1993-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400554" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="404009" joined="1993-11-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1541-1543)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
		<term name="Abortion"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Contraceptives"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Food relief"/>
		<term name="Gynecology"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Human fertility"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Illiteracy"/>
		<term name="Infant mortality"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Literacy programs"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
		<term name="Obstetrics"/>
		<term name="Population growth"/>
		<term name="Population policy"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Reproduction"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
		<term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
		<term name="Sterilization (Birth control)"/>
		<term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women's education"/>
		<term name="World health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/17/1993--Introduced.
International Population Stabilization and Reproductive Health Act - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to set forth population assistance authorities and requirements. Makes such assistance available to a country that: (1) accounts for a significant portion of the world's annual population increment; (2) has significant unmet needs for methods of contraception, prevention and treatment of sexually transmitted diseases, and obstetric and gynecological care and requires foreign assistance to sustain quality reproductive health services; or (3) demonstrates a strong commitment to population stabilization and reproductive health strategies. Prohibits nongovernmental and multilateral organizations from being subjected to requirements which are more restrictive than those applicable to foreign governments for such assistance. Makes funds available for: (1) the United Nations Population Fund if it agrees to prohibit the use of funds for coerced abortion or involuntary sterilization; and (2) the Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training to further international cooperation in the development of contraceptive technology. Authorizes appropriations. Makes development assistance available on a priority basis for countries which have agreed to address specific education, literacy, and health issues. Authorizes the President to establish a grant program, to be known as the Safe Motherhood Initiative, to improve the access of girls and women to reproductive health care services. Earmarks amounts of development and economic assistance for programs in support of equalizing male and female levels of primary and secondary school enrollment. Authorizes appropriations for the Child Survival Fund, the Safe Motherhood Initiative, and for research on, and treatment and control of, acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) in developing countries. Requires the U.S. executive directors of specified international financial institutions to report anually to the Congress on allocations to population activities and, if such allocations total less than $1 million, to set forth actions to encourage increased allocations. Establishes the Commission on World Population Stabilization and Reproductive Health to coordinate U.S. participation in the 1994 International Conference on Population and Development. Authorizes appropriations. Provides for certain actions to support the United Nations Forward Looking Strategies for the Advancement of Women and the United Nations Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination Against Women.

	</summary>
</bill>
