<bill session="103" type="h" number="2448" updated="2012-07-17T04:24:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-28T15:20:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-07-28T15:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="361"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Radon Awareness and Disclosure Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Radon Awareness and Disclosure Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Radon Awareness and Disclosure Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the accuracy of radon testing products and services, to increase testing for radon, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400253"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="409650" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400553" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="1994-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="410567" joined="1993-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1994-02-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1549-1550)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Joint Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials and by the Subcommittee on Health and Environment Prior to Referral (Jul 14, 93).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and the Environment"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and the Environment"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-05-18"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-06-30T16:15:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 103-574.</text></action>
		<calendar number="319" datetime="1994-06-30T16:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 319.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-27T16:12:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 491 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2448 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Energy and Commerce now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T12:58:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 491 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T12:58:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 491.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6395-6410"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T12:58:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2448 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Energy and Commerce now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T12:58:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 491 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T12:58:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Patricia Schroeder to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T12:59:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T15:00:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2448.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T15:00:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T15:01:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="361" datetime="1994-07-28T15:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 255 - 164 (Roll no. 361).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28T15:20:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="491" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Building laws"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Defective products"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Lung cancer"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Presidential commissions"/>
		<term name="Quality of products"/>
		<term name="Radon"/>
		<term name="Real estate business"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Special weeks"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h801"/>
		<amendment number="h802"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1994--Passed House amended. Radon Awareness and Disclosure Act of 1994 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate model construction standards for controlling radon levels in new vulnerable premises (any frequently occupied space below the third floor of any building other than one used for industrial purposes) which are located in high radon areas and are covered by standards published on March 21, 1994. Requires promulgation of such standards in new vulnerable premises that are not covered by the March 1994 standards within two years of this Act's enactment. (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator to ensure that organizations responsible for developing national model codes for new vulnerable premises adopt, and State and local authorities which regulate construction of such premises adopt and enforce, Federal model construction standards. Requires the Administrator to publish a pamphlet describing the standards and their costs and benefits. Directs any person who sells a new vulnerable premises, prior to the signing of a sales contract, to: (1) provide the purchaser with a specified pamphlet on radon prevention in construction; (2) inform the purchaser that the premises are located in a high radon area and that the Administrator recommends that such premises be constructed in compliance with model construction standards; and (3) disclose to the purchaser whether the premises have been, or will be, constructed in compliance with such standards. Directs the Administrator to promulgate guidance for existing vulnerable premises not covered by proposed model standards published on April 12, 1993. (Sec. 5) Authorizes set-asides of grants made to States for radon abatement for local governments in high radon areas. (Sec. 6) Requires the Administrator to promulgate regulations to require: (1) products for radon measurement to meet performance criteria; and (2) persons offering services for radon measurement or mitigation to meet a level of proficiency. Provides for fees to be imposed on persons manufacturing or importing such products and on persons offering such services to cover program costs. Waives fees for employees of child care facilities, schools, hospitals, or other care facilities. (Sec. 7) Requires the Administrator to promulgate regulations for the disclosure of radon in vulnerable premises offered for sale or lease (except leases for terms of one year or less that do not provide for extensions). Requires contracts for such premises to contain radon warning statements and affords potential purchasers the right to conduct a test and access to a radon hazard information pamphlet. (Sec. 8) Authorizes State programs to enforce Federal requirements for incentives for voluntary compliance, radon measurement or mitigation services, or disclosure of information concerning radon, subject to the Administrator's approval. (Sec. 9) Makes Federal agencies subject to Federal, State, and local requirements respecting radon in the same manner as such requirements are applied to nongovernmental entities. (Sec. 10) Directs the Administrator to develop a strategy for identifying areas and buildings within the United States with exceptionally high levels of radon and for reducing such radon levels. (Sec. 11) Requires the Administrator to implement an outreach program to provide information about radon to the medical community. (Sec. 12) Directs the Administrator to ensure that the presentation of information on the health risks associated with exposure to radon is unbiased and informative. (Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations for radon control activities (except activities to address radon in schools) for FY 1994 through 1997. (Sec. 15) Establishes the President's Commission on Radon Awareness. Requires the Administrator to establish a national education campaign to increase awareness of radon health risks and motivate action to reduce radon levels. (Sec. 16) Expresses the sense of the Congress, in the case of any equipment or products that may be authorized to be purchased with financial assistance provided under this Act, that entities receiving such assistance should purchase only American-made equipment and products.

	</summary>
</bill>
