<bill session="103" type="h" number="2459" updated="2010-04-19T05:35:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Bureau of Investigation Appropriations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations to carry out the activities of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for fiscal year 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403776"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400192" joined="1993-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Automation"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="DNA fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Government aircraft"/>
		<term name="Government vehicles"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Police training"/>
		<term name="Presidential protection"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Protection of officials"/>
		<term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Undercover operations"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="White collar crime"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/1993--Introduced.
Federal Bureau of Investigation Appropriations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1994 - Authorizes appropriations to carry out the activities of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) for FY 1994. Directs the FBI to fully support implementation of NCIC 2000 by the States. Bars the use of funds authorized by this Act to relocate management and administrative operations for the National Crime Information Center or the Uniform Crime Reporting Program. Authorizes the Attorney General to use funds authorized to be appropriated for the FBI to make payments for the conduct of its activities. Bars the use of such payments to pay the compensation of any employee in the competitive service, but permits payments for: (1) expenses necessary for the detection and prosecution of crimes against the United States; (2) protection of the President and the Attorney General; (3) investigations regarding official matters under the control of the Department of Justice and the Department of State; and (4) acquisition, collection, classification, and preservation of identification and other records and their exchange with, and for the official use of, authorized officials of the Federal Government, States, cities, and other institutions, with such exchange subject to cancellation if dissemination is made outside the receiving departments or agencies.

	</summary>
</bill>
