<bill session="103" type="h" number="2462" updated="2010-04-19T05:35:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act and the Solid Waste Disposal Act to limit the liabilities under these Acts of both fiduciaries and lending institutions, including finance lessors, guarantors, and others directly or indirectly holding indicia of ownership primarily to protect a security interest in property which is subject to either Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400537"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405939" joined="1993-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400596" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400023" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="407838" joined="1993-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400520" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="406625" joined="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="1993-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="406605" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400056" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="409966" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="405258" joined="1994-06-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1553)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-27"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>See H.R.3800.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3800" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Commercial law"/>
		<term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to exclude from the definition of &quot;owner or operator,&quot; for purposes of limiting liability for releases of hazardous substances, a person who, without participating in the management of a vessel or facility, holds indicia of ownership primarily to protect a security interest in such vessel or facility. Defines &quot;indicia of ownership&quot; as an interest in property acquired: (1) for securing payment of a loan or indebtedness or the performance of an obligation; (2) evidencing ownership under a lease financing transaction where the lessor does not initially select or ordinarily control the daily operation or maintenance of the property; or (3) in the course of protecting a security interest or right of reimbursement or subrogation under a guaranty. Makes liable for any release or threatened release of a hazardous substance attributable to their activities: (1) a holder of a security interest who takes certain actions concerning transfer, protection, or abandonment of property; and (2) a fiduciary or trustee who acquires ownership or control of a property. Makes conforming amendments to the Solid Waste Disposal Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
