<bill session="103" type="h" number="2469" updated="2010-04-19T05:36:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Campaign and Election Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 and related laws to strengthen public confidence in the integrity of the legislative process, to reform campaign practices for congressional elections, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410589"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1993-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="404723" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400506" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="401033" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="408556" joined="1993-07-29" withdrawn="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="406863" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300156" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400269" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1993-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="404602" joined="1993-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1993-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1993-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400334" joined="1993-11-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Broadcast journalism"/>
		<term name="Campaign contributors"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Congressional candidates"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Equal time rule"/>
		<term name="Extortion"/>
		<term name="Fund raising"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
		<term name="Political conventions"/>
		<term name="Political parties"/>
		<term name="Presidential candidates"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Radio in politics"/>
		<term name="State politics and government"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Television in politics"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers in politics"/>
		<term name="Voter registration"/>
		<term name="Voting"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/1993--Introduced.
Congressional Campaign and Election Reform Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to reduce maximum contribution amounts to candidates for Federal office from: (1) multicandidate political committees (PACs); and (2) persons other than PACs. (Sec. 4) Delineates circumstances in which a person's contribution shall be considered as being made through an intermediary or a conduit (and therefore treated as contributions from such person). (Sec. 5) Treats contributions by dependents not of voting age as contributions of the person or persons upon whom they are dependent. (Sec. 6) Aggregates, for contribution limit purposes, contributions from State and local party committees with all contributions from such political party. (Sec. 7) Makes it unlawful to secure or to use contributions secured by physical force or other intimidation. (Sec. 8) Prohibits a candidate from accepting cash contributions aggregating more than $100 from any one person. (Sec. 9) Defines &quot;generic campaign activity&quot; and &quot;State Party Grassroots Fund.&quot; (Sec. 10) Establishes individual and PAC contribution limits to State Party Grassroots Funds and other State party committees. Allows individuals to contribute up to a specified amount of funds annually to State party committees in addition to current amounts contributed annually to all candidates and their authorized committees. Replaces the current individual contribution limits for any calendar year with aggregate contribution limits for an election cycle. Revises presidential campaign expenditure limits. (Sec. 11) Prohibits, with exceptions, a national committee and a congressional campaign committee from soliciting or accepting contributions not subject to certain limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements. Subjects to such requirements any amount (&quot;soft money&quot;) solicited, received, or expended by a national, State, district, or local committee of a political party with respect to certain activities such as voter registration or get-out-the vote efforts. (Sec. 12) Sets forth fundraising limitations for Federal candidates and office holders and certain political committees. (Sec. 13 and 14) Sets forth reporting requirements for: (1) political committees; (2) exempt contributions; (3) State committees; and (4) certain independent expenditures. (Sec. 15) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a licensee to provide equal broadcast time to qualified candidates for public office. (Sec. 16) Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit Federal candidates from establishing leadership committees. Restricts contributions between principal campaign committees. (Sec. 17) Prohibits fund transfers among noncandidate, nonparty political committees. (Sec. 18) Restricts certain connected political action committee activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
