<bill session="103" type="h" number="248" updated="2010-04-18T23:38:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ethics in Foreign Lobbying Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit contributions and expenditures by multicandidate political committees controlled by foreign-owned corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407320"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Business and politics"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Foreign corporations"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Ethics in Foreign Lobbying Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit multicandidate political committees or separate segregated funds of certain organizations or corporations which are controlled by foreign persons from making any contributions or expenditures with respect to an election for Federal office. Directs the Federal Election Commission to require reporting of ownership interest percentages and to list them. Prohibits foreign nationals from participating in the decisionmaking process of domestic organizations engaged in Federal, State, or local election-related activities. Establishes within the Federal Election Commission a clearinghouse of public information regarding the political activities of foreign principals and their agents. Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to require agents to file quarterly supplemental registration statements.

	</summary>
</bill>
