<bill session="103" type="h" number="2483" updated="2010-04-19T05:38:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to make changes in the laws relating to nonimmigrants and immigrants.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407306"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="1993-06-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Law, Immigration, and Refugees.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
		<term name="Adopted children"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Orphans"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Residence requirements"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="United States Information Agency"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/1993--Introduced.
Immigration Amendments of 1993 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to repeal the sunset date for certain retired international organization officers and employees (G-4 visa holders) to file for special immigrant status. Grants special immigrant status to certain immigrant employees of the United States Information Agency (USIA) having essential foreign language skills. Grants nonimmigrant status to an alien coming to work for USIA if: (1) he or she has essential language skills; and (2) no other qualified workers can be found in the United States. Provides with regard to foreign adopted children that the child: (1) does not have to be adopted abroad by a U.S. citizen; and (2) may be up to 18 years old. Provides for the adoption of children from foreign states which are certified by the Secretary of State as having met specified adoption standards. Amends Federal law to impose a criminal penalty upon a U.S. citizen or national who purchases an alien child with the intent to establish U.S. permanent residency for such child. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide permanent resident status for refugees admitted into the United States as of their date of U.S. arrival. Grants nonimmigrant status to: (1) an alien coming to testify in a Federal or State criminal investigation or prosecution; and (2) an alien spouse and child of a U.S. citizen.

	</summary>
</bill>
