<bill session="103" type="h" number="2490" updated="2010-04-19T05:39:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-22">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-06-22" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Transportation and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402325"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Transportation"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Transportation"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Transportation"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Transportation"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22T21:41:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-149, by Mr. Carr.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-22"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Ordered to be Reported.</text></calendar>
		<calendar number="82" datetime="1993-06-22T22:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 82.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-06-28T23:58:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 211 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2490. Upon adoption of this resolution points of order against consideration of the bill for failure to comply with clause 7 of rule XXI shall be waived. During consideration of the bill, all points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 o r 6 of rule XXI shall be waived, with exceptions specified in the text of this resolution. Where points of order are waived against only part of a paragraph, a point of order against the balance of the paragraph may apply only within the balance of the paragraph and not the entire paragraph. Amendments en bloc offered by Rep. Carr may amend portions of the bill not yet read for amendment and portions already passed in reading, shall be considered read, and not subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. Amendments en bloc specified in the report accompanyi...</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21T19:08:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 221 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2490. All points of order against provisions in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI are waived in instances specified in the text of the resolution. House Resolution 211 is considered laid on the table upon agreement to House Resolution 221. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="211" />
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="221" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2750" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Air traffic"/>
		<term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Airlines"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
		<term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
		<term name="Aviation insurance"/>
		<term name="Aviation safety"/>
		<term name="Boating accidents"/>
		<term name="Boats and boating"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Capital budgets"/>
		<term name="Coast guard"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Commercial aviation"/>
		<term name="Common carriers"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Drunk driving"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Government consultants"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Government vehicles"/>
		<term name="Harbors"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Highspeed ground transportation"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Highway research"/>
		<term name="Illinois"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Inland water transportation"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
		<term name="Interoceanic canals"/>
		<term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
		<term name="Interstate highway system"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Landing aids (Aeronautics)"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Magnetic levitation vehicles"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Marine transportation"/>
		<term name="Maryland"/>
		<term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Metric system"/>
		<term name="Michigan"/>
		<term name="Military dependents"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="Military pensions"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="Minnesota"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Motor buses"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Motorcycles"/>
		<term name="National Transportation Safety Board"/>
		<term name="Navigation (Aeronautics)"/>
		<term name="Navigational aids"/>
		<term name="Noise"/>
		<term name="North Carolina"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution control"/>
		<term name="Oklahoma"/>
		<term name="Panama Canal"/>
		<term name="Panama Canal Commission"/>
		<term name="Pipelines"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Railroad engineering"/>
		<term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
		<term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
		<term name="Railroad research"/>
		<term name="Railroad safety"/>
		<term name="Railroad terminals"/>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Rent"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Rubber"/>
		<term name="Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Seat belts"/>
		<term name="Shipbuilding"/>
		<term name="Ships"/>
		<term name="Signs and signboards"/>
		<term name="Space industrialization"/>
		<term name="Speed limits"/>
		<term name="St. Lawrence Seaway"/>
		<term name="Statistical services"/>
		<term name="Tennessee"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Traffic congestion"/>
		<term name="Transportation and the physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Transportation planning"/>
		<term name="Transportation research"/>
		<term name="Transportation safety"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Tunnels"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
		<term name="Weather forecasting"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Transportation Title II: Related Agencies Title III: General Provisions Department of Transportation and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994 - Title I: Department of Transportation - Makes appropriations for FY 1994 for: (1) the Office of the Secretary of Transportation; (2) the Coast Guard; (3) the Federal Aviation Administration; (4) the Federal Highway Administration; (5) the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration; (6) the Federal Railroad Administration; (7) the Federal Transit Administration; (8) the Saint Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation; (9) Research and Special Programs Administration; and (10) the Office of the Inspector General. Title II: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 1994 for: (1) the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board; (2) the National Transportation Safety Board; (3) the Interstate Commerce Commission; (4) the Panama Canal Commission; (5) the Department of the Treasury; and (6) the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority. Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth specified prohibitions, limitations, permissions, and mandates with respect to the use of appropriations under this Act. (Sec. 308) Prohibits the use of funds for the planning or implementation of any change in the current Federal status of the Volpe National Transportation Systems Center (except for further development planning that does not alter such status) or the Turner-Fairbank Highway Research Center. (Sec. 310) Requires the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to distribute, on a ratio-formulated basis, Federal-aid highway State obligation limitations for FY 1994 for Federal-aid highways. Prohibits a State from obligating more than 25 percent of its allocation for such projects during the first three months of FY 1994. Sets forth additional specified obligation limits for States during FY 1994. (Sec. 311) Limits funds available for salaries and expenses to no more than 110 political and presidential appointees in the Department of Transportation. Prohibits the assignment of such personnel on temporary detail outside of the Department. (Sec. 314) Prohibits the use of funds for the construction of the Central Automated Transit System (Downtown People Mover) in Detroit, Michigan. (Sec. 319) Prohibits the use of funds to establish a vessel traffic safety fairway less than five miles wide between the Santa Barbara Traffic Separation Scheme and the San Francisco Traffic Separation Scheme. (Sec. 320) Authorizes airports to transfer to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) instrument landing systems which were purchased through a Federal airport aid or development program and which conform to FAA performance specifications. (Sec. 321) Prohibits the use of funds by the FAA for a new National Weather Graphics System. (Sec. 322) Prohibits the use of funds to award multiyear contracts for production end items that include: (1) economic order quantity or long lead time material procurement in excess of $10 million in any one year of the contract; or (2) a cancellation charge greater than $10 million which at the time of obligation has not been appropriated to the limits of the Government's liability; or (3) a requirement that permits performance under the contract during the second and subsequent years of such contract without conditioning such performance upon the appropriation of funds. (Sec. 324) Prohibits the use of funds for any changes in the current Federal status of the FAA's flight service stations at Red Bluff Airport, Red Bluff, California, and Tri-City Airport, Bristol, Tennessee. (Sec. 328) Terminates the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Regulatory Review Panel. (Sec. 329) Requires the Secretary to permit the obligation of not more than $9 million for the Rail Impact project in the Interstate 40/85 corridor from Raleigh to Charlotte, North Carolina, during each year that such corridor is under reconstruction. (Sec. 333) Limits to $79.5 million the maximum Federal obligation for Capital Development Program projects at Washington National Airport unless the cost to complete the program remains within the parameters of the Use/Lease Agreement between the user airlines and the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority. (Sec. 338) Prohibits the use of funds for the construction of an additional air carrier runway at Tulsa International Airport. (Sec. 341) Prohibits the use of funds to place speed limit or distance signs using the metric system on any State highway.

	</summary>
</bill>
