<bill session="103" type="h" number="2519" updated="2012-07-17T04:58:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1993-10-27" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Appropriations bill FY94, Commerce, Justice, State</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Commerce Department FY94 Appropriations bill</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Justice Department FY94 Appropriations bill</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">State Department FY94 Appropriations bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Justice and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of State and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Justice and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Justice and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Justice and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Department of Justice and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Department of State and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410076"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-13"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Rogers reserved all points of order against the bill.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:49:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-157, by Mr. Smith (IA).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-24"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Ordered to be Reported.</text></calendar>
		<calendar number="89" datetime="1993-06-24T18:50:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 89.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T10:05:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4412-4454"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T10:05:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved to resolve into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T10:05:00-04:00"><text>Pending the foregoing motion, Mr. Smith (IA) asked unanimous consent that the time for general debate on the bill be limited to not to exceed one hour, equally divided between Mr. Smith (IA) and Mr. Rogers. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T10:06:00-04:00"><text>On motion to resolve into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T10:06:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable George E. Brown Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T10:06:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T11:57:00-04:00"><text>LIMITATION ON TIME FOR DEBATE - Mr. Smith asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Hunter amendment be limited to not to exceed 40 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T13:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Walker raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Walker stated that the provisions in the bill beginning on page 32, lines 19-26, regarding the appropriation of funds for the Industrial Technology Services, consisted of an appropriation of unathorized funds and was, therefore, in violation of the rules of the House. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T13:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Diaz-Balart raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Diaz-Balart stated that the provisions in the bill beginning on page 33, lines 1-6, appropriating funds for construction of facilities for the National Institute of Standards and Technology, consisted of an appropriation of unauthorized funds and was, therefore, in violation of the rules of the House. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T13:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Mr. Smith asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Walker amendment be limited to not to exceed 10 minutes, equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T13:10:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walker amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T13:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Dingell raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Dingell stated that the provisions of the bill beginning on page 39, line 16, through page 40, line 16 consisted of an appropriation of funds without authorization. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T13:39:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Walker raised a point of order against the content of the measure. The provisions on page 42, line 9, after the word &quot;Act&quot;, through line 13, regarding the appropriation of funds for Information Infrastructure Grants for planning and construction of telecommunications networks, consisted of an unauthorized appropriation of funds. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T14:15:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Hall (TX) raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Hall (TX) stated that the provisions of the bill on beginning on page 58, line 3, through line 12, regarding the appropriation of funds for the Legal Services Corporation, consitituted an unauthorized appropriation of funds. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T14:16:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Penny raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Penny stated that the provision of the bill beginning on page 58, lines 15-25, regarding the appropriation of funds for the Economic Development Assistance Programs, constituted an unauthorized appropriation of funds. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T14:17:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T14:18:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2519 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01T14:18:00-04:00"><text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Pending before the Committee of the Whole is consideration of the Hefley amendment, left unfinished upon agreeing to the motion to rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T13:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4788-4818"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T13:04:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved to resolve into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T13:05:00-04:00"><text>On motion to resolve into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T13:05:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable George E. Brown Jr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T13:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the Hefley amendment, be limited to not to exceed 20 minutes, equally divided. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T14:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE LIMITATION - Mr. Smith of Iowa asked unanimous consent that debate on the Oberstar amendment be limited to not to exceed 30 minutes, equally allocated and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T15:37:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Linder raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Linder stated that the text of the bill on page 63, lines 1-17, appropriates funds for a program not previously authorized. (The funding affects the appropriation for contributions to international organizations.) The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T15:50:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Berman raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Berman stated that the text of the bill on page 67, lines 14-22, appropriates funds for a program not previously authorized. (The funding in question is for grants and expenses for the Board for International Broadcasting.) The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T16:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Berman raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Berman stated that the provisions of the bill beginning on page 73, lines 1 through 7, appropriating $17.5 million for the National Endowment for Democracy, constituted an unauthorized appropriation of funds. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T16:26:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Skaggs raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Skaggs stated that the provisions of the bill beginning on page 73, lines 6 through 16 appropriate funds for a program not previously authorized. (The funds affected are for radio broadcasting to Cuba.) The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T16:38:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T16:39:00-04:00"><text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by Division vote: 9 - 8.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T16:40:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2519.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T16:40:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T16:41:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the remaining amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T17:24:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Kolbe moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4818"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T17:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit the bill to the Committee on Appropriations with instructions to report the bill back with amendments to restore funding in the following areas: detention of U.S. prisoners in the custody of the U.S. Marshals Service; salaries and expenses within the FBI; the purchase of equipment within the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency. The amendment would restore funding to the afore-mentioned areas to the levels requested by the President.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T17:35:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T17:54:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 112 - 315 (Roll no. 345).</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="346" datetime="1993-07-20T18:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 327 - 98 (Roll no. 346).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T18:02:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, State. Approved for full committee consideration without amendment favorably.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-07-22" ><text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-22"><text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings with amendments. With written report No. 103-105.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="150" datetime="1993-07-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 150.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27"><text>Measure laid before Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9511-9532"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27"><text>Amendment SP 697 proposed by Senator Kerrey.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27"><text>Motion to table SP 697 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 92-7. Record Vote No: 220.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27"><text>Amendment SP 698 proposed by Senator D'Amato.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9601-9679"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Point of order raised in Senate with respect to SP 698.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>SP 698 determined germane by Yea-Nay Vote. 75-25. Record Vote No: 221.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 698 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 701 proposed by Senator Glenn.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 701 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 702 proposed by Senator Hollings for Senator Baucus.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 702 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 703 proposed by Senator Helms.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 703 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 77-23. Record Vote No: 222.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 704 proposed by Senator DeConcini.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 704 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 705 proposed by Senator Reid.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Proposed amendment SP 705 withdrawn in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 706 proposed by Senator Pryor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 706 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>The Committee amendment on page 83, lines 12-16, was not tabled by Yea-Nay Vote. 23-74. Record Vote No: 223.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 708 proposed by Senator Pressler.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 708 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 713 proposed by Senator Hollings for Senator Riegle.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 713 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 714 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Amendment SP 714 proposed by Senator Hollings for Senator Levin.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9804-9805, S9807-9820"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 723 proposed by Senator Bryan.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 723 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 724 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Dole.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 724 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 725 proposed by Senator Brown.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 725 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 726 proposed by Senator Brown.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 726 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>The committee amendment on page 83, lines 12 through 16, was agreed to by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 727 proposed by Senator Hollings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 727 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 728 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Dole.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 728 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 729 proposed by Senator Domenici.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 729 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 730 proposed by Senator Simon.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 731 proposed by Senator Pressler.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 731 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 732 proposed by Senator Domenici for Senator Hatch.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 732 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 730 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 733 proposed by Senator Hollings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Amendment SP 733 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="225" datetime="1993-07-29" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 87-13. Record Vote No: 225.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Senate insists on its amendments asks for a conference, appoints conferees Hollings; Inouye; Sasser; Bumpers; Lautenberg; Kerrey; Byrd; Domenici; Stevens; Hatfield; Gramm; McConnell.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:07:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Rogers moved that the House instruct conferees.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Rogers motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion require the managers on the part of the House to agree to the Senate amendment relating to the formation of an &quot;Inspector General&quot; to oversee United Nations Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:21:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:43:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 420 - 0 (Roll no. 466).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7197-7199"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:43:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29T13:43:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Smith (IA), Carr, Mollohan, Moran, Skaggs, Price (NC), Natcher, Rogers, Kolbe, Taylor (NC), and McDade.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T15:40:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Natcher asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on Oct. 14 to file a conference report on H.R. 2519. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14T22:09:00-04:00"><text>Conference report H. Rept. 103-293 filed with 63 amendments in disagreement. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text><reference label="text of conference report" ref="CR H7968-8000"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-15T13:13:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 276 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2519. Waiving all points of order against the conference report. Motions printed in the joint explanatory statement of the committee of conference shall be considered as read.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T12:13:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 276 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T19:38:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) brought up conference report H. Rept. 103-293 for consideration as a privileged matter.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T19:38:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T20:36:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T20:37:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="517" datetime="1993-10-19T20:55:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 303 - 100, 1 Present (Roll No. 517).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8161-8172"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T20:59:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 3.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T20:59:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 5.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T20:59:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 3 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:00:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 5 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:00:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) asked unanimous consent to consider enbloc the Senate amendments Nos. 7, 11, 62, 79, 80, 99, 120, 137 and 145. Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8173-8174"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendments en bloc.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8173-8174"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:01:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendments Nos. 7, 11, 62, 79, 80, 99, 120, 137, and 145 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 10.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:01:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 10 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 21.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:01:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 21 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 22.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:02:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 22 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:02:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 23.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:02:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 23 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:02:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 27.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:02:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 27 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:02:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 30.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:02:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 30 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:03:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 31.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:03:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 31 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:03:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 34.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:04:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 34 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:04:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 37 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:04:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 37.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:04:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 44.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:04:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 44 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:04:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 52.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:05:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 52 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 63.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 63 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 64.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 64 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 67.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 67 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 71.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 71 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 73.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:06:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 73 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 75.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 75 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 78.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 78 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 81.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 81 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 84.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:07:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 84 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 93.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 93 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 97.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 97 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 101.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 101 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 110.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 111.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:08:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 110 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:09:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 113.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:09:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 111 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:09:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 113 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:09:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 114.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:09:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 114 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 115.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 115 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 122.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 122 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 129.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:12:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 129 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:17:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 130.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 132.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 130 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 133.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 132 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 133 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 135.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 135 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 138.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:19:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 138 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 139.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:19:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 139 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 140.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:19:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 140 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 141.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:20:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 141 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:20:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 142.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:20:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 142 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:20:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 149.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:21:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 150.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:21:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 149 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:21:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 150 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:21:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 159.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:21:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 159 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:21:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 161.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:22:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 161 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:22:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 162.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:22:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 162 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:22:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 166.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:22:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 169.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:22:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 166 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:23:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 169 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:23:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 170.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:23:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 170 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19T21:23:00-04:00"><text>Further proceedings were postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T12:07:00-04:00"><text>The House proceeded to continue consideration of amendments in disagreement accompanying the conference report on H.R. 2519 as unfinished business pursuant to a previous order of the House.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8218-8227, H8248-8250"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T12:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 147.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T12:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Smith of Iowa motion to recede and concur in Senate amendment No. 147 with an amendment. Senate amendment No. 147 provides for the contribution in funding by the United States to International Organizations. The proposed House amendment would seek to withhold 10 percent of the funding until such time as an Inspector General is appointed and in place to oversee reduction of waste, fraud, and abuse in the United Nations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T12:33:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T12:51:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 147 Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 422 - 2 (Roll No. 519).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T12:56:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 148.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T12:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Smith of Iowa motion to recede and concur in Senate amendment No. 148 with an amendment. Senate amendment No. 148 provides funding for U.S. contributions for international peacekeeping activities. The proposed House amendment settles on a dollar figure of $401,607,000 for such activities. Further, the amendment contains no limitation or earmarking of funds for arrearage payments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T13:30:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T13:53:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 148 Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 367 - 61 (Roll No. 520).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T13:53:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur in the Senate amendment No. 171.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T13:54:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Smith of Iowa motion to recede and concur in Senate amendment No. 171. Senate amendment No. 171 appropriates $35,000,000 for the National Endowment for Democracy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:24:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:24:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Kanjorski demanded that the question on the motion be divided. The House moves to consider the motion to recede.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:41:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede from its disagreement to the Senate amendment No. 171 Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 259 - 172 (Roll No. 521).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:42:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House concur with the Senate amendment No. 171.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:42:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 174.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:42:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House concur with the Senate amendment No. 171 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:43:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Smith (IA) moved that the House recede and concur with an amendment in the Senate amendment No. 175.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:43:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 174 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:43:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House recede and concur with amendment in the Senate amendment No. 175 Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20T15:43:00-04:00"><text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="323" datetime="1993-10-21" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 90-10. Record Vote No: 323.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14073-14083"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><text>Senate agreed to the House amendments to the Senate amendment nos. 3, 5, 10, 21, 22, 23, 27, 30, 31, 34, 37, 44, 52, 63, 64, 67, 71, 73, 75, 78, 81, 84, 93, 97, 101, 110, 111, 113, 114, 115, 122, 129, 130, 132, 133, 135, 138, 139, 140, 141, 142, 147, 148, 149, 150, 159, 161, 162, 166, 169, 170, 174, and 175 by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14078-14083"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1993-10-21" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident datetime="1993-10-25" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1993-10-27" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-121" type="public" datetime="1993-10-27"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-121.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup" />
		<committee code="" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" />
		<committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Commerce, Justice, State, and the Judiciary" activity="Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="276" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Abortion"/>
		<term name="Administration of justice"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Air piracy"/>
		<term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
		<term name="Arabs"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Arms Control and Disarmament Agency"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="Asian American ethnic groups"/>
		<term name="Assassination"/>
		<term name="Atmospheric research"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Bank fraud"/>
		<term name="Bankruptcy"/>
		<term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
		<term name="Biological weapons"/>
		<term name="Biotechnology"/>
		<term name="Board for International Broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Bombings"/>
		<term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Cartels"/>
		<term name="Census"/>
		<term name="Chemical weapons"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation in crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Civil service retirement"/>
		<term name="Civil war"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Clothing industry"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Coffee"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Commercial blacklisting"/>
		<term name="Commission on Civil Rights"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Community policing"/>
		<term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
		<term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
		<term name="Concentration camps"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Corporate mergers"/>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Credit cards"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Cuba"/>
		<term name="Cubans"/>
		<term name="Cultural centers"/>
		<term name="Cultural relations"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense contracts"/>
		<term name="Defense industries"/>
		<term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="Disaster loans"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Droughts"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Drunk driving"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Economic statistics"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Educational exchanges"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational television"/>
		<term name="Embassies"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission"/>
		<term name="Estonia"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Executives"/>
		<term name="Exhibitions"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
		<term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
		<term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Fish culture"/>
		<term name="Fish inspection"/>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Fishery products"/>
		<term name="Fishing"/>
		<term name="Fishing boats"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
		<term name="Foreign exchange"/>
		<term name="Foreign fishing"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign service"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Gangs"/>
		<term name="Genetic research"/>
		<term name="Government aircraft"/>
		<term name="Government attorneys"/>
		<term name="Government consultants"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Government vehicles"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Haitians"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Hijacking"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Hostages"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Human genetics"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Hurricanes"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Immigration policy"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Industrial engineering"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="Insurgency"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="International Trade Commission"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International broadcasting"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="International cooperation in science"/>
		<term name="International fishery management"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="International relief"/>
		<term name="Investment advisers"/>
		<term name="Israel"/>
		<term name="Japan"/>
		<term name="Japan-U.S. Friendship Commission"/>
		<term name="Japanese Americans"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Judicial compensation"/>
		<term name="Judicial officers"/>
		<term name="Juries"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
		<term name="Kansas"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Latvia"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Legal Services Corporation"/>
		<term name="Legal assistance to the poor"/>
		<term name="Legal education"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
		<term name="Lithuania"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Maps"/>
		<term name="Marine Mammal Commission"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Marine mammal protection"/>
		<term name="Maritime operations"/>
		<term name="Martin Luther King Day"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="Merchant ships"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Migrant labor"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military occupation"/>
		<term name="Miners"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minorities in the mass media industry"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="Missing persons"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Nevada"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="New York City"/>
		<term name="Nicaragua"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Oceanographic research"/>
		<term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
		<term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Patents"/>
		<term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
		<term name="Pesticides"/>
		<term name="Police-community relations"/>
		<term name="Population growth"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Prison labor"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Protection of foreign officials"/>
		<term name="Public defenders"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Reconnaissance aircraft"/>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
		<term name="Repatriation"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Russian Republic"/>
		<term name="Sabotage"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
		<term name="Seafood"/>
		<term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
		<term name="Securities regulation"/>
		<term name="Security measures"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment"/>
		<term name="Shipbuilding"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Special prosecutors"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State courts"/>
		<term name="Storms"/>
		<term name="Supreme Court"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
		<term name="Taiwan"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication policy"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Television and children"/>
		<term name="Television broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Television stations"/>
		<term name="Temporary employment"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Textile industry and fabrics"/>
		<term name="Tourist trade"/>
		<term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
		<term name="Trademarks"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="United Nations finances"/>
		<term name="United Nations structure"/>
		<term name="United States Information Agency"/>
		<term name="Uranium"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Utah"/>
		<term name="Vaccines"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Weather forecasting"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
		<term name="World War II"/>
		<term name="Wyoming"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h191"/>
		<amendment number="h192"/>
		<amendment number="h193"/>
		<amendment number="h194"/>
		<amendment number="h195"/>
		<amendment number="h196"/>
		<amendment number="h219"/>
		<amendment number="h220"/>
		<amendment number="h221"/>
		<amendment number="h222"/>
		<amendment number="h223"/>
		<amendment number="h224"/>
		<amendment number="h225"/>
		<amendment number="s697"/>
		<amendment number="s698"/>
		<amendment number="s699"/>
		<amendment number="s701"/>
		<amendment number="s702"/>
		<amendment number="s703"/>
		<amendment number="s704"/>
		<amendment number="s705"/>
		<amendment number="s706"/>
		<amendment number="s708"/>
		<amendment number="s713"/>
		<amendment number="s714"/>
		<amendment number="s723"/>
		<amendment number="s724"/>
		<amendment number="s725"/>
		<amendment number="s726"/>
		<amendment number="s727"/>
		<amendment number="s728"/>
		<amendment number="s729"/>
		<amendment number="s730"/>
		<amendment number="s731"/>
		<amendment number="s732"/>
		<amendment number="s733"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/20/1993--House receded and concurred with amendment. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Justice and Related Agencies Title II: Department of Commerce Title III: The Judiciary Title IV: Related Agencies Title V: Department of State and Related Agencies Title VI: General Provisions Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994 - Title I: Department of Justice and Related Agencies - Department of Justice and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994 - Makes FY 1994 appropriations to the Department of Justice. (Sec. 103) Prohibits the use of funds to require any person to perform, or facilitate the performance of, any abortion. (Sec. 111) Increases bankruptcy filing fees. Requires the Judicial Conference of the United States to report to the congressional Judiciary Committees on the bankruptcy fee system. Makes appropriations for the following related agencies for FY 1994: (1) the Commission on Civil Rights; (2) the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; (3) the Federal Communications Commission; (4) the Federal Maritime Commission; (5) the Federal Trade Commission; (6) the Securities and Exchange Commission; and (7) the State Justice Institute. Title II: Department of Commerce - Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 1994 - Makes FY 1994 appropriations to the Department of Commerce and related agencies. Title III: The Judiciary - Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1994 - Appropriates FY 1994 funds for activities of the Judiciary, including: (1) the Supreme Court; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit; (3) the U.S. Court of International Trade; (4) the Courts of Appeals, district courts, and judicial services; (5) the Administrative Office of the United States Courts; (6) the Federal Judicial Center; and (7) the U.S. Sentencing Commission. Title IV: Related Agencies - Appropriates FY 1994 funds for: (1) the Maritime Administration of the Department of Transportation; (2) the Commission on Immigration Reform; (3) the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe; (4) the Competitiveness Policy Council; (5) the Marine Mammal Commission; (6) the Martin Luther King, Jr. Federal Holiday Commission; (7) the Office of the United States Trade Representative; (8) the Small Business Administration; (9) the Legal Services Corporation; and (10) the Thomas Jefferson Commemoration Commission. Title V: Department of State and Related Agencies - Department of State and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1994 - Appropriates FY 1994 funds for the Department of State. Appropriates FY 1994 funds for: (1) the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency; (2) the Board for International Broadcasting; (3) the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad; (4) the International Trade Commission; (5) the Japan-United States Friendship Commission; and (6) the United States Information Agency. Establishes the Advisory Panel on Radio Marti and TV Marti to study the purposes, policies, and practices of radio and television broadcasting to Cuba by the Cuba Service of the Voice of America. Requires a report to the Congress and the U.S. Information Agency. Title VI: General Provisions - Sets forth limitations and prohibitions on the use of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 606) Expresses the sense of the Congress that entities receiving assistance under this Act should purchase only American-made equipment and products to the extent feasible.

	</summary>
</bill>
