<bill session="103" type="h" number="2550" updated="2010-04-19T05:49:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Markets and Trading Reorganization and Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Markets and Trading Commission in order to combine the functions of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission in a single independent regulatory commission, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404602"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="1993-06-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1660-1661)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-02"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Credit and Rural Development.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-02"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Commodity Futures Trading Com.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Growth and Credit Formation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Received from Commodity Futures Trading Com.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Environment, Credit and Rural Development" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Growth and Credit Formation" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Securities"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
		<term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal reserve system"/>
		<term name="Futures trading"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Margins (Security trading)"/>
		<term name="Options (Contract)"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
		<term name="Securities regulation"/>
		<term name="Transfer of employees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/29/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Establishment of Commission Title II: Transfers of Functions Title III: Federal Financial Markets Coordinating Council Title IV: Administrative Provisions Title V: Transitional, Savings, and Conforming Provisions Title VI: Effective Date Markets and Trading Reorganization and Reform Act - Title I: Establishment of Commission - Establishes the Markets and Trading Commission (the Commission) as an independent regulatory body. Title II: Transfers of Functions - Transfers to the Commission: (1) all functions of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and of the Securities and Exchange Commission; and (2) the margin authority of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Empowers the Commission to adjust and prescribe margin levels with respect to futures contracts. Title III: Federal Financial Markets Coordinating Council - Establishes the Federal Financial Markets Coordinating Council to: (1) coordinate the regulatory operations of the Federal regulatory agencies represented on the Council; and (2) establish an advisory committee composed of representatives of the futures, commodities, options, securities exchanges, and the banking industry; and (3) present biennial status reports to the Congress. Title IV: Administrative Provisions - Sets forth guidelines for Commission personnel and administration. Authorizes appropriations. Title V: Transitional, Savings, and Conforming Provisions - Prescribes procedural guidelines for the transfer and allocation of appropriations and personnel. Title VI: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
