<bill session="103" type="h" number="2586" updated="2010-04-19T05:54:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reorganization of the Federal Administrative Judiciary Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reorganize the Federal administrative law judiciary, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404602"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400553" joined="1994-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400210" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="408052" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="401547" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400534" joined="1994-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="409570" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407838" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="410589" joined="1994-08-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400329" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="407306" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="407400" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400395" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400568" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400536" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="402152" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400544" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="401417" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400291" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1994-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300096" joined="1994-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400314" joined="1993-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="403776" joined="1993-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400537" joined="1993-09-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1717-1718)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-09"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative law judges"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Judicial ethics"/>
		<term name="Judicial tenure"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
Reorganization of the Federal Administrative Judiciary Act - Establishes an administrative Law Judge Corps to be comprised of all current administrative law judges. States that the chief administrative law judge shall be the chief administrative officer of the Corps as well as its presiding judge. Specifies the qualifications for chief judge. States that such judge shall be appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate. Makes the chief judge responsible for developing programs and practices which foster economy and efficiency in the processing of cases heard by administrative law judges. Establishes eight divisions within the Corps, with each division headed by a division chief judge appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate. Identifies the divisions and their respective areas of jurisdiction. Specifies qualifications required for division chief judges. States that the Corps' policymaking body shall be the Council of the Corps comprised of the chief judge and the division chief judges. Authorizes the Council to: (1) assign judges to divisions and to transfer or reassign judges from one division to another; (2) appoint persons as administrative law judges; (3) file charges against an administrative law judge; (4) prescribe certain rules of practice and procedure for proceedings before the Corps; (5) issue rules and regulations for the efficient conduct of the Corps; and (6) perform other administrative functions. Directs the Council to appoint new judges from a register maintained by the Office of Personnel Management. Confers jurisdiction upon members of the Corps to adjudicate cases under specified sections of the Administrative Procedure Act. Requires cases arising under such sections to be referred to the Corps. Directs the Council to issue regulations for assigning such cases. Authorizes agencies and courts to refer cases to the Corps, subject to specified requirements. Requires guidelines for the removal and discipline of administrative law judges. Establishes a Complaints Resolution Board within the Corps to recommend action upon complaints against the official conduct of judges. Details the membership of such Board and the procedures to be followed. Declares Board proceedings and the contents of complaints to be privileged and confidential. Exempts: (1) documents and reports considered by the Board from the disclosure and publication requirements of the Freedom of Information Act; and (2) the Board from compliance with the public meeting requirements of specified Federal law. Directs the Corps' chief judge to study the various types of agency review to which decisions of administrative law judges are subject. Sets guidelines for such studies and directs the Council to report the findings of such studies to the President and the Congress. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
