<bill session="103" type="h" number="2593" updated="2010-04-19T05:55:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Fair Franchise Practices Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish minimum standards of fair conduct in franchise business relationships, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400537"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400579" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400578" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="407672" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400615" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="1993-07-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-07"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
		<term name="Contracts"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
Federal Fair Franchise Practices Act - Prohibits a franchisor or subfranchisor, in connection with the promotion, sale, licensing, performance, enforcement, and termination of any franchise agreement, from: (1) engaging in an action which operates as a fraud or deceit upon any person; (2) employing unlawful or deceptive acts or practices; (3) discriminating among franchisees on the basis of race, sex, religion, disability, or national origin, with exceptions; (4) prohibiting a franchisee from obtaining equipment, supplies, or services from sources of the franchisee, with exceptions; (5) terminating a franchise prior to its normal expiration without good cause; (6) prohibiting a franchisee from engaging in another business after the expiration of the franchise; (7) prohibiting the free association of a franchisee for any lawful purpose; or (8) establishing a new outlet or point of sale of good or services similar to that offered by a franchisee and identified by the same trade name used by a franchisee in unreasonably close proximity to such franchisee. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) minimum standards of conduct (good faith, due care, and limited fiduciary duty) for each party to a franchise agreement; (2) a prohibition against requiring the inclusion of a franchise agreement term or condition which violates this Act or relieves a person from a duty or liability under this Act; (3) a prohibition against the waiver from compliance under this Act; (4) legal actions brought by persons injured or damaged by a violation of this Act; (5) the right to arbitration or mediation in lieu of a legal action; and (6) the obligation to comply with all applicable State franchising laws to the extent not inconsistent with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
