<bill session="103" type="h" number="2594" updated="2010-04-19T05:56:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Miscellaneous Small Business Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400537"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4477)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="American technical assistance"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Central Europe"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidential commissions"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="White House conferences"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
Miscellaneous Small Business Amendments Act of 1993 - Amends the Small Business Act to increase the authorization of appropriations for loans and other financing under the certified development company program. Amends the White House Conference on Small Business Authorization Act to: (1) revise the dates by which the President must conduct a National White House Conference on Small Business; (2) direct the President to appoint 11 individuals to a Commission conducting such Conference; and (3) increase the authorization of appropriations under such Act. Authorizes the Small Business Administration to make grants or enter into cooperative agreements with one or more small business development centers to carry out the purposes of the Small Business Development Center Program. Amends the Small Business Credit and Business Opportunity Enhancement Act of 1992 to delete a provision prohibiting the proposed regulations for the program from being published in the Federal Register. Allocates the authorized funding for the Central European Small Business Enterprise Development Commission through FY 1996. (Currently, all such funding is authorized for FY 1993.)

	</summary>
</bill>
