<bill session="103" type="h" number="2610" updated="2010-04-19T05:58:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mediplan Health Care Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a Mediplan that assures the provision of health insurance coverage to all residents, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400354" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400543" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="411947" joined="1993-09-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1707-1709)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E307)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Coinsurance"/>
		<term name="Computer software"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Data transmission systems"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Eyeglasses"/>
		<term name="Facsimile transmission"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Health surveys"/>
		<term name="Hearing aids"/>
		<term name="Hospital records"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medical residents"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="National health insurance"/>
		<term name="Obstetrics"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Prescription pricing"/>
		<term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Sales personnel"/>
		<term name="Sales promotion"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Health Care Eligibility and Benefits Title II: Cost Containment Title III: Financing Provisions Mediplan Health Care Act of 1993 - Title I: Health Care Eligibility and Benefits - Adds a new title XXI to the Social Security Act (SSA) entitled &quot;Mediplan Health Benefits.&quot; Makes all U.S. residents eligible for Mediplan benefits, which include prescription drugs and biologicals. Requires the development of a Mediplan enrollment mechanism that includes automatic enrollment at birth and the issuance of Mediplan cards for identification and claims processing purposes. Provides the same benefits under the Mediplan program as are provided under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to individuals who are entitled to benefits under part A (Hospital Insurance) and enrolled under part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of the Medicare program. Provides additional Mediplan coverage to children under age 23, pregnant women, and low-income individuals. Establishes the Mediplan Trust Fund which shall consist of revenues raised by this Act's financing mechanism. Requires the modification of Medicaid (SSA title XIX) and other Federal health programs to avoid their duplication of Mediplan coverage. Requires group health plans which provide their current beneficiaries with benefits in addition to Mediplan benefits to continue to do so, though they need not provide such additional benefits to individuals not entitled to them before this Act's enactment. Provides for the regulation of Mediplan supplemental policies. Allows States to elect to have health care benefits made available instead under an alternative program meeting specified requirements. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to impose an excise tax with respect to Mediplan supplemental policies which fail to meet certain requirements. Title II: Cost Containment - (Sec. 201) Establishes a national budget for Mediplan expenditures. Details formulae for determining such expenditures and subsequent adjustments to them. (Secs. 202 and 203) Provides for the establishment of separate classes of health care services and the allocation of the national Mediplan expenditure budget by class of service. (Sec. 204) Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national health expenditures reporting system for purposes related to the national Mediplan expenditure budget. (Secs. 205 and 206) Provides for the adjustment of Medicare payment rates for purposes related to Mediplan health expenditure allocations and graduate medical education. Title III: Financing Provisions - (Sec. 301) Amends IRC to impose an additional income tax on individuals and health service providers in order to finance Mediplan health care premiums.

	</summary>
</bill>
