<bill session="103" type="h" number="2624" updated="2010-04-19T06:00:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Health Care and Cost Containment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for comprehensive health care and health care cost containment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400316"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Forces and Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.R.3600.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Forces and Personnel" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" subcommittee="Compensation and Employee Benefits" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3600" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Alcohol tax"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Cigarettes"/>
		<term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Drug industry"/>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Drugstores"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health facilities"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indian medical care"/>
		<term name="Indians"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Insurance rates"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Malpractice"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical associations"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Medical malpractice insurance"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Military dependents"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="National health insurance"/>
		<term name="Patents"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Prescription pricing"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Price regulation"/>
		<term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State budgets"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State politics and government"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Tobacco tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/13/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Federal and State Administration Subtitle A: Federal Administration Subtitle B: State Administration Title II: Health Care Services Subtitle A: National Health Insurance Program Subtitle B: Payment Amounts for Health Care Practitioner Services and for Covered District Health Care Services Title III: Malpractice Insurance Reform Title IV: Provisions Relating to ERISA and Federal and State Antitrust Laws Title V: Health Care Education Trust Fund Title VI: Tax Treatment of Health Insurance Premiums Title VII: Private Options Title VIII: Prescription Drug Review Board Title IX: Termination of Programs Comprehensive Health Care and Cost Containment Act of 1993 - Title I: Federal and State Administration - Subtitle A: Federal Administration - Subtitle A: Federal Administration - Establishes within the Department of Health and Human Services a Federal Health Board. Requires the Board to: (1) determine national per capita spending rates for covered district health care services and for health care practitioner services; (2) establish a single national insurance premium for enrollment catgories; (3) make Federal payments to States and insurers; (4) certify State compliance with this Act; (5) enter into reciprocity agreements with foreign countries; and (6) report to the Congress on duplicative Federal health care programs. Requires an annual report to the Congress on the status of the health care system in the United States. Establishes within the Department of Education a Federal Health Education Commission to manage the Federal grant program to States for consumer education programs and for primary care practitioners. Subtitle B: State Administration - Requires each State to provide for a State Health Board to establish health districts to appoint district health care boards, set global budgets for each health care district, establish fee schedules for practitioner groups, and develop long-range plans for future health care infrastructure. Requires each State Health Board to establish a State Health Care Education Commission to be responsible for specified activities. Title II: Health Care Services - Subtitle A: National Health Insurance Program - Sets forth national standards for health insurance for district health care services or health care practitioner services, including enrollment requirements. Authorizes reduced premiums for low-income individuals. Subtitle B: Payment Amounts for Health Care Practitioner Services and for Covered District Health Care Services - Requires each State to provide for the chartering of practitioner associations with respect to fee schedules and medical malpractice insurance. Provides for the establishment of annual per capita rates for district health care costs and the development of State and district budgets for health care services. Requires the Board to disseminate Federal payments to States for such services. Title III: Malpractice Insurance Reform - Sets forth requirements for States with respect to physician medical malpractice liability in order to be eligible for Federal payments. Title IV: Provisions Relating to ERISA and Federal and State Antitrust Laws - Declares that provisions of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act are superseded to the extent inconsistent with the requirements of this Act. Provides that the antitrust laws do not apply to health service entities covered under this Act. Title V: Health Care Education Trust Fund - Establishes the Health Care Education Trust Fund to be administered by the Federal Health Care Commission in making grants for health care consumer education. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the tax on cigarettes and distilled spirits. Title VI: Tax Treatment of Health Insurance Premiums - Allows a tax deduction for health insurance expenses, whether or not the taxpayer itemizes deductions. Title VII: Private Options - States that individuals are not precluded from obtaining insurance for services that are covered health care services. Title VIII: Prescription Drug Review Board - Establishes in the executive branch the Prescription Drug Price Review Board to develop guidelines for determining excessive prescription drug prices. Permits the Board, after following specified procedures, to determine: (1) if such a price is excessive; and (2) to revoke the patent of a drug determined to have an excessive price. Title IX: Termination of Programs - Amends the Social Security Act to repeal the Medicare and Medicaid programs. Repeals specified CHAMPUS provisions. Repeals the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program.

	</summary>
</bill>
