<bill session="103" type="h" number="2633" updated="2010-04-19T06:02:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To revise the boundaries of the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor in Massachusetts and Rhode Island, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400291"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401547" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4659-4660)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.5044.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="5044" />
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1222" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1222" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Culture"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Landscape protection"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Regional planning"/>
		<term name="Rhode Island"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/1993--Introduced.
Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 1993 - Modifies the boundaries of the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor pursuant to a specified Act (the Act). Requires the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Commission to revise the Cultural Heritage and Land Management Plan to address the boundary change and include a natural resource inventory of areas or features that should be protected, restored, managed, or acquired because of their contribution to the understanding of national cultural landscape values. Prohibits changes other than minor revisions in the approved plan as amended without the approval of the Secretary of the Interior. Extends the date of termination of the Commission until ten (currently, five) years after the Act's enactment, subject to specified conditions. Directs the Secretary to approve an extension if the Secretary finds that: (1) the Governors of Massachusetts and Rhode Island provide adequate assurances of continued tangible contribution and effective policy support toward achieving the purposes of the Act; and (2) the Commission is effectively assisting Federal, State, and local authorities to retain, enhance, and interpret the distinctive character and nationally significant resources of the Corridor. Authorizes the Secretary to provide funds for projects in the Corridor that exhibit national significance or provide a wide spectrum of historic, recreational, environmental, educational, or interpretive opportunities, without regard to whether the projects are in public or private ownership, subject to specified requirements. Increases and extends the authorization of appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
