<bill session="103" type="h" number="2664" updated="2010-04-19T06:06:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dairy Budget Reconciliation and Self-Help Initiative Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To achieve needed savings in net Federal expenditures under the milk price support program through establishment of a milk producer self-help program to dispose of surplus dairy products, expand exports, and stabilize the market for milk and dairy products, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411166"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400578" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400526" joined="1994-10-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Received from USDA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAG-03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Butter"/>
		<term name="Cattle"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Dairy industry"/>
		<term name="Dairy products"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
		<term name="Milk"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/15/1993--Introduced.
Dairy Budget Reconciliation and Self-Help Initiative Act of 1993 - Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 (the Act) to revise milk price support provisions concerning reduction in price received and enforcement to provide that from 1994 through 1998 the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide for: (1) budget reconciliation saving deductions from producer revenues on milk of ten cents per hundredweight of milk marketed, which shall be adjusted annually to compensate for refunds; and (2) market stabilization deductions from producer revenues on milk of up to ten cents per hundredweight. Sets forth the deduction process. Provides refunds to producers. Sets forth collection and enforcement provisions. Establishes in the Commodity Credit Corporation the Dairy Stabilization Fund to provide for the expenditures of the Dairy Stabilization Board. Provides that there shall be deposited into the Fund: (1) all monies from the market stabilization deductions; (2) a specified portion of the monies from the budget reconciliation savings deduction; (3) monies collected from any excess purchases reduction in price, as specified; (4) revenues received by the Dairy Stabilization Board from sales of dairy products it has removed from the market; and (5) credits from the Commodity Credit Corporation representing interest earned on the outstanding balance of the Fund. Terminates the Fund when the Dairy Stabilization Board winds up its affairs. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish the Dairy Stabilization Board in order to develop and implement Dairy Stabilization Plans. Sets forth the specific powers of the Board, including the power to: (1) remove dairy products from the domestic commercial market; (2) dispose of dairy products removed from the market through export sales; (3) cause the export of dairy cattle; and (4) transfer to the Commodity Credit Corporation, at the Corporation's announced price, dairy products removed from the market, as necessary. Requires the Board to prepare and implement a Dairy Stabilization Plan for each year from 1994 through 1998 that provides a business plan of operation for the Dairy Stabilization Board. Sets forth Plan requirements providing for market intervention measures when estimated Commodity Credit Corporation purchases exceed certain levels. Provides for the continuation of deficit reduction activities through 1998 under specified provisions of: (1) the Act; (2) the Agriculture and Food Act of 1981; (3) Public Law 90-484; and (4) the Food Security Act of 1985. Sets forth provisions relating to: (1) estimates of Commodity Credit Corporation purchases; (2) allocation of purchase prices for butter and nonfat dry milk; and (3) Federal milk order supply balancing cost sharing plan.

	</summary>
</bill>
