<bill session="103" type="h" number="267" updated="2010-04-18T23:41:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 47 of title 10, United States Code (the Uniform Code of Military Justice), to establish procedures for the adjudication by courts-martial of sentences of capital punishment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400596"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Forces and Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-02"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Received from DOD.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Forces and Personnel" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to establish procedures under which a court-martial may prescribe the death sentence. Requires that: (1) the sentence of death be concurred in unanimously; (2) the offense must be one expressly made punishable by death; and (3) the trial counsel must notify the accused of the intent to prove the existence of an aggravating factor, which is required before a sentence of death may be pronounced. Lists aggravating factors, including committing an offense in the presence of the enemy, presenting a grave risk to national security, and attempting to avoid hazardous duty. Requires the military judge, in the presence of the accused and counsel, to instruct the members of the court-martial on the aggravating factors, all applicable requirements and procedures, and the requirement to consider all evidence in extenuation and mitigation before adjudging a sentence of death. Prohibits a death sentence from being adjudged unless each member of the court-martial concurs that: (1) at least one aggravating factor has been proven beyond a reasonable doubt; and (2) the aggravating circumstances substantially outweigh any extenuating or mitigating circumstances or are themselves sufficient to justify a sentence of death. Requires that any aggravating factors found be announced by the military judge upon determination of the death sentence.

	</summary>
</bill>
