<bill session="103" type="h" number="2703" updated="2010-04-19T06:12:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mickey Leland Telecommunications and Education Assistance to Africa of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the National Telecommunications and Information of the Department of Commerce to conduct a study of the feasibility of establishing a satellite-based educational network to provide educational programming to African children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404068"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="1993-07-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1844)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.2639.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2639" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Africa"/>
		<term name="Communication satellites"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational technology"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/21/1993--Introduced.
Mickey Leland Telecommunications and Education Assistance to Africa Act of 1993 - Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to require the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to conduct a feasibility study identifying the opportunities, facilities, programming, and other resources necessary for establishment of networks using modern telecommunications technologies to provide educational and other training essential to ensure growth and opportunities in Africa, paying particular attention to educational needs and opportunities in rural and remote areas. Directs such: (1) Administration to identify resources and programs of governmental, nongovernmental, and multinational agencies that may be deployed promptly and economically; and (2) study to identify any legal, procedural, or technical impediments to the establishment of such a network or networks and the appropriate steps to remove such impediments. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
