<bill session="103" type="h" number="2715" updated="2010-04-19T06:14:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Women's Health Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve programs for women's health in the Department of Defense.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409650"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1993-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="1993-07-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-26"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Forces and Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-26"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1865)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2186-2187)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Forces and Personnel" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Breast cancer"/>
		<term name="Cancer research"/>
		<term name="Clinical trials"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Military dependents"/>
		<term name="Military hospitals"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Women soldiers"/>
		<term name="Women veterans"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/22/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Women's Health Care Title II: Women's Health Research Title III: Women's Health Education Defense Women's Health Improvement Act of 1993 - Title I: Women's Health Care - Requires female members and former members of the armed forces who are entitled to medical care under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS) to be furnished primary and preventive health care services for women as part of such care. Provides the same coverage for female dependents of members and former members of the armed forces. Directs the Secretary of Defense to prepare and submit to the Congress a report evaluating the provision of health care services through military medical treatment facilities and CHAMPUS to female members of the armed forces and female covered beneficiaries. Requires the Secretary to include a study to determine the needs of female members and dependents for health care services, including primary and preventive health care services for women. Title II: Women's Health Research - Directs the Secretary to establish a Defense Women's Health Research Center within the Department of the Army to be the coordinating agent for multidisciplinary and multiinstitutional research within the Department of Defense on women's health issues related to service in the armed forces. Directs the Secretary of the Army, during FY 1994, to continue the breast cancer research program as established under prior law. Directs the Secretary of Defense, in conducting or supporting clinical research, to ensure that women and minority group members of the armed forces are included as research subjects. Provides a waiver of such requirement. Directs the Secretary to submit three annual reports on research relating to female members and dependents within the armed forces. Title III: Women's Health Education - Directs the Secretary to establish at the F. Edward Hebert School of Medicine of the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences a women's health curriculum advisory committee to promote the comprehensive integration of women's health issues into the curriculum.

	</summary>
</bill>
