<bill session="103" type="h" number="2729" updated="2010-04-19T06:16:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the application of certain employment protection laws to the Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400370"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400579" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="407124" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1994-04-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1993-07-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27"><committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Personnel and Police.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-30"><committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Administration" subcommittee="Personnel and Police" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Age and employment"/>
		<term name="Age discrimination"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional privileges and immunities"/>
		<term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employee selection"/>
		<term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
		<term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Grievance procedures"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Older workers"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Parental leave"/>
		<term name="Party affiliation"/>
		<term name="Promotions"/>
		<term name="Public records"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Sick leave"/>
		<term name="Subpoena"/>
		<term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/1993--Introduced.
Congressional Accountability Act - Makes any provision of Federal law applicable to the House of Representatives and to the Senate to the extent that it relates to: (1) the terms and conditions of employment (including hiring, promotion or demotion, salary and wages, overtime compensation, benefits, work assignments or reassignments, termination, and family and medical leave) of employees; (2) protection from discrimination in personnel actions, including discrimination based on race, color, religion, sex (including marital and parental status), or national origin within the meaning of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, age within the meaning of the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, or handicap or disability within the meaning of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990; (3) the health and safety of employees; or (4) the availability of information to the public. Establishes in the legislative branch an Office of Compliance to study and report to the Congress on the application of such laws. Sets forth provisions relating to congressional procedures for approval of Office regulations. Requires the Board of Directors of the Office to carry out an information program to acquaint Members of the House, Senators, and congressional employees with the provisions, including remedies, of the laws applicable to the Congress under this Act. Requires the procedure for consideration of alleged violations of such laws to consist of the following steps: (1) counseling; (2) mediation; (3) formal complaint and hearing by a hearing board; and (4) judicial review of a hearing board's decision. Declares that any intimidation of, or reprisal against, any employee because of the exercise of a right under this Act constitutes an unlawful employment practice that may be remedied in the same manner under this Act as is a violation of a law made applicable to the Congress. Requires the records and decisions of hearing boards and the decisions of the Select Committee on Ethics to be made public if required for judicial review. Limits a congressional employee to the judicial proceeding provided by this Act to redress prohibited practices.

	</summary>
</bill>
