<bill session="103" type="h" number="2728" updated="2010-04-19T06:16:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Technology Education Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize a program of grants to States to improve the use of technology in elementary and secondary schools.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400539"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="401033" joined="1993-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1993-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400390" joined="1993-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400595" joined="1993-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1993-10-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1905-1906)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Education of handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Educational statistics"/>
		<term name="Educational technology"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federal incorporation"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Literacy programs"/>
		<term name="Minority students"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Regional educational laboratories"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: State and Local Educational Agency Grants Title II: Educational Technology Governance Title III: Regional Support, Research and Development Title IV: Authorization of Appropriations Technology Education Assistance Act of 1993 - Title I: State and Local Educational Agency Grants - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to States to improve elementary and secondary school teachers' skills and student learning through the use of technology. Requires allocation of each State's grant allotment to: (1) elementary and secondary education programs; (2) partnerships programs between local educational agencies and higher education institutions; and (3) library and literacy programs. Title II: Educational Technology Governance - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to establish an Education Technology Council within the Department of Education. Establishes the Educational Technology Authority as a nonprofit organization. Establishes the Educational Technology Fund within the Department of Education, with assets to be available to the Authority to provide grants to State and local educational agencies or other entities eligible to receive funding under this Act to augment programs and projects established under this Act. Title III: Regional Support, Research, and Development - Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to the ten regional educational laboratories to establish Regional Educational Technology Assistance Consortia. Requires the Consortia to serve as resources facilitating availability of technology to schools, conducting research, and providing for information dissemination, professional development, technical support, and evaluation of educational technology applications. Authorizes the Secretary to establish Educational Technology Research and Development Grants, to be administered by the Office of Educational Research and Improvement. Makes eligible for such competitive grants State education agencies, school districts, regional educational agencies, consortia of districts, and other nonprofit educational agencies including regional educational laboratories and national research centers. Title IV: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
