<bill session="103" type="h" number="2726" updated="2010-04-19T06:16:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mathematics Education Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for improved instruction in mathematics and science education.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400539"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Mathematics"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/1993--Introduced.
Mathematics Education Act of 1993 - Establishes the Fund for the Improvement of Mathematics (the Fund) to provide grants to schools to: (1) improve mathematics education; and (2) implement the Curriculum and Evaluation Standards for School Mathematics (the Standards). Directs the Secretary of Education (the Secretary) to select to administer the Fund a national education professional association which: (1) has demonstrated at least a ten-year professional and financial commitment to improving mathematics education; and (2) provides specified assurances. Requires that priority in funding and assistance be given to schools in the most disadvantaged areas in a State. Directs the Fund to provide grants to schools and institutions of higher education to improve mathematics education and meet the goals outlined in the Standards. Sets forth requirements for grant and contract applications. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
