<bill session="103" type="h" number="2731" updated="2010-04-19T06:17:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Space Commercialization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Space Business Incentives Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Space Transportation Services Purchase Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the development of a commercial space industry in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411247"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400115" joined="1994-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400382" joined="1993-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1993-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="404009" joined="1993-07-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations and Nutrition.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-12"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-16"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Department Operations and Nutrition" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Space" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Space sciences"/>
		<term name="Advertising"/>
		<term name="Agricultural education"/>
		<term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Capital gains tax"/>
		<term name="Commercialization"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee selection"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Farm lands"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government securities"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indemnity"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Inventions"/>
		<term name="Inventories"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Launch vehicles"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Local taxation"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Negligence"/>
		<term name="Patents"/>
		<term name="Privatization"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Remote sensing"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Research and development contracts"/>
		<term name="Space flight"/>
		<term name="Space industrialization"/>
		<term name="Space policy"/>
		<term name="Space shuttles"/>
		<term name="Spacecraft"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
		<term name="Sunset legislation"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
		<term name="Tariff"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax incentives"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Teaching materials"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Space Launch and Launch Support Facilities Title II: Purchase of Space Transportation Services Title III: Intellectual Property Disposition Title IV: Tax Incentives for Commercial Space Activities Title V: Miscellaneous Omnibus Space Commercialization Act of 1993 - Title I: Space Launch and Launch Support Facilities - Directs the Comptroller General to conduct a comprehensive inventory of all U.S. space launch and launch support facilities. Requires all facilities identified as surplus to be referred to the General Services Administration for disposition. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish criteria for and designate launch facilities as Commercial Space Centers. Exempts all Centers and associated property, services, and products from Federal corporate income and other taxes and excises, imports, duties, and all other Federal tariffs. Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to make public land available for new space launch and launch support facilities. Title II: Purchase of Space Transportation Services - Space Transportation Services Purchase Act of 1993 - Amends the Launch Services Purchase Act of 1990 to require the Federal Government to purchase space transportation services from commercial providers, unless the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) or the Secretary of Defense determines: (1) the payload requires the unique capabilities of the space shuttle; (2) commercial services are not available; or (3) the use of commercial services poses an unacceptable risk of loss of a unique scientific opportunity. Title III: Intellectual Property Disposition - Requires that a commercial provider making an invention under contract with the Government have the same rights as would a small business firm under specified provisions of Federal patent law. Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to require (current law permits) each Federal agency to permit the director of any of its Government-operated Federal laboratories and, in certain circumstances, the director of any of its Government-owned, contractor-operated laboratories to enter into cooperative research and development agreements and to negotiate licensing agreements. Title IV: Tax Incentives for Commercial Space Activities - Space Business Incentives Act of 1993 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction for the amount of the purchase of Commercial Space Center stock. Excludes from gross income gain on the sale or exchange of common stock of a corporation that is substantially engaged in space-related activities. Adds space launch and launch support facilities to the list of exempt facility bonds. Excludes from gross income: (1) income from the commercial sale of any product manufactured in space and returned to Earth; and (2) income from services performed in space in a commercial space activity. Excludes products manufactured in space and returned to Earth from all Federal excises, imposts, duties, and other Federal tariffs. Directs the President to encourage State and local governments to offer tax and other incentives for commercial space activities. Title V: Miscellaneous - Declares that, notwithstanding specified provisions of the Clayton Act and the National Cooperative Research Act of 1984, standing to conduct litigation arising from activities carried out under this Act is reserved to the Department of Justice. Establishes in the Department of Commerce the Office of Space Commerce. Requires NASA to purchase space science data from the private sector. Requires the Administrator to establish within the Office of Advanced Concepts and Technology a procurement demonstration program. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture and the Administrator to provide specified farmers with grants to purchase land remote sensing information.

	</summary>
</bill>
