<bill session="103" type="h" number="2757" updated="2010-04-19T06:21:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act regarding alien smuggling, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406277"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1993-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1993-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="1993-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400604" joined="1993-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400536" joined="1993-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400314" joined="1993-07-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-09"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Law, Immigration, and Refugees.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Common carriers"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/27/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that, in the case of an offense (with respect to bringing in and harboring certain aliens) involving ten or more aliens committed for the purpose of commercial advantage or private financial gain, violators shall be fined, imprisoned for up to ten years, or both, for each alien in respect to whom such a violation occurs. Revises seizure and forfeiture provisions regarding the bringing in and harboring of aliens to provide that any property which has been or is being used in the commission of a violation, or is derived from or traceable to any proceeds obtained as the result of a violation, or which is used to facilitate or is intended to be used in the commission of such a violation, shall be seized and subject to forfeiture, with exceptions. (Current law provides that any conveyance which has been or is being used in the commission of a violation shall be seized and subject to forfeiture, with exceptions.) Directs the Attorney General to develop a plan to coordinate efforts to combat alien smuggling by organized crime syndicates, including: (1) increased coordination by Federal agencies; (2) procedures for Federal, State, and local coordination in information gathering, investigations, and prosecution; (3) a timetable for the creation of an alien smuggling task force in adversely affected areas; and (4) establishment of a national data base of information essential to combat alien smuggling. Sets forth reporting requirements. Applies penalties under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act to peonage and slavery.

	</summary>
</bill>
