<bill session="103" type="h" number="2769" updated="2010-04-19T06:23:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve education for migrant children in elementary and secondary schools.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404220"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1993-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400586" joined="1993-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-08-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1903)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational technology"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Literacy programs"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Migrant education"/>
		<term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
		<term name="Puerto Rico"/>
		<term name="School-to-work transition"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Student records"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to revise provisions for programs for migrant children. Includes under program requirements a comprehensive plan which describes: (1) advocacy and outreach activities for migrant children and their families, including education, health, nutrition, and other supportive social services; (2) coordination efforts; (3) professional development; (4) parent involvement; (5) integration of information technology; and (6) transition programs. Directs the Secretary of Education to reserve funds for up to 15 competitive grants to State educational agencies with approved consortium agreements. Revises the period of eligibility so that a migrant child is one aged three through 21 whose family meets migrant requirements and has moved within the past 24 months. Allows continuation of migrant child status for an additional school year only if comparable services are not available through other programs. Directs the Secretary to begin by October 1, 1994, to work with States to provide model information forms or other assistance to help ensure the timely transfer of students' educational and health records. Prohibits: (1) continuation of the contract for the Migrant Student Record System beyond June 30, 1995; or (2) award of a new contract for that or any comparable system.

	</summary>
</bill>
