<bill session="103" type="h" number="28" updated="2010-04-18T23:04:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Reserve System Accountability Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote accountability, diversity, and the public interest in the operation of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404634"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405939" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400500" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="406420" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400028" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400084" joined="1993-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="411947" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="407672" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="402454" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="404139" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400526" joined="1993-06-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-14"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Growth and Credit Formation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-15"><text>Printed with additional cosponsors.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H401-402)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H652-653)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H883-885)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H898-900)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H979-980)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1758-1759)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1949-1950)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3348-3354)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Growth and Credit Formation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Bank directors"/>
		<term name="Bank employees"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Checks"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Community organization"/>
		<term name="Consumer organizations"/>
		<term name="Dividends"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal reserve system"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign exchange"/>
		<term name="Foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Low-income housing"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Moderate income housing"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Open market operations"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
		<term name="Valuation"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Federal Reserve System Accountability Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Reserve Act to declare that the president of each Federal reserve bank shall be appointed by the President, with the consent of the Senate. (Currently such appointment authority is exercised by each Federal reserve bank's board of directors.) Mandates that such presidents represent diverse segments of the population. Modifies the corporate structure of the Federal reserve banks. Authorizes the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to prescribe regulations under which Federal reserve banks may extend credit to member banks. Confers responsibility upon the board of directors of a Federal reserve bank to ascertain whether undue use is being made of bank credit for speculative securities, real estate, or commodities transactions. Grants the Board discretionary authority to deny the use of Federal Reserve System credit facilities to a member bank for its undue use of bank credit. Elaborates details of a two-tiered board of directors for each Federal reserve bank. Bars from board membership any director, officer, employee, or controlling shareholder of banking entities controlled by a foreign government. Amends the Federal Reserve Act to mandate independent annual financial audits. Mandates prompt public disclosure of Federal Open Market Committee meetings and actions. Prescribes guidelines for the management of each Federal reserve branch by a board of directors (subject to Board-prescribed regulations). Mandates that each Federal reserve bank establish at least one advisory council to advise it on pertinent issues. Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to include within its purview the Board and the Federal reserve banks. Establishes the Federal Reserve Accountability Commission to study specified issues and to report findings and conclusions to the President, the Board, and the Congress. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Federal Reserve Act to prohibit recess appointees and acting presidents of the Federal reserve banks from participating in Federal Open Market Committee decisions. Requires voting participants to hold their positions by virtue of presidential appointment, by and with the consent of the Senate. Amends the Freedom of Information Act to treat Federal reserve banks as Federal agencies.

	</summary>
</bill>
