<bill session="103" type="h" number="2804" updated="2010-04-19T06:28:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Primary Care Workforce Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national policy respecting medical residency training programs and the health care workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400425"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="1993-07-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1925-1926)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1315" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical residents"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Public health personnel"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Teaching hospitals"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/1993--Introduced.
Primary Care Workforce Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national policy respecting the number of positions in each State in each approved medical residency training program of the different medical specialties conducted in the State. Limits the total number of entry positions. Prohibits the national policy allowing nonprimary care residents to exceed 50 percent of the total number of medical residents in a State. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide medical education support only if programs are in compliance with the national policy. Establishes the National Health Professional Workforce Advisory Board to make recommendations regarding the national policy. Provides, under the Medicare program, for graduate medical education payments to non-hospital providers operating residency training programs. Increases the authorization of appropriations under the Public Health Service Act for the scholarship program and the loan repayment program. Establishes a program to retrain specialist physicians in primary care. Establishes a commission to study requiring students attending health professions schools pursuant to Federal assistance (for either the student or school) to complete a period of providing service to medically underserved individuals.

	</summary>
</bill>
