<bill session="103" type="h" number="2816" updated="2010-04-19T06:30:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Care Security Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to the treatment of long-term care insurance policies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410529" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400510" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400156" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1993-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400574" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400028" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-11-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-04"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Accident insurance"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Caregivers"/>
		<term name="Charitable contributions"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Critically ill"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Grandparents"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Parents"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Support of dependents"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Treatment of Long-Term Care Insurance Title II: Protection of Assets Under Medicaid Through Use of Qualified Long-Term Care Insurance Title III: Studies Long-Term Care Security Act of 1993 - Title I: Tax Treatment of Long-Term Care Insurance - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the treatment of qualified long-term care insurance as accident and health insurance for purposes of insurance company taxation. Excludes from gross income benefits provided under a long-term care insurance contract. Includes in gross income employer-provided coverage for long-term care services. Includes amounts paid for qualified long-term care services as medical expenses for individual itemized deductions. Includes any parent or grandparent as a dependent for purposes of such expenses. Provides for the nonrecognition of gain or loss on the exchange of any life insurance contract or an endowment or annuity contract for a long-term care insurance contract. Excludes from gross income certain amounts withdrawn from individual retirement accounts and certain employer cash or deferred arrangements to pay long-term care premiums. Provides for the exclusion as a death benefit of any amount paid or advanced to an individual under a life insurance contract because such individual is terminally ill or chronically ill and confined to a qualified facility. Allows insurance companies to issue accelerated death benefit riders on life insurance contracts. Title II: Protection of Assets Under Medicaid Through Use of Qualified Long-Term Care Insurance - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to disregard assets which are attributable to coverage under a qualified long-term care insurance contract for purposes of eligibility. Title III: Studies - Directs the Comptroller General to study the feasibility of: (1) encouraging health care providers to donate their services to homebound patients; and (2) providing heads of households who care for elderly family members in their homes with a tax credit.

	</summary>
</bill>
