<bill session="103" type="h" number="2825" updated="2010-04-19T06:31:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Training for Future Jobs Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To demonstrate the economy and efficiency of centralizing Federal job training programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400080"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-14"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-14"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Employment"/>
		<term name="Community colleges"/>
		<term name="Conversion of industries"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational television"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Occupational retraining"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Teaching materials"/>
		<term name="Technical education"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Unemployment"/>
		<term name="Vocational guidance"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/1993--Introduced.
Training for Future Jobs Act of 1993 - Establishes a five-year demonstration of centralizing Federal job training programs. Establishes the Job Training Council, composed of the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, Defense, Education, Health and Human Services, and Labor, and the Director of the Office of Management and the Budget as Chairperson. Authorizes the Council to make matching grants to: (1) nonprofit organizations for retraining dislocated workers; and (2) nonprofit educational telecommunications organizations for developing, producing, and distributing instructional telecommunications materials and services for local vocational and technical educational schools and colleges. Sets forth priorities for persons to be served and for areas of high labor unemployment rates. Authorizes the Council to waive for a nonprofit organization inconsistent requirements of different Federal job training assistance programs for adults and out-of-school youth under specified conditions, including local government certification. Directs the Council to disseminate information on successful retraining models developed by any grant recipient under this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
