<bill session="103" type="h" number="2835" updated="2010-04-19T06:33:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Ethics Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the acceptance of gifts, meals, and travel by Members of Congress and congressional staff, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409829"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400553" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="408839" joined="1993-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="404083" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="407124" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1993-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="406420" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="402890" joined="1993-10-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400106" joined="1993-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="406482" joined="1993-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="407306" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400205" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="407153" joined="1993-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="401854" joined="1993-10-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="405560" joined="1993-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400269" joined="1993-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="401134" joined="1993-10-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="402152" joined="1993-10-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="409633" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="409627" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1993-09-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8801)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Charitable contributions"/>
		<term name="Congressional Record"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional travel"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Honoraria"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/1993--Introduced.
Congressional Ethics Reform Act of 1993 - Prohibits a Member of Congress or employee of the legislative branch from soliciting or accepting a gift from any source except as provided in this Act. Provides that a gift accepted under the standards set forth in this Act shall not constitute an illegal gratuity otherwise prohibited by Federal law. Prohibits such a Member or employee from: (1) accepting a gift in return for being influenced in the performance of an official act; (2) soliciting or coercing the offering of a gift; (3) accepting gifts on a basis so frequent that a reasonable person would be led to believe the Member or employee is using his or her public office for private gain; (4) accepting a gift in violation of any statute; or (5) accepting vendor promotional training contrary to any applicable regulations, policies, or guidance relating to the procurement of supplies and services for the Congress. Specifies conditions under which such prohibitions shall not apply with respect to: (1) gifts of $20 or less; (2) gifts based on a personal relationship; (3) discounts and similar benefits based on affiliation; (4) honorary degrees; (5) gifts based on outside business or employment relationships; (6) political events; (7) widely attended gatherings in the District of Columbia area and other specified events; and (8) limits the amount of personal hospitality (food and lodging for non-business purposes) a Member or employee may accept without a waiver from the Ethics Committee. Sets forth provisions regarding disposition by a Member or employee of prohibited gifts received, including permitting use of appropriated funds and franked mail to return such gifts. Provides that a Member or employee who promptly complies with disposition requirements shall not be deemed to have improperly accepted a gift. Repeals provisions of: (1) the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 permitting payments of honoraria on behalf of a Member, officer, or employee to a charitable organization or to an organization from which such an individual, his or her spouse, or any relative derives any financial benefit; (2) the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 regulating acceptance of gifts and payment of foreign travel for Members, officials, or employees of the Senate, their spouses or dependents. Directs the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct and the Senate Select Committee on Ethics to prescribe rules establishing the conditions under which their respective Houses may accept payment, or authorize a Member or employee to accept payment on the House's behalf, from non-Federal sources for travel, subsistence, and related expenses with respect to attendance of the Member or employee (or his or her spouse) at any meeting or similar function relating to official duties. Requires a Member to publish reports in the Congressional Record of payments accepted above $20 by the Member or his or her employee. Prohibits a Member or employee from knowingly soliciting contributions from any registered lobbyist for a tax-exempt organization. Provides that the fact that the name of a Member or employee is on the letterhead of a solicitation is not sufficient to establish that the named Member or employee has solicited a contribution. Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil action in any appropriate U.S. district court against any individual who knowingly and willfully accepts or solicits a gift in violation of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
