<bill session="103" type="h" number="2892" updated="2010-04-19T06:42:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violent Crime Control and Regional Prison Partnership Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for Federal-State partnerships in order to provide sufficient prison space for particularly dangerous State offenders.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400596"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Prison administration"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/5/1993--Introduced.
Violent Crime Control and Regional Prison Partnership Act of 1993 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish a Regional Prison Task Force comprised of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Prisons and a senior correctional officer of each State wishing to participate, designated by the Governor of the State; and (2) create a plan, in consultation with the Task Force, for the establishment of a nationwide regional prison system. Requires the plan to: (1) define the boundaries and number of regions in which regional prisons will be placed; (2) establish the terms of the partnership agreements that States must enter into with the Attorney General in order to participate in the regional prison system; (3) set forth the role of the Federal Bureau of Prisoners in administering the prisons; (4) determine the way two or more States in a region will share responsibility for the activities associated with such prisons; and (5) specify both the Federal responsibility and the State responsibility (which shall not be less than 50 percent) for construction and operating costs of such prisons. Prohibits a State from sending prisoners to be held at a regional prison unless such State: (1) enters into a partnership under this Act and abides substantially by its terms; (2) establishes minimum mandatory sentences of ten years for persons who are convicted of a serious felony and are subsequently convicted of a crime of violence involving the use of a firearm or a crime of violence involving a sexual assault; (3) establishes a truth in sentencing policy under which offenders will serve no less than 85 percent of the term of imprisonment to which they are sentenced after specified dates; (4) provides pretrial detention similar to that provided in the Federal system; (5) takes steps to eliminate court-imposed limitations on its prison capacity resulting from consent decrees or statutory provisions; and (6) provides specified assurances. Sets forth provisions regarding prisoner eligibility. Establishes in the U.S. Treasury a Regional Prison Fund. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
