<bill session="103" type="h" number="2895" updated="2010-04-19T06:42:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Disability Review Standards Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to provide for timely review of disability claims and to provide for presumed disability in cases of delayed disposition of such claims.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408109"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2049)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-13"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Blind"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Personnel management"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/5/1993--Introduced.
Social Security Disability Review Standards Act of 1993 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) require that applicants for disability benefits meet face-to-face with a disability examiner early in the process before being denied disability benefits; (2) set time limits for processing disability applications and appeals; and (3) provide for presumptive disability in cases where timely disability determinations are not made. Amends SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) to provide for presumptive blindness and disability in cases where timely blindness or disability determinations are not made. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to study and report to the Congress on any additional staff needs required to implement this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
