<bill session="103" type="h" number="2911" updated="2010-04-19T06:45:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the President to establish an advisory commission to study the merger of the BIF and SAIF funds and the implications for the banking and thrift industries of such a merger.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400115"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2070)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Deposit insurance"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress with respect to the continued availability of housing credit and the avoidance of a thrift industry crisis caused by specified structural impediments involving a separate fund concept mandated by the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989. Establishes the Advisory Commission on BIF and SAIF Funds (Bank Insurance Fund and Savings Association Fund, respectively) to investigate and advise the President and the Congress on: (1) the viability of merging or maintaining the separation of the deposit insurance funds; and (2) the future status of the deposit insurance system.

	</summary>
</bill>
