<bill session="103" type="h" number="2917" updated="2010-04-19T06:46:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the Federal Reserve System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401494"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Growth and Credit Formation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Growth and Credit Formation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Money"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Federal reserve system"/>
		<term name="Monetary policy"/>
		<term name="Open market operations"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Reserve Act to provide that the President shall appoint the five Federal Reserve Bank representatives who sit on the Federal Open Market Committee after consultation with, and consideration of, candidates selected by the Federal Advisory Council. (Currently such representatives are elected by the boards of directors of selected Federal Reserve Banks.) Requires the Federal Open Market Committee to meet and consult, on a quarterly basis, with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers. Provides that the terms of office of the Chairman and Vice-chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (the Board) shall coincide with the term of office of the President. Amends Federal finance law to require the Board to submit annually to the President, for subsequent submission to the Congress, its estimated receipts and proposed expenditures for the current year, and for the next two succeeding years (including those of the Federal Reserve Banks).

	</summary>
</bill>
