<bill session="103" type="h" number="2928" updated="2010-04-19T06:47:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of State, acting through the Commissioner of the International Boundary and Water Commission, to conclude agreements with the appropriate representative of the Government of Mexico to correct pollution along the U.S.-Mexico border.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403308"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-10"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-10"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Operations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA-07" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Sewage disposal"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of State, acting through the U.S. Commissioner of the International Boundary and Water Commission, to conclude agreements with the Ministry of Foreign Relations of Mexico to correct the problem of pollution along the U.S.-Mexican border caused by discharge of raw and inadequately treated sewage and other pollution related problems along the border. Declares that such agreements should consist of recommendations to the U.S. and Mexican Governments of measures to protect the health and welfare of persons along the border from the effects of pollution. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, to act jointly with the appropriate representative of the Mexican Government to supervise the planning, construction, and operation of facilities recommended in agreements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
