<bill session="103" type="h" number="2932" updated="2010-04-19T06:48:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ozark Heritage Conservation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the establishment of a center for the conservation and interpretation of Ozark culture and heritage at the Ozark National Scenic Riverways, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403864"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-16"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1520" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Culture"/>
		<term name="Missouri"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Public buildings"/>
		<term name="Social life and customs"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Ozark Heritage Conservation Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to establish a center for the conservation and interpretation of Ozark culture within the State of Missouri. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to construct a visitor center for the Ozark National Scenic Riverways on lands under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture at the site of the U.S. Forest Service Van Buren District Ranger Station within the Mark Twain National Forest. Requires the center to provide interpretive services for the Ozark National Scenic Riverways and the Mark Twain National Forest and to function as a regional cultural center for the study of Ozark folklife, history, and culture. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
