<bill session="103" type="h" number="2952" updated="2010-04-19T06:51:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide for a Great Lakes pollution prevention demonstration program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400211"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-19"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Industrial pollution"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Waste reduction"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) establish a multimedia Great Lakes pollution demonstration program to increase the use of modernizing industrial source reduction practices; and (2) maintain a registry of modernizing toxic use and waste reduction technologies requiring demonstration. Exempts participants in the program from paying fees under such Act for the development of revised effluent guidelines and grants them an additional year to comply with new or revised effluent standards if the extension is appropriate. Directs the Administrator to establish a: (1) pollution prevention extension service to provide an outreach effort to encourage pollution prevention by industrial discharges to the Great Lakes system; and (2) Great Lakes pollution prevention clearinghouse. Authorizes municipalities within the Great Lakes basin to apply for technical and financial assistance from the Administrator to implement source reduction of toxic pollutants in urban runoff, wastewater, and stormwater. Permits funding for such source reduction to be obtained from State water pollution control revolving funds.

	</summary>
</bill>
