<bill session="103" type="h" number="2955" updated="2010-04-19T06:52:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Business and Consumer Lending Stimulus Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To stimulate the economy by encouraging bank and thrift institution lending to small and medium-sized businesses and to consumers by reducing and standardizing the leverage limit capital standard for safe and sound depository institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406277"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1994-03-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Growth and Credit Formation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSBA-04" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Growth and Credit Formation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Bank capital"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Bank reserves"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Credit cards"/>
		<term name="Credit unions"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
		<term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
		<term name="Federal Home Loan Bank Board"/>
		<term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
		<term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Business and Consumer Lending Stimulus Act - Prohibits Federal banking regulatory agencies from imposing or enforcing for a specified period any leverage limit for an adequately capitalized insured depository institution requiring a ratio of tangible equity to total assets greater than three percent. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to require Federal banking regulatory agencies to: (1) consider, when prescribing real estate lending standards, their impact upon the availability of credit for certain target groups; and (2) minimize any negative impact. Amends the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (FIRREA) to direct the Appraisal Subcommittee to encourage the States to enter into reciprocity agreements with sister States allowing licensed appraisers in one State to perform appraisals in other States. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to certain congressional committees on the effect of risk based capital standards upon insured depository institutions, the availability of credit, and the domestic economy. Requires Federal banking regulatory agencies and the National Credit Union Administration to establish an independent appellate process within each agency to review regulatory determinations. Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (the Board) to study and report to the Congress on the effect of sterile reserves. Directs the Office of Management and Budget and the Congressional Budget Office to study and report to the Congress on the budgetary impact of the payment of interest on sterile reserves. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to cite circumstances under which the Resolution Trust Corporation may waive its rights to repudiate an agreement to sell credit card accounts receivable. Requires Federal banking regulatory agencies to coordinate examinations conducted at an insured depository institution with Federal and State sister agencies so as to minimize the disruptive effects upon the institution's operations. Directs the Board and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to jointly study and report to the Congress on ways to streamline the credit-granting process. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation Improvement Act of 1991 to increase the number and kinds of disclosures required of insured depository institutions with respect to loans made to small businesses, minority-owned businesses, and start-up enterprises. Amends the Home Owners' Loan Act to treat as a bank, for certain purposes of the Federal Reserve Act, a savings association that is well capitalized without including goodwill in calculating its core capital (thus accelerating the effective date of the sister thrift exemption for well-capitalized institutions).

	</summary>
</bill>
