<bill session="103" type="h" number="2954" updated="2010-04-19T06:51:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Civilian Facilities Closure and Realignment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Civilian Facilities Closure and Realignment Commission to reduce unnecessary spending in the Federal Government by closing or realigning duplicative, wasteful, or otherwise unnecessary civilian facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400590"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="404083" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="406768" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400085" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="401547" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400161" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="407558" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400601" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="405033" joined="1993-08-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-12"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Civilian Facilities Closure and Realignment Act of 1993 - Establishes the Civilian Facilities Closure and Realignment Commission. Requires the heads of executive agencies (except for the Secretary of Defense) to submit to the Commission recommendations for closing or realigning civilian facilities. Directs the Office of Management and Budget to submit to the Commission estimates of the administrative costs and savings that would result from the implementation of such recommendations. Requires the Commission to report its recommendations for closures and realignments of Federal facilities and proposed legislation to the President. Provides for presidential approval of the report. Sets forth procedures for congressional consideration of the proposed legislation. Requires proceeds from the sale of any agency's assets resulting from closures or realignments to be applied to reduce the Federal deficit and deposited in the Treasury and treated as general receipts. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) in the fiscal year immediately following the submission of an agency's recommendation, there should be appropriated to each agency at least 25 percent of the amount of estimated administrative savings applicable to such agency in the three fiscal years following such submission; and (2) the appropriated amount should be in addition to funds which would otherwise be appropriated if not for this Act and made available for expenditure to improve the agency's management, efficiency, or productivity.

	</summary>
</bill>
