<bill session="103" type="h" number="3010" updated="2010-04-19T07:00:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Economic Impact Notification Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect employment and the economy of the District of Columbia by requiring any Federal agency that seeks to permanently transfer employees from the District of Columbia to receive Congressional approval of such transfer and to submit a District of Columbia economic impact statement, to require that headquarters functions of Federal agencies be carried out in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="411488" joined="1993-08-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2003)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-01"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fiscal Affairs and Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House District of Columbia" subcommittee="Fiscal Affairs and Health" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Federal office buildings"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Relocation of employees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
District of Columbia Economic Impact Notification Act - Requires a Federal agency that proposes to carry out any program or activity that would result in the transfer of 50 or more employees whose official station or agency is located in the District of Columbia to another station or agency outside of the District for permanent duty to: (1) prepare a District of Columbia economic impact statement; (2) submit the statement to specified congressional committees within 12 months before such program or activity is scheduled to begin; (3) submit the statement to the National Capital Planning Commission, the Congress, the Administrator of General Services, the Mayor of the District, and the District of Columbia Council; and (4) publish the statement in the Federal Register. Provides that the entering into of a contract to construct a new facility or to lease an existing one as the official station or agency of employees of a Federal agency shall be considered a program or activity carried out by the agency. Requires congressional approval before such program or activity can be carried out unless an emergency exists and the program or activity would be in the national security interest of the United States. Sets forth provisions relating to the preparation of a District of Columbia impact statement. Requires the headquarters functions of each executive department to be carried out in the District. Defines &quot;Federal agency&quot; as an executive department and &quot;headquarters functions&quot; as a Federal function or activity relating to the administration of national laws, the formulation of policy directives and regulations, the needs of the President for consultation with executive department officers, or any other necessary activities for the efficient functioning of the Government, including related administrative and support services.

	</summary>
</bill>
