<bill session="103" type="h" number="305" updated="2010-04-18T23:47:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Biological Diversity Conservation and Environmental Research Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national policy for the conservation of biological diversity; to support environmental research and training necessary for conservation and sustainable use of biotic natural resources, to establish mechanisms for carrying out the national policy and for coordinating related activities; and to facilitate the collection, synthesis, and dissemination of information necessary for these purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400604"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="1993-05-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-14"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment, and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-29"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-29"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce, DOD, DOE, Interior, EPA, CEQ.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Received from DOE.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
		<term name="Biological research"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Endangered species"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
National Biological Diversity Conservation and Environmental Research Act - States that the conservation of biological diversity is a national priority. Requires Federal actions to be consistent with such goal. Directs the Council on Environmental Quality to: (1) issue regulations to require agencies to assess the impacts of Federal actions on biological diversity in preparing environmental impact statements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969; and (2) identify those biotic communities, species, and populations that appear to be in decline, in imminent danger of loss of viability, or otherwise of special concern. Requires Federal agencies to review their programs for consistency with the conservation of biological diversity and to report review results to the President, the Council, and the Congress. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in reviewing environmental impact statements, to take into account the impacts of proposed actions on biological diversity. Establishes an Interagency Working Committee on Biological Diversity to develop a coordinated Federal strategy for conservation of biological diversity. Dissolves the Committee after submission to the Congress of the strategy. Establishes a National Center for Biological Diversity and Conservation Research within the Smithsonian Institution to set research priorities and coordinate the understanding and promotion of knowledge of the biota. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Council to retain the National Academy of Sciences to: (1) provide scientific and technical advice and counsel in the preparation of the Federal strategy; and (2) provide a general reference and scientific and technical advisory source for the Nation in matters relating to the conservation of biological diversity.

	</summary>
</bill>
