<bill session="103" type="h" number="3089" updated="2010-04-19T07:12:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family Medicine and Primary Care Research Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for programs and activities regarding primary health care.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406431"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-07"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Family medicine"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Gynecology"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical residents"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
		<term name="Obstetrics"/>
		<term name="Osteopathy and osteopaths"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/15/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Office of Family Medicine and Primary Care Research Title II: Incentives for Rural Physicians Regarding Primary Care Title III: Primary Care Physicians Under Approved Medical Residency Training Programs Family Medicine and Primary Care Research Act of 1993 - Title I: Office of Family Medicine and Primary Care Research - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish in the National Institutes of Health (NIH) the Office on Family Medicine and Primary Care Research to monitor and coordinate all NIH research, training, and information dissemination activities regarding family medicine and other primary medical care disciplines. Provides for the development, modernization, and operation of new and existing research centers in family care and primary care. Mandates an advisory council. Title II: Incentives for Rural Physicians Regarding Primary Care - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction for medical education loan interest that accrues while a physician is providing primary care or obstetrical and gynecological services in a medically underserved rural area and living in that area. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 with regard to the Stafford Federal Student Loan Program to defer principal payments and with regard to the Perkins Direct Student Loan Program to defer principal and interest payments while the borrower is serving in an internship or residency program in preparation for practice in primary care or obstetrics and gynecology. Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to modify requirements regarding substitute billing arrangements. Title III: Primary Care Physicians Under Approved Medical Residency Training Programs - Mandates a national policy that at least 50 percent of entry positions in medical residency training programs be in primary care. Allows waiver for a State if application of the general rule would not be practicable. Amends Medicare provisions to tie to that policy Medicare payments to hospitals for direct graduate medical education costs and for indirect costs of medical education. Establishes the National Health Professional Workforce Advisory Board to make recommendations on: (1) the distribution of such positions among primary and non-primary care residents at various sites; (2) the supply and role of non-physician primary care providers; and (3) the appropriateness of spending Medicare direct graduate medical education funds available for the clinical training of physicians and nurses for the clinical training in primary care of additional practitioners. Repeals provisions of the Health Professions Education Extension Amendments of 1992 establishing the Council on Graduate Medical Education. Mandates annual publication of a list of the total amount of payments made to each hospital in the United States during the previous year under Medicare provisions relating to direct graduate medical education costs.

	</summary>
</bill>
