<bill session="103" type="h" number="308" updated="2010-04-18T23:47:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Geothermal Energy Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To create a commission to grant exclusive franchises for the exploration for and the commercial development of geothermal energy and for the right to market any such energy in its natural state, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408976"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF-03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy and Power" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Energy law and legislation"/>
		<term name="Citizenship"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Geothermal resources"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Prospecting"/>
		<term name="Public utilities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Geothermal Energy Control Act of 1993 - Establishes the National Geothermal Energy Commission. Requires the Commission to determine and publish in the Federal Register a list of those areas in the United States which have a potential for the extraction of geothermal resources. Directs the Commission to grant exclusive 99-year licenses to persons capable of carrying out exploration and development of geothermal resources in such areas. Permits a licensee under this Act to apply for a license to market the geothermal resources from the licensee's area in their natural state. Requires the Commission to grant a marketing license for the most reasonable geographic area to successfully market geothermal resources. Limits marketing licenses to one per geographic area. Provides that a marketing license shall be valid for as long as the licensee holds the exploration and development license. Permits the transfer of exploration, development, and marketing licenses with the Commission's approval. Requires that a licensee under this Act be a U.S. citizen or a person owned or controlled by a U.S. citizen. Restricts the sale of geothermal resources which have been converted to electrical or other energy forms to existing utility companies or other persons licensed to transmit such energy. Permits the sale of geothermal resources to such a company or person for conversion into other energy forms.

	</summary>
</bill>
