<bill session="103" type="h" number="3096" updated="2010-04-19T07:13:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Readjustment Counseling Service Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the organization and administration of the Readjustment Counseling Service, to improve eligibility for readjustment counseling and related counseling, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400126"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="1993-10-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-01"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Mental health services"/>
		<term name="Psychologists"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/21/1993--Introduced.
Readjustment Counseling Service Amendments of 1993 - Includes a Readjustment Counseling Service (RCS) as part of the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs. Prohibits the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from altering or revising the organizational structure of RCS until he or she has notified specified congressional committees and 60 days have elapsed since such notification. Requires RCS budget information to be included annually in the President's budget submitted to the Congress. Outlines eligibility requirements for one of the Assistant Under Secretaries for Health in the Department, including at least three years of clinical experience and two years of administrative experience in RCS or other comparable mental health care counseling service. Makes such a qualified person the director of RCS. Directs the Secretary, upon the request of any veteran (currently, only veterans discharged or released from active duty but not otherwise eligible for such counseling), to furnish counseling in readjusting to civilian life. Allows the provision of counseling to survivors of members of the armed forces who die while serving on active duty or from a condition incurred or aggravated by military service. Provides for the confidentiality of the records of any patient of RCS, permitting disclosure only in specific limited circumstances. Establishes in the Department the Advisory Committee on Veteran Readjustment Counseling to perform advisory services with respect to veterans' readjustment, taking into special account Vietnam era veterans. Requires specified reports from the Advisory Committee and the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees a plan for the expansion of the Vietnam Veteran Resource Center program as established under prior law. Directs the Secretary to carry out and report to the Congress on a pilot program for the provision of health-related services to eligible veterans at readjustment counseling centers.

	</summary>
</bill>
