<bill session="103" type="h" number="3093" updated="2010-04-19T07:13:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Fraud Prosecution Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to health care fraud, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-09-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-27"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Common carriers"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Express service"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicare fraud"/>
		<term name="Money laundering"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public prosecutors"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/21/1993--Introduced.
Health Care Fraud Prosecution Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to set penalties for: (1) knowingly executing a scheme or artifice to defraud to obtain a health care payment; or (2) presenting a statement as part of, or in support of, a claim for health care payment, knowing that such statement contains false or misleading information concerning any material fact. Limits such penalties to a fine and ten years' imprisonment, unless the offender knowingly or recklessly caused: (1) serious bodily injury to, or endangered the life of, an individual (up to 15 years' imprisonment); or (2) caused the death of an individual (up to 25 years' imprisonment). Sets forth provisions regarding illegal remunerations. Permits: (1) persons injured by violations of such provisions to recover treble damages in a civil action; and (2) the court to award the prevailing party a reasonable attorney fee. Makes provisions regarding injunctions against fraud and criminal forfeiture of fraud proceeds applicable to health care fraud. Authorizes the Attorney General to pay specified rewards for information leading to the prosecution and conviction of persons engaging in health care fraud, with exceptions. Directs the Attorney General to establish: (1) regional health care fraud task forces and a data base for the reporting of final adverse actions against health care providers, suppliers, or practitioners; and (2) a national, toll-free health care fraud and abuse hotline. Authorizes appropriations: (1) for the Federal Bureau of Investigation, U.S. Attorneys, and the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to hire, equip, and train personnel in connection with the investigation and prosecution of health care fraud cases; and (2) to establish, operate, and administer health care task forces and the national health care fraud and abuse data base and hotline, and to publicize the data base and hotline. Amends the Federal criminal code to make: (1) activity which, if engaged in by the U.S. Postal Service, would be a violation of mail fraud provisions, punishable to the same extent with respect to private or commercial interstate carriers (express company fraud); and (2) health care fraud and express company fraud predicates to violations of prohibitions against the laundering of monetary instruments.

	</summary>
</bill>
