<bill session="103" type="h" number="3101" updated="2010-04-19T07:14:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Window of Opportunity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a temporary reduction in the tax on capital gains and to provide for the indexing of certain assets.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300062"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400604" joined="1993-11-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2484)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Capital gains tax"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Losses"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Valuation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/21/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Temporary Reduction in Tax on Capital Gains Title II: Indexing of Certain Assets Window of Opportunity Act - Title I: Temporary Reduction in Tax on Capital Gains - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce the individual and corporate capital gains taxes to six percent (three percent for low- and middle-income taxpayers) on capital gains during a moratorium period of one year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act. Title II: Indexing of Certain Assets - Requires indexing, based on the gross national product deflator, of the adjusted basis of certain assets (corporate stock and tangible property that is a capital asset or property used in a trade or business) that have been held for more than one year at the time of sale or other transfer, solely for the purpose of determining gain or loss.

	</summary>
</bill>
