<bill session="103" type="h" number="3115" updated="2010-04-19T07:16:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Competitive Affordable Health Care Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve access, affordability, and competition in health care, through the implementation of flexible savings accounts and malpractice reform, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400115"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2229-2230)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.R.3600.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3600" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Catastrophic health insurance"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Data transmission systems"/>
		<term name="Debt"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical services"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Malpractice"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical ethics"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural hospitals"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Provisions Encouraging Low-Cost Health Plans and Health Care Savings Accounts Title II: Health Care Cost Containment Subtitle A: Health Care Liability Reform Subtitle B: Limit on Self-Referrals by Health Care Provider Subtitle C: Administrative Cost Savings Subtitle D: Limitation of Antitrust Recovery for Certain Hospital Joint Ventures Subtitle E: Medicaid Program Flexibility Title III: Refundable Credit for Costs of Providing Emergency Indigent Care Competitive Affordable Health Care Act of 1993 - Title I: Tax Provisions Encouraging Low-Cost Health Plans and Health Care Savings Accounts - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a refundable tax credit in the case of individuals not covered under an employer-provided health plan for 15 percent of the lesser of: (1) the health care expenses of the taxpayer (amount allowable as a medical expense deduction); or (2) the maximum health care expense amount (limited, based on number of personal exemptions). Allows such individuals an alternative election of a deduction for the lesser of the health care expenses of the taxpayer or the maximum health care expense amount. Denies the use of the medical expense deduction for the credited amount or the deducted amount. Repeals the special rules for health insurance costs for self-employed individuals under the trade or business expense deduction. (Sec. 102) Limits the amount excludable from gross income for employer-provided coverage to the lowest-cost available market health plan. (Sec. 103) Excludes from the gross income of an employee amounts contributed by the employer to a health care savings account of such employee. Describes the terms and conditions applicable to a health care savings account used to pay the health care expenses of the account beneficiary. Title II: Health Care Cost Containment - Subtitle A: Health Care Liability Reform - Reforms health care liability actions regarding: (1) a statute of limitations; (2) use of alternative dispute resolution systems (ADRs); (3) noneconomic and punitive damages; (4) mandatory offsets for collateral source payments; (5) contingent attorney's fees; (6) several and joint liability; and (7) supersedure of certain State laws. Subtitle B: Limit on Self-Referrals by Health Care Provider - Sets forth requirements for health care providers that refer patients to facilities in which they have a financial interest. Subtitle C: Administrative Cost Savings - Regulates: (1) data elements, uniform claims forms, and uniform electronic transmission of data elements; (2) provider claims submission; and (3) hospital and non-hospital electronic medical data. (Sec. 242) Requires hospitals, in order to participate in Medicare, to maintain and electronically transmit clinical data on patients in a set of electronic comprehensive data elements. (Sec. 243) Provides for electronic transmission of data elements to Federal agencies. (Sec. 244) Establishes an advisory commission to monitor and advise the Secretary of Health and Human Services concerning standards and operational concerns. (Sec. 251) Provides for a comparative health care value program in each State. Authorizes grants and appropriations. (Sec. 252) Requires each Federal agency concerned with health insurance or care to develop comparative value information. (Sec. 253) Mandates model systems for the gathering and analysis of data on health care cost, quality, and outcome. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 261) Provides for standards regarding Medicare and Medicaid identification cards. Establishes a Medicare and Medicaid system to provide information on primary payors. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 262) Nullifies any State law requiring that medical or health insurance records be maintained in written rather than electronic form. (Sec. 263) Provides for standards regarding: (1) beneficiary and provider identification numbers; and (2) coordination of benefits. Subtitle D: Limitation of Antitrust Recovery for Certain Hospital Joint Ventures - Limits antitrust recovery to actual damages if certain requirements are met, including the filing and publication of information regarding hospital joint ventures. Subtitle E: Medicaid Program Flexibility - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to modify: (1) Federal requirements to allow States more flexibility in contracting for coordinated care services under Medicaid; and (2) provisions regarding the extension of certain waivers. Title III: Refundable Credit for Costs of Providing Emergency Indigent Care - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit of 15 percent of the unreimbursed eligible costs incurred in providing emergency health care services to indigent individuals. Provides for payments to tax-exempt entities in lieu of such credit.

	</summary>
</bill>
