<bill session="103" type="h" number="3122" updated="2010-04-19T07:17:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Long-Term Care Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to revise and improve the long-term care programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400504"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="406768" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400127" joined="1993-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400307" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400028" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300151" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="403308" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400610" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="411178" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2223-2224)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-01"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E895-896)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Clinics"/>
		<term name="Coinsurance"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Extended care facilities"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Hospital rates"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Rent subsidies"/>
		<term name="Rental housing"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Social work"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/1993--Introduced.
Veterans' Long-Term Care Act of 1993 - Defines &quot;long-term care,&quot; for veterans' benefits purposes, as a continuum of institutional and noninstitutional programs and services that provide restorative care and support through a time period generally exceeding 90 days. Makes eligible for long-term care provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs any veteran: (1) being treated for a service-connected disability (SCD); (2) who has an SCD of 50 percent or more, for the treatment of any disability; (3) who is eligible for pension from the Department, for the treatment of any disability; and (4) for any disability resulting from Department treatment. Authorizes the Secretary to provide long-term care to certain nonqualifying veterans when medically necessary and subject to facility availability. Requires the Secretary to establish a schedule of long-term care copayments, and a long-term care coinsurance plan. Deems Department long-term care providers to be Medicare participating providers for purposes of Medicare payments under the Social Security Act. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with non-Department facilities for the provision of long-term care for veterans when Department facilities are inaccessible or otherwise incapable of providing such care. Requires such facilities to meet certain standards. Authorizes the provision of in-kind assistance to such facilities in lieu of payments. Authorizes the Secretary to provide social support services, including personal care and homemaker services, as part of long-term care services provided. Directs the Secretary to designate geographic areas of the United States as veterans' service areas in which long-term care will be available. Requires a report. Requires operation of such service areas by October 1, 1999. Directs the Secretary to regularly assess Department needs for new long-term care services. Establishes in the Treasury the Veterans' Long-Term Care Fund. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements for the establishment on Department property of veterans' continuing care facilities in which veterans reside while receiving appropriate care. Requires a Department medical center, outpatient clinic, or nursing home to be colocated with such facilities. Requires at such facilities the establishement of a team of primary care providers to be known as the Veterans' Continuing Care Center Health team. Requires congressional reports.

	</summary>
</bill>
