<bill session="103" type="h" number="3123" updated="2010-04-19T07:18:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1993-11-01" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Electrification Loan Restructuring Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Rural Electrification Loan Restructuring Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Rural Electrification Loan Restructuring Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the interest rates electric and telephone borrowers pay under the lending programs administered by the Rural Electrification Administration and otherwise restructure the lending programs carried out by that Administration.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403308"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400079" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="403873" joined="1993-09-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-23"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-09-23"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T18:49:00-04:00"><text>Mr. de la Garza moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T18:49:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7127-7133"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T18:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-09-28T19:00:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T19:00:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T19:00:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1993-10-04" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S13031"/></vote>
		<topresident datetime="1993-10-04" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06T19:23:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Con. Res. 160, enrollment corrections have been made.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2437-2438)</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1993-10-20" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1993-11-01" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-129" type="public" datetime="1993-11-01"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-129.</text></enacted>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Favorable Executive Comment Received from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hc" number="160" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hc" number="160" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1167" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Electric utilities"/>
		<term name="Electric utility rates"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Rural electrification"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/28/1993--Passed House amended. Rural Electrification Loan Restructuring Act of 1993 - Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to prescribe guidelines under which the Rural Electrification Administrator (the Administrator) shall make insured electric and telephone loans (including hardship, municipal rate, and cost of money loans). Repeals authority for the current two-percent interest hardship loan, setting such rate at five percent. Repeals authority for the current five-percent interest direct electric and telephone loan program. Caps both electric and telephone interest rates at seven percent, depending on specified circumstances. Directs the Administrator to approve State telecommunications modernization plans if they meet specified requirements. Prescribes guidelines for loans made by the Governor of a telephone bank in the rural telephone bank loan program. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) electric hardship loans; (2) electric municipal rate loans; (3) telephone hardship loans; and (4) telephone cost-of-money loans. Amends the parameters of the rural telephone bank loan program. Prohibits the Administrator and the Governor of the telephone bank from imposing any charges not expressly provided for in this Act in connection with any loan or guarantee made under this Act. Specifies circumstances under which the Administrator may use consultants funded by the borrower. Redefines the size of a statutorily defined rural area. Prescribes guidelines for: (1) distribution borrower eligibility for loans, loan guarantees, and lien accommodations; and (2) administrative prohibitions applicable to electric borrowers. Grants borrowers who refinance a loan the option to limit the new interest rate to seven percent per year, for a fee equal to one percent of the loan's outstanding principal balance, so long as the total amount of the borrower's loans for which such option would be exercised does not exceed 50 percent of the outstanding principal balance of all the borrower's loans under such Act. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to make loans for water and waste disposal facilities serving certain rural residents to any borrower to whom a loan has been made under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936. Declares that no Federal rural development program assistance shall be conditioned on any requirement that the recipient accept or receive electric service from any particular utility, supplier, or cooperative. Requires the Secretary to establish adequate safeguards to ensure compliance with such prohibition. States that a borrower of a loan or loan guarantee under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 is eligible for assistance under all programs administered by the Rural Development Administration.

	</summary>
</bill>
