<bill session="103" type="h" number="3129" updated="2010-04-19T07:18:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Interstate Bank Consolidation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To allow interstate banking through acquisitions of existing banks, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406729" joined="1993-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1994-01-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Bank capital"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank holding companies"/>
		<term name="Bank mergers"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Branch banking"/>
		<term name="Community development banking"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Interstate banking"/>
		<term name="Local taxation"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="Tax administration"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/1993--Introduced.
Interstate Bank Consolidation Act of 1993 - Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to cite circumstances under which a bank holding company may combine its subsidiary banks that are located in more than one State. Precludes such combinations within a State that has elected to prohibit them. Subjects such interstate bank combinations to the regulatory scheme of the host State. Permits the imposition of a proportion of a shares tax on an out-of-State bank by a host State. Grants the States a specified period within which to elect to either permit or prohibit on a nondiscriminatory basis such interstate combinations within their borders. Amends Federal banking law to reflect the provisions of this Act. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to authorize host State regulatory authorities to enter into cooperative agreements to coordinate their examinations of out-of-State bank branches. Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to include within its purview evaluations of the interstate branches of regulated financial institutions. Amends Federal banking law to permit State taxing authorities to review the records of a federally chartered depository institution for State tax purposes. Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to prescribe guidelines for the use of bank names in a host State by a bank holding company seeking to consolidate its banks.

	</summary>
</bill>
