<bill session="103" type="h" number="3125" updated="2010-04-19T07:18:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Felon Identification and Police Safety Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the identification of felons and persons adjudicated mentally incompetent on driver's licenses and certain identification documents through a magnetic strip containing coded information and through the establishment of a national system for the identification of such persons, and to impose criminal penalties on any federally licensed firearms dealer who sells a handgun to a person without using a device to read the magnetic strip on the driver's license or identification document of the person.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400017"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="1993-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400085" joined="1993-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400322" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400348" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="1993-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400104" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1994-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400382" joined="1993-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="401134" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400544" joined="1994-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400601" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="409633" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="401081" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400537" joined="1993-10-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H6905-6906)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Driver licenses"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/1993--Introduced.
Felon Identification and Police Safety Act of 1993 - Requires the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to reduce by 25 percent the annual allocation to a State for a fiscal year under title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 if the State has in effect a waiting period, or a system for identifying felons, before the purchase of a handgun and if the State does not have in effect specified laws and procedures regarding: (1) a records check requirement before the issuance of a driver's license and the use of magnetic strips to identify prohibited persons; (2) seizure and voiding of the driver's license upon a felony conviction or adjudication of mental incompetency; (3) funding of records checks; and (4) a requirement that the State maintain and update a computerized list of prohibited persons by reason of a conviction or adjudication in the State. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) create a national, computerized list of prohibited persons; (2) incorporate State criminal history records into the Federal criminal records system maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation; (3) develop hardware and software systems to link State lists with the national list; and (4) provide any responsible State agency with access to the national list upon request. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) procedures for correcting erroneous records; and (2) judicial review with respect to persons erroneously identified as prohibited persons. Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit (with exceptions) any licensed dealer from knowingly: (1) selling a handgun to an unlicensed person unless the dealer has used an electronic device to read the magnetic strip affixed to an identification document issued to such person by the transportation agency of the State in which the premises of the dealer is located; or (2) failing to notify local law enforcement authorities, within 72 hours, of any person attempting to purchase a handgun who is identified as a prohibited person through the use of such a device. Sets penalties for violations.

	</summary>
</bill>
