<bill session="103" type="h" number="3144" updated="2010-04-19T07:21:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize funding within the Department of the Interior to implement the plan of the Steel Industry Heritage Project, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400543"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408052" joined="1993-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1993-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400591" joined="1993-09-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2259-2261)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-31"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.5044.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="5044" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Architecture"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Culture"/>
		<term name="Engineering"/>
		<term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
		<term name="Pennsylvania"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/28/1993--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) review and approve the report submitted by the Southwestern Pennsylvania Heritage Preservation Commission concerning the cultural and historical resource values of the greater Allegheny and Washington Counties/Mon-Valley Area (known as the Concept Plan; Steel Industry Heritage Project); and (2) approve projects consistent with this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into consultative agreements with the Steel Industry Heritage Task Force on projects and studies necessary to fulfill the Concept Plan. Authorizes the Task Force to receive appropriations through the Department of the Interior for projects and studies within the region of Southwestern Pennsylvania comprising the geographical area within the counties of Allegheny, Beaver, Fayette, Greene, Washington, and Westmoreland based on the project criteria established in the Concept Plan. Requires the Secretary, in cooperation with the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and the Task Force, to undertake plans and studies, including studies of alternatives, special resources studies and new area studies, and management action plans necessary to determine and identify the appropriate role of the Government, through the National Park Service, to conserve and interpret the history of the region. Directs the Historic American Building Survey/Historic American Engineering Record to conduct those studies necessary to document the industrial, engineering, building, and architectural history of the region. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
