<bill session="103" type="h" number="3162" updated="2010-04-19T07:24:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Asylum at Ports of Entry System Improvements Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for expedited asylum and exclusion procedures for certain aliens and to provide for enhanced penalties for alien smuggling and asylum abuse.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400289"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="1993-09-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-04"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Law, Immigration, and Refugees.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Right to counsel"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/28/1993--Introduced.
Asylum at Ports of Entry System Improvements Act of 1993 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to create grounds for exclusion of an alien who: (1) uses or attempts to use a fraudulent document to enter the United States or to board a common carrier for such purpose; or (2) uses a document to board a common carrier and then fails to present such document to an immigration official upon arrival at a U.S. port of entry. Directs the Attorney General to designate a class of senior asylum officers who shall perform specified expedited asylum examinations at U.S. airports or other ports of entry. Authorizes such officers, upon a finding of frivolous claim or resettlement in another country, to exclude the alien from the United States. Sets forth limited petition and review provisions. Increases penalties for certain alien smuggling offenses. Creates a separate offense and penalty for an alien smuggler who seriously injures or jeopardizes an alien's life.

	</summary>
</bill>
