<bill session="103" type="h" number="3169" updated="2010-04-19T07:25:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Insurance Disclosure Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for public access to information regarding the availability of insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406277"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404634" joined="1993-09-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Automobile insurance"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Business insurance"/>
		<term name="Business losses"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Casualty insurance"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Computer software"/>
		<term name="Computers and government"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Insurance"/>
		<term name="Insurance agents"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Loans"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Property insurance"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Statistics"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women in business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/1993--Introduced.
Insurance Disclosure Act - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (the Secretary) to establish requirements for insurers to compile and submit information to the Secretary for each annual reporting period concerning the affordability and availability of insurance coverage for: (1) noncommercial insurance; (2) commercial insurance for residential properties and small businesses in urban areas; (3) bid, performance, and payment bonds for small businesses; and (4) insurance in designated rural areas. Authorizes the Secretary to waive such disclosure requirements if the State within which the insurer transacts business has an equivalent disclosure mechanism in place. Directs the Financial Institutions Examination Council to determine the extent to which private mortgage insurers make available to the public and to regulatory agencies the mortgage information required to be reported under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975. Provides for contracting out such data collection or submission of such data through statistical agents. Directs the Secretary to set forth specified annual disclosure requirements for loans and investments made by designated insurers in a designated metropolitan statistical area. Prescribes guidelines for: (1) the compilation and public accessibility of the disclosures mandated by this Act; and (2) written notification by an insurer to applicants and policyholders regarding the reasons that coverage was denied. Sets forth civil penalties for insurers in violation of this Act. Directs the Secretary to establish a task force to report to certain congressional committees on insurance agency appointments affecting inner city and minority agents. Requires the Secretary to conduct studies and report to certain congressional committees on: (1) prescreening of insurance applicants; (2) insurer practices affecting the insurance needs of low- and moderate-income neighborhoods, minority neighborhoods, and small businesses located in such neighborhoods; (3) disparate treatment of policyholders by insurers based upon sex, race, or income level; (4) the disparate impact upon policyholders of basing insurance premiums upon the territory in which the insured risk is located; and (5) community reinvestment requirements for insurers that are comparable to those for depository institutions.

	</summary>
</bill>
