<bill session="103" type="h" number="3170" updated="2010-04-19T07:25:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to consult with representatives of physicians and to use the most recent available data in making geographic adjustments to the payment rates for physicians' services under part B of the medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402454"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/1993--Introduced.
Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to consult with appropriate representatives of physicians in reviewing the geographic adjustment factors used to determine reimbursements for physician services under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance). Requires the Secretary to: (1) base such factors on the most recent available data; (2) first review and revise such factors by January 1, 1995; and (3) study and report to specified congressional committees on the construction of the geographic cost of practice index and the review and revision of the geographic indices under Medicare. Directs the Physician Payment Review Commission to study and report to the Congress on criteria to refine fee schedule areas in applying geographic adjustment factors for computing payment amounts under Medicare for physicians' services.

	</summary>
</bill>
