<bill session="103" type="h" number="3190" updated="2010-04-19T07:28:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue a discharge permit which modifies certain requirements with respect to the discharge of pollutants into the ocean from a publicly owned treatment works where an aggressive water reclamation program is being implemented.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-08"><text>Executive Comment Requested from EPA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Sewage disposal"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water rates"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, with the concurrence of a State, to issue a permit which modifies certain requirements with respect to the discharge of pollutants from a publicly owned treatment works into marine waters if the applicant demonstrates that: (1) such discharge is at a depth that will not damage the marine environment and is subject to chemically enhanced primary treatment; and (2) the applicant is implementing an aggressive water reclamation and reuse program that will result in a significant reduction in the amount of suspended solids mass load and effluent volume discharged into the marine environment.

	</summary>
</bill>
