<bill session="103" type="h" number="3216" updated="2010-04-19T07:32:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-12-17">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1993-12-17" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Chemical Diversion Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Domestic Chemical Diversion Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Domestic Chemical Diversion Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 to control the diversion of certain chemicals used in the illicit production of controlled substances such as methcathinine and methamphetamine, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400391"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400553" joined="1993-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1993-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="402890" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="409423" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="402325" joined="1993-11-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2341)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-08"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7713)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8791-8793)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and the Environment"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and the Environment"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-16"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18T22:54:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 103-379, Part I.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-21T16:08:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Waxman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-21T16:08:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10541-10545"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-21T16:08:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-11-21T16:10:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-11-21T16:11:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1993-11-24" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S17225"/></vote>
		<topresident datetime="1993-11-24" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<action datetime="1993-11-26"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1993-12-08" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1993-12-17" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-200" type="public" datetime="1993-12-17"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-200.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1767" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Amphetamines"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Chemical industries"/>
		<term name="Chemicals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug industry"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="LSD (Drug)"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/21/1993--Passed House amended. Domestic Chemical Diversion Control Act of 1993 - Amends the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (Comprehensive Act) to: (1) replace references to &quot;listed precursor chemicals&quot; with &quot;list I chemicals&quot; and &quot;listed essential chemicals&quot; with &quot;list II chemicals&quot;; and (2) revise the definitions of &quot;regulated person&quot; (to include individuals who act as brokers or traders for international transactions involving a listed chemical, tableting machine, or encapsulating machine) and &quot;regulated transaction&quot; (to include international transactions involving shipment of a threshold amount of a listed chemical and to exclude specified transactions). (Sec. 2) Removes the exemption for products in which ephedrine is the only active medicinal ingredient in therapeutic amounts. Permits the Attorney General to remove the exemption for other drugs containing listed chemicals if it is determined that they are being diverted for use in the illicit production of a controlled substance, with exceptions. (Sec. 3) Provides registration requirements for list I chemicals, including the authority to revoke or deny based on public interest grounds, immediate suspension in cases of imminent danger to the public health or safety, and criminal penalties for distribution, importation, or exportation without the required registration. (Sec. 4) Makes any person located in the United States who is a broker or trader for an international transaction in a listed chemical that is a regulated transaction solely because of that person's involvement as broker or trader with respect to such transaction subject to all of the notification, reporting, recordkeeping, and other requirements placed upon exporters of listed chemicals by the Comprehensive Act. Sets penalties for knowingly or intentionally importing or exporting a listed chemical in violation of the registration requirements. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Attorney General to reduce controls on the importation of specified chemicals by modifying or eliminating the advance notice requirement. Adds specific criminal penalties for: (1) attempting to evade reporting requirements by falsely claiming that a shipment is destined for a country for which a waiver has been established; and (2) smuggling of listed chemicals. (Sec. 6) Makes provisions of the Comprehensive Act regarding administrative inspections, and threshold amounts of substances applicable to listed chemicals, as well as to controlled substances. (Sec. 8) Amends list I to add benzaldehyde and nitroethane, and delete D-lysergic acid, N-ethylephedrine, and N-ethylpseudoephedrine. (Sec. 9) Eliminates &quot;regular supplier&quot; status and creates &quot;regular importer&quot; status. (Sec. 10) Requires each regulated person that manufactures a listed chemical to report annually to the Attorney General information concerning listed chemicals manufactured by such regulated person.

	</summary>
</bill>
