<bill session="103" type="h" number="3223" updated="2010-04-19T07:33:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Asylum Abuse Prevention and System Improvements Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish fair and expedited procedures for adjudicating political asylum claims and to prevent fraud and abuse in the asylum process.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400021"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="1993-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2360-2361)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Law, Immigration, and Refugees.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Administrative law judges"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political refugees"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Right to counsel"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1993--Introduced.
Asylum Abuse Prevention and System Improvements Act of 1993 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to impose criminal penalties upon any person who knowingly assists in fraudulent asylum applications for commercial advantage or private financial gain. Sets forth procedures for: (1) adjudicating political asylum claims; and (2) detention and release of asylum applicants. Directs the Attorney General to ensure that specified amounts are made available each fiscal year to the Central Asylum Office in the Executive Office of Immigration Review for adjudication implementation. Authorizes appropriations for additional Department of Justice asylum adjudication staff. Directs the Attorney General to report to certain congressional committees on the backlog in adjudicating asylum claims. Authorizes the Attorney General to use specified amounts from the Immigration Emergency Fund to manage large and sudden numbers of asylum applicants.

	</summary>
</bill>
