<bill session="103" type="h" number="3221" updated="2012-07-17T06:25:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-28T15:01:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-04-28T15:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="146"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraq Claims Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Iraq Claims Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Iraq Claims Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the adjudication of certain claims against the Government of Iraq.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404996"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Motion to Recommit to Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East Passed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-10-28"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20T15:05:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 103-396, Part I.</text></action>
		<calendar number="221" datetime="1993-11-20T15:05:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 221.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-01-25T16:15:00-05:00"><text>Discharged from Union Calendar.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-25"><text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Judiciary for a period ending not later than Feb. 28, 1994 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(l), rule X.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-28T12:13:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="236" datetime="1994-02-28T12:14:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 236.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21T15:50:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 410 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3221 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Foreign Affairs now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T13:34:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 410 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T13:34:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 410.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2854-2870"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T13:34:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3221 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Foreign Affairs now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T13:35:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 410 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T13:35:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Anna G. Eshoo to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T13:36:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:48:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3221.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:49:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:50:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:50:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Manzullo moved to recommit with instructions to Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:51:00-04:00"><text>The instructions contained in the motion to recommit direct that the bill be reported back to the House with an amendment to strike the existing section 10(a) and to insert a new section which provides that individuals who have served in the armed forces of Iraq during the Persian Gulf conflict may not be admitted to the United States as refugees under the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2869"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Hamilton raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion to recommit seek to change existing law regarding immigration and as such, the motion is not germane to the bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:54:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Manzullo moved to recommit with instructions to Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the second Manzullo motion to recommit with instructions.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:58:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:58:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2869"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T14:58:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to the instructions contained in the Manzullo motion to recommit the bill to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, Mr. Hamilton reported the bill back to the House with an amendment.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="146" datetime="1994-04-28T15:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 398 - 5 (Roll no. 146).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T15:20:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28T15:20:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3221.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-21"><committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/><text>Subcommittee on International Economic Policy. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East" activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="International Economic Policy, Trade, Oceans and Environment" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="410" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Aggression"/>
		<term name="Alien property"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Arab refugees"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Crimes against humanity"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Frigates"/>
		<term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Immigration policy"/>
		<term name="International courts"/>
		<term name="International relief"/>
		<term name="Iraq"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Kuwait"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
		<term name="Military occupation"/>
		<term name="Military personnel"/>
		<term name="Naval personnel"/>
		<term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
		<term name="War casualties"/>
		<term name="War crime trials"/>
		<term name="War crimes"/>
		<term name="War relief"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h527"/>
		<amendment number="h528"/>
		<amendment number="h529"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/28/1994--Passed House amended. Iraq Claims Act of 1994 - Authorizes the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission to receive and determine the validity and amounts of any claims: (1) with respect to which the United States has received lump-sum payments from the United Nations Compensation Commission (UNCC); and (2) of U.S. nationals against Iraq that are determined to be outside the UNCC's jurisdiction. (Sec. 2) Requires the Commission, in deciding such claims, to apply, in the following order: (1) relevant decisions of the United Nations Security Council and the UNCC; (2) applicable substantive law; and (3) principles of justice and equity. Directs the Commission to decide all pending non-commercial claims of members of the armed forces and other individuals arising out of Iraq's invasion and occupation of Kuwait or out of the 1987 attack on the USS Stark before deciding any other claim. Applies titles I and VII of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 to claims under this Act. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to establish in the Treasury: (1) UN Commission Claims Funds composed of amounts transferred by the Secretary of State pursuant to this Act; and (2) the Iraq Claims Fund composed of amounts allocated by the President from liquidated assets of the Iraqi Government. Authorizes the President to vest and liquidate as much of the assets of the Iraqi Government in the United States that have been blocked pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act as necessary to satisfy claims of U.S. nationals or the U.S. Government that are outside the UNCC's jurisdiction. (Sec. 6) Sets forth payment and recordkeeping requirements. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to publish a notice of the statute of limitations on unpaid certified claims nine years after the last date on which the Secretary covers funds into the UN Commission Claims Funds or the Iraq Claims Fund. Bars demands for payments on such claims one year after the publication of such notice. (Sec. 10) Expresses the sense of the Congress that individuals who served in the armed forces of Iraq during the Persian Gulf conflict should not be admitted to the United States as refugees under the Immigration and Nationality Act, except in exceptional circumstances, until all certified claims by U.S. nationals outside the UNCC's jurisdiction have been paid in full. (Sec. 11) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the United States should immediately provide humanitarian assistance to alleviate the disaster in Iraq; and (2) such assistance should be reimbursed from any available Iraqi resources so long as such reimbursement does not delay or reduce amounts paid on priority claims of members of the armed forces and others. (Sec. 12) Urges the President to request the United Nations to establish a tribunal to charge Saddam Hussein and other Iraqi Government officials for war crimes, acts of aggression, and crimes against humanity.

	</summary>
</bill>
