<bill session="103" type="h" number="3252" updated="2012-07-17T05:01:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-23T01:25:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-11-23T01:25:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="without objection" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">West Virginia Rivers Conservation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">West Virginia Rivers Conservation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">West Virginia Rivers Conservation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">West Virginia Rivers Conservation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conservation, management, or study of certain rivers, parks, trails, and historic sites, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400612"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="1993-11-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="1993-11-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="1993-11-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="1993-11-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="1993-11-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-07"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Previous Action See H.R.1584.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Late Referral to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands (Nov 15, 1993).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-10-13"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08T23:24:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 103-332.</text></action>
		<calendar number="183" datetime="1993-11-08T23:24:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 183.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-23T01:22:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Vento asked unanimous consent to discharge the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union and consider.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-23T01:24:00-05:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR 11/22/1993 H10924-10928)</text></action>
		<vote how="without objection" type="vote" datetime="1993-11-23T01:25:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-11-23T01:25:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-23"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-05"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Army Corps of Engineers, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21" ><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="658" datetime="1994-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 658.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-11-30"><text>By Senator Johnston from Committee on Energy and Natural Resources filed written report. Report No. 103-432.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hj" number="67" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1584" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1584" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2478" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Beaches"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Common carriers"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Illinois"/>
		<term name="Islands"/>
		<term name="Kentucky"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Lincoln Administration"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Mountains"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="New Jersey"/>
		<term name="Pennsylvania"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Sewage disposal"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Tennessee"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Trucks"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Utah"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
		<term name="West Virginia"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
		<term name="Wyoming"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h421"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/1994--Reported to Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Rivers Title II: Trails Title III: Parks Title I: Rivers - West Virginia Rivers Conservation Act of 1993 - Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978, the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987, and the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to modify boundaries of the: (1) New River Gorge National River; (2) Gauley River National Recreation Area; and (3) Bluestone National Scenic River. (Sec. 105) Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a segment of the Upper New River, West Virginia, as a component of the National Wild and Scenic River System (NWSRS). (Sec. 106) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to study and report to specified congressional committees on the eligibility and suitability of designating a specified segment of the Elk River, West Virginia, as either a component of the NWSRS or a unit of the National Park System (NPS) as a national river or recreation area. (Sec. 107) Provides for consolidated management between offices and personnel administering the segment of the Upper New River designated by this Act and offices and personnel administering the New River Gorge National River, the Gauley River National Recreation Area, and the Bluestone National Scenic River. (Sec. 108) Makes provisions of the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987 (the Act) relating to cooperative agreements and remnant lands in the Gauley River National Recreation Area applicable to the New River Gorge National River. (Sec. 109) Amends the Act to set forth provisions relating to access of the Gauley River National Recreation Area by certain noncommercial recreational users. (Sec. 110) Authorizes the Secretary to construct a visitor center in the vicinity of the confluence of the New and Gauley Rivers. (Sec. 111) Extends certain provisions of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act with respect to segments of the Bluestone and Meadow Rivers that were found eligible for addition to the wild and scenic rivers system in studies completed by NPS in 1983 but that were not designated as part of the Bluestone National Scenic River or the Gauley River National Recreation Area under the Act. (Sec. 112) Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to set forth provisions relating to public access to the Bluestone River. (Sec. 113) Ceases the force and effect of any boundary modification of the Gauley River National Recreational Area relating to new project construction in the Area if construction is not commenced within the time required in the license or if such license is surrendered. Title II: Trails - Amends the National Trails System Act to designate the Great Western Scenic Trail, extending from the Arizona-Mexico border to the Idaho-Montana-Canada border, for study as an addition to the National Scenic Trail System. Title III: Parks - Provides that at noon on July 30, 2000, the use of Highway 209 within the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area by commercial vehicles shall be prohibited when such use is in no way connected with the operation of the Area unless permitted by the Secretary, under specified conditions. Repeals provisions of Federal law, on such date, relating to steps to be taken to further the purposes of the Area and to provide public safety in it. Authorizes the Secretary to continue to collect and utilize a commercial user fee in an amount not to exceed $25 per vehicle from the date of enactment of this Act through July 30, 2000. (Sec. 302) Authorizes the Secretary to purchase lands within the Cumberland Gap National Historical Park in Tennessee, Kentucky, and Virginia with appropriated funds and to use such funds to purchase or maintain property within the Park's boundaries. (Sec. 303) Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director of the NPS, to enter into cooperative agreements relating to Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area: (1) with appropriate organizations or groups to promote education concerning the natural and cultural resources of the Area and adjacent lands; and (2) in which the Secretary agrees to maintain the facilities at 2600 Franklin Canyon Drive, Beverly Hills, California, for eight fiscal years and to provide funding for programs of the William O. Douglas Outdoor Classroom that utilize those facilities (in return for which the Classroom agrees that at the end of the term of such agreement, all right, title, and interest in and to such facilities will be donated to the United States for addition to the Area). Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 304) Authorizes the Secretary to establish the Abraham Lincoln Presidential Center to be added to and administered as part of the Lincoln Home National Historic Site in Illinois. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 305) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer that portion of the U.S. existing sewage disposal system within the Colonial National Historical Park to York County, Virginia, without reimbursement, together with such rights-of-way determined to be necessary to maintain and operate such system. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a cooperative agreement with York County to pay a specified maximum amount of the repair and rehabilitation costs for the system. Requires the cooperative agreement to: (1) reduce or eliminate the amounts charged to the NPS for its sewage disposal; and (2) minimize the impact of the system on the Park and its resources. Prohibits such system from being enlarged or substantially altered without NPS concurrence. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire specified lands to be included within the Park's boundaries. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 306) Designates the visitors center at Channel Islands National Park, California, as the Robert J. Lagomarsino Visitors Center.

	</summary>
</bill>
