<bill session="103" type="h" number="3258" updated="2010-04-19T07:38:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To assist States in establishing and increasing the utilization of boot camp prisons.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400246"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military training camps"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/12/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Boot Camp Grants Title II: Boot Camp Option for Nonviolent Drug Offenders Title I: Boot Camp Grants - Authorizes the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to States for establishing boot camp prisons, with priority given to applications to establish such prisons by utilizing surplus Federal property (including military bases that are no longer in use). Conditions grant eligibility on a prison providing: (1) an organized program of manual labor and discipline designed to build character, instill a sense of maturity, promote a positive self-image for offenders, and foster respect for authority; (2) training or vocational education; (3) treatment and counseling to all inmates who are addicted to drugs or alcohol; (4) a corrective therapeutic environment; (5) an agreement that specifies procedures to ensure compliance with boot camp requirements and resentencing by the court to traditional prisons for noncompliance; and (6) a community adjustment phase that begins after an inmate has successfully completed a boot camp prison term which includes specified restrictions. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) application requirements; (2) review of State applications; (3) allocation and distribution of funds; and (4) evaluation (including reports on recidivism rates among participants). Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Boot Camp Option for Nonviolent Drug Offenders - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to authorize the court, in the case of a defendant who is convicted of simple possession of a controlled substance that did not involve violence, to sentence the defendant to incarceration in an intensive confinement center (i.e., a boot camp prison) and make any mandatory minimum sentence of imprisonment otherwise required inapplicable (with provision for resentencing the defendant to a term not less than the sentence otherwise required if the defendant is in substantial noncompliance with the requirements of the center).

	</summary>
</bill>
