<bill session="103" type="h" number="3264" updated="2010-04-19T07:39:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Work Incentives Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XVI and XIX of the Social Security Act to improve work incentives for people with disabilities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1993-10-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1993-10-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-15"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Older workers"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Sick leave"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Students"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Workers' compensation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/12/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Access to SSI Work Incentives Title II: Work Incentives Waiver Authority Title III: Amendments to Work Incentives Provisions Title IV: Effective Date Work Incentives Amendments of 1993 - Title I: Access to SSI Work Incentives - Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to access to work incentives under SSI for SSI disability benefits (SSDI)-only recipients who lose eligibility for SSDI benefits because of working. Title II: Work Incentives Waiver Authority - Amends SSA titles XIX (Medicaid) and XVI with respect to: (1) the eligibility of certain individuals with disabilities for coverage under Medicaid and community-based care waivers; and (2) work incentives waiver authority. Title III: Amendments to Work Incentives Provisions - Amends SSA title XVI: (1) to disregard the deemed income of an ineligible spouse when determining continued Medicaid eligibility for certain individuals; (2) to provide for continuation of Medicaid for the aged who lose SSI due to excessive earnings; (3) to deem approved self-support plans not disapproved within 30 days; (4) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a time limit by which activities under a plan for achieving self-support must be completed; (5) to provide for the expansion of self-support plans to include housing goals; and (6) with regard to self-support plans for the aged, additional State supplementation requirements, treatment of unemployment compensation, workers' compensation, and sick pay as earned income for SSI purposes, treatment of certain grant, scholarship, or fellowship income as earned income for SSI purposes, and SSI eligibility for students temporarily abroad. Amends SSA title XIX to provide for the exclusion of income and resources under self-support plans in determining Medicaid eligibility in certain States. Title IV: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
