<bill session="103" type="h" number="3268" updated="2010-04-19T07:40:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Firearms License Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to reform the laws relating to Federal firearms licenses and licensees.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400079"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409578" joined="1993-10-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1993-10-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="403864" joined="1993-10-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-30"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.R.1025.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1025" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Freight"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Interstate commerce"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Pawnbroking"/>
		<term name="Photography"/>
		<term name="Riots"/>
		<term name="Robbery"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/13/1993--Introduced.
Federal Firearms License Reform Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit a common or contract carrier from: (1) requiring or causing to be placed on the outside of any package, luggage, or other container any label, tag, or other written notice that the container contains a firearm; and (2) delivering a firearm in interstate or foreign commerce without obtaining written acknowledgement of receipt of the firearm from the recipient. Permits the personal transfer of firearms between licensees outside their business premises. Prohibits and sets penalties for: (1) stealing, unlawfully converting, or taking by fraud from a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer any firearm in the business inventory of the licensee which has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce; and (2) knowingly violating such provision during and in relation to a robbery or riot (in which case, if death results, such violator shall be subject to life imprisonment without release or to death). Revises firearms licensing provisions to provide for a three-year license to deal in firearms and an increase in the application fee. Requires Federal firearms licensees to: (1) report the theft of firearms within five business days of discovery; and (2) respond within five days to requests from the Secretary of the Treasury for information contained in required records regarding disposition of a firearm. Expands the definitions of &quot;curios or relics&quot; and &quot;antique firearm.&quot; Requires: (1) Federal firearms license applicants to notify local law enforcement authorities of the intention to apply for such license; and (2) the Secretary to publish and provide to all licensees a compilation of relevant State laws and published ordinances, and periodically provide a copy of all changes in regulations and new rulings. Amends: (1) the National Firearms Act to require importers, manufacturers, and dealers in firearms who register pursuant to such Act to provide a photograph and fingerprints at the time of registration; and (2) the Federal criminal code to authorize the award of attorney fees in cases of unauthorized denial or revocation of a firearms license.

	</summary>
</bill>
