<bill session="103" type="h" number="3306" updated="2010-04-19T07:46:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Depository Institution Retail Investment Sales and Disclosure Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to regulate the retail sale of nondeposit investment products by insured depository institutions to prevent customer confusion about the uninsured nature of the products, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404634"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="1993-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1994-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1994-02-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8325-8326)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Brokers"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Deposit insurance"/>
		<term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
		<term name="Investment advisers"/>
		<term name="Investments"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Mutual funds"/>
		<term name="Pensions"/>
		<term name="Securities industry"/>
		<term name="Securities regulation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/19/1993--Introduced.
Depository Institution Retail Investment Sales and Disclosure Act - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to add provisions regulating the retail sales of nondeposit investment products (shares issued by a registered investment company) by insured depository institutions. Prohibits insured depository institutions from permitting any person to engage in any practice or advertising which could mislead a customer as to: (1) the uninsured nature of any nondeposit investment product offered or sold by the institution; or (2) the investment risk associated with such product. Requires specified disclosures to potential customers, including disclosure that the nondeposit investment product is not insured by the FDIC (Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation) and that the product poses investment risks and may involve the loss of principal. Requires signed purchaser declarations acknowledging understanding of the disclosures. States that an insured depository institution may not allow any person who accepts deposits to sell or offer investment advice regarding any nondeposit investment product. Prescribes requirements which must be met by persons selling nondeposit investment products. Places restrictions on names, designs, and logos used by depository institutions in connection with investment activities. Provides for confidentiality of customer information. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Federal banking agencies use testers to monitor compliance with the requirements of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
