<bill session="103" type="h" number="3300" updated="2012-07-17T05:58:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-12T12:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-09-12T12:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Resource Management on Military Lands Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Natural Resource Management on Military Lands Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Act popularly known as the &quot;Sikes Act&quot; to enhance fish and wildlife conservation and natural resources management programs on military installations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1993-10-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2468-2469)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-25"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-25"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD, Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-08-11"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12T12:05:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries. H. Rept. 103-718.</text></action>
		<calendar number="395" datetime="1994-09-12T12:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 395.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12T12:31:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Studds moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12T12:31:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9037-9039"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12T12:32:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-09-12T12:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12T12:37:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-27" ><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported to Senate by Senator Baucus without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="715" datetime="1994-10-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 715.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" />
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Forest management"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetland restoration"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/12/1994--Passed House amended. Natural Resource Management on Military Lands Act of 1994 - Amends the Act of September 15, 1960 (commonly referred to as the Sikes Act) to direct (current law authorizes) the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program of wildlife, fish, and game conservation on each U.S. military installation. Requires an integrated natural resource management plan (plan) to be included in each program. Requires the plan to address the needs for fish and wildlife management, land management, forest management, and wildlife-oriented recreation. Requires an opportunity for public comment on each plan prepared. Requires the: (1) Secretaries of each military department to review and report to the Secretary on military installations under their jurisdiction which would be appropriate for a plan; and (2) Secretary to report to the Congress on such reviews. Provides a deadline for the establishment of such plans. Directs the Secretary to annually review the extent to which plans were prepared or in effect and implemented during the preceding year. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to report to specified congressional committees on funds expended on conservation activities conducted pursuant to such plans. Provides for the enforcement on military installations of all Federal laws relating to natural resources conservation on Federal lands. Requires the Secretary of each military department to ensure that sufficient numbers of trained natural resource management and law enforcement personnel are available and assigned to perform tasks necessary to ensure plan compliance. Entitles the Act of September 15, 1960, as the Sikes Act. Extends through FY 1997 the authorization of appropriations for natural resources conservation programs on military installations, as well as equivalent programs on other public lands.

	</summary>
</bill>
