<bill session="103" type="h" number="3317" updated="2010-04-19T07:47:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the United States representative to the United Nations from voting to approve, expand, or extend any United Nations peacekeeping, peacemaking, or peace-enforcing operation unless the President notifies the Congress before that vote.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400340"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-02"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/19/1993--Introduced.
Prohibits the U.S. representative to the United Nations (UN) from voting to approve, expand, or extend any UN peacekeeping, peacemaking, or peace-enforcing operation unless, at least 15 days before such vote, the President notifies the appropriate congressional committees of: (1) the total estimated cost of the operation; (2) the source of funding for the U.S. contribution to the operation and whether the funding will require a budget request or an amendment to an existing one, a reprogramming of existing funds, or a request for supplemental appropriations; (3) the anticipated duration, scope, and termination date of the operation; (4) the operation's goals; and (5) the U.S. interests that will be served by such operation.

	</summary>
</bill>
