<bill session="103" type="h" number="3310" updated="2010-04-19T07:46:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Barbara McClintock AIDS Cure Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Barbara McClintock Project to Cure AIDS.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400289"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1994-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1994-02-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
		<term name="Clinics"/>
		<term name="Communication in science"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Drug industry"/>
		<term name="Eminent domain"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Medical ethics"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Scientists"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/19/1993--Introduced.
Barbara McClintock AIDS Cure Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a project to develop a cure for acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS). Prohibits the program from being administered by any officer or employee of the National Institutes of Health. Requires the Secretary to ensure that the project: (1) pursues all basic science investigations, based on diverse theories and schools of thought which elucidate the pathogenesis of AIDS; and (2) identifies, based on this work, all promising curatives and oversees their timely and adequate testing. Establishes a governing council to set policy and oversee research priorities, ethical standards, conflict of interest rules, and hiring of researchers. Establishes a coordinating committee to facilitate communication among the different scientists working on the project, evaluate the progress of its work, and convene the entire staff on some regular schedule (or when necessary) to evaluate the progress of the project as a whole, reevaluate its direction, and consider newly developed theories emanating from both within and outside the project. Grants the Secretary extraordinary powers in carrying out such project.

	</summary>
</bill>
