<bill session="103" type="h" number="3323" updated="2010-04-19T07:48:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that rates of pay for the President and Members of Congress shall be made equivalent to the rates of pay for their counterparts in the United Mexican States if legislation implementing the North American Free Trade Agreement is enacted.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400357"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8205-8206)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
		<term name="Customs unions"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Free trade"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="North America"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Presidential compensation"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/20/1993--Introduced.
Makes the compensation of the President of the United States equivalent to the annual rate of pay for the President of the United Mexican States. Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to make the annual rate of pay of a U.S. Senator equivalent to that of a Senator in the Congress of the Union of the United Mexican States with respect to a U.S. Senator and of a Member of the House of Representatives equivalent to that of a Deputy in the Congress of the Union of the United Mexican States. Provides that this Act shall not take effect unless the United States enacts legislation implementing the North American Free Trade Agreement.

	</summary>
</bill>
