<bill session="103" type="h" number="3336" updated="2010-04-19T07:50:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide mandatory life imprisonment for persons convicted of a third violent felony and to provide for the conversion of three military installations to be closed under the base closure laws into Federal prison facilities capable of incarcerating these persons.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406863"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-22"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-22"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-22"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from DOD.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/21/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to require the court, in the case of a conviction for a Federal violent felony, to sentence the defendant to life imprisonment if the defendant has previously been convicted of two other violent felonies. Specifies that this provision shall not be construed to prevent the imposition of the death penalty. Requires the Secretary of Defense and the Attorney General to study all military installations selected before the enactment of this Act to be closed pursuant to a base closure law to: (1) evaluate the suitability of any of these military installations, or portions thereof, for conversion into Federal prison facilities; and (2) identify three of them that are most suitable for such conversion. Directs the Secretary to transfer, without reimbursment, jurisdiction over the three installations to the Attorney General for conversion into Federal prison facilities designed to incarcerate persons convicted of a Federal violent felony. Authorizes the Attorney General to accept transfers, upon a space available basis, from overcrowded State prisons of persons previously convicted of a Federal violent felony or who are serving a sentence of more than 20 years.

	</summary>
</bill>
