<bill session="103" type="h" number="3353" updated="2010-04-19T07:53:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-03T18:15:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-11-03T18:15:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="542"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to allow grants to develop more effective programs to reduce juvenile gang participation and juvenile drug trafficking.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401837"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="1993-10-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2532)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-10-28"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T14:29:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 103-322.</text></action>
		<calendar number="173" datetime="1993-11-03T14:29:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 173.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T15:23:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Brooks moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T15:23:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8734-8739"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T15:23:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T15:57:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T18:07:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8753"/></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="542" datetime="1993-11-03T18:15:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 413 - 12 (Roll No. 542).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03T18:15:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="270" datetime="1993-11-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 270.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
		<term name="Drugs and youth"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Elementary school students"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
		<term name="Gangs"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Public housing"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
		<term name="School violence"/>
		<term name="Secondary school students"/>
		<term name="Sports"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/3/1993--Passed House amended. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to assist States and local governments in planning, operating, coordinating, and evaluating projects for the development of more effective programs, including education, prevention, treatment, and enforcement programs, to reduce: (1) the formation or continuation of juvenile gangs; and (2) the use and sale of illegal drugs by juveniles. Specifies the uses of such grants, including: (1) reducing juvenile participation in drug-related crimes (particularly in and around elementary and secondary schools) and juvenile involvement in organized crime, drug- and gang-related activity (particularly activities that involve the distribution of drugs by or to juveniles and such activity in public housing projects); (2) developing new and innovative means to address the problems of juveniles convicted of serious, drug- and gang-related offenses; (3) promoting the involvement of all juveniles in lawful activities; (4) providing pre- and post-trial drug abuse treatment to juveniles in the juvenile justice system and education and treatment programs for youth exposed to severe violence in their homes, schools, or neighborhoods; (5) identifying promising new juvenile drug demand reduction and enforcement programs, replicating and demonstrating such programs to serve as national, regional, or local models, and providing technical assistance and training to public or private organizations to implement similar programs; and (6) coordinating violence, gang, and juvenile drug prevention programs with other existing Federal programs that serve community youth. Sets forth: (1) application requirements; and (2) Federal share requirements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
