<bill session="103" type="h" number="3362" updated="2010-04-19T07:54:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Employer Sanctions Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to strengthen sanctions relating to employment of unauthorized aliens.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407306"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Law, Immigration, and Refugees.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-21"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Driver licenses"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/26/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Promoting Enforcement Title II: Improving the Employment Verification System Title III: Additional Penalties and Increases in Penalties Employer Sanctions Improvement Act of 1993 - Title I: Promoting Enforcement - Amends Federal immigration law to repeal the Federal preemption of State law regarding sanctions against the employment of unauthorized aliens. Creates a private right of action for violation of Federal law prohibiting employment of unauthorized aliens. Directs the Attorney General to provide grants to the States for immigration assistance and enforcement. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to condition Federal assistance upon assurances that the recipient State actively enforces sanctions against the employment of unauthorized aliens. Amends Federal immigration law to permit complaints alleging employment of unauthorized aliens to be registered in person or by toll-free telephone number. Authorizes the Attorney General to seek judicial review if adversely affected by a final order regarding an assessment for employment of unauthorized aliens. Title II: Improving the Employment Verification System - Restricts the authority of the Attorney General to expand the list of acceptable employment verification documents. Transfers from the President to the Attorney General responsibility for monitoring and evaluating the employment verification system. Directs the Attorney General to report to the Congress on the consolidation into a single tamper-resistant document of documentation evidencing temporary work authorization. Title III: Additional Penalties and Increases in Penalties - Declares alien employment without authorization unlawful and establishes civil penalties. Precludes aliens engaged in unlawful employment from eligibility for adjustment of immigration status. Increases the civil and criminal penalties for: (1) employment of unauthorized aliens; and (2) document fraud.

	</summary>
</bill>
