<bill session="103" type="h" number="3366" updated="2010-04-19T07:55:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Endangerment and Abuse Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide penalties for child endangerment and abuse in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408364"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400084" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="409650" joined="1993-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400569" joined="1993-11-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1993-11-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1993-10-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Criminal negligence"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/26/1993--Introduced.
Child Endangerment and Abuse Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prescribe the following penalties to be imposed against anyone who, in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, inflicts, or having the care or custody of a minor, permits another to inflict, any physical injury upon a minor: (1) if the injury is a serious physical injury and the conduct required for the offense is committed intentionally or knowingly, a fine and up to 20 years' imprisonment, if committed recklessly, a fine and up to ten years' imprisonment, or if committed with criminal negligence, a fine and up to five years' imprisonment; and (2) if the injury is other than a serious physical injury and the conduct required for the offense is committed intentionally or knowingly, a fine and up to one year's imprisonment, if committed recklessly, a fine and up to six months' imprisonment, or if committed with criminal negligence, a fine and up to three months' imprisonment.

	</summary>
</bill>
