<bill session="103" type="h" number="3385" updated="2010-04-19T07:58:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Counterfeiting Deterrence Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the integrity of the Nation's financial system from international counterfeiting and economic terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400236"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404634" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1993-10-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8540-8541)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-06"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-06"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-16"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Export credit"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International banking"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="International finance"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Money"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/27/1993--Introduced.
International Counterfeiting Deterrence Act of 1993 - Establishes the International Counterfeiting Deterrence Strike Force, chaired by the Secretary of the Treasury, to study: (1) means for international coordination and cooperation to combat counterfeiting, including international agreements; (2) available technological devices and methods to enhance detection and enforcement; and (3) the usage of U.S. currency overseas and the correlation of such uses with counterfeiting. Establishes the Currency Design Commission and empowers it to redesign U.S. currency for counterfeit deterrence purposes. Charges the Director of the U.S. Secret Service with establishing a team of experts to assist and provide training to foreign government entities with respect to counterfeit detection, investigation, and prosecution activities. Directs the Chairperson of the Strike Force to: (1) seek to enter into negotiations with officials of foreign countries in which a significant amount of U.S. currency is counterfeited; and (2) report to certain congressional committees. Cites circumstances under which the President may proscribe any transfer of funds between persons in the United States and those of a foreign country in which significant amounts of U.S. currency is counterfeited. Amends Federal criminal law to establish penalties, including imprisonment, for counterfeiting U.S. currency abroad. Directs the Strike Force to recommend to the President and the Congress sanctions against State-supported counterfeiting. Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the Export-Import Bank from engaging in any credit activity with a country determined by the President to be involved in State-supported counterfeiting. Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979 to set license requirements for countries involved in State-supported counterfeiting. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit Federal assistance to a country determined by the President to be involved in State-supported counterfeiting.

	</summary>
</bill>
