<bill session="103" type="h" number="3393" updated="2010-04-19T07:59:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Deficit Reduction Franking Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the provisions of title 39, United States Code, relating to the franking privilege for Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400390"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405939" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="401547" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="409650" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400526" joined="1994-09-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8513, E2568-2569)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Congressional allowances"/>
		<term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Small towns"/>
		<term name="Sparsely populated areas"/>
		<term name="Voter registration"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/27/1993--Introduced.
Deficit Reduction Franking Act - Revises prohibitions on franked mass mailings by Members of Congress. Permits a Member to mail a franked mass mailing only if it is: (1) in direct response to communication from a person to whom the matter is mailed; (2) a follow-up to such mailing; (3) sent to other Members of Congress or to Federal, State, or local government officials; (4) a news release to the communications media; or (5) related solely to a notice of appearance or a scheduled itinerary of the Member or Member-elect and is sent solely to residents of towns or villages in his or her congressional district with populations under 1,000 and without a daily newspaper published within 50 miles (limits such mass mailings to three during any Congress). Repeals Federal law that makes frankable mail matter which consists of voter registration, election information, or assistance prepared and mailed in a nonpartisan manner. Requires any amount remaining in an official allowance of a Member of the House of Representatives at the end of the session of the Congress or other period for which the allowance is made available to be returned to the Treasury for deficit reduction.

	</summary>
</bill>
