<bill session="103" type="h" number="3399" updated="2010-04-19T08:00:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Response and Recovery Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the ability of the Federal Government to prepare for and respond to major disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400542"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1994-03-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-12"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-06" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Disasters"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Civil defense"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Emblems"/>
		<term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical services"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fire prevention"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="Interstate compacts"/>
		<term name="Inventories"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="National Guard"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Regional planning"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/28/1993--Introduced.
Disaster Response and Recovery Act of 1993 - Amends The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (Disaster Act) and other specified Federal law to establish a new framework for governing the Federal Government's and State and local governments' preparedness for, response to, and recovery from, major disasters, emergencies, and terrorist attacks and coordination among such entities (including private relief agencies) in responding to such events through a reorganization of operations of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). (Sec.) Defines &quot;catastrophic disaster.&quot; (Sec. 4) Transfers to the FEMA Director certain authority granted to the President under the Disaster Act, such as the authority to make grants to States for disaster preparedness, hazard mitigation, and assistance for individuals and families adversely affected by a major disaster. Imposes new duties on FEMA under the Disaster Act, such as: (1) developing plans for providing Federal assistance, when requested, to affected States and establishing chains of command, Federal agency duties, and the relationship between them and those of the State and local governments and private relief agencies involved; (2) establishing respective systems for utilizing volunteers and managing donated goods in disasters and emergencies as well as disaster suport teams for use in areas where a major disaster or emergency is likely to be declared or has been declared; (3) issuing performance standards for ensuring State preparedness for major disasters and emergencies; (4) reviewing such State preparedness annually as well as the role of fire services in responding to such events; (5) inventorying resources available regionally to the Federal Government for post-disaster and -emergency use; and (6) ensuring that such regional inventories are made available to the Governor of each State in the region. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary of Defense to direct the Chief of the National Guard Bureau to review the role of the National Guard in responding to major disasters and emergencies and develop an interstate compact for the mutual use of National Guard assets across State borders during major disasters and emergencies. (Sec. 8) Repeals the limitation on the use of sliding scales. (Sec. 14) Requires that the Director of FEMA have appropriate experience in order to be appointed. Redesignates FEMA Regional Director positions as career reserved positions. Requires various specified positions to be subject to presidential appointment without Senate confirmation. (Sec. 15) Revises the Federal Civil Defense Act of 1950 to abolish the Federal Civil Defense Adminstration and vest in FEMA the Federal Government's responsibility for the civil defense of the United States (which includes Federal disaster preparedness, response, and recovery activities with respect to major and catastrophic disasters and emergencies). Grants FEMA the authority to delegate civil defense responsibilities to the the appropriate Federal departments and agencies, and review and coordinate the civil defense activities of such entities with each other and with the activities of the States and neighboring countries.

	</summary>
</bill>
