<bill session="103" type="h" number="3406" updated="2010-04-19T08:01:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to clarify the scope of the Gun-Free School Zones Act of 1990 and to prohibit the possession of a handgun or handgun ammunition by, or the private transfer of a handgun or handgun ammunition to, a juvenile.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405507"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-16"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.3098.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3098" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="School violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/28/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Gun-Free School Zones Act of 1990 to prohibit knowingly possessing a firearm which has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce (currently, a firearm) at a place that the individual knows, or has reasonable cause to believe, is a school zone. Prohibits the sale, delivery, or transfer to a juvenile of a handgun or ammunition suitable for use only in a handgun, except: (1) with the permission of a parent or legal guardian; (2) for target practice, hunting, or a course of instruction in the safe use of a handgun under the supervision of an adult who is not prohibited by Federal, State, or local law from possessing a firearm; and (3) in accordance with State and local law. Prohibits a juvenile from possessing a handgun or ammunition that is suitable for use only in a handgun, except during such activities and in accordance with State and local law. Sets penalties for violations of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
