<bill session="103" type="h" number="3410" updated="2010-04-19T08:02:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dairy Promotion Program Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Dairy Production Stabilization Act of 1983 to ensure that all persons who benefit from the dairy promotion and research program contribute to the cost of the program, to terminate the program on December 31, 1996, and to prohibit bloc voting by cooperative associations of milk producers in connection with the program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400300"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-02"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAG-03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural research"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Dairy industry"/>
		<term name="Dairy products"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
		<term name="Milk"/>
		<term name="Referendum"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/28/1993--Introduced.
Dairy Promotion Program Improvement Act of 1993 - Amends the Dairy Production Stabilization Act of 1983 to increase the membership of the National Dairy Promotion and Research Board (the Board) by two members who shall be representatives of dairy product importers. Requires dairy product importers to pay an assessment to the Board. Prescribes guidelines under which the Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a referendum in connection with this Act. Sets a termination date for the assessment orders for dairy product importers. Prohibits the Secretary, when required to determine the approval or disapproval of individual producers, from considering the bloc-voted approval or disapproval of any cooperative association of producers.

	</summary>
</bill>
