<bill session="103" type="h" number="341" updated="2010-04-18T23:52:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sweatshops Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase the penalties for employers who violate such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Child labor"/>
		<term name="Clothing industry"/>
		<term name="Clothing workers"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Construction workers"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Home labor"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Wage restitution"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Sweatshops Prevention Act of 1993 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA) to increase the civil and criminal penalties (and liability for settlements) for employers who violate standards for minimum wages, overtime, and child labor. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to seize garments, up to the value of the employer's liability under the FLSA, from the premises of a garment manufacturer employer who has violated any such standards more than two times in a three-year period. Authorizes seizures of all garments produced by homeworkers in violation of the FLSA (or up to the employer's liability if the employer has obtained a certificate to employ such homeworkers but has violated its terms). Sets forth procedural requirements. Amends the Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 to extend the statute of limitations on actions to enforce unpaid minimum wages, unpaid overtime compensation, or liquidated damages under the FLSA, Walsh-Healey Act, or Davis-Bacon Act. Directs the Secretary to establish and encourage closer working relationships among Federal and State agencies responsible for enforcing labor, safety and health, and immigration laws.

	</summary>
</bill>
