<bill session="103" type="h" number="3413" updated="2010-04-19T08:02:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Savings Plan Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction for contributions to a medical savings account, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300085"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405939" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400398" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-11-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400104" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="1994-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400504" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400205" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400590" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400604" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="404068" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400012" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="405033" joined="1993-10-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Catastrophic health insurance"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Dental care"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/28/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Medical Savings Accounts Title II: Development and Distribution of Comparative Value Information Health Care Savings Plan Act of 1993 - Title I: Medical Savings Account - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individuals a tax deduction for contributions made to a medical care savings account established for the benefit of an eligible individual. Defines an eligible individual as: (1) one who is not covered by an employer-provided group health plan; or (2) one who is covered by such a plan which is a qualified catastrophic coverage health plan and is not covered by any other health plan. Allows penalty-free withdrawals from such accounts to the extent that amounts in such accounts exceed $15,000. Allows such deduction in arriving at adjusted gross income. Excludes employer contributions to such accounts from employment taxes. Establishes an excise tax for excess contributions to medical care savings accounts and makes such accounts subject to the tax on prohibited transactions. Allows the transfer of unused amounts in flexible spending accounts of cafeteria plans to medical savings accounts. Allows the full deduction for medical and dental expenses for amounts paid for qualified catastrophic coverage health plans. Title II: Development and Distribution of Comparative Value Information - Requires each State to develop and implement information programs regarding comparative health values for purchasers of health care. Makes grants available for the development of such programs. Requires Federal implementation of a program for any State that does not develop or continue to implement such a program. Requires the dissemination of comparative value information relative to Federal programs of health insurance and health care services. Requires the development of model systems to facilitate the gathering and analyzing of data on health care cost, quality, and outcome with respect to health insurance plans and hospitals. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
