<bill session="103" type="h" number="3432" updated="2010-04-19T08:05:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Telephone Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the disclosure of certain information concerning customer's uses of telephone services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400253"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410589" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="406482" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="401947" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="1993-11-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2745-2746)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer complaints"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/3/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Privacy of Customer Proprietary Network Information Title II: Privacy of Calling Party Information Title III: Access to Telephone Records Title IV: Privacy of Subscriber Information Telephone Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 1993 - Title I: Privacy of Customer Proprietary Network Information - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) to prohibit a local exchange carrier (LEC), except upon the customer's request, from: (1) using customer proprietary network information (CPNI) in the provision of any service other than telephone exchange or toll service, in the identification of solicitation of potential customers for any service other than the service from which such information is derived, or in the provision of customer premises equipment; or (2) disclosing such information to any affiliate of, or any other person that is not an employee of, such common carrier. Requires the common carrier to: (1) disclose such information to any customer designee at the customer's request; (2) notify the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) of the availability of aggregate customer proprietary information it provides or to any other person that is not an employee or affiliate of such carrier or to its personnel (any) that are engaged in providing any service that is not necessary to the provision of telephone exchange service or customer premises equipment; and (3) provide such aggregate information on reasonable terms and conditions to any other service or equipment provider, upon reasonable request. Prohibits the common carrier from discriminating between affiliated and unaffiliated service or equipment providers in providing individual and aggregate or compiled information. States that this Act shall not be construed to prohibit the disclosure of CPNI as necessary to render, bill, and collect for telephone exchange or toll service or for any other telecommunications service that the customer has requested. Requires an LEC that provides subscriber list information to any affiliated or unaffiliated service provider or person to provide such list on a timely and unbundled basis, under nondiscriminatory and reasonable rates, terms, and conditions, to any person upon reasonable request. Title II: Privacy of Calling Party Information - Amends the Act to require the FCC to prescribe regulations: (1) requiring any caller identification service offered through a common carrier to allow the caller to withhold the display of the caller's identity to the individual receiving the call; (2) prohibiting any charges for such service; and (3) requiring every common carrier to notify subscribers that their calls may be identified to a called party. Requires any common carrier or affiliate providing automatic number identification (ANI) services to any person to provide such services under a contract or tariff containing telephone subscriber information requirements that: (1) permit such person to use the information provided for billing and collection, completion of the customer's call or transaction, or for services directly related to the customer's call or transaction; (2) prohibit such person from reusing or selling the information provided without the customer's consent; and (3) prohibit such person from disclosing, without the customer's consent, any information derived from such service or from the analysis of the characteristics of a telecommunications transmission for any purpose other than performing the services or transactions that are the subject of the customer's call, ensuring network performance, security, and the effectiveness of call delivery, compiling, using, and disclosing aggregate information, and complying with applicable law or legal process. States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent a common carrier from offering services enabling a telephone subscriber receiving a call to block the call where the caller has chosen to withhold display of the caller's identity. Title III: Access to Telephone Records - Amends the Act to require a common carrier that, pursuant to a subpoena or on demand of other lawful authority, divulges a subscriber's billing information or other information about any interstate or foreign communication by wire or radio, to inform such subscriber within ten days of the identity of the recipient, unless prohibited from doing so by the lawful authority. Title IV: Privacy of Subscriber Information - Requires the FCC to commence a proceeding to: (1) examine the impact on the privacy rights and remedies of consumers of the integration into interconnected communications networks of wireless telephone, cable, satellite, and other technologies; (2) examine the impact that the globalization of such integrated communications networks has on the international dissemination of consumer information and the privacy rights and remedies to protect consumers; (3) propose changes in the FCC's regulations to ensure that consumer privacy rights are protected in new telecommunications services; and (4) prepare recommendations to the Congress for any legislative changes required to correct defects in privacy rights and remedies.

	</summary>
</bill>
