<bill session="103" type="h" number="3431" updated="2010-04-19T08:05:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Computer and Communications Trade Freedom Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 with respect to export of computers, telecommunications equipment, and semiconductors.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400252"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1994-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="409423" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400083" joined="1993-11-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400256" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1993-11-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2769-2770)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-17"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Computer software"/>
		<term name="Computers"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Semiconductors"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
		<term name="Trading with the enemy"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/3/1993--Introduced.
Computer and Communications Trade Freedom Act - Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979 to declare that no validated license or reexport authorization may be required for the export or reexport for the consumption or use in any country (other than a targeted country) of currently controlled computers, telecommunications equipment, and semiconductors (unless they are subject to missile technology controls). Prohibits the United States from: (1) proposing to the Coordinating Committee (COCOM) the transfer of such items from the Industrial List of the COCOM to the International Munitions Lists of the COCOM; or (2) agreeing to any proposal for such transfer. Prohibits the control on the export or reexport of such items under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, the Trading with the Enemy Act, or any other law that would control such exports. Declares that nothing in this Act shall prohibit the Secretary of Commerce from requiring a validated license for exports to: (1) a country against which the United States maintains an embargo; or (2) a party lawfully denied export privileges under this Act. Directs the President to negotiate with COCOM and other relevant multilateral export control regimes to attain agreement on applying export controls consistent with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
