<bill session="103" type="h" number="3482" updated="2010-04-19T08:13:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Safety and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a system for regulating the possession and transfer of handguns and handgun ammunition, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400350"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409154" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1993-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="402626" joined="1993-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1993-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-11-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-16"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/9/1993--Introduced.
Public Safety and Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the possession or transfer of a handgun or handgun ammunition, with exceptions, including: (1) transfers among members of a licensed handgun club, an authorized security guard service, and specified others licensed under the code; and (2) possession by members of a licensed handgun club on the premises of the club, by an individual authorized by a State to provide security services and employed as a security guard within the scope of employment, and by an individual certified or commissioned as a police officer under Federal, State, or local law at any location within the scope of the certification or commission. Makes such prohibition inapplicable to the United States or any department or agency thereof, or to any State or any department, agency, or political subdivision thereof. Sets forth: (1) requirements for the licensing of handgun clubs, recordkeeping, and the inspection of the premises of such clubs, and theft and loss reporting requirements; and (2) penalties for violations, including seizure and forfeiture of handguns or handgun ammunition. Repeals: (1) prohibitions against recording firearms records at, or transferring such records to, a public facility and against establishing a system for the registration of firearms, firearms owners, or firearms dispositions; and (2) limitations on recordkeeping for dealers selling firearms from personal collections. Permits the Secretary of the Treasury to revoke a firearms license if the holder of such license has violated (currently, willfully violated) specified provisions of the Federal criminal code. Increases firearms dealer license fees. Provides for annual expiration of dealers' licenses. Requires such dealers to have obtained any license, permit, or other document required under State or local law to engage in such a business as a condition of obtaining a Federal license to deal in firearms. Prohibits dealing in firearms from a private residence, unless specified conditions are met. Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations requiring the secure storage of firearms by licensed dealers. Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to include firearms within the definition of &quot;consumer product.&quot;

	</summary>
</bill>
