<bill session="103" type="h" number="3487" updated="2010-04-19T08:14:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Procedural Improvements Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to improve review procedures (particularly those involved in the disability determination process) under the OASDI, SSI, and medicare programs by making such procedures more cost-effective and by providing greater equity and efficiency for claimants and beneficiaries.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400567"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2840)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-20"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Appellate procedure"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Civil service retirement"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Court records"/>
		<term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Improvements in Administrative Determination of Disability Entitlements Title II: Establishment of Social Security Court and Abolition of Appeals Council Social Security Procedural Improvements Act of 1993 - Title I: Improvements in Administrative Determinations of Disability Entitlements - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to make the Secretary of Health and Human Services' decision to assume a State's disability determination function discretionary. Authorizes the Secretary to implement a plan for assuming the disability determination function of a State when it notifies the Secretary that it no longer wishes to perform the function. (Sec. 102) Converts to employment with the Department of Health and Human Services State employees whose disability determination function is assumed by the Secretary. (Sec. 103) Eliminates survivor benefits which are payable solely on the basis of &quot;currently insured&quot; status. (Sec. 104) Requires a report to the Congress by the Secretary regarding certain demonstration projects piloting case management techniques in the SSA title II program. Title II: Establishment of Social Security Court and Abolition of Appeals Council - Establishes the Social Security Court (Court) which shall have exclusive jurisdiction over actions arising under SSA titles II, XVI (Supplemental Security Income), and XVIII (Medicare). Authorizes any individual who was a party to a hearing to which the Secretary has rendered a final decision to bring a timely action for Court review of the decision. Authorizes the Court to affirm, modify, or reverse the decision, but restricts its authority to reconsider factual findings. (Sec. 202) Amends SSA title VII (Administration) to provide for the President's appointment of judges to the Court. Authorizes the chief judge to divide the Court into divisions so that claimants have an opportunity to appear before the Court anywhere within the country. Provides that within 60 days of a division's decision such decision shall become final unless, within that period, a party petitions for review. Gives the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit exclusive jurisdiction to review Court decisions upon an appeal, but prohibits an appeal until the Court has reviewed or denied a petition for review. (Sec. 203) Abolishes the Department's Appeals Council without limiting the Secretary's authority to hold hearings and conduct investigations.

	</summary>
</bill>
