<bill session="103" type="h" number="3491" updated="2010-04-19T08:14:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FECA Fraud Deterrence Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Employees' Compensation Act, and title 18 of the United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1993-11-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400161" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400239" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400192" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404869" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400586" joined="1993-11-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400569" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="405033" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1994-08-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2857)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-16"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Workers' compensation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Introduced.
FECA Fraud Deterrence Act - Amends the Federal Employees' Compensation Act to provide that an individual convicted of making a false statement to obtain Federal employees' compensation or of other fraud related to the application for or receipt of benefits shall forfeit entitlement to benefits for any injury occurring before conviction. Specifies that no benefits shall be provided to any individual confined in a correctional facility pursuant to that individual's conviction of a felony offense, except that the Secretary of Labor may pay a specified percentage of the benefits to such individual's dependents. Requires a Federal, State, or local agency to make the name and social security account number of any individual who is confined in a correctional facility under the agency's jurisdiction pursuant to the individual's conviction of felony offense available to the Secretary upon request to carry out provisions of the Act. Revises provisions of the Federal criminal code to provide that whoever knowingly and willfully falsifies, conceals, or covers up a material fact or makes or knowingly uses a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation in connection with the application for or receipt of Federal employees' compensation shall be guilty of a felony punishable by a fine of up to $250,000 and/or up to five years' imprisonment.

	</summary>
</bill>
