<bill session="103" type="h" number="3503" updated="2010-04-19T08:16:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Peacekeeping Policy Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish limitations on the use of funds for international peacekeeping activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2889-2890)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-27"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Operations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Intelligence activities"/>
		<term name="Intelligence services"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="Military command and control"/>
		<term name="Military intervention"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="Peace"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Prisoners of war"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="United Nations finances"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Introduced.
International Peacekeeping Policy Act of 1993 - Prohibits funds appropriated to the Department of State Contributions for International Peacekeeping Account or funds appropriated to pay for contributions for United Nations peacekeeping activities from being available to the United Nations for the establishment, expansion, or modification in mission of a United Nations peacekeeping operation unless the President makes the certification required by this Act. Directs the President to certify that the peacekeeping operation meets the following policy guidelines: (1) the operation involves an international conflict in which hostilities have ceased and all significant parties to the conflict agree to the imposition of United Nations forces to seek a solution to the conflict; (2) the Congress was notified of the intent to support the operation under specified reprogramming procedures at least 15 days before approval of the operation by the United Nations Security Council; (3) the percentage of the U.S.-assessed share of the operation is no greater than the percentage assessment for the regular United Nations budget; (4) no U.S. intelligence information involving sensitive sources and methods of intelligence gathering will be provided to support the operation; and (5) with respect to units of the armed forces trained to carry out direct combat missions, the operation advances U.S. national security interests, the units are critical to the success of the operation and will be under the command of the United States, and any armed forces member would be protected by the Geneva Convention Relative to the Treatment of Prisoners of War.

	</summary>
</bill>
