<bill session="103" type="h" number="3534" updated="2010-04-19T08:21:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Equipment and Technology Export Control Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 with respect to export controls on computers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403776"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1994-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400083" joined="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="410887" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400537" joined="1994-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-06"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Biological weapons"/>
		<term name="Chemical weapons"/>
		<term name="Computer software"/>
		<term name="Computers"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Supercomputers"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Weapons systems"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/18/1993--Introduced.
Computer Equipment and Technology Export Control Reform Act - Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) conduct annual reviews of export controls on computer equipment and technology; (2) increase certain export control thresholds if warranted by the review; and (3) report review findings to the Congress and the Computer Systems Technical Advisory Committee. Exempts from license requirements for export or reexport to any controlled country digital computers valued at less than $5,000. Directs the Secretary to: (1) identify specified items that will be installed for end-use outside the United States; and (2) publish in the Federal Register the name and specified license requirements for exports to a proliferation end-user (any entity engaged in the design, development, or production of nuclear, chemical, or biological weapons or missiles which is located in a country that is not party to an agreement, to which the United States is a party, to limit the spread of such weapons and activities). Prohibits the Secretary from requiring a license applicant to supply information about proliferation-related activities of an end-user, as a condition of granting a license for export of goods or technology to such end-user, unless the Secretary has: (1) identified the end-user's country as engaged in proliferation activities; or (2) determined there is a specific risk that the exports will be diverted to a country for use in such activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
