<bill session="103" type="h" number="3545" updated="2010-04-19T08:23:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Counsel Accountability and Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the independent counsel statute, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400192"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400596" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407676" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400156" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="406768" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400161" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400104" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407899" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400534" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="406863" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="411247" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="408553" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400544" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1994-02-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3034-3035)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-30"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Ethics"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Government attorneys"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Local officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Removal of officials"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Special prosecutors"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Subpoena"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
Independent Counsel Accountability and Reform Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal judicial code to reauthorize the independent counsel statute (the Act). Makes the Act applicable to Members of Congress. Revises the Act to: (1) require specific information from a credible source sufficient to constitute grounds to investigate whether a person covered by the Act has violated specified Federal criminal laws; and (2) permit the Attorney General to issue subpoenas. Requires the division of the court that appoints an independent counsel to: (1) define with specificity the independent counsel's prosecutorial jurisdiction; (2) assure that the independent counsel has adequate authority to fully investigate and prosecute the alleged violations of criminal law with respect to which the Attorney General has requested the appointment and matters directly related to such criminal violations; and (3) strongly consider appointing independent counsel prosecutors from State or local governments. Revises provisions regarding compensation of staff of an independent counsel. Directs the independent counsel, to the greatest extent possible, to use personnel of the Department of Justice (DOJ) on a reimbursable basis in lieu of appointing employees. Directs (currently, authorizes) the division to award reimbursement for attorney's fees upon the request of an individual who is the subject of an investigation conducted by an independent counsel if no indictment is brought against such individual pursuant to that investigation (as under current law), if such individual is acquitted of all charges, if no conviction is obtained against such individual, or if the conviction of such individual is overturned on appeal. Establishes or revises provisions regarding: (1) treatment of classified information by, per diem expenses of, administrative support for, compliance with DOJ policies by, limitations on expenditures of, periodic reports on activities of, and the removal, termination, and periodic reappointment of, an independent counsel; and (2) job protections for individuals under investigation. Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to report to the Congress with recommendations of ways to improve controls on costs of offices of independent counsel.

	</summary>
</bill>
