<bill session="103" type="h" number="3557" updated="2010-04-19T08:25:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Criminal Records Identification Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the establishment of a Federal system for the purpose of conducting background checks to prevent the employment of child abusers by child care providers, to establish a Federal point-of-purchase background check system for screening prohibited firearms purchasers, to provide accurate and immediately accessible records for law enforcement purposes, to assist in the identification and apprehension of violent felons, and to assist the courts in determining appropriate bail and sentencing decisions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404296"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-16"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="891" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Child molesting"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Criminal statistics"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
Federal Criminal Records Identification Act of 1993 - Provides for the establishment by each State of an instant criminal check system for handgun purchases. Sets forth requirements with respect to: (1) the privacy and security of the information contained in the system; (2) prohibited uses of such information; (3) identification procedures, once such a system is operational; and (4) penalties for noncompliance. Provides for the establishment by each State of a criminal history system. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) assuring the accuracy of responses; (2) notification of the existence and purpose of the system; (3) operation of the system; and (4) correction of, and remedies for disseminating, erroneous information. Establishes a Federal criminal background check system to which a designated agency in each State is required to report child abuse crime information for purposes of background checks of child care providers. Directs the Attorney General to establish guidelines for the reporting of such information. Requires the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to begin a study to determine various factors relating to potential child abuse crimes and offenders. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) expedite the incorporation of the remaining State criminal history records into the Federal criminal records systems maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the development of hardware and software systems to link State criminal history check systems into the National Crime Information Center; and (2) take specified other steps to improve access to State criminal records. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to permit the use of funds under formula grants for the improvement of State record systems and the sharing of certain records with the Attorney General. Authorizes additional funding for such purposes. Amends the Federal criminal code to increase the special assessment on persons convicted of offenses against the United States, with a portion of each assessment to be used for purposes of carrying out this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
