<bill session="103" type="h" number="3561" updated="2010-04-19T08:25:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mickey Leland Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention and Parenthood Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize adolescent family life demonstration projects, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1994-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1994-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400161" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="406284" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1994-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400502" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1994-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407817" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="405524" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="1994-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400516" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1994-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1994-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2982)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Abortion"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Health counseling"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
Mickey Leland Adolescent Pregnancy Prevention and Parenthood Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to replace the title on adolescent family life demonstration projects with a title on adolescent pregnancy prevention, care, and research grants. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to provide, supplement, or improve the quality of prevention and care services to pregnant adolescents and their male partners, adolescent parents, and nonpregnant adolescents. Requires grantees to charge fees for services only under a fee schedule, approved by the Secretary, based on the income of the person and taking into account the difficulty adolescents face in obtaining resources to pay for services. Prohibits discrimination because of an individual's inability to pay for services. Sets forth priorities in making grants, including giving priority to applicants that: (1) serve an area with a high incidence of adolescent pregnancy; and (2) serve an area with a high proportion of low-income families and low availability of care programs. Directs the Secretary to coordinate Federal policies and programs providing services relating to the prevention of initial and recurrent adolescent pregnancies and providing care services, including by requiring grantees under these provisions to report concerning Federal, State, and local policies that interfere with delivery and coordination of programs of care for pregnant adolescents and adolescent parents. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to institutions of higher education to support and disseminate the results of research relating to adolescent pregnancy. Limits grants or contracts to: (1) one year, subject to renewal for four additional one-year periods; and (2) subject to waiver, a specified dollar amount. Directs the Secretary to establish a system for the review of grant and contract applications which is similar to the system of scientific peer review of the National Institutes of Health. Allows grants only to programs determined by the review panel to have scientific merit. Authorizes appropriations. Prohibits using grant funds for the performance of an abortion.

	</summary>
</bill>
