<bill session="103" type="h" number="3565" updated="2010-04-19T08:26:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Trade in Services Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide regulatory incentives to promote national treatment by foreign countries to United States providers of certain financial and communications services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400253"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2981)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-20"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-20"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Brokers"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Corporate mergers"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Financial services"/>
		<term name="Foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="International finance"/>
		<term name="Investment advisers"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
		<term name="Reciprocity"/>
		<term name="Securities industry"/>
		<term name="Securities regulation"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Financial Services Title II: Telecommunications Products and Services Fair Trade in Services Act of 1993 - Title I: Financial Services - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) submit biennial status reports to the Congress regarding foreign treatment of certain U.S. business interests; and (2) initiate negotiations with foreign countries to ensure that they offer U.S. securities brokers and dealers and investment advisers the same competitive opportunities as are available to their foreign counterparts. Authorizes Federal securities agencies to deny applications filed by foreign persons to conduct securities or investment advice activities in the United States if the Secretary has published a determination in the Federal Register that the relevant foreign country does not accord national treatment to such U.S. business interests. Directs the Secretary to review such determination annually. Provides that subsequent to the Secretary's determination in the Federal Register that a foreign country does not accord national treatment to U.S. securities or investment adviser interests, a person from such foreign country may not acquire control of a registered broker, dealer, or investment adviser unless the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has been duly notified and has not prohibited such acquisition. Directs the SEC to conduct an investigation to determine the extent of interdependence of U.S. financial services sectors and foreign countries and the economic, strategic, and other consequences of that interdependence for the United States. Directs the SEC to report the results of this investigation within two years to the President, the Congress, and the Secretary. Title II: Telecommunications Products and Services - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the United States Trade Representative to publish a notice in the Federal Register identifying any foreign country that has failed to reach a telecommunications trade agreement with the United States or has violated an existing agreement. Directs the Federal Communications Commission to deny applications filed by such countries. Directs the U.S. Trade Representative to review annually notices in the Federal Register regarding non-complying countries. Directs the FCC to consider, when making a determination of public convenience and necessity with respect to foreign applicants for line extensions, whether the countries identified in the application (including the country that is the applicant's principal place of business) offer equivalent or comparable telecommunications services opportunities to U.S. applicants. Authorizes the FCC to find that granting the application is not in the public interest if such countries do not provide equivalent or comparable opportunities to U.S. applicants.

	</summary>
</bill>
