<bill session="103" type="h" number="3566" updated="2010-04-19T08:26:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Campaign Finance Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 and related laws to establish incentives to limit the cost of campaigns for the Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400269"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><committee name="House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postal Operations and Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-20"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" subcommittee="Postal Operations and Services" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Broadcast journalism"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Computers"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional candidates"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional publications"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Deaf"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Equal time rule"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Fund raising"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
		<term name="Political advertising"/>
		<term name="Political conventions"/>
		<term name="Political parties"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Primaries"/>
		<term name="Radio in politics"/>
		<term name="Special elections"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Television in politics"/>
		<term name="Voter registration"/>
		<term name="Voting"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Expenditure Limitations, Contribution Limitations, Matching Funds, and Reduced Third-Class Mail Rate for Eligible House of Representatives Candidates Title II: Elimination of Multicandidate Political Committee Contributions in House of Representatives Elections; Miscellaneous Provisions Relating to Contributions Under the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 Title III: Requirement of Budget Neutrality Title IV: Independent Expenditures Title V: Contributions Through Intermediaries and Conduits; Provisions Relating to Political Party Committees Title VI: Prohibitions Relating to Political Committees and Foreign Nationals Title VII: Limitation on Carryover of Campaign Funds Title VIII: Campaign Advertising Title IX: Contribution Solicitation Title X: Reporting Requirements Title XI: Effective Date Comprehensive Campaign Finance Reform Act - Title I: Expenditure Limitations, Contribution Limitations, Matching Funds, and Reduced Third-Class Mail Rate for Eligible House of Representatives Candidates - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to set forth limitations regarding House of Representatives (House) election expenditures, contributions, and matching funds. Limits aggregate expenditures made by an eligible House of Representatives candidate in an election cycle to $500,000, with specified limitations in primary, special, and runoff elections. Sets forth graduated civil penalties for excess expenditures and contributions. Establishes the Make Democracy Work Fund (the Fund) for payment of matching funds and initial expenditures incurred by the Federal Election Commission (FEC) in the administration of this Act. Outlines FEC examination, audit, and repayment procedures. Subjects FEC actions to judicial review. Precludes a House candidate from receiving Fund assistance without prior certification that any television commercial prepared or distributed by the candidate permits closed captioning. Amends Federal Postal Service law to provide reduced third-class mailing rates to eligible House of Representatives candidates during a general election period. Title II: Elimination of Multicandidate Political Committee Contributions in House of Representatives Elections; Miscellaneous Provisions Relating to Contributions Under the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 - Amends FECA to prohibit a House candidate from accepting any multicandidate political committee (PAC) contributions. (Sec. 202) Treats contributions by dependents not of voting age as contributions of the persons upon whom they are dependent. (Sec. 203) Aggregates, for contribution limit purposes, contributions from State and local party committees with all contributions from such political party. (Sec. 204) Excludes from the meaning of &quot;contribution&quot; certain reimbursed campaign expenses voluntarily paid for by a campaign worker as an advance to the campaign. (Sec. 205) Reduces the maximum Federal election contribution permitted to be made by a person other than a PAC. Title III: Requirement of Budget Neutrality - Provides that the net costs of providing certain benefits under this Act must be fully offset by specified measures that either raise revenues or reduce spending by a specified deadline (thus achieving budget neutrality). Title IV: Independent Expenditures - Sets forth reporting requirements for certain independent expenditures. Title V: Contributions Through Intermediaries and Conduits; Provisions Relating to Political Party Committees - Amends FECA to delineate circumstances where a person's contribution shall be considered as being made through an intermediary or a conduit (and therefore treated as contributions from such person). (Sec. 502) Defines &quot;State Party Grassroots Fund.&quot; (Sec. 503) Subjects national, State, and local party committees to &quot;soft money&quot; limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements. (Sec. 504) Prohibits Federal office holders or candidates from soliciting contributions from tax-exempt organizations significantly involved in voter registration or get-out-the-vote campaigns. Title VI: Prohibitions Relating to Political Committees and Foreign Nationals - Prohibits the use of leadership committees and establishes a deadline for their disbursement of funds. Prohibits an unauthorized political committee from using the name of any candidate in any fundraising activity on its behalf in a context which suggests that the committee is the candidate's authorized committee. (Sec. 602) Prohibits a foreign national from controlling, influencing, or participating in election-related activities, including making contributions or expenditures. Title VII: Limitation on Carryover of Campaign Funds - Amends FECA to limit the carryover of surplus House campaign funds for a subsequent election. Title VIII: Campaign Advertising - Amends FECA to prescribe guidelines for print and broadcast campaign advertising. (Sec. 802) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require equal candidate broadcasting time. (Sec. 803) Revises broadcast rate determinations. Prohibits licensee preemption of a candidate's broadcast time except in an emergency. Title IX: Contribution Solicitation - Amends FECA to prohibit the solicitation of contributions by false representation by any person as a candidate or as a representative of a candidate or of a political party or committee. Title X: Reporting Requirements - Amends FECA to require certain reports to identify any person (other than a committee) who contributes more than $50 (currently, more than $200). Directs the FEC to: (1) require that operating expenditures be reported on an election cycle basis, by category; and (2) maintain computerized indices of contributions of $50 or more. Title XI: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
