<bill session="103" type="h" number="3575" updated="2010-04-19T08:28:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Animal Enterprise Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide more complete protection to animal enterprises and the people associated with them.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400389"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-30"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Aquariums"/>
		<term name="Assault"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Exhibitions"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Laboratory animals"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Livestock"/>
		<term name="Protection of animals"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Zoos"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
Animal Enterprise Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit and set penalties for intentionally: (1) injuring, intimidating, or interfering with any person by force, threat of force, or physical obstruction because that person is engaging in activities in an animal enterprise; or (2) damaging or destroying the property of a facility because that facility is in part or in whole such an enterprise. Defines &quot;animal enterprise&quot; as a commercial or academic enterprise that uses animals for food or fiber production, agriculture, research, or testing; a zoo, aquarium, circus, rodeo, or lawful competitive animal event; or any fair or similar event intended to advance agriculture. Provides for civil actions by aggrieved persons, the U.S. Attorney General, and State attorneys general. Specifies that the Congress does not intend this Act to provide exclusive remedies with respect to the conduct prohibited by it, nor to preempt the legislation of States that may provide such remedies.

	</summary>
</bill>
