<bill session="103" type="h" number="3582" updated="2010-04-19T08:29:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to improve and expand the school lunch and related programs under those Acts.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Abandonment of family"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Boarder babies"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child nutrition"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Day care centers for the aged"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Food relief"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Guardian and ward"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Homeless children"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Infants"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Nutrition"/>
		<term name="Nutrition and the aged"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
		<term name="School lunch program"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
Amends the National School Lunch Act (NSLA) to make Head Start participants automatically eligible for free meals under the NSLA school lunch program and the school breakfast program of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA). Revises the child and adult care food program under NSLA. Broadens the definition of eligible institution. Provides for additional reimbursement for family or group day care home sponsoring organizations and an enhanced administrative reimbursement rate for such organizations serving rural or low-income area providers. Increases the allowable amount of startup and expansion funds. Allows expansion funds to be used for outreach to unlicensed day care homes. Extends the authorization of appropriations for such program. Adds provisions relating to information about Medicaid and the special nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC). Expands eligibility for meal supplements for the afterschool care program to youths up to age 18. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to report on demonstration projects to improve food service for homeless children. Directs the Secretary to use certain funds for nutrition counseling, assessments, and referrals for participants in such homeless demonstration program, WIC, Medicaid, and similar programs for homeless pregnant women or those at risk of becoming so, homeless mothers with newborn infants, or the guardians of boarder babies or other abandoned infants. Requires periodic reports. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA) to require States to use a portion of certain increased grant funds for nutrition education and training assistance for family day care home sponsors and day care center staff.

	</summary>
</bill>
