<bill session="103" type="h" number="3588" updated="2010-04-19T08:30:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Abuse and Neglect Accountability Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require a State, in order to be eligible for a grant for child abuse and neglect prevention and treatment programs, to have in effect a State law providing for the prosecution of a person who makes a report of child abuse or neglect without having a reasonable belief that the report is true, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400586"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2995)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Local laws"/>
		<term name="Privileges and immunities"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
Child Abuse and Neglect Accountability Act of 1993 - Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require a State, in order to be eligible for a grant for child abuse and neglect prevention and treatment programs, to have in effect a law providing for the prosecution of a person who makes a report of child abuse or neglect without having a reasonable belief that the report is true, or with the intent to expose the reported person to public hatred, ridicule, or criminal investigation. Requires such State law to also make it a criminal offense to cause or persuade a child to make such a report.

	</summary>
</bill>
