<bill session="103" type="h" number="3595" updated="2010-04-19T08:31:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Handgun Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the possession of a handgun by, and the transfer of a handgun to, a minor, with certain exceptions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300085"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-30"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Criminal negligence"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
Youth Handgun Control Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit a handgun from being possessed by or transferred or made available to an individual who has not attained 18 years of age: (1) if the person making the gun available knows or has reasonable cause to believe that the individual has not attained such age and has been convicted of a crime of violence; or (2) has been found to be a juvenile delinquent for an offense which would constitute such a crime if committed by an adult. Makes exceptions if the handgun is: (1) used to attend a course of instruction in hunter safety or firearms safety that is conducted by a certified instructor; (2) used for practice, target shooting, or hunting in accordance with State and local law; (3) unloaded and locked in a container while traveling to or from the hunter or firearms safety activities; (4) possessed by the individual, with the consent of his or her parent or legal guardian, on real property that is owned or leased by them; or (5) transferred with the consent of the parent or legal guardian of the individual, with an exception. Prescribes penalties.

	</summary>
</bill>
