<bill session="103" type="h" number="36" updated="2010-04-18T23:05:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Preventive Health and Promotion Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a schedule of preventive health care services and to provide for coverage of such services in accordance with such schedule under private health insurance plans and health benefit programs of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400536"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-03-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E76)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-15"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-25"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1015)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1059)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1599)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2309)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" subcommittee="Compensation and Employee Benefits" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Geriatrics"/>
		<term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medically uninsured"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Military dependents"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Comprehensive Preventive Health and Promotion Act of 1993 - Mandates establishment and annual revision of a schedule of recommended preventive health care services (preventive services). Requires each carrier and employer health benefit plan to include coverage for the preventive services. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a tax on the failure of a carrier or an employer plan to comply. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to include the preventive services in the definition of &quot;medical and other health services.&quot; Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to mandate Medicaid coverage of the preventive services and, in some circumstances, for: (1) home and community care for functionally disabled elderly individuals; and (2) community supported living arrangements services. Amends Federal law relating to health care services for veterans include the preventive services under this Act in the definition of &quot;medical services.&quot; Regulates provision of the preventive services on an outpatient basis. Amends Federal law relating to health insurance for Federal employees to add the preventive services to the list of benefits which may be provided under service or indemnity benefit plans. Amends Federal law relating to medical care for dependents of members of the uniformed services to add coverage of the preventive services. Mandates: (1) grants to counties for a project to demonstrate the effectiveness of providing preventive services to improve and reduce health costs; (2) dissemination of information on the benefits of practicing preventive care; (3) grants to employers to establish and conduct on-site workshops on health care promotion for employees; and (4) a program of on-site workshops on health care promotion for Federal employees.

	</summary>
</bill>
