<bill session="103" type="h" number="3625" updated="2010-04-19T08:35:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">GSP Renewal and Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To renew and improve the operation of title V of the Trade Act of 1974 (relating to the Generalized System of Preferences).</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400572"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-06"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Air pollution"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Customs unions"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Free trade"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Russia"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Tariff preferences"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
GSP Renewal and Reform Act of 1993 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to revise provisions for the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP). Grants the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) the authority to extend preferences. (This authority is currently the President's.) Requires the USTR to certify that a country meets requirements for beneficiary developing country status before the President may make such a designation. Bars countries with free trade agreements with the United States from such designation. Includes compliance with internationally recognized worker rights and enforcement of environmental protection standards as conditions for such designation. Requires the USTR (rather than the President) to list articles to be considered for designation. Makes an article ineligible if it has been made under conditions that violate specified internationally recognized worker rights. Revises limitations on preferential treatment. Requires the USTR to withdraw or suspend duty-free treatment for any article that no longer meets specified requirements. Provides for petitions by any interested person alleging article or country noncompliance, USTR investigations, and judicial review of removal of articles or withdrawal of designations as beneficiary developing countries. Sets forth competitive need limitations. Extends to July 4, 2003, the termination date for GSP duty-free treatment. Requires general reports on GSP by the USTR, annual reports by the Secretary of Labor on the status of internationally recognized worker rights within each beneficiary developing country, and a special joint report by the USTR, the Secretaries of Commerce and of Labor, and the Comptroller General. Requires training on international labor standards for Labor Reporting Officers for U.S. Embassies and for members of certain special committees created by the USTR. Adds a fourth Deputy USTR. Establishes a Bureau of Trade-Related Standards.

	</summary>
</bill>
