<bill session="103" type="h" number="3624" updated="2010-04-19T08:35:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Superfund Liability Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to establish a program for assigning shares of liability to liable parties at Superfund sites, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="408976" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="410529" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="406024" joined="1994-02-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3118-3120)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-06"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-20"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E857)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-27"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>See H.R.3800.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3800" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative law judges"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Health surveys"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Parties to actions"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
Superfund Liability Reform Act - Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to provide that with respect to any National Priority List (NPL) site, each liable party who accepts or sucessfully appeals the results of the allocation of responsibility process (established by this Act) shall be liable only for its assigned share of the costs for: (1) removal or remedial action incurred by the United States, a State, or an Indian tribe; (2) response incurred by any other person; and (3) any health assessment or health effects study. (Sec. 3) Requires the orphan share of a NPL site to be paid out of the Hazardous Substance Superfund or by a liable party who unsuccessfully appeals a final binding allocation of responsibility decision. (Sec. 4) Makes potentially responsible parties (PRPs) and liable parties who fail to perform response actions at an NPL site subject to civil action and liable for all action costs. Requires PRPs who perform and pay for a response action at such a site to be reimbursed by Superfund. Authorizes liable parties who perform and pay for such actions to recover costs as a creditor party in accordance with this Act. (Sec. 5) Provides that certain recycling transactions in which a material is being used or sold to make a new product and that meet other specification grade conditions shall not be considered as actions subject to liability for response actions. Excludes transactions that lead to the burning of material or the use of material in a manner that constitutes a disposal as determined by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. (Sec. 6) Directs the Administrator to appoint panels of administrative law judges to perform expedited administrative proceedings, to be known as &quot;binding allocations of responsibility (BARs),&quot; for purposes of determining the liability of PRPs at NPL sites. Provides that BARs shall not address or affect liability concerning damages to natural resources. Provides for the initiation of a BAR by the filing of a petition with the EPA Office of Administrative Law Judges by the Administrator or a State where the site is located. Authorizes de micromis parties (PRPs that contributed only a miniscule amount of hazardous substances to the site) to resolve liability by paying $1,000 to the Superfund. Requires final BARs to be issued within 18 months of the publication of a notice of petition (or 24 months for cases of exceptional complexity). Bases the assigned share of liability on specified allocation factors. Requires the Administrator to make firm offers of settlement to all de minimis parties (parties that contributed only one percent or less of the total quantity of hazardous substances present at the site). Makes a BAR decision binding as to all past, present, and future liability for response costs and for contributions in civil proceedings. Permits judicial review of final BAR decisions. Sets forth procedures for recovery by creditor parties. Provides for stays of certain pending enforcement actions and private party litigation until a BAR is issued. Authorizes any group of PRPs to submit a private allocation for the NPL site, to be known as a &quot;voluntary binding allocation of responsibility,&quot; to the allocation panel. Provides that a BAR shall constitute a permanent determination of the assigned share of a liable party and of the orphan share and, except for specified additions to the orphan share and judicially mandated changes, shall not be subject to any change for at least five years after the date of final decision. Permits a new BAR only if the request demonstrates that due to new information not reasonably available during the first BAR, a 35 percent or greater increase in total waste-in volume has been discovered.

	</summary>
</bill>
