<bill session="103" type="h" number="3655" updated="2010-04-19T08:40:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Prepayment Penalty Relief Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Small Business Administration to reduce the interest rate on certain outstanding debentures, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400537"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10981-10982)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Securities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
Small Business Prepayment Penalty Relief Act of 1993 - Title II (sic) - Authorizes the Small Business Administration (SBA), upon the request of the issuer, to annually buy-down the interest rate on any debenture purchased by the Federal Financing Bank which has been issued by a development company or a small business investment company (SBIC) pursuant to appropriate provisions of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958. Allows such buy-down to reduce such interest rate to 7.5 percent annually. Title III - Directs the SBA, after the appropriations Act for each year has been enacted, to calculate the amount needed to carry out the buy-downs authorized in title II. Allows the SBA, after such determination, to notify the debenture issuers that it will receive offers from any interested issuer to prepay the debenture in full. Requires a prioritization of such offers based on the amount of prepayment penalty an issuer offers to pay. Prohibits the imposition against the issuer, the borrower, or the SBA of fees or penalties (with exceptions) as a condition of such prepayment. Allows regular and specialized SBICs which are the issuer of a debenture purchased by the SBA under such Act to offer to prepay the debenture under prior provisions of this Act, subject to specified conditions, and with the same prohibition against the imposition of fees or penalties for such prepayment. Title IV - Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
