<bill session="103" type="h" number="3650" updated="2010-04-19T08:39:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dietary Supplement Access and Claims Moratorium Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to assure access to dietary supplements and to amend the Dietary Supplement Act of 1992 to extend the moratorium with respect to the issuance of regulations on dietary supplements, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400425"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410496" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="404220" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="1994-01-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3108)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Dietary supplements"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
		<term name="Food safety"/>
		<term name="Herbs"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Vitamins"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
Dietary Supplement Access and Claims Moratorium Act of 1993 - Title I: Access to Dietary Supplements - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from requiring: (1) a prescription for a dietary supplement marketed on or before November 15, 1993; and (2) premarket approval for dietary supplements. Specifies that a food shall be deemed to be adulterated if it contains a dietary ingredient at a level that may be injurious to health or is a dietary supplement which when used in accordance with the conditions of use may be injurious to health. Title II: Moratorium on Dietary Supplement Claims - Amends the Prescription Drug User Fee Act of 1992 to prohibit the Secretary from implementing the Nutrition Labeling and Education Act of 1990 or any amendment made by such Act earlier than June 30, 1994, with respect to dietary supplements of vitamins, minerals, herbs, amino acids, or other similar nutritional substances. Prohibits the Secretary from issuing any final regulations applicable to such substances before that date. Specifies that any such proposed regulations shall not be considered to be final regulations until that date. Makes the effective date for provisions dealing with State enforcement with respect to such substances June 30, 1994. Permits the Secretary, earlier than that date, to approve specified health claims made with respect to such substances.

	</summary>
</bill>
