<bill session="103" type="h" number="3682" updated="2010-04-19T08:44:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bucket Drowning Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require that 4-gallon to 6-gallon buckets distributed in commerce bear a permanent label warning of a potential drowning hazard to young children, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400308"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3074)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-20"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Child welfare"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Industrial standards"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Retail trade"/>
		<term name="Signs and symbols"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
Bucket Drowning Prevention Act of 1993 - Establishes a consumer product safety standard requiring four- to six-gallon buckets to bear a warning label that includes a picture of a child falling into a bucket and the words, in English and Spanish: &quot;WARNING. Children Can Fall into Bucket and Drown. Keep Children Away From Buckets With Even a Small Amount of Liquid.&quot; Exempts buckets manufactured or imported before the effective date of this labeling standard. Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission to prohibit a manufacturer, filler, distributor, and retailer from stockpiling such buckets. Requires the Commission to conduct a study to determine: (1) consumer use patterns of new and used four- to six-gallon steel and metal buckets; and (2) the prevalence of incidents of death or injury to children associated with their use. Exempts metal containers from the labeling requirements of this Act during the pendency of the study and in the absence of any regulation of four- to six-gallon containers by the Commission thereafter. Requires the Commission, upon the review of the results of the study, to decide whether to continue this exemption, to require compliance by metal containers, or to consider a further study.

	</summary>
</bill>
