<bill session="103" type="h" number="3681" updated="2010-04-19T08:44:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Voluntary Environmental Response Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the establishment of qualified voluntary environmental response programs in States and to encourage the expeditious remediation of contaminated sites.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400307"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3066-3067)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-06"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-20"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-27"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>See H.R.3800.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3800" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Air pollution"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Carcinogens"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
		<term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Liability for water pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
Voluntary Environmental Response Act of 1993 - Sets forth elements of qualified voluntary environmental response programs to be certified by States under this Act. Withdraws approval of programs that are not enforced in accordance with this Act. (Sec. 5) Applies this Act to, and requires qualified programs to provide for eligibility of, any site where there has been a release or threat of a release of a hazardous substance or constituent. Makes this Act inapplicable to any portion of a site: (1) included on the National Priorities List under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (CERCLA) for which a Record of Decision has been issued by the President; (2) with respect to which a closure notification under the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA) has been submitted and closure requirements have been specified in a closure plan or permit; (3) with respect to which a corrective action permit condition or order has been issued or modified to require implementation of specific corrective measures pursuant to RCRA; (4) controlled by, or to be remediated by, a Federal agency; or (5) at which assistance for response activities may be obtained pursuant to RCRA from the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund. (Sec. 6) Requires qualified programs to direct persons conducting response actions to submit response action plans. Authorizes approval of a response action based on performance of a site-specific risk assessment or demonstrated control measures that are cost-effective and practicable remedial actions at generic site types. Requires response action plans to include: (1) a site investigation assessing the factors necessary to determine the appropriateness of the response action; (2) a description of the plan; (3) supporting information for selection of the response action in accordance with the required methods; (4) a schedule for completion of the response action; and (5) recordkeeping and reporting requirements. (Sec. 7) Provides that any site for which a response action plan has been approved pursuant to a qualified program shall not be subject to further response actions under the Clean Air Act, the Clean Water Act, CERCLA, the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (OPA), RCRA, the Safe Drinking Water Act, the Toxic Substances Control Act, or State and local laws concerning response actions. Absolves persons conducting such actions of liability for damages for response or restoration requirements under such Acts. (Sec. 8) Requires qualified programs to provide for the appointment of an environmental trustee who is authorized to acquire sites which are the subject of response actions on behalf of the State. (Sec. 9) Amends CERCLA to provide for assistance to States to establish programs under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
