<bill session="103" type="h" number="3699" updated="2010-04-19T08:47:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Minority Health Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish, reauthorize and revise provisions to improve the health of individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410407"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402763" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400580" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="409154" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="404213" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400502" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="411350" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="410974" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407672" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="402626" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404139" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="411488" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404067" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="1994-02-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10980-10981)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-22"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Black colleges"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Family medicine"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Health surveys"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
		<term name="Minority students"/>
		<term name="Minority teachers"/>
		<term name="Pacific Islanders"/>
		<term name="Pharmacists"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Psychologists"/>
		<term name="Psychology"/>
		<term name="Public housing"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Urban areas"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Health Policy Title II: Health Services Title III: Health Professions Title IV: Research and Data Collection Title V: Miscellaneous Minority Health Improvement Act of 1993 - Title I: Health Policy - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Advisory Committee on Minority Health to advise the Secretary of Health and Human Services on the development of the goals of the Office of Minority Health for each racial and ethnic group. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1994 through 1998. (Sec. 102) Provides for the establishment of an Office of Minority Health at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration, and the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research. Requires such Offices to develop and implement health programs that target racial and ethnic minority populations. (Sec. 103) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to States for the purpose of improving the health status in minority communities, through the operation of State offices of minority health established to monitor and facilitate the achievement of the Health Objectives for the Year 2000 as they affect minority populations. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 through 1997. (Sec. 104) Establishes in the Department of Health and Human Services an Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Title II: Health Services - Extends authorized appropriations for grants to States for the community scholarship program until FY 1996. Revises the eligibility requirements for such program. (Sec. 202) Extends the authorized appropriations for the grant program for health services for residents of public housing to FY 1996. (Sec. 203) Amends the Disadvantaged Minority Health Improvement Act of 1990 to allow substance abuse services under the grant program for health service for Pacific Islanders. Extends authorized appropriations for such program through FY 1996. Requires a report to the Congress on the effectiveness of projects funded under such program. Title III: Health Professions - Extends authorized appropriations until FY 1996 for: (1) loans for disadvantaged students; (2) the Cesar Chavez Scholarship Program (currently known as the Exceptional Financial Need Program); (3) the Thurgood Marshall Scholarship Program (currently known as the Scholarship for Disadvantaged Students program); (4) loan repayments and fellowships regarding faculty positions at health professions schools; (5) Centers of Excellence; and (6) educational assistance regarding undergraduates. Exempts from certain residency training requirements: (1) students from disadvantaged backgrounds who are underrepresented in the health professions; and (2) historically black colleges. (Sec. 305) Requires Centers of Excellence (health professions schools) to carry out community-based training programs to prepare students in secondary schools and institutions of higher education for attendance at such schools. Requires such schools to provide training to students to enable them to provide health service to minorities at community-based health facilities. Allows such schools to establish consortia. Allows schools of pharmacy and clinical psychology to be Centers of Excellence. Allows Centers of Excellence to collaborate with the National Institutes of Health. Title IV: Research and Data Collection - Requires the Director of the Office of Minority Health to ensure that activities address the most prevalent morbidity and mortality concerns of the various racial and ethnic minority groups. Establishes the Advisory Subcommittee on Research on Minority Health to advise the Advisory Committee to the Director of the National Institutes of Health. (Sec. 402) Extends authorized appropriations through FY 1997 for the National Center for Health Statistics. (Sec. 403) Requires that research, demonstration projects, and evaluations be carried out on the health status of, and the delivery of, health care to racial and ethnic minority groups residing in medically underserved urban and rural areas and low-income groups, including the elderly, women, and children with low incomes. Title V: Miscellaneous - Directs the Secretary to study and report to the Congress on the need to combine the designations of medically underserved area and health professional shortage area. (Sec. 502) Establishes in the Department of Health and Human Services the Office of Urban Health Policy to collect and disseminate information on health care issues, research findings, and innovative approaches to deliver health care to such areas. Authorizes the making of grants to States to improve health care in underserved urban areas. (Sec. 503) Authorizes the making of grants and contracts regarding organ and bone marrow transplantation for minority populations. (Sec. 504) Extends the demonstration project for grants to States for Alzheimer's disease through FY 1998. Requires improved access for individuals with Alzheimer's disease, particularly racial and ethnic minorities and individuals living in isolated rural areas, to services that are home-based or community-based. (Sec. 505) Waives individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds who are underrepresented in the health professions from certain obligations regarding training or practicing in primary health care.

	</summary>
</bill>
