<bill session="103" type="h" number="370" updated="2010-04-18T23:57:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To make the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 applicable to the House of Representatives and the instrumentalities of the Congress, to give certain employees of the House of Representatives and the instrumentalities of the Congress the right to petition for judicial review for violations of certain laws and rules concerning civil rights and employment practices, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-19"><committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Personnel and Police.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.4822.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Administration" subcommittee="Personnel and Police" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Civil and Constitutional Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4822" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Age and employment"/>
		<term name="Age discrimination"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional privileges and immunities"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Grievance procedures"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Older workers"/>
		<term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Applies the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 and the remedies and procedures referred to in the Fair Employment Practices Resolution to any: (1) employee of (or applicant for employment by) the House of Representatives; (2) employing authority of the House; or (3) employee of (or applicant for employment by) the Architect of the Capitol, the Congressional Budget Office, the General Accounting Office, the Government Printing Office, the Office of Technology Assessment, or the U.S. Botanic Garden. Applies the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to: (1) the Congressional Budget Office; (2) the General Accounting Office; (3) the Government Printing Office; (4) the Library of Congress; (5) the Office of Technology Assessment; and (6) the U.S. Botanic Garden. Requires the Architect of the Capitol to report to the Congress on steps taken pursuant to the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1989 relating to the minimum wage rate of its employees. Expresses the sense of the House that the Committee on House Administration should make recommendations regarding the application of the Occupational Safety and Health Act to the House. Authorizes any employee of (or applicant for employment by) the House who has been aggrieved by a violation of the Fair Employment Practices Resolution (relating to nondiscrimination), the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, the Civil Rights Act of 1991, the Fair Labor Standards Amendment of 1989, or the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to petition for review by the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit of the final decision pursuant to the Fair Employment Practices Resolution. Expresses the sense of the House that the Rules of the House should be amended to address the issue of the source of payments by the House to satisfy a judgment against a Member who has been found guilty of a violation of one of such Acts. Gives employees of instrumentalities of the Congress who have been aggrieved by the violations of the following Acts the right to petition for judicial review: (1) the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (excluding Library of Congress employees); (2) the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990; (3) the Civil Rights Act of 1991; and (4) the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (excluding employees of the Architect of the Capitol).

	</summary>
</bill>
