<bill session="103" type="h" number="3708" updated="2012-07-17T04:25:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-12T13:14:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-07-12T13:14:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Corinth, Mississippi, Battlefield Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the operation, maintenance, and development of the Steamtown National Historic Site, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400612"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24" state="REPORTED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3121-3123)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-21" state="REFERRED"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-31"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-22"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12T13:05:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 103-588.</text></action>
		<calendar number="325" datetime="1994-07-12T13:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 325.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12T13:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Vento moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12T13:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5482-5487"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12T13:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-07-12T13:14:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12T13:14:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21" ><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="660" datetime="1994-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 660.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Archives"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Art objects"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="Civil war"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Locomotives"/>
		<term name="Maps"/>
		<term name="Military history"/>
		<term name="Mississippi"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="New Jersey"/>
		<term name="Pennsylvania"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Railroad maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
		<term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Tunnels"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/1994--Reported to Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Steamtown National Historic Site Title II: Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Title III: Civil War Battlefield of Corinth, Mississippi Title I: Steamtown National Historic Site - Repeals the Steamtown National Historic Site Act of 1986 and sets forth new provisions establishing the Steamtown National Historic Site to preserve and interpret certain elements of railroading, especially steam-operated railroads during the period of 1850 to 1950. (Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to prepare and submit a new comprehensive general management plan for the Site to specified congressional committees. (Sec. 103) Prohibits the Secretary from acquiring any lands or interests in lands contaminated with hazardous substances that would require removal or remedial action at the expense of the United States. Directs the Secretary to take steps to obtain cost recovery under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (Superfund) for any funds of the National Park Service expended on removal or remedial action with respect to contamination within the Site. (Sec. 104) Directs the Secretary to preserve the collection of railroad equipment (including locomotives and rolling stock) present at the Site as of enactment of this Act. Limits the number of locomotives operating at the Site to the number operating as of June 22, 1994. Prohibits Federal funds from being expended for access between the Site and any structure that is privately owned or operated for profit. Requires the Secretary to preserve the artifact collection and archival materials located at the Site. Authorizes the Secretary to provide a regular excursion from Scranton, Pennsylvania, to Moscow, Pennsylvania. Prohibits the Secretary from expending funds of the National Park Service for the restoration or maintenance of tracks, bridges, or tunnels outside the Site, except certain funds appropriated before November 15, 1991. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) pay customary and appropriate track usage fees; and (2) provide additional annual excursions if no such excursion is longer than 60 miles one way. Sets forth user and interpretive fee provisions. (Sec. 105) Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area - Amends Federal law to change the map reference for the Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area with respect to its boundary. Title III: Civil War Battlefield of Corinth, Mississippi - Corinth, Mississippi, Battlefield Act of 1994 - Authorizes the Secretary to acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange such lands or interests as the Secretary deems necessary for the construction of an interpretive center to commemorate and interpret the 1862 Civil War Siege and Battle of Corinth. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) construct, operate, and maintain on the property so acquired a center for the interpretation of the Siege and Battle of Corinth and associated historical events; and (2) mark sites associated with the Siege and Battle of Corinth National Historic Landmark if such sites are determined by the Secretary to be protected by State or local governmental agencies. (Sec. 305) Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
