<bill session="103" type="h" number="3710" updated="2010-04-19T08:49:05-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Parks and Landmarks Conservation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the protections afforded to units of the National Park System and certain other nationally significant historic and natural places, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400612"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3121-3123)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-31"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Cultural property"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Humanities"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="National monuments"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural monuments"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/22/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Director of National Park Service Title II: National Park Conservation Title III: National Landmark Conservation Title IV: Federal Program Consistency and Resource Protection Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions National Parks and Landmarks Conservation Act - Title I: Director of National Park Service - Requires the Director of the National Park Service (NPS) to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to administer, protect, and preserve the natural and cultural resources of the United States. Prohibits the Director and the officers and employees of the National Park Service from being responsible to, or subject to the supervision or direction of, any officer, employee, or agent of the Department of the Interior, except for the Secretary. Provides that only career appointees or persons in the competitive service may be appointed as Deputy Director, Associate Director, or Regional Director of the NPS. Title II: National Park Conservation - Requires the Director to prepare and transmit to specified congressional committees a &quot;State of the National Parks&quot; report to document the condition of the National Park units, including appropriate baseline information and documentation of problems related to their use and management and proposed solutions to such problems. (Sec. 202) Requires the Director to establish a research program, within the National Park Service, to: (1) develop an appropriate knowledge base regarding the natural and cultural resources of the National Park System; (2) evaluate and protect such resources; and (3) understand and improve the effects of human interactions with them. (Sec. 203) Requires the superintendent of each National Park System unit to maintain a current and comprehensive resource management plan to be reviewed and revised at least biennially to conform with this Act and to provide data for the report. Provides that general management plans developed for each park unit shall fully consider, and be prepared using, the unit's resource management plan. Sets forth procedures for revision of general management plans for National Park System units. Requires agencies to withhold from the public information about historic resources if disclosure may invade privacy, risk harm to resources, or impede use of a traditional religious site. (Sec. 204) Requires the Director to initiate a program to prepare National Park Conservation Plans for units in order to develop specific programs of cooperation among the National Park Service, other Federal agencies, State and local governments, Indian tribes, the private sector, appropriate experts, the general public, or any combination of the foregoing addressing current or potential factors, forces, and conditions affecting such units. Sets forth procedures for the preparation of a conservation plan. Authorizes the Director to make grants to State and local governments, Indian tribes, and private entities for assisting in the preparation of a conservation plan. Allows the Director, under certain conditions, to provide grants to State and local governments and to Indian tribes to facilitate the implementation of the conservation plan. Requires the Director to review such approved conservation plans regularly to ensure that they meet the requirements of this Act. Provides that Federal activities that may affect National Park System units, with an approved conservation plan, shall be consistent with the plan. Requires the Director to develop a program to inform visitors to National Park System units about the condition of such units and their resources and the actions being taken to address any current or potential affect on them. Title III: National Landmark Conservation - Requires the Director to maintain a complete and current list of all National Landmarks which meet criteria promulgated by the Director for designating a National Landmark as endangered. Sets forth procedures by which the Director shall list such endangered historic places. (Sec. 302) Requires the Director to enter into National Landmark conservation agreements providing for long-term conservation of sites. Authorizes grants to assist owners, State and local governments, and Indian tribes in the preparation agreements and implementation of such agreements. Title IV: Federal Program Consistency and Resource Protection - Prohibits a Federal agency from conducting or approvaing a Federal or federally assisted undertaking that will or is likely to adversely affect a National Heritage Resource (a unit of the NPS or a National Historic or Natural Landmark) with exceptions for national security and disasters. Prescribes procedures required of an agency before it may proceed with any undertaking that may adversely affect such a resource. Prohibits, with specified exceptions, the granting of Federal assistance with respect to a resource to an applicant if the applicant has created or permitted activities that caused an adverse affect on such a resource, unless the agency determines circumstances still justify such assistance. (Sec. 402) Sets forth provisions relating to temporary enjoining of harmful actions to, or destruction of, a National Heritage Resource. Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions - Sets forth provisions relating to: (1) definitions; and (2) civil penalties and enforcement of Title IV of this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
