<bill session="103" type="h" number="3719" updated="2010-04-19T08:50:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Well America Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a wellness program for Americans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400239"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3123)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Cholesterol"/>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Nutrition"/>
		<term name="Obesity"/>
		<term name="Physical fitness"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Smoking"/>
		<term name="Tobacco"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/23/1993--Introduced.
Well America Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to issue a voucher card to each enrollee in the wellness program established by this Act who is: (1) age 30 or older; (2) under age 30 and certified by his or her primary care provider as in special need of wellness benefits resulting from unusual physical characteristics or conditions; or (3) under age 30 and uses tobacco for a tobacco-use-cessation program or whose cholesterol condition or body weight is certified by his or her primary care provider to place the individual at high health risk for the purpose of a weight-loss, nutrition, or exercise program. Establishes in the Treasury the Wellness Trust Fund from which the cost of covered benefits under this Act and related claims shall be paid to participating providers. Appropriates to such Fund for each year four percent of all health care premiums and Federal expenditures on health care populations served outside of health care plans.

	</summary>
</bill>
