<bill session="103" type="h" number="371" updated="2010-04-18T23:57:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to limit the influence of nonparty multicandidate political committees in elections for Federal office, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an income tax credit for contributions to candidates for the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Campaign contributors"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Congressional candidates"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
		<term name="Depletion allowances"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Oil well drilling"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to decrease the limitation on contributions to candidates for Federal office by a multicandidate political committee (PAC). Prohibits a nonparty committee from acting as an intermediary or conduit (to facilitate bundling) with respect to such contributions. Prohibits a candidate for Federal office from establishing, maintaining, financing, or controlling a political committee (leadership committee) other than the principal campaign committee. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for congressional campaign contributions to candidates for the House of Representatives. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal the minimum tax deduction based on intangible drilling cost preferences.

	</summary>
</bill>
