<bill session="103" type="h" number="3746" updated="2010-04-19T08:54:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Firearms Exchange Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to approve local programs that exchange merchandise vouchers for firearms and make grants to the programs, to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide amnesty for individuals who surrender firearms under the programs, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow tax deductions for taxpayers who donate merchandise vouchers for use in the programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406420"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1994-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="1994-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="1994-02-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Amnesties"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Charitable contributions"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Programs to Exchange Vouchers for Firearms Title II: Tax Deduction for Taxpayers Who Donate Merchandise Vouchers National Firearms Exchange Act - Title I: Programs to Exchange Vouchers for Firearms - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (Omnibus Act) to require the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to establish procedures under which any unit of local government may apply for approval of a program to exchange merchandise vouchers for firearms. Requires the Director to establish criteria and procedures to determine whether any such program should be approved under this title. Prohibits the Director from approving any program that does not provide that all firearms surrendered to the program will be destroyed, but does not require the destruction of a firearm until it is no longer needed for investigatory or evidentiary purposes. Sets forth provisions regarding the timing of the approval process and the duration of approval status. Requires the Director to make every effort to secure from State governments amnesty for certain offenses for persons surrendering firearms. Authorizes the Director to make grants to approved programs. Requires the Director to establish grant application and award procedures for local governments whose programs are approved. Requires the Director to submit to the Congress an assessment of the effectiveness of this title regarding programs to exchange merchandise vouchers for firearms and of approved programs and to establish criteria for evaluating such effectiveness. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Federal criminal code to grant amnesty to an individual surrendering, or in the process of surrendering, a firearm to an approved program (thus making specified provisions of the Omnibus Act and the National Firearms Act inapplicable with respect to such individual), with exceptions. Title II: Tax Deduction for Taxpayers Who Donate Merchandise Vouchers - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction for the fair market value of certain contributions of property or vouchers to be transferred to individuals surrendering firearms under a qualified gun exchange program.

	</summary>
</bill>
