<bill session="103" type="h" number="3744" updated="2010-04-19T08:54:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Peace Powers Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the United Nations Participation Act of 1945 to facilitate coordination between the executive and legislative branches of Government regarding United States participation in, or the use of United States funds for, United Nations peacekeeping activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400192"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1994-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400340" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400536" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400079" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400610" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1994-06-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E35-36)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-06" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Operations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="Intelligence activities"/>
		<term name="Intelligence services"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Military command and control"/>
		<term name="Military intelligence"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Prisoners of war"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Torture"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="United Nations finances"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1994--Introduced.
Peace Powers Act of 1994 - Amends the United Nations Participation Act to prohibit the President from subordinating any element of the armed forces participating in a United Nations peacekeeping activity to the command or operational control of any foreign nationals unless the President submits specified documents to the appropriate congressional committees or the Congress enacts an Act or joint resolution authorizing such subordination. Lists as the specified documents determinations by the President that: (1) the proposed subordination is in the national security interest (along with a justification for such determination); (2) the unit commanders of the armed forces proposed for subordination will retain the ability to report independently to higher U.S. military authorities; (3) the United States will retain authority to withdraw the armed forces from the peacekeeping activity at any time and to take any action to protect such forces if endangered; (4) the armed forces will remain under U.S. administrative command for purposes of discipline and evaluation; and (5) the proposed foreign command arrangement does not violate the Constitution. (Sec. 5) Provides for notification to the Congress of proposed participation in, or expenditure of funds for, United Nations peacekeeping activities and other related matters. (Sec. 9) Requires the President to report annually to the Congress on the anticipated budget for, and U.S. contributions to, United Nations peacekeeping activities. (Sec. 11) Revises provisions that authorize the President to waive reimbursement from the United Nations for U.S. participation in peacekeeping activities. Permits the Secretary of Defense to authorize such a waiver if an emergency exists, subject to congressional notification requirements. Bars U.S. contributions to United Nations peacekeeping activities, beginning in FY 1995, until the Secretary certifies to the Congress that the United Nations has reimbursed the Department of Defense (DOD) directly for all goods and services provided on a reimbursable basis for such activities. (Sec. 12) Makes DOD funds available for United Nations peacekeeping activities, beginning in FY 1996, only to the extent that the Congress has by law specifically made funds available for such purposes. (Sec. 13) Declares that, effective FY 1996, the Congress does not intend to make funds available for payment of U.S. contributions to such activities that exceed 25 percent of the total of such contributions of all countries unless the Congress enacts a statute specifically authorizing a greater percentage contribution. (Sec. 14) Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds to pay U.S. contributions for such activities unless the Secretary of State certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that U.S. manufacturers and suppliers are being given equal opportunities to provide equipment, services, and material for such activities. (Sec. 16) Permits intelligence to be provided to the United Nations only pursuant to specified agreements and advance notification to the Congress. (Sec. 17) Withholds, beginning in FY 1995, 50 percent of the funds for U.S. contributions for United Nations peacekeeping activities unless the President makes a specified certification regarding the establishment of an Office of Inspector General within the United Nations.

	</summary>
</bill>
