<bill session="103" type="h" number="3751" updated="2010-04-19T08:55:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Katie O'Connell Safe Food Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Meat, Poultry, and Eggs Inspection Agency to administer the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspection Act, and the Egg Products Inspection Act, to expand the application of these Acts, to provide for the establishment of safe cooking standards for meat and poultry products, and to improve scientific research and understanding of foodborne illnesses.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300156"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1994-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1994-03-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations and Nutrition.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E75-76)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Department Operations and Nutrition" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSAG-03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Digestive diseases"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
		<term name="Food handling"/>
		<term name="Food industry"/>
		<term name="Food poisoning"/>
		<term name="Food safety"/>
		<term name="Food service"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Health surveys"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Meat"/>
		<term name="Meat inspection"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Poultry"/>
		<term name="Poultry industry"/>
		<term name="Poultry inspection"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Restaurants"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Whistle blowing"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Meat, Poultry, and Eggs Inspection Agency Subtitle A: Establishment and Authorities of Agency Subtitle B: Transitional Provisions Subtitle C: Other Matters Title II: Expansion of Foods Covered by Inspection Laws Title III: Establishment and Enforcement of Safe Cooking Standards for Meat and Poultry Products Title IV: Epidemiological Activities Regarding Foodborne Diseases Title V: Research on Treatment of Foodborne Diseases Katie O'Connell Safe Food Act - Title I: Meat, Poultry, and Eggs Inspection Agency - Subtitle A: Establishment and Authorities of Agency - Establishes in the executive branch the Meat, Poultry, and Eggs Inspection Agency which shall be responsible for administering inspection, research, and oversight activities regarding meat, poultry, and eggs (including retail safe cooking standards). (Sec. 104) Establishes: (1) within the Agency the Bureau for Improved Inspection Capabilities; and (2) an advisory commission on inspection. Authorizes the Director of the Agency to make grants and enter into contracts for related research. Subtitle B: Transitional Provisions - Provides for the termination of the Food Safety and Inspection Service of the Department of Agriculture and the transfer of assets, appropriations, and personnel to the Agency. (Sec. 135) Provides for the establishment of the Office of Inspector General of the Agency. Subtitle C: Other Matters - Defines &quot;Agency,&quot; &quot;Director,&quot; and &quot;inspection laws&quot; for purposes of this title. Title II: Expansion of Foods Covered by Inspection Laws - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to authorize coverage of additional meats (such as deer, bison, and rabbits). (Sec. 202) Amends the Poultry Products Inspection Act to authorize coverage of additional poultry (such as quail, pheasant, and squab). Title III: Establishment and Enforcement of Safe Cooking Standards for Meat and Poultry Products - Requires the Agency to establish meat and poultry safe cooking standards for restaurants and other food establishments. (Sec. 302) Provides for enforcement inspections, including civil monetary penalties. Title IV: Epidemiological Activities Regarding Foodborne Diseases - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to carry out foodborne disease prevention and control activities, including population-based surveillance of selected diseases. Authorizes appropriations. Title V: Research on Treatment of Foodborne Diseases - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require: (1) the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases to carry out foodborne disease research and treatment activities; and (2) the National Digestive Diseases Data System and the National Digestive Diseases Information Clearinghouse to include foodborne disease activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
