<bill session="103" type="h" number="3808" updated="2010-04-19T09:04:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs has the necessary authority and flexibility to provide staffing levels for the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs as necessary to meet the responsibility of the United States to provide health care services to eligible veterans and to permit implementation of national health care reform by the Department.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407838"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408725" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="409570" joined="1994-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="404213" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="409442" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="410695" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-03-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H324)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-15"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E405-406)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Occupational retraining"/>
		<term name="Privatization"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Veterans' employment"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/1994--Introduced.
Prohibits, during FY 1995 through 1999, any reduction in the number of full-time employees in the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs other than as specifically required by law or by the availability of funds. Requires such personnel to be managed during such period on the basis of the needs of eligible veterans and the availability of funds. Provides that, during such period, whenever an activity at a Department health-care facility is converted from performance by Federal employees to performance by contracted employees, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall: (1) require the contractor to give an employee preference to former Department employees displaced by the award of such contract; and (2) provide to such former employees all possible assistance in obtaining other Federal employment or entrance into job training and retraining programs. Requires information concerning the use of such contracting-out authority to be included in the Secretary's annual budget and activities report to the Congress.

	</summary>
</bill>
