<bill session="103" type="h" number="3818" updated="2010-04-19T09:05:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Middle East Peace and Development Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Middle East Development Initiative to provide development assistance to countries in the Middle East region for the purpose of promoting the peace process in that region.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408618"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400527" joined="1994-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="1994-04-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E131)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-22"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Egypt"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Israel"/>
		<term name="Jordan"/>
		<term name="Middle East"/>
		<term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
		<term name="National self-determination"/>
		<term name="Palestinians"/>
		<term name="Peace"/>
		<term name="Peace negotiations"/>
		<term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
		<term name="Syria"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/1994--Introduced.
Middle East Peace and Development Act of 1994 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should continue to promote peace in the Middle East region by: (1) encouraging the establishment of diplomatic relations and friendly relationships among Israel, Egypt, Syria, Jordan, and other nations in the region; (2) promoting the shared development and use of human, natural, material, and technological resources of the region; and (3) supporting self-determination for the Palestinian people in the West Bank and Gaza. Requires the President to establish a Middle East Development Initiative to provide development assistance to countries in the Middle East for purposes of promoting the peace process in such region. Makes eligible for such assistance: (1) countries whose governments are engaged in bilateral or multilateral discussions or negotiations which promote the Middle East peace process; and (2) organizations located in the West Bank and Gaza that are engaged in such discussions or negotiations. Authorizes appropriations. Reduces foreign assistance for Egypt and Israel in FY 1995 through 1997 by specified amounts.

	</summary>
</bill>
