<bill session="103" type="h" number="382" updated="2010-04-18T23:59:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Capital Punishment Procedures Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform procedures for the imposition of capital punishment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410147"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Civil and Constitutional Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Air piracy"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Assassination"/>
		<term name="Bank robberies"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Hostages"/>
		<term name="Information leaking"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Presidential protection"/>
		<term name="Prison violence"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Protection of officials"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Treason"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Capital Punishment Procedures Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to establish criteria for the imposition of the death penalty for Federal crimes. Requires the Government, for any offense punishable by death, to serve notice upon the defendant a reasonable time before trial or acceptance of a plea, that it intends to seek the death penalty and the aggravating factors upon which it will rely. Requires a separate sentencing hearing before a jury, or the court upon motion by the defendant, when the defendant is found guilty or pleads guilty to an offense punishable by death. Allows the defendant and the Government to present any information relevant to sentencing, but permits evidence to be excluded where its probative value is substantially outweighed by the danger of creating unfair prejudice, confusing the issues, or misleading the jury. Specifies mitigating factors which the defendant must establish by a preponderance of the information and aggravating factors which the Government must prove beyond a reasonable doubt. Sets forth special aggravating factors for espionage, treason, homicide, and the attempted murder of the President. Directs the court, or the jury by unanimous vote, to impose the death penalty upon a finding that such sentence is justified based on consideration of both the aggravating and mitigating factors. States that no person who was under 18 years of age at the time of the offense may be sentenced to death. Requires the court to instruct the jury not to consider the race, color, national origin, creed, or sex of the defendant or victim in its consideration of the sentence. Sets forth procedures for: (1) appeal from a death sentence; and (2) implementation of the sentence of death. Provides for the imposition of the death penalty for specified offenses, including murder committed by prisoners in Federal prisons, &quot;murder for hire,&quot; and murder in the aid of a racketeering activity. Increases the minimum sentence to life imprisonment for the crime of bank robbery which results in death.

	</summary>
</bill>
