<bill session="103" type="h" number="3821" updated="2010-04-19T09:06:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-11">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-08-11" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Passenger Vessel Development Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote construction and operation of passenger vessels in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411040"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400542" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400091" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="410496" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400117" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="410567" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="406482" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="407141" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="405524" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400189" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="409627" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="1994-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1994-02-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-15"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee On Merchant Marine.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-15"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-13"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Navigation Prior to Referral.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-08-11"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Text of Measure Incorporated into H.R.4422.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Merchant Marine" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Navigation" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Marine transportation"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Citizenship"/>
		<term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
		<term name="Corporations"/>
		<term name="Flags of convenience"/>
		<term name="Foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="International finance"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Passenger ships"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Shipbuilding"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/9/1994--Introduced.
United States Passenger Vessel Development Act - Amends Federal shipping law to authorize endorsement of a certificate of documentation for an eligible passenger vessel with an interim coastwise passenger trade endorsement if it is: (1) owned by, or demise chartered for at least 18 months to, a U.S. citizen; (2) at least 250 gross tons, with at least 175 berths; and (3) not a ferry. Conditions issuance of such an endorsement on the vessel owner's or charterer's entering into one or more contracts for the construction in the United States of one or more vessels having a total berthing capacity at least 80 percent of the capacity of the vessel for which the endorsement is issued. Conditions renewal of such endorsements on specified progress in vessel construction. Requires an interim coastwise passenger trade endorsement to prohibit the operation of the vessel in any trade served by another documented passenger vessel of at least 250 gross tons and having at least 175 berths, unless the owner or operator of the vessel so operated is also the owner or operator of the other vessel having the endorsement. Amends the Shipping Act, 1916 to authorize a person to place under a foreign registry or operate under the authority of a foreign country, without the Secretary of Transportation's approval, any vessel with an interim coastwise passenger trade endorsement if such person notifies the Secretary within certain deadlines. Amends Federal shipping law to require the Secretary to issue the appropriate inspection, load line, and tonnage certificates to any documented vessel with an interim coastwise passenger trade endorsement that meets the standards for passenger vessel construction for safety of life at sea (SOLAS) issued under the International Maritime Organization convention to which the United States is a party. Amends the Shipping Act, 1916 to define U.S. citizenship of a corporation for purposes of documentation with an interim coastwise passenger trade endorsement as the vesting of at least 51 percent of the corporation's stock in U.S. citizens free from any trust or fiduciary obligation in favor of any non-citizen. Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from permitting a person to operate a vessel in any unit of the National Park System except in accordance with a specified priority giving first place to U.S.-documented vessels. Requires the Secretary to revoke permission for operation of a foreign-documented vessel if: (1) a person requests permission to operate a U.S.-documented vessel; and (2) the permission may not be granted because the number of permits that may be issued is limited.

	</summary>
</bill>
