<bill session="103" type="h" number="3842" updated="2010-04-19T09:09:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Head Start Act Amendments of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Head Start Act to extend authorization of appropriations for programs under that Act, to strengthen provisions designed to provide quality assurance and improvement, to provide for orderly and appropriate expansion of such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400595"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="411677" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="403314" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="408052" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400146" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="401033" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400539" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="1994-04-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="407817" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="404220" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400586" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="402626" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400615" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400554" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="1994-04-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="1994-04-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400516" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1994-02-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>See H.R.4250.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4250" />
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1852" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Academic performance"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child development"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="College teachers"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational planning"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government internships"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Infants"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Literacy programs"/>
		<term name="Migrant education"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
		<term name="Parent-teacher relationships"/>
		<term name="Poverty"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Teachers"/>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/10/1994--Introduced.
Head Start Act Amendments of 1994 - Amends the Head Start Act to reauthorize and revise Head Start programs. (Sec. 2) Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish quality standards for Head Start agencies and programs, including standards for performance in providing required health, education, parental involvement, social, and other services, for administrative and financial management, and for facilities' condition and location. Provides for monitoring and for corrective actions or terminations if minimum standards are not met. (Sec. 3) Eliminates a provision freezing regulations. Provides that terminations, reductions, or suspensions of financial assistance upheld in administrative hearings shall not be stayed pending any judicial appeal. (Sec. 4) Revises classroom teacher qualifications and waiver requirements. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide technical assistance and training to enable Head Start agencies to establish positions for mentor teachers; and (2) review and revise standards for family service workers, and promote model curricula and credentials for such workers. Authorizes the Secretary to establish a program of Head Start Fellowships for staff in local Head Start programs and other individuals working in the field of child development and Directs the Secretary to develop model staffing pattern plans to guide local Head Start agencies and programs. (Sec. 5) Sets forth goals and priorities for training and technical assistance. (Sec. 6) Allocates funds for program expansion. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary to allow certain amounts to be allocated to quality improvement activities (in addition to the required 25 percent portion of appropriations). Sets forth goals and authorized activities for which quality improvement funds are to be used. (Sec. 8) Requires each Head Start agency to coordinate with schools and promote parental involvement to facilitate children's transition from program to school. Directs the Secretaries of HHS and of Education to assess results of demonstration projects under the Head Start Transition Project Act and provide technical assistance to communities to implement promising practices from those demonstrations. Extends the set-aside for the Head Start Transition Project Act. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to carry on a continuing program of research, demonstrations, and evaluations of Head Start programs, and to report on such activities. (Sec. 10) Establishes programs for families with infants and toddlers. Directs the Secretary to make grants for: (1) programs providing family-centered services for low-income families with very young children, designed to promote child development, parental role fulfillment, and movement toward self-sufficiency; and (2) evaluation of, and training and technical assistance for, projects under the Comprehensive Child Development Centers Act of 1988. (Repeals the latter Act because its functions are being consolidated under the Head Start Act.) (Sec. 11) Revises parental involvement considerations with respect to designation of new Head Start agencies well as functions of such agencies. Requires agencies to offer family literacy services and parenting skills training to parents of participating children. Allows agencies also to opt to offer such parents parental social self-sufficiency training, substance abuse counseling, or other partnership in education activities. Requires a family needs assessment, including consultation with the parents, for each participating family. (Sec. 12) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 13) Revises the poverty line definition. Updates hold-harmless provisions for Indian and Migrant programs. Specifies that each Head Start program may use Head Start funds for full-day and full-year services and shall be permitted to provide more than one year of services to eligible children in the State.

	</summary>
</bill>
