<bill session="103" type="h" number="3844" updated="2010-04-19T09:10:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Brownfield Cleanup and Redevelopment Revolving Loan Fund Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide loans to States to establish revolving loan funds for the environmental cleanup of sites in distressed areas that have the potential to attract private investment and create local employment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400417"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409154" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404083" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="408052" joined="1994-05-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1994-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400603" joined="1994-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400591" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400334" joined="1994-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400611" joined="1994-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1994-02-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E160)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-04"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Factories"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Job creation"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/10/1994--Introduced.
Brownfield Cleanup and Redevelopment Revolving Loan Fund Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to provide capitalization loans to States to establish or expand a State revolving loan fund for purposes of providing loans for voluntary environmental cleanups of eligible facilities. Defines &quot;eligible facilities&quot; as facilities or property that are determined by a State to have environmental contamination that: (1) could prevent the timely use, development, or reuse of the facility or property; and (2) is limited in scope and can be comprehensively and readily evaluated. Sets forth loan application requirements, including: (1) evidence that the State is carrying out a voluntary cleanup program for eligible facilities and will provide a matching share of at least 20 percent of the costs of such cleanup from either new or existing sources of State funding; (2) a description of the State's proposed revolving loan program and capability to manage the program; and (3) a statement that the State will begin repayment of the loan within five years (and evidence of the State's ability to repay) and that a loan from the revolving loan fund will not be used to pay for new construction, environmental fines or penalties, or for speculative assessments or rehabilitation at facilities with little or no potential for economic development. Directs the Administrator to determine the distribution of funds among the eligible States. Limits the amount of a capitalization loan made by the Administrator under this Act to a State to 15 percent of the amount available each year to all the eligible States. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
