<bill session="103" type="h" number="3861" updated="2010-04-19T09:12:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to permit the District of Columbia to subject the income of the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and the Student Loan Marketing Association to taxation by the District of Columbia, to require the Federal National Mortgage Association to maintain its principal office in the District of Columbia, and to require the Mayor of the District of Columbia to submit a report to Congress on the economic impact of such entities on the District of Columbia.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E170-171)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-23"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fiscal Affairs and Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House District of Columbia" subcommittee="Fiscal Affairs and Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Local taxation"/>
		<term name="Location of industries"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Relocation"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/10/1994--Introduced.
Amends the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to: (1) include within the legislative power of the District of Columbia the power to subject the income of the Federal National Mortgage Association (FNMA), the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (FHLMC), and the Student Loan Marketing Association (SLMA) to taxation for any taxable year, beginning with 1994; and (2) require FNMA to maintain its principal office in the District. Directs the Mayor to study and report to specified congressional committees on the economic impact on the District of the activities of the FNMA, FHLMC, and SLMA, including an analysis of the potential effects on District revenues of permitting the District to subject such enterprises to taxation.

	</summary>
</bill>
