<bill session="103" type="h" number="3870" updated="2010-04-19T09:14:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-26T17:37:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-07-26T17:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Green Technologies bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Technologies Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Environmental Technologies Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Environmental Technologies Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the research and development of environmental technologies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400572"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="1994-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="404083" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="401014" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="406420" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="402890" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="407306" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="411065" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400035" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="401134" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400615" joined="1994-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1994-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="406024" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="1994-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400611" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1994-02-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400526" joined="1994-02-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H653-654)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-13"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-04-13"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08T18:14:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space and Technology. H. Rept. 103-536.</text></action>
		<calendar number="296" datetime="1994-06-08T18:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 296.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-20T19:26:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 483 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3870 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of H.R. 4799. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T14:23:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 483 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T14:23:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 483.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6213-6242"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T14:23:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3870 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of H.R. 4799. Measure will be read by title. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T14:24:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 483 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T14:24:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable G. V. (Sonny) Montgomery to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T14:24:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T17:35:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3870.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T17:36:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T17:36:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-07-26T17:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26T17:37:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="534" datetime="1994-07-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 534.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="483" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3603" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4799" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Air pollution"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Building materials"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Competition"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Green products"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Industrial standards"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Materials research"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Metals"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="New products"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Product development"/>
		<term name="Production engineering"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Quality of products"/>
		<term name="Radiation safety"/>
		<term name="Radioactive decontamination"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research and development contracts"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Scientific education"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Socially handicapped"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
		<term name="Sustainable development"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology assessment"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Test facilities"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Waste reduction"/>
		<term name="Weapons systems"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women in business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h785"/>
		<amendment number="h786"/>
		<amendment number="h787"/>
		<amendment number="h788"/>
		<amendment number="h789"/>
		<amendment number="h790"/>
		<amendment number="h791"/>
		<amendment number="h792"/>
		<amendment number="h793"/>
		<amendment number="h794"/>
		<amendment number="h795"/>
		<amendment number="h796"/>
		<amendment number="h797"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/1994--Passed House amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Policy Coordination and Technology Programs Subtitle A: Policy Coordination and Program Planning Subtitle B: Environmental Technology Innovation Initiative Subtitle C: Other Research Activities Title III: Performance Measurements Title IV: Department of Energy Environmental Technology Development Title V: Authorization of Appropriations Title VI: Risk Assessment Improvement Title VII: Buy America Title I: General Provisions - Environmental Technologies Act of 1994 - Sets forth congressional findings and purposes. Title II: Policy Coordination and Technology Programs - Subtitle A: Policy Coordination and Program Planning - Requires the President, acting through the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, to develop an interagency strategy that: (1) ensures the coordinated, interagency promotion of the research, development, and demonstration of environmental technologies; and (2) develops priorities for Federal environmental technology efforts. (Sec. 202) Requires the Director to coordinate Federal activities and resources that are applied to life-cycle assessment and other design-for-environment resources in order to maximize the contribution of such assessments and resources to the efficient design, development, and use of such technologies and to sustainable economic development. (Sec. 203) Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to include goals for sustainable economic development within technology innovation programs. Includes such goals in other existing programs under specified Acts. Subtitle B: Environmental Technology Innovation Initiative - Establishes an Environmental Innovation Initiative, to be administered by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to promote the research, development, and demonstration of technologies that will contribute to sustainable economic development. Includes programs established under this Act in the Initiative. Provides assistance to eligible entities. (Sec. 211) Requires the Administrator to encourage the participation of socially and economically disadvantaged individuals and entities located in economically depressed areas in carrying out the Initiative. (Sec. 212) Directs the Administrator to conduct an interagency innovative environmental technology program to develop or demonstrate advanced precommercial environmental technologies. Makes U.S. companies and partnerships eligible for financial assistance for projects, subject to certain conditions. Provides for recoupment of assistance in connection with projects which have led to the development of a marketed product or process. (Sec. 213) Establishes the President's Total Environmental Quality Award to be awarded periodically to companies and other organizations which have benefited the United States through environmental technologies. Establishes a National Environmentally Sound Technology Award for individuals who have pioneered the development and use of a highly innovative environmental technology. (Sec. 214) Directs the Administrator to use existing information network capabilities to provide access to data on environmental technologies developed, tested, verified, or certified by programs under this Act and by other appropriate sources. (Sec. 215) Requires the Administrator to establish a program to demonstrate the performance of environmental technologies at Federal laboratories and facilities. (Sec. 216) Directs the Administrator to enter into an agreement with the National Research Council to study the influences on technological innovation in environmental technologies of economic, governmental, and other incentives and barriers. (Sec. 218) Authorizes the Administrator to establish a demonstration program to promote research and development on environmentally efficient building materials. (Sec. 219) Permits the Administrator to enter into agreements with the heads of other agencies that support the export of technologies to provide support for demonstrating the technical and economic feasibility of innovative environmental technologies substantially manufactured in the United States and used in other nations. Subtitle C: Other Research Activities - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to support research activities that will advance the integration of engineering practices and environmental protection in the development of advanced technologies. Title III: Performance Measurements - Requires the Secretary of Commerce, through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to establish a program that provides for performance measurements for environmental technology products (excluding those primarily intended to improve the environment through pollution control, remediation, and monitoring). (Sec. 302) Authorizes the Administrator to designate entities to perform environmental technology verification. (Sec. 303) Requires the President to consider performance measurements for environmental technologies developed pursuant to this title in any program for evaluating and approving Federal purchases of environmental technologies. Title IV: Department of Energy Environmental Technology Development - Directs the Secretary of Energy to conduct programs of research, development, and demonstration on: (1) new and improved technologies for environmental restoration and waste management; (2) training for environmental technicians, engineers, and scientists; and (3) technologies for reducing worker exposure to radioactivity in association with site remediation. (Sec. 402) Requires the Secretary to establish a program to demonstrate the technological and economic feasibility of recycling and reusing radioactively uncontaminated and decontaminated metals and equipment and of other waste minimization techniques. Provides for the recycling and reuse of the metals and equipment at a minimum of three national laboratories or former nuclear weapons production facilities. (Sec. 403) Directs the Secretary to incrementally increase the proportion of the annual budget request for the Environmental Restoration and Waste Management program that is attributable to research and development until such proportion is at least ten percent. Requires the Secretary to ensure that such increase does not affect other Department of Energy programs. Authorizes appropriations for nondefense research and development activities of the Office of Technology Development. Title V: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations. Title VI: Risk Assessment Improvement - Sets forth criteria for risk assessment used in developing priorities for Federal environmental technology research, development, and demonstration efforts. Title VII: Buy America - Expresses the sense of the Congress that, to the greatest extent practicable, all equipment and products purchased with funds made available in this Act should be American-made.

	</summary>
</bill>
