<bill session="103" type="h" number="3896" updated="2010-04-19T09:18:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Minority Health Promotion and Disease Prevention Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for demonstration projects to improve the health of racial and ethnic minority groups by preventing disease and death.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402762"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E262)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-11"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/24/1994--Introduced.
Minority Health Promotion and Disease Prevention Act of 1994 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities to carry out demonstration projects to provide preventive health and health promotion services to racial and ethnic minority groups. Provides a project priority for low-income individuals. Requires at least two projects to be carried out in urban, distressed communities and one project to be carried out in a rural community. Provides fund uses, grant restrictions, and other requirements. Allows grants to be awarded for three years and to be renewed. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 through 1997.

	</summary>
</bill>
