<bill session="103" type="h" number="3899" updated="2010-04-19T09:18:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-20">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-20" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To create police partnerships for children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404602"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400146" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="1994-02-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E258)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-01"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-20"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child development"/>
		<term name="Child mental health services"/>
		<term name="Child welfare"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Community policing"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
		<term name="Police training"/>
		<term name="Police-community relations"/>
		<term name="Social services"/>
		<term name="Social workers"/>
		<term name="Socially handicapped"/>
		<term name="Socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
		<term name="Youth services"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/24/1994--Introduced.
Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to States for use by local law enforcement agencies for the establishment of law enforcement and child and family services partnership programs to: (1) augment law enforcement services and community policing efforts by providing accessible crisis intervention services for children who are involved in violent incidents and training for law enforcement officers (officers) in child development, family, and cultural issues; (2) facilitate interaction between law enforcement agencies, child, and family service organizations, local educational agencies, and other community members for the purpose of building coalitions for the prevention of community violence; (3) provide mentors for high-risk children and youth; (4) promote conflict resolution training for children and youth; and (5) identify children and families at high risk for developing behavioral or emotional problems resulting from exposure to community violence and provide mental health and other support services to such children and families, including crisis intervention for children witnesses and victims of violence. Directs the Attorney General, in awarding such grants, to give priority to States that have law enforcement agencies that: (1) are engaged in community-based policing; and (2) intend to target programs for disadvantaged communities. Authorizes the use of such grants to: (1) provide 24-hour response to crisis situations affecting children and youth, training for officers jointly taught by officers and child guidance professionals, and formal mentoring programs; (2) develop or expand community activities for children and families that are designed jointly by the law enforcement and child and family services partnership; (3) establish weekly case conferences by a team of child guidance professionals and officers; and (4) assist and support the local educational agency located in or near the community the partnership serves in developing and implementing conflict resolution programs. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) limitations on the use of grant funds; (2) State and local application requirements; (3) the Federal share; and (4) evaluations and reporting requirements. Authorizes the National Institute of Justice to provide training and technical assistance to law enforcement and child and family service partnerships. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
