<bill session="103" type="h" number="3941" updated="2010-04-19T09:25:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Revolving Door Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 207 of title 18, United States Code, to tighten restrictions on former executive and legislative branch officials and employees.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400156" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="401014" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="1994-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-04"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Ex-presidents"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Political ethics"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Vice Presidents"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/2/1994--Introduced.
Revolving Door Reform Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the President or Vice President, any person employed in the executive branch at a rate payable for level I of the Executive Schedule or in a position in the Executive Office of the President (Executive Office) at a rate payable for level II, and specified high-level presidential or vice presidential appointees, for one year after such person's termination of service or employment, from: (1) knowingly making, with intent to influence, any communication or appearance before any Member, officer, or employee of Congress on behalf of any other person seeking action by such a Member in his or her official capacity; or (2) holding a supervisory position over any person who is likely to make such a communication or appearance. Sets forth a similar prohibition with respect to any person whose position is listed at level I of the Executive Schedule, who is employed in a full-time, noncareer position in the Executive Office, or who is a full-time, noncareer presidential, vice presidential, or agency head appointee in an executive agency whose rate of basic pay is not less than $110,000 and is not an appointee of the senior foreign service or a uniformed service commissioned officer. Prohibits any Member of Congress, elected officer of either House, or congressional employee with a rate of pay of $110,000 or above, for one year after leaving office or employment, from: (1) knowingly making, with intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before the President, Vice President, or any officer or employee of a department or agency on behalf of any other person seeking official action; or (2) holding a supervisory position over any person who is likely to make such a communication or appearance.

	</summary>
</bill>
