<bill session="103" type="h" number="3968" updated="2010-04-19T09:29:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-17">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-03-17" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violent Repeat Offender Incarceration Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Violent Repeat Offender Incarceration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to States to assist in the incarceration of violent repeat offenders and to manage the problems associated with overcapacity in correctional facilities and programs and to support comprehensive programs that will reduce the rate of recidivism.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405775"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-09"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-03-17"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25T15:51:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 103-462.</text></action>
		<calendar number="255" datetime="1994-03-25T15:52:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 255.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSJU-03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3963" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Correctional institutions"/>
		<term name="County politics and government"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Interstate compacts"/>
		<term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Prison administration"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Punishment"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/25/1994--Reported to House amended. Violent Repeat Offender Incarceration Act - Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to individual States and to States organized as multi-State compacts to develop, expand, modify or improve (develop) correctional facilities and programs to ensure that prison cell space is available for the confinement of violent repeat offenders. Sets eligibility requirements for such grants, including assurances that: (1) the States have implemented, or will implement, correctional policies and programs designed to provide sufficiently severe punishment for violent repeat offenders, including violent juvenile offenders, and that the prison time served is appropriately related to the determination that the inmate is a violent repeat offender and is for a period deemed necessary to protect the public; (2) the States have implemented policies that provide for recognition of victims' rights and needs; (3) funds received will be used to develop correctional facilities and programs to ensure that prison space is available for the confinement of violent repeat offenders and will be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal, State, and local funds; (4) the States have a comprehensive correctional plan which represents an integrated approach to the management and operation of correctional facilities and programs and meets specified requirements; and (5) the States have involved counties and other units of local government, when appropriate, in the development of correctional facilities and programs designed to ensure the incarceration of violent offenders. Directs the Attorney General, in making such grants, to give special consideration to the special burden placed on States which incarcerate a substantial number of inmates who are in the United States illegally. Authorizes the Attorney General to request: (1) the Directors of the National Institute of Corrections (NIC) and the Federal Bureau of Prisons to provide technical assistance and training to States that receive a grant under this Act to achieve the purposes of this Act; and (2) the Director of the NIC to assist with an evaluation of programs established with funds under this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
