<bill session="103" type="h" number="3962" updated="2010-04-19T09:28:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lower Mississippi Delta Initiatives Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Energy to undertake initiatives to address certain needs in the Lower Mississippi Delta Region, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400402"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-11"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>See S.21.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF-03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy and Power" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4043" />
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4043" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4224" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="21" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
		<term name="Aquaculture"/>
		<term name="Archaeology"/>
		<term name="Arkansas"/>
		<term name="Biomass energy"/>
		<term name="Black colleges"/>
		<term name="Black history"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Career education"/>
		<term name="Colleges"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cultural centers"/>
		<term name="Cultural property"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy industries"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Humanities"/>
		<term name="Illinois"/>
		<term name="Indians"/>
		<term name="Industry-university relations"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Kentucky"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Louisiana"/>
		<term name="Low-income housing"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Mathematics"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Mississippi"/>
		<term name="Missouri"/>
		<term name="Museums"/>
		<term name="Music"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Regional economic development"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural conditions"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Scientific education"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Technical education"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology policy"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Tennessee"/>
		<term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women scientists"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Initiatives Within the Department of the Interior Title II: Initiatives Within the Department of Energy Lower Mississippi Delta Initiatives Act of 1994 - Title I: Initiatives Within the Department of the Interior - Establishes within the Department of the Interior an Office of Education to: (1) promote education in selected areas of environmental, natural, historic, and cultural resources; and (2) establish initiatives at minority schools of higher education. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) submit annual status reports to the Congress regarding the inventory and coordination of Departmental education programs; (2) report annually to certain congressional committees on opportunities for minority schools of higher education to participate in Departmental programs; (3) establish a scholarship program for degrees in natural resource and environmental related fields at minority schools of higher learning in the Lower Mississippi Delta Region; (4) encourage pre-college education programs in designated subject areas; (5) implement a volunteer educational enrichment program in cooperation with State departments of education and local school districts in the Delta Region; (6) establish a Center for Excellence in the Sciences and a Center for Aquaculture to encourage women and minority students in the Delta Region to pursue careers in the sciences and in aquaculture; and (7) coordinate the educational programs under this Act with those of other Federal agencies. (Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary to transmit to the Congress: (1) a study of nationally significant sites within the Delta Region; (2) recommendations for a transportation network linking such sites; and (3) a study outlining recommendations for funding a Delta Region Native American Heritage Corridor and Heritage and Cultural Center, and a Delta Region African American Heritage Corridor and Heritage and Cultural Center (including a Music Heritage Program). Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to State Humanities Councils to assist minority and rural museums and related associations in the Delta region. (Sec. 105) Directs the Secretary to provide technical and financial assistance to historically Black colleges and universities to undertake: (1) a survey of historic and prehistoric structures on campus; and (2) their preservation. (Sec. 106) Directs the Secretary to: (1) transmit to the Congress a feasibility study regarding the establishment of a Delta Antiquities Trail or Delta Antiquities Heritage Corridor; and (2) conduct a research and preservation program of significant historic and archaeological resources in the Delta. (Sec. 108) Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Initiatives Within the Department of Energy - Directs the Secretary of Energy (the Secretary) to establish the Delta Energy Technology and Business Development Center (the Center). Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to the Center. (Sec. 203) Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to require the Secretary to make grants to schools or hospitals for energy conservation projects, and to provide supplemental Federal financing for energy conservation projects at schools and hospitals in the Delta Region. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 204) Requires the Secretary to: (1) report annually to certain congressional committees regarding opportunities for minority colleges and universities to participate in Department of Energy (DOE) activities and laboratories; (2) establish scholarship programs for students pursuing energy-related and/or technical disciplines either at minority colleges or universities in the Delta Region; (3) encourage pre-college programs in energy-related and/or technical disciplines; (4) implement a volunteer program for education at DOE; and (5) implement a program to encourage women and minority students in the Delta Region to pursue careers in technical disciplines. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 205) Directs the Secretary to conduct a research and demonstration program to determine the economic viability of integrated biomass energy systems within the Delta Region. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 206) Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to direct the Secretary to make grants to States and Indian tribal organizations in the Delta Region for weatherization of low-income dwelling units. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 207) Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to qualify for incentive payments certain renewable energy facilities owned by the Tennessee Valley Authority.

	</summary>
</bill>
