<bill session="103" type="h" number="3974" updated="2010-04-19T09:30:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Trade in Insurance Services Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for fair trade in insurance services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400236"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E373-374)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-11"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-14"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign corporations"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="International finance"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Reciprocity"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/1994--Introduced.
Fair Trade in Insurance Services Act of 1994 - Directs the President to: (1) identify foreign countries that deny national treatment to U.S. insurance organizations; and (2) determine whether such denial has a significant adverse effect on them. Requires the President, when making such determinations, to consider specified factors, including: (1) the ability and extent to which U.S. insurance organizations can operate or seek to operate in the foreign country's market; (2) the importance of operations by such organizations in the foreign country to the export of goods and services by U.S. firms to such country; (3) the extent to which such organizations may conduct activities or provide services in the foreign country that insurance organizations organized under such foreign country's laws may not conduct or provide there; and (4) the extent to which such U.S. organizations are affected in their operations and ability to compete on an equal basis in such foreign country's market. Authorizes the President to recommend to the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary) that the Secretary suspend the acceptance of, or not accept, a certain registration statement filed by a person of an identified foreign country if the President determines that: (1) such action would assist the United States in negotiations to eliminate denials of national treatment against U.S. insurance organizations; (2) such negotiations are not likely to result in an agreement to eliminate such denial; or (3) the country has not adhered to such an agreement. Prohibits such sanctions with respect to any registration filed by an alien insurance organization which does business in the United States as of March 8, 1994. Requires the President to report biennially to the Congress on: (1) foreign countries that deny national treatment to U.S. insurance companies; and (2) the results of any negotiations with respect to the elimination of such treatment denials. (Sec. 3) Prohibits alien insurance organizations from engaging in insurance activities within the United States unless certain registration and related requirements are met.

	</summary>
</bill>
