<bill session="103" type="h" number="3980" updated="2010-04-19T09:31:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To support and assist drug courts.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-11"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug testing"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
		<term name="Social services"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/1994--Introduced.
Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to State and local governments and to other public and private entities for programs that involve continuing judicial supervision over specified categories of persons with substance abuse problems and the integrated administration of other sanctions and services, including: (1) testing for the use of controlled substances or other addictive substances; (2) substance abuse treatment; (3) diversion, probation, or other supervised release involving the possibility of prosecution, confinement, or incarceration based on noncompliance with program requirements or failure to show satisfactory progress; and (4) programmatic or health related aftercare services such as relapse prevention, education, vocational training, job placement, housing placement, and child care or other family support services. Authorizes the Attorney General to consult or collaborate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and any other appropriate officials and utilize any component of the Department of Justice in carrying out this Act. Sets forth grant application requirements. Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) provide technical assistance and training in furtherance of the purposes of this Act; and (2) evaluate programs that receive support under this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
