<bill session="103" type="h" number="3997" updated="2010-04-19T09:33:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Balanced Economic and Environmental Priorities Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the preparation of economic impact analyses with respect to certain actions to protect endangered species and threatened species, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400113"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business losses"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Eminent domain"/>
		<term name="Endangered species"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Indemnity"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Losses"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Unemployment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1994--Introduced.
Balanced Economic and Environmental Priorities Act of 1994 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to prohibit a Federal officer or employee from implementing or enforcing a designation of critical habitat, an issued protective regulation, or a developed recovery plan under such Act unless the Secretary (either the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as program responsibilities are vested): (1) prepares an economic impact analysis with respect to such designation, regulation, or recovery plan; (2) determines that the benefits of it outweigh the costs of it; and (3) publishes an economic impact statement describing the findings of the analysis. Establishes guidelines for such economic impact analysis. Directs the Secretary to: (1) limit economic losses incurred by persons caused by listing species as endangered or threatened; and (2) compensate such persons for any diminishments in the value of tangible or intangible property, and in the loss or diminishment of a job. Requires congressional approval of any additions to the endangered species list. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) review endangered or threatened species added on or after such date to a published list of endangered or threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973; (2) prepare an economic impact analysis and statement with respect to them; and (3) publish a list of all designations of critical habitat, regulations, and recovery plans in effect on the date of that publication (the implementation and enforcement of which is prohibited by the amendments made by this Act). Prohibits a person from being paid for any loss incurred by species being added to a list of endangered species or threatened species published under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 during the period beginning January 1, 1986, and ending on the enactment of this Act, except for losses resulting from the implementation or enforcement of designations of critical habitat, regulations, and recovery plans that are not included in the list published under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
