<bill session="103" type="h" number="3998" updated="2010-04-19T09:34:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Check Cashing Consumer Protection Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the consumers of check cashing services by encouraging States to establish uniform laws on the regulation of check cashing services and to require the Secretary of the Treasury to study the effectiveness of State efforts with respect to such regulation and make appropriate recommendations to the Congress on such efforts.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404190"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-18"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Checks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Financial services"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Money laundering"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1994--Introduced.
Check Cashing Consumer Protection Act of 1994 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that States should: (1) establish uniform laws for licensing and regulating businesses which are not depository institutions and which provide check cashing services, transmit money, or issue or redeem money orders, travelers' checks, and similar instruments; and (2) provide sufficient resources to the appropriate State agency to enforce such laws and regulations. Asks the States to develop a model statute which includes, with respect to such businesses: (1) licensing requirements and standards; (2) procedures to ensure compliance with Federal cash transaction reporting requirements; and (3) criminal penalties for operation of such a business without a license. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and report to the Congress on the States' progress in developing and enacting a model statute meeting appropriate requirements and recommendations for appropriate legislative and administrative action, including possible incentives or sanctions for States failing to enact an appropriate model statute or failing to enforce such statute.

	</summary>
</bill>
