<bill session="103" type="h" number="4001" updated="2010-04-19T09:34:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gun Dealer Responsibility Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for tort liability of firearms dealers who transfer firearms in violation of Federal firearms law.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E406)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Retail trade"/>
		<term name="Torts"/>
		<term name="Wholesale trade"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1994--Introduced.
Gun Dealer Responsibility Act of 1994 - Authorizes any person suffering bodily injury or death as a result of the discharge of a firearm to bring an action in any U.S. district court against any dealer who transferred the firearm to a person in violation of Federal firearms provisions for damages and such other relief as the court deems appropriate. Directs the court to allow a prevailing plaintiff a reasonable attorney fee as part of the costs. Provides that the defendant in such an action shall be held liable in tort, without regard to fault or proof of defect, for all direct and consequential damages that arise from bodily injury or death proximately resulting from the illegal sale of a firearm if it is established by a preponderance of the evidence that the defendant transferred the firearm to any person in violation of Federal firearms provisions. Makes exceptions where it is established by a preponderance of the evidence that: (1) the plaintiff suffered the injury while committing a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding one year; or (2) the injury was suffered as a result of the discharge by a law enforcement officer or a member of the armed forces in the performance of official duties. Specifies that this Act shall not be construed to limit the scope of any other cause of action available to a person injured as a result of the discharge of a firearm.

	</summary>
</bill>
