<bill session="103" type="h" number="4032" updated="2010-04-19T09:39:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-17">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-03-17" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide the penalty of death for certain crimes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice Forwarded an Original Measure to Full Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-03-17"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25T19:16:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 103-466. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text></action>
		<calendar number="258" datetime="1994-03-25T19:17:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 258.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Air piracy"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Artificial satellites"/>
		<term name="Assassination"/>
		<term name="Automobile theft"/>
		<term name="Bank robberies"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Child molesting"/>
		<term name="Child pornography"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Criminal negligence"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Equality before the law"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Family violence"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
		<term name="Genocide"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Hijacking"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Hostages"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Judicial officers"/>
		<term name="Juries"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Labor disputes"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Local officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Mass destruction weapons"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Offshore structures"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Postal service"/>
		<term name="Prison violence"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Protection of foreign officials"/>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Rape"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Sabotage"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="Sex offenders"/>
		<term name="Space activities"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Torture"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Treason"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Weapons systems"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/25/1994--Reported to House amended. Provides for imposition of the death penalty where a defendant has been found guilty of: (1) treason or gathering or delivering defense information to aid a foreign government; (2) an offense for which the death sentence is provided if the defendant intentionally killed the victim, inflicted serious bodily injury that resulted in the victim's death, participated in an act contemplating that the life of a person would be taken or intending that lethal force would be used and the victim died as a direct result, or engaged in an act of violence knowing that the act created a grave risk of death such that participation in the act constituted reckless disregard for human life and the victim consequently died; and (3) certain drug-related offenses committed as part of a continuing criminal enterprise involving twice the amount of drugs or money required under present law to mandate a sentence of life imprisonment or involving an attempt or directed attempt to kill a public officer, juror, witness, or member of the family or household of such a person in order to obstruct investigation or prosecution of the offense. Prohibits sentencing to death a person under age 18 at the time of the offense. Amends the Federal criminal code to limit imposition of the death sentence in espionage cases to situations where the jury (or court, if there is no jury) finds that the offense resulted in the identification and killing of a U.S. agent by a foreign power, or directly concerned nuclear weaponry, satellites, and specified other defense-related information. Makes conforming amendments to authorize imposition of the death penalty for various offenses where death results, including: (1) hostage taking; (2) murder for hire; (3) murder or kidnapping in aid of racketeering activity; (4) genocide; (5) carjacking; (6) sexual abuse; (7) sexual exploitation of children; (8) homicides involving firearms in Federal facilities; (9) murder of Federal witnesses; (10) civil rights murders; (11) murder by Federal prisoners, or by escaped prisoners; (12) drive-by-shootings; (13) gun murders during Federal crimes of violence and drug trafficking crimes; (14) murder of State or local officials assisting Federal law enforcement officials and State correctional officers; (15) use of weapons of mass destruction; (16) violence at international airports; (17) violence against maritime navigation or fixed platforms; and (18) torture. Sets forth: (1) penalties for attempted killings of court officers and jurors, and for attempted retaliatory killings of witnesses, victims, and informants; and (2) procedures regarding prosecutions for the foreign murder of U.S. nationals. Makes an exception to the requirement that a person charged with a capital offense be furnished with a list of veniremen and witnesses if the court finds by a preponderance of the evidence that providing such list may jeopardize the life or safety of any person.

	</summary>
</bill>
