<bill session="103" type="h" number="4058" updated="2010-04-19T09:43:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Towing Safety Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, to improve the safety of towing vessels.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1994-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="1994-06-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E454-455)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Navigation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee On Merchant Marine.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Navigation" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Merchant Marine" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Marine transportation"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for marine accidents"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Maps"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Merchant seamen"/>
		<term name="Navigational aids"/>
		<term name="Passenger ships"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Tugboats"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/16/1994--Introduced.
Towing Safety Act - Amends Federal law to subject towing vessels to certain safety inspection requirements. Exempts a vessel from such requirements if it is: (1) used for towing disabled vessels; or (2) not used to pull, push, or haul alongside a barge that is subject to inspection. Requires the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to prescribe regulations requiring the installation of certain navigational and safety equipment on towing vessels. (Sec. 3) Requires certain passenger vessels subject to inspection to maintain a minimum number of licensed masters and mates. Authorizes the Secretary to classify merchant seamen licenses and certificates of registry based on, among other factors, barge tonnage, and barge number or configuration. Authorizes the issuance of a license as a master or mate of a towing vessel only to an individual who has demonstrated proficiency in: (1) using certain navigational and safety equipment; and (2) operating such vessel, or has completed a Coast Guard-approved towing vessel simulator course. Sets forth conforming licensing requirements. Requires individuals employed on merchant vessels of at least five (currently, 100) gross tons to have a a merchant mariner's document authorizing service in the capacity for which the individual is employed. Exempts from such licensing requirements individuals employed on small passenger vessels or uninspected passenger vessels. Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations which exempt employment categories from such licensing requirements. Authorizes: (1) such regulations to exempt an employment category from such licensing requirements only if the responsibilities of such employed individual do not relate to the safe operation of a merchant vessel; and (2) the employment of unlicensed individuals upon such vessel for a 60-day period. Requires a specified percentage of the new crew employed on passenger vessels of at least 100 gross tons to be able seamen. Includes &quot;able seaman-towing vessel&quot; as a classification authorized for endorsement as able seamen. Declares that an individual may be rated as &quot;able seaman-towing vessel&quot; if he has at least 18 months' service on deck on board towing vessels operating in U.S. navigable waters, including the Great Lakes. (Sec. 4) Requires marine casualties to be reported as soon as practicable, but in no case later than within five days. (Currently, within five days.) Increases penalties for an individual in charge of a vessel for failing to report a casualty. Creates a presumption of liability for individuals in charge of a vessel who unreasonably fail to provide assistance to an individual in danger of being lost as a result of a collision between two or more vessels.

	</summary>
</bill>
