<bill session="103" type="h" number="405" updated="2010-04-19T00:03:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bank and Thrift Disclosure Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require public disclosure of examination reports of certain failed depository institutions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="1993-03-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-01"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Bank capital"/>
		<term name="Bank directors"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank failures"/>
		<term name="Bank holding companies"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Credit unions"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Deposit insurance"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Public records"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
		<term name="Whistle blowing"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Bank and Thrift Disclosure Act of 1993 - Requires each appropriate banking agency to disclose to the public the reports of all examinations of each failed depository institution performed during the five-year period preceding its transfer, failure, or receipt of certain Federal depository insurance (or other Federal &quot;bail-out&quot; funds). Limits such disclosure requirement to an institution that received such funds while it was critically undercapitalized within the one-year period before its failure. Cites conditions under which public disclosure may be delayed because of threats to safety, soundness, or pending administrative, civil, or criminal investigations. Subjects a holding company of such a failed institution to the same public disclosure requirements, but excludes open institutions and affiliated solvent institutions. Mandates public disclosure of settlement agreements between the Resolution Trust Corporation or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and any other party with respect to certain failed depository institutions. Applies the public disclosure requirements of this Act to specified kinds of failed institutions. Shields certain identifying and customer information from the disclosure requirements. Requires the appropriate banking agencies to: (1) make public disclosures of loans by insiders (senior personnel and principal shareholders) who have defaulted on loans made by a failed institution; and (2) provide the public with periodic updates of pending and settled lawsuits brought by such agencies involving transactions that caused a material loss to either the failed depository institution or to the deposit insurance fund. Directs the Comptroller General to selectively audit examination reports and public disclosures made by the appropriate banking agencies to assess their compliance with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
