<bill session="103" type="h" number="4072" updated="2010-04-19T09:45:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Amendments Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to minimize the adverse effects of employment dislocation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404220"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400300" joined="1994-08-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-14"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Employment"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Part-time employment"/>
		<term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Subpoena"/>
		<term name="Wage restitution"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/17/1994--Introduced.
Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Amendments Act - Amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Act to cover employers of 50 or more employees (currently 100). Covers single-site plant closings or mass layoffs affecting 25 or more employees (currently 500 or more, or 50 or more if this comprises one-third of the workers at the site). Eliminates the single-site requirement for plant closings or mass layoffs affecting 100 or more employees, thus covering such closings or layoffs by one employer regardless of the number of sites involved. Specifies that the 90-day aggregate rule covers all related layoffs within that period, whether or not they are each above or below the threshold levels. Extends coverage to part-time employees. (Sec. 3) Revises the notice period based on the number of employees affected: (1) 25-49, 30 days; (2) 50-99, 60 days; and (3) 100 or more, 90 days. (The current period is 60 days.) Requires employer notice to each affected employee (as well as to the employee representative, if there is one). (Sec. 4) Revises and adds enforcement requirements. Adds to employer liability for violations: (1) interest on back pay owed; and (2) an additional amount as liquidated damages equal to the back pay and interest. Limits a good faith exemption to reduction of liability for interest and for a civil penalty. Limits the maximum period for which liability may be calculated. Allows aggrieved employees to enforce employer liability by bringing suit and/or filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor. Directs the Secretary to investigate and resolve such complaints. Authorizes the Secretary to bring civil actions on behalf of the employee for back pay, interest, benefits, and liquidated damages. Establishes a two-year statute of limitations. (Sec. 5) Requires employers to post notices to employees of pertinent provisions of the Act and information on filing complaints. Establishes fines for willful violations of such posting requirement.

	</summary>
</bill>
