<bill session="103" type="h" number="4081" updated="2010-04-19T09:47:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Congressional Office for Public Opinion Research and Assessment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400591"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400906" joined="1994-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1994-03-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional allowances"/>
		<term name="Congressional mail"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Interactive media"/>
		<term name="Public opinion"/>
		<term name="Public opinion polls"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Teleconferencing"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/17/1994--Introduced.
Establishes the Congressional Office for Public Opinion Research and Assessment to set out research priorities and methods for choosing research topics. Requires the Board of the Office to establish an Advisory Council to advise the Board on research priorities and methods which are the most promising and cost effective to pursue and to keep itself informed on the state-of-the-art of opinion research (including such developments as interactive television, electronic fora and town meetings, computer network conferencing, and all methods for enhancing democracy in this country). Requires the Director of the Office to set up an expert, ad hoc panel for each survey to assist in design and analysis. Requires a report to be prepared at the conclusion of each survey including a master questionnaire containing the questions as asked, with frequencies or percentage responses and an analysis prepared by the advisory panel with the assistance of in-house or contractor personnel. Requires the survey, along with its data, to be made public to the news media and to organizations and individuals specializing in public policy or opinion. Makes FY 1994 appropriations for the Office. Rescinds specified appropriations earmarked for official mail costs in the Senate and for such costs, salaries, and expenses earmarked for the House of Representatives for FY 1994.

	</summary>
</bill>
