<bill session="103" type="h" number="4085" updated="2010-04-19T09:47:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Amendments of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 to reauthorize appropriations for fiscal years 1996 through 1999, remove impediments to the exercise of States' discretion to shape their programs and to concentrate their resources on those with the greatest home energy needs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400595"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="404220" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="409793" joined="1994-03-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy and Power"/><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Energy Conservation and Power Prior to Referral.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-18"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>See H.R.4250.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF-03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy and Power" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4250" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Energy law and legislation"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
		<term name="Households"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/17/1994--Introduced.
Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Amendments of 1994 - Amends Federal law with respect to Home Energy Assistance to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to States to assist low-income households, particularly those that pay a high proportion of household income, both for meeting immediate energy needs and in attaining the capacity to meet such needs independently in the future. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes appropriations for home energy assistance needs arising from a natural disaster or other emergency. Modifies the authorized uses of funds including: (1) outreach activities and assistance particularly to low income households that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy; (2) intervention in energy crisis situations; (3) low-cost residential weatherization; and (4) State program planning and development, including leveraging programs. Authorizes the States to give priority to households with the highest home energy burdens. Requires State applications for assistance to include a plan which targets assistance to households with high home energy burdens. Repeals the prohibition against the Secretary's prescription of the manner in which the States will comply with the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981. Requires State applications for assistance to include: (1) a plan which describes which Department of Energy rules for Low Income Weatherization Assistance Program the State will follow with respect to repairs and improvements; and (2) specified data on the households assisted under this Act. Requires each State to notify the Secretary of any amounts that remain unobligated prior to the close of the fiscal year.

	</summary>
</bill>
