<bill session="103" type="h" number="4097" updated="2010-04-19T09:49:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Depository Institution Service Corporation Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the Federal regulation of depository institution service corporations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400236"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-07"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Bank capital"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Financial services"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Investments"/>
		<term name="Investors"/>
		<term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/21/1994--Introduced.
Depository Institution Service Corporation Reform Act of 1994 - Title I: Bank Service Corporation Act Amendments - Amends the Bank Service Corporation Act to place insured depository institutions under its jurisdiction and rename such Act the &quot;Depository Institutions Service Corporation Act.&quot; Allows an insured depository institution to invest in more than one depository institution service corporation. Prescribes investment limits, and reduces from five percent to three percent the percentage of total assets that may be so invested. Requires a depository institution service corporation to obtain prior written approval of the appropriate Federal banking agency before paying management fees to an institution-affiliated party (or to any corporation owned by such party). Prohibits a depository institution service corporation from performing activities or services that are not permissible for a national bank.

	</summary>
</bill>
