<bill session="103" type="h" number="4110" updated="2010-04-19T09:51:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the imposition of enhanced criminal penalties for carrying a firearm during and in relation to a crime of violence.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411677"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-29"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	
3/22/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for the imposition of enhanced criminal penalties for carrying a firearm during and in relation to a crime of violence. Prohibits the court from imposing a probationary sentence on, or suspending the sentence of, any individual convicted of such a violation or from making any term of imprisonment so imposed run concurrently with any other term of imprisonment, including that imposed for the crime of violence in which the firearm was carried. Permits: (1) any individual age 65 or older who has been imprisoned for at least ten years pursuant to a sentence imposed under this Act to petition the court for suspension of the remainder of such sentence of imprisonment; and (2) the court to suspend the remainder of such sentence upon determining that the person does not pose a danger to the community.

	</summary>
</bill>
