<bill session="103" type="h" number="4111" updated="2010-04-19T09:51:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-19">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-07-19" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Amtrak Investment Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Amtrak Investment Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410567"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E507)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-07-19"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11T17:59:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 103-698.</text></action>
		<calendar number="380" datetime="1994-08-11T17:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 380.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="2002" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Air pollution"/>
		<term name="Air quality"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Capital investments"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Connecticut"/>
		<term name="Cost accounting"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Highspeed trains"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="New York City"/>
		<term name="Postal facilities"/>
		<term name="Railroad commuting traffic"/>
		<term name="Railroad electrification"/>
		<term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
		<term name="Railroad terminals"/>
		<term name="Railroads and state"/>
		<term name="Rhode Island"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Transportation and the physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/11/1994--Reported to House amended. Amtrak Investment Act of 1994 - Amends Federal transportation law to make it a goal of the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (AMTRAK) to manage its capital investment in such a way as to provide its customers with world class service. (Sec. 4) Requires AMTRAK to include in its annual report on its operations to the President and the Congress projections of anticipated and realized benefits of proposed and previously funded projects. (Sec. 5) Requires applications by a State, agency, or person requesting AMTRAK to provide rail passenger transportation, or to keep a train, route, or service that AMTRAK intends to discontinue, to commit it to provide at least 65 percent of the long-term loss (currently, short-term loss) of providing such transportation in the first year, and at least 55 percent of such loss in each succeeding year. Requires a State, agency, or person, with respect to the renewal of such service, to state that it agrees to pay at least 55 percent of the long-term avoidable losses of operating such service and at least 50 percent of the associated capital costs. Authorizes AMTRAK for each year of operation to contribute no more than 55 percent of the long-term avoidable losses in the first year of operation, and no more than 45 percent in each succeeding year. Directs the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to review AMTRAK's State-assisted rail passenger services program and report the results, including recommendations for revising such program, to the Congress. (Sec. 6) Directs AMTRAK to make capital improvements for the Northeast Corridor improvement project necessary for reliable, high- speed rail passenger service and enhancement of capacity for intercity and commuter passenger service. Requires AMTRAK to construct an electrification system between Boston, Massachusetts, and New Haven, Connecticut, to accommodate the installation of a third mainline track between Davisville and Central Falls, Rhode Island, to be used for double-stack freight service to and from the Port of Davisville. Requires AMTRAK to report to the Congress on its electrification design between Davisville and Central Falls, Rhode Island. (Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations for: (1) capital acquisition and corridor development; (2) AMTRAK operating expenses; (3) AMTRAK operating losses; and (4) certain mandatory payments. (Sec. 8) Directs AMTRAK to establish a Capital and Equipment Acquisition Account. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress on the on-time performance of AMTRAK as compared to other modes of commercial transportation. (Sec. 10) Requires AMTRAK to cooperate with the Virginia State Department of Transportation on a study of the feasibility of reestablishing rail service between Washington, D.C., and Bristol, Virginia. (Sec. 11) Requires AMTRAK to develop plans for new station facilities at the Burbank-Glendale-Pasadena Airport and in Ontario, California. (Sec. 13) Confirms the conveyance of U.S. interests in certain real property to Tulare County, California.

	</summary>
</bill>
