<bill session="103" type="h" number="4128" updated="2010-04-19T09:54:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sarah Weber Home Infusion Consumer Protection Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require providers of home infusion therapy services to be licensed and to limit physician referrals for services in which the physician has a financial interest.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404083" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400502" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="410407" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="1994-05-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1964)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-31"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Chemotherapy"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Medical ethics"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/24/1994--Introduced.
Sarah Weber Home Infusion Consumer Protection Act of 1994 - Prohibits any: (1) person from providing home infusion therapy services in a State unless the person is licensed by the State to provide such services; and (2) State from licensing such a person unless the person meets licensing standards to be established by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Specifies that a licensed person shall only provide services to an individual who is under the care of, and under a plan established and periodically reviewed by, a physician. Sets forth licensing requirements, including having been determined capable of providing services, maintaining clinical records, adhering to written protocols and policies, making services available seven days a week on a 24-hour basis, coordinating services with the patient's physician, conducting a quality assessment and assurance program, assuring that only trained personnel provide infusion products, assuming responsibility for the quality of services provided by others under arrangements with such person, and establishing appropriate protocols and explaining such protocols clearly to patients before the initiation of treatment. Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) cancellation of services; (2) limits on fees; and (3) enforcement of Act requirements. Prohibits a physician (or an immediate family member) who has a financial relationship with a specified entity under the Medicare program from making a referral to such entity for the furnishing of such services. Makes Medicare physician ownership and referral provisions applicable to this Act. Specifies that the prescription of a drug to be administered through home infusion shall constitute a referral by a physician.

	</summary>
</bill>
