<bill session="103" type="h" number="4147" updated="2010-04-19T09:57:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hudson and Mohawk Rivers National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Hudson and Mohawk Rivers National Heritage Corridor in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400268"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-27"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="New York State"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Regional planning"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Signs and signboards"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/24/1994--Introduced.
Hudson and Mohawk Rivers National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 - Establishes the Hudson and Mohawk Rivers National Heritage Corridor in New York. Establishes the Hudson and Mohawk Rivers National Heritage Corridor Commission to assist appropriate Federal, State, and local authorities and regional planning organizations in the development and implementation of an integrated resource management plan for the Corridor. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire any property within the Corridor or any interest therein if such property is: (1) designated for acquisition in the plan or as a key site in the National Historic Landmark Theme Study on American Labor History; (2) listed in the National Register of Historic Places; or (3) determined by the Secretary to be of national significance. Prohibits the Secretary from acquiring the fee simple title to any property without the owner's consent. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
