<bill session="103" type="h" number="4166" updated="2010-04-19T10:00:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Payment Formula Reauthorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to revise and reauthorize the use of a formula based on adjusted District General Fund revenues as the basis for determining the amount of the annual Federal payment to the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400571"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1994-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="1994-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="1994-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fiscal Affairs and Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House District of Columbia" subcommittee="Fiscal Affairs and Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Federal-city relations"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Municipal budgets"/>
		<term name="Municipal finance"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/12/1994--Introduced.
Federal Payment Formula Reauthorization Act of 1994 - Amends the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to provide that the authorization of appropriations for the annual Federal payment to the District of Columbia for FY 1996 through 1998 shall be an amount equal to 24 percent of the adjusted District General Fund revenues for the second fiscal year preceding such fiscal year, as such revenues are reported in the audited financial report of the District of Columbia and as reviewed by the Comptroller General. Amends the District of Columbia Code to include, in the annual independent audit of the District's financial operations, a report of the adjusted District General Fund revenues for the fiscal year. Requires the Comptroller General to submit to specified congressional committees an annual review of such report.

	</summary>
</bill>
