<bill session="103" type="h" number="4213" updated="2010-04-19T10:07:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">River and Watershed Protection and Restoration Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish a national registry of rivers and watersheds to be protected and restored, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1994-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400269" joined="1994-08-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="409400" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400516" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1994-08-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-15"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E669-670)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Credit and Rural Development.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-11"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture" subcommittee="Environment, Credit and Rural Development"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Environment, Credit and Rural Development" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agricultural credit"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Easements"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection groups"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Forest management"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Maps"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Postage stamps"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Soil conservation"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Stream conservation"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetland restoration"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/14/1994--Introduced.
River and Watershed Protection and Restoration Act of 1994 - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish and maintain a National River and Watershed Registry to be comprised of rivers and associated watershed areas whose natural, scenic, cultural, or recreational values are to be protected or restored. Requires the Secretary to promulgate rules establishing criteria for the inclusion of rivers and associated watershed areas on the Registry, including a requirement that the designated State agency or an Indian tribe has submitted a petition for inclusion that contains a strategy specifying methods contributing to the protection and restoration of riverine and riparian resources within the area concerned. (Sec. 303) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) submission of nominations for the inclusion of any river and associated watershed area on the Registry by an appropriate State agency, a governing body of an Indian Tribe, or by a State agency for another entity; (2) inclusion of segments on the Registry; (3) periodic review of strategy implementation; (4) removal from the Registry; and (5) application for assistance under the Act by qualified watershed councils. Requires the appropriate Federal or State department, agency, or instrumentality, before approving or authorizing a planned undertaking that may adversely effect the implementation of a strategy in effect for a river and associated watershed area listed on the Registry, to notify the Secretary, the designated State agency, any affected Indian tribe, the appropriate local governmental officials, and the public. Sets forth conditions under which such approval or authorization may be issued. Exempts an undertaking: (1) determined by a Federal agency to be necessary for national security; (2) in a major disaster area; (3) involving only the repair or reconstruction of a building or facility constructed before the date on which the river and associated watershed area concerned were included on the Registry; or (4) that is required to be undertaken pursuant to Federal or State law. (Sec. 307) Directs the Secretary to: (1) enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to develop and publish standards for the protection and restoration of rivers, associated watershed areas, and riverine and riparian resources; and (2) provide technical assistance to qualified watershed councils, State, tribal and local governments, individuals, and private nonprofit organizations: (1) engaged in the restoration and conservation of rivers and watershed areas listed in the Registry; and (2) proposing to nominate a river or area for the Registry. (Sec. 308) Requires the Secretary to make capitalization grants to the States and Indian Tribes to be deposited in river and watershed restoration and conservation revolving funds established by the State or by the Tribal governing body and to be used by the designated State agency (or by the Indian Tribe) only for carrying out its responsibilities and authorities under this Act and for providing grants and loans to qualified watershed councils or other entities contributing to the applicable strategy. Requires such grants and loans to be used only to carry out projects contributing to the protection or restoration of rivers and associated watershed areas listed on the Registry. Authorizes the Secretary to arrange for the design, printing, and sale of river and watershed restoration stamps. Requires the net proceeds of all such sales to be retained by the Secretary and to be transferred to the revolving fund for the State in which such stamps are sold. Requires the Secretary, if stamps are sold in any State which has not established a revolving fund, to disburse such net proceeds to other States which have established such fund on a pro rata basis according to the volume of stamps sold in such other States. Provides for modified applicability of provisions governing the following with respect to projects or assistance for the protection or restoration of a river or associated watershed area which is listed on the Registry: (1) assistance from the Bureau of Reclamation; (2) the conservation reserve program; (3) the forestry incentives program; (4) the wetlands reserve program; (5) conservation easements; (6) the agricultural conservation program; (7) assistance from the National Park Service; and (8) assistance under the Agricultural Credit Act of 1978. (Sec. 309) Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
