<bill session="103" type="h" number="422" updated="2010-04-19T00:06:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Homicide Violence Reduction and Mediation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to reduce the number of homicides and the incidents of violence by students, ages 13 to 21, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400409"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Community and school"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal statistics"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Curriculum planning"/>
		<term name="Educational counseling"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="School violence"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Urban education"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
		<term name="Youth"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Youth Homicide Violence Reduction and Mediation Act of 1993 - Requires the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) most directly affected by crime and violence, giving priority to LEAs in urban areas in which the homicide rate for youth has increased by more than five percent in comparison to the preceding year or exceeds the State or national homicide rate for youth by more than seven percent. Requires an LEA, to be eligible to receive a grant, to give assurances that it has developed, or is developing, violence reduction and peer counseling programs as part of the educational curriculum at each school. Permits grants to be used for: (1) training programs for teachers and counseling staff to assist students in the effective use of interpersonal and negotiation skills; (2) counseling programs for victims and witnesses of crime in schools; (3) programs for conflict resolution and peer mediation counseling for students, teachers, and other personnel in regular contact with students at school; and (4) training of parents and community members in techniques that reduce violence and promote mediation. Sets forth application and reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
