<bill session="103" type="h" number="4242" updated="2010-04-19T10:12:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enforce the law regulating the height of buildings in the District of Columbia by prohibiting the District of Columbia from issuing any building or occupancy permit for the project described in Zoning Commission Case 93-9C unless the project is modified to conform to such law.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400571" joined="1994-04-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E695)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1069-1070)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Building laws"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Federal-city relations"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/1994--Introduced.
Prohibits the District of Columbia from issuing any building or occupancy permit for the project described in Zoning Commission Case 93-9C, as approved by the Commission for the District on April 11, 1994, unless the project is modified so that: (1) in the building proposed to be constructed under the project, any space above a studio that is used primarily to house servicing equipment for the studio is not more than 110 feet above the applicable measurable point; and (2) any penthouse on such building is set back from the building's exterior or bounding walls by a distance at least equal to the penthouse's height.

	</summary>
</bill>
