<bill session="103" type="h" number="4245" updated="2010-04-19T10:12:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Long-Range Solvency Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the long-range solvency of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409422"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E703-704)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Fire fighters"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Local officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Police"/>
		<term name="Retirement"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/19/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Provisions Relating to Future Entitlements Title II: Provisions Relating to Current and Future Entitlements Title III: Coverage of Newly Hired State and Local Employees Title IV: Social Security Payroll Tax Social Security Long-Range Solvency Act of 1994 - Title I: Provisions Relating to Future Entitlements - Amends title II (Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act with respect to persons who initially become eligible for benefits between the years 2001 through 2051 to adjust the earnings bracket and bend point formula used to determine the primary insurance amount for individuals. Provides for a graduated increase in the &quot;normal&quot; statutory retirement age from age 65 to 67 by the year 2011. Title II: Provisions Relating to Current and Future Entitlements - Reduces the 1995 cost-of-living adjustment. Amends the Internal Revenue Code relating to social security and tier 1 railroad retirement benefits to lower the income thresholds at which 85 percent of social security benefits are subject to income taxation. Title III: Coverage of Newly Hired State and Local Employees - Amends the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code to mandate social security coverage of all State and local government employees hired after January 1, 1995. Title IV: Social Security Payroll Tax - Increases the social security payroll tax over a five-year phase-in period beginning in the year 2020.

	</summary>
</bill>
