<bill session="103" type="h" number="424" updated="2010-04-19T00:06:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pollution Prevention, Community Recycling, and Incinerator Control Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish certain requirements with respect to solid waste and hazardous waste incinerators, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400409"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1993-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E222)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1579)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Air pollution"/>
		<term name="Chlorine"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Compost"/>
		<term name="Electric batteries"/>
		<term name="Electronics"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Food contamination"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Plastics"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Soil pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Waste reduction"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Yard waste"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Pollution Prevention, Community Recycling, and Incinerator Control Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit the issuance of permits for construction or expansion of municipal solid waste incinerators. Prohibits Federal agencies, State or local governments, or other waste management jurisdictions from issuing permits to such incinerators after December 31, 1999, unless the applicant demonstrates that: (1) an annual waste composition analysis of the solid waste generated within the area to be served by the facility is conducted; (2) specified percentages of certain waste categories are diverted to waste management methods other than incineration; (3) the facility will not interfere with diversion rates; (4) it is not feasible to manage the remaining solid waste through source reduction, reuse, or recycling; (5) the facility will not adversely affect the environment, human health, or the local economy and is not situated in a nonattainment area identified under the Clean Air Act; (6) the full cost of the facility over its entire life will be less costly than reducing, recycling, or composting waste; (7) the waste management jurisdiction conducts a public participation process; (8) the proposed construction or expansion is approved by the affected unit of local government; (9) firms operating the facility are in compliance with environmental and public health statutes, have paid outstanding fines for violations of such statutes, and make disclosure statements available; and (10) an approved environmental impact statement is completed. Treats ash from municipal solid waste incinerators as a hazardous waste. Requires such ash to be managed in a monofill that contains only such ash and meets specified design requirements. Prohibits the use of such ash for any purpose. Prohibits the incineration of household hazardous waste, batteries, chlorinated plastics, consumer electronics, and yard waste in such incinerators. Prohibits the issuance of permits or prior approval for the construction or expansion of hazardous waste incinerators unless requirements similar to those for municipal solid waste incinerators have been met. Directs hazardous waste management permit applicants to demonstrate that the State in which the incinerator is located, and each State in which generators of hazardous waste to be incinerated at the facility are located, are implementing toxics use reduction programs. Applies this Act to any facility that burns hazardous waste.

	</summary>
</bill>
