<bill session="103" type="h" number="4269" updated="2010-04-19T10:16:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Investment and Savings Incentive Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce the tax on capital gains of individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400381"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400192" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1994-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="411725" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="403545" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="403864" joined="1994-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Capital gains tax"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Investments"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1994--Introduced.
Economic Investment and Savings Incentive Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a capital gains deduction for noncorporate taxpayers of 60 percent of a three-year capital gain, 40 percent of a two-year capital gain, and 20 percent of a one-year capital gain. Requires indexing, based on the consumer price index, of the adjusted basis of certain assets (corporate stock and tangible property that is a capital asset of property used in a trade or business) that have been held for more than one year at the time of sale or other disposition, solely for the purpose of determining gain or loss. Allows an individual an exclusion from gross income for qualified investment income. Limits such exclusion to individuals whose modified adjusted income does not exceed $50,000 ($25,000 in the case of separate return by a married individual) and at least 50 percent of such income is attributable to earned income. Allows such exclusion in computing alternative minimum tax.

	</summary>
</bill>
