<bill session="103" type="h" number="4261" updated="2010-04-19T10:15:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on International Coordination of Financial Regulation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Commission on International Coordination of Financial Regulation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404634"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2619-2621)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="International Development, Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Financial services"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="International banking"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="International finance"/>
		<term name="Securities regulation"/>
		<term name="Stock exchanges"/>
		<term name="Tax havens"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1994--Introduced.
Commission on International Coordination of Financial Regulation Act - Establishes the Commission on International Coordination of Financial Regulation to: (1) identify the various regulatory bodies and mechanisms pertaining to international capital markets, including those used by governments to manage international capital market instability; (2) appraise the adequacy of cooperation between such various regulators; (3) propose solutions for improving such cooperation; (4) identify the various methods used by countries to enforce capital market regulations and the adequacy of international cooperation; (5) propose solutions for improving global regulatory enforcement of the international financial system; (6) analyze the major clearing and settlement systems and their impact upon the stability of other payments and settlements systems; (7) propose solutions for improving coordination among major clearing and settlements systems; (8) identify and analyze the role of &quot;off-shore tax havens&quot; in the international capital markets; and (9) propose solutions for minimizing any adverse effect that tax havens may have on the international financial system. Directs the Commission to report to the Congress and the President on its findings and recommendations. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
