<bill session="103" type="h" number="4272" updated="2010-04-19T10:16:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to expand the authority of the United States Naval Postgraduate School to admit civilians as students and to authorize the United States Air Force Institute of Technology to admit civilians as students.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400129"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400538" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="404013" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400269" joined="1994-05-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-25"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Forces and Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-25"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-30"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Favorable Executive Comment Received from DOD.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Forces and Personnel" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Air force"/>
		<term name="Civil-military relations"/>
		<term name="Colleges"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational finance"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Military education"/>
		<term name="Navy"/>
		<term name="Service academies"/>
		<term name="Technical education"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1994--Introduced.
Authorizes the Superintendent of the Naval Postgraduate School (currently, the Secretary of the Navy) to enter into agreements with higher educational institutions whereby certain civilian students receive instruction at the School on a tuition-free basis in exchange for officers receiving instruction at the participating institution on the same basis. Expands the list of eligible students to include those lawfully admitted to the Unitedd States to pursue courses in higher education (currently, only U.S. citizens or those lawfully admitted for permanent residence are permitted). Allows others to receive instruction at the School on a cost-reimbursable, space-available basis, with funds received to be used to maintain and operate the School. Provides identical authority for the Commandant of the United States Air Force Institute of Technology, with the approval of the Secretary of the Air Force.

	</summary>
</bill>
