<bill session="103" type="h" number="4270" updated="2010-04-19T10:16:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Education Begins With Families Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Head Start Act to extend authorization of appropriations for programs under that Act, to strengthen provisions designed to provide quality assurance and improvement, to provide for orderly and appropriate expansion of such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411040"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2513)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Alcoholism counseling"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child development"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Indian children"/>
		<term name="Infants"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Literacy programs"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Migrant education"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Social services"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1994--Introduced.
Education Begins with Families Act of 1994 - Amends the Head Start Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish quality standards for Head Start agencies and programs, including standards for performance in providing required health, education, parental involvement, nutritional, social, and other services, for administrative and financial management, and for facilities' condition and location. Provides for monitoring and for corrective actions or terminations if minimum standards are not met. (Sec. 3) Sets forth goals and priorities for training and technical assistance. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to take certain factors into consideration in allocating funds for program expansion. (Sec. 5) Allocates at least 25 percent of certain excess funds to specified quality improvement activities, plus such additional amounts as the Secretary finds necessary. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to carry out a continuing program of research, demonstrations, and evaluations of Head Start programs, including longitudinal studies, and to report on such activities. (Sec. 7) Establishes programs for families with infants and toddlers. Directs the Secretary to make grants for: (1) programs providing family-centered services for low-income families with very young children, designed to promote child development, parental role fulfillment, and movement toward self-sufficiency; and (2) evaluation of, and training and technical assistance for, projects under the Comprehensive Child Development Centers Act of 1988. Gives time-limited priority to certain entities, including Parent-Child Centers receiving assistance under the Head Start Act and programs receiving assistance under the Comprehensive Child Development Centers Act of 1988, and provides for selection of other grant recipients. Repeals the Comprehensive Child Development Centers Act of 1988 because its functions are being consolidated under the Head Start Act. (Sec. 8) Revises parental involvement considerations with respect to designation of new Head Start agencies. Requires agencies to offer to parents of participating children: (1) family literacy services; (2) parenting skills training; (3) nonpunitive discipline training; (4) child development training; (5) communication skills development assistance; and (6) opportunities to share experiences with other parents. Allows agencies also to opt to offer such parents parental social self-sufficiency training, substance abuse counseling, in-home visitation for families at risk of child abuse and neglect, or other partnership in education activities. Requires a family needs assessment, including consultation with the parents, for each participating family. (Sec. 9) Extends the authorization of appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
