<bill session="103" type="h" number="4306" updated="2010-04-19T10:22:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-20">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-07-20" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Risk Assessment Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Risk Assessment Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a comprehensive risk assessment program within the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406420"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400509" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400389" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="410496" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="410589" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400520" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="411065" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400035" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400604" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="401134" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="1994-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400572" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="406024" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1994-04-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2847)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Environment and Aviation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E852-853)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-07-20"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T22:16:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space and Technology. H. Rept. 103-857.</text></action>
		<calendar number="474" datetime="1994-10-07T22:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 474.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Technology, Environment and Aviation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Surveys"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1994--Reported to House amended. Risk Assessment Improvement Act of 1994 - Establishes a Risk Assessment Program in the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Requires the Director of the Program to: (1) develop a process to conduct independent scientific peer review of all risk assessment guidelines developed by EPA; and (2) provide recommendations to the EPA Administrator on risk assessment, research needs, and development of guidelines. Directs the Director to regularly issue risk assessment guidelines. Sets forth contents of such guidelines. Requires the Director to oversee the use of risk assessment guidelines by EPA Program and Regional Offices and ensure consistency in the use of such guidelines as is appropriate in application to various environmental media or hazards. Permits departures from guidelines under specified conditions. Requires the Director to: (1) regularly develop, issue, and update guidance within EPA for any risk characterizations that may be conducted by EPA; and (2) ensure that such characterizations distinguish human health risks from ecological and other risks. Sets forth contents of such guidance. Requires the Director to: (1) promote open dialogue to improve the understanding of risk assessments by decisionmakers and to accurately and clearly communicate risk characterizations; and (2) regularly evaluate risk assessment research and training needs of EPA and develop a strategy and schedule for carrying out such research and training. Provides for, as part of the Program, a two-year study using comparative risk analysis to rank dissimilar environmental risks and provide a common basis for evaluating strategies for reducing or preventing such risks. Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to: (1) periodically survey the manner in which Federal agencies are conducting risk assessment; (2) provide recommendations to the President and the Congress based on such surveys; and (3) establish interagency mechanisms to promote coordination of Federal risk assessment and mechanisms between Federal and State agencies to communicate state-of-the-art risk assessment practices. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress on at least ten environmental research issues: (1) correlating to environmental hazards which are in the category of highest risk; (2) regarding which there are significant scientific uncertainties with respect to the assessment of such risks; and (3) with respect to which uncertainties could be significantly reduced through research. Requires the Administrator to carry out a research program to reduce scientific uncertainties with respect to the assessment of environmental risks posed by identified issues.

	</summary>
</bill>
