<bill session="103" type="h" number="4309" updated="2010-04-19T10:22:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require a local hiring preference for certain defense contracts and subcontracts performed in or near labor surplus areas and closing military bases.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404978"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1994-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1994-04-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Construction workers"/>
		<term name="Defense contracts"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Employee selection"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Public buildings"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/28/1994--Introduced.
Requires each contract or subcontract entered into by the Department of Defense during FY 1995 for construction services to be performed in whole or in part in, or within 30 miles of, a labor surplus area and within 30 miles of a military installation approved for closure or realignment to include provisions requiring the contractor or subcontractor to employ individuals who: (1) are residents of such labor surplus area or the county in which such area is located; and (2) possess or would be able to acquire promptly the necessary skills for any craft or trade needed to perform the contract or subcontract. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to: (1) waive such requirement if it would be inconsistent with the national security objectives of the United States; and (2) allow a contractor to make an exception in the case of a particular craft or trade if there is no individual residing or available for hire in the labor surplus area or county who possesses the skills for that craft or trade.

	</summary>
</bill>
