<bill session="103" type="h" number="4312" updated="2010-04-19T10:23:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Imposing certain restrictions and requirements on the leasing under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act of lands offshore Florida, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406082"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400156" joined="1994-04-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oceanography, Gulf of Mexico, and the Outer Continental Shelf.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-11"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Oceanography, Gulf of Mexico and the Outer Continental Shelf" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="584" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Energy law and legislation"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Continental shelf"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
		<term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Oceanography"/>
		<term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
		<term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
		<term name="Prospecting"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/28/1994--Introduced.
Precludes the Secretary of the Interior from permitting oil and gas development activities in specified parts of the Eastern Gulf of Mexico Planning Area, the Straits of Florida Planning Area, and the South Atlantic Planning Area, unless: (1) certain environmental studies and assessments have been completed; and (2) the Secretary has certified to the Congress that specified environmental information has been obtained which adequately enables the Secretary to implement his or her Federal stewardship of the environment with a minimal level of uncertainty. Prohibits the Secretary from conducting any: (1) oil or gas development activity under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act in a specified part of the Eastern Gulf of Mexico Planning Area; or (2) preleasing activity or lease sale in the three above-mentioned Planning Areas for a specified period. Mandates specified assessments and studies of the Areas addressed by this Act. Establishes the Joint Federal-State Outer Continental Shelf Task Force to request additional studies and surveys as needed to minimize the uncertainty about the effects of preleasing, leasing, and exploration activities. Subjects the first exploration plan submitted after the date of enactment of this Act to the requirements of detailed environmental impact statements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
