<bill session="103" type="h" number="4327" updated="2010-04-19T10:25:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Franked Mail Savings Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate franked mail for the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="405939" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400078" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400015" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401547" joined="1994-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="408618" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="410887" joined="1994-09-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional allowances"/>
		<term name="Congressional candidates"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional mail"/>
		<term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Congressional publications"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/1994--Introduced.
Franked Mail Savings Act - Prohibits a Member, Member-elect, officer, or employee of the House of Representatives from sending franked mail matter. Requires persons previously authorized to use the frank to use postage stamps, postage meters, or other authorized methods of prepayment of postage. Applies this prohibition to mail matter mailed after December 31, 1994. Prohibits the amount provided for official mail costs of the House: (1) for FY 1995 from exceeding 50 percent of the amount made available for FY 1994; and (2) for FY 1996 from exceeding 25 percent of the amount made available for FY 1994. Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991 to prohibit a Member of the House from transferring amounts from his or her Official Expenses Allowance and Clerk Hire Allowance to his or her Official Mail Allowance. Requires any amount provided for official mail costs of the House for FY 1994 that remains unobligated at the end of that fiscal year to be deposited in the Treasury for the sole purpose of deficit reduction. Expresses the intent of the Congress that a Member of, or Member-elect to, the Congress may not mail any mass mailing paid from official funds (currently, as franked mail) if the mass mailing is postmarked fewer than 120 (currently, 60) days immediately before the date of any primary or general election in which the Member is a candidate for reelection. Prohibits appropriated funds from being used to purchase United States Capitol Historical Society calendars for the House.

	</summary>
</bill>
