<bill session="103" type="h" number="4323" updated="2010-04-19T10:24:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require ammunition to bear serial numbers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401494"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-09"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Exhibitions"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Inventories"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to require licensed importers and licensed manufacturers to identify, by means of an engraved serial number, each item of ammunition imported or manufactured by the importer or manufacturer. Makes recordkeeping requirements of licensed importers, manufacturers, dealers, and collectors concerning the disposition of firearms applicable to the disposition of ammunition. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury, without reasonable cause or warrant when necessary to determine the disposition of items of ammunition in the course of a bona fide criminal investigation, to: (1) inspect or examine the inventory and records of a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer; and (2) inspect the inventory and records of a licensed collector. Requires licensed importers, manufacturers, and dealers who conduct business at a temporary location for a gun show to keep records of disposition of ammunition transactions occurring at such location. Limits any inspection or examination of inventory and records at such location to inventory consisting of, or records relating to, firearms (as under current law) and ammunition held or disposed of at such location. Allows establishment of a system of registration of ammunition transactions.

	</summary>
</bill>
