<bill session="103" type="h" number="4332" updated="2010-04-19T10:26:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To set forth the policy of the United States for nuclear nonproliferation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407351"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="1994-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="China"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Fissionable materials"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="France"/>
		<term name="Great Britain"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Military strategy"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Plutonium"/>
		<term name="Russia"/>
		<term name="Russian Republic"/>
		<term name="Weapons systems"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/1994--Introduced.
Declares that it shall be U.S. policy to: (1) develop and maintain a nuclear weapons posture consistent with promoting U.S. nuclear nonproliferation policy objectives; and (2) reduce the proliferation risks posed by the world's stockpile of plutonium. Requires the United States, in order to develop and maintain such a posture, to: (1) withdraw from deployment and dismantle all tactical nuclear weapons in the context of a bilateral agreement with the Russian Federation to eliminate such weapons; (2) adopt a policy of no-first-use of nuclear weapons against countries who are parties to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons or a comparable international regime; and (3) declare its intention to reduce its strategic nuclear arsenal to levels below START II, in the context of similar reductions by the Russian Federation and strategic reductions by the United Kingdom, France, and China. Directs the United States to: (1) choose a weapons-plutonium disposition option that cannot be perceived as representing U.S. approval of separated plutonium fuel cycles; (2) discourage the civil use of plutonium overseas by identifying alternatives to civilian reprocessing of plutonium and pursuing these alternatives; and (3) seek a nondiscriminatory, multilateral, and internationally verifiable treaty that ends production of weapons-usable fissile material for any other purpose.

	</summary>
</bill>
