<bill session="103" type="h" number="4333" updated="2010-04-19T10:26:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain lands in Rocky Mountain National Park as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409954"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409650" joined="1994-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E835-836)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-11"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Colorado River development"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Tunnels"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Water rights"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/1994--Introduced.
Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness Act of 1994 - Designates certain lands in Rocky Mountain National Park, Colorado, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System which, together with specified lands within the Indian Peaks Wilderness, shall be known as the Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness. Reserves water rights in such area sufficient for purposes of the wilderness designation. Provides that this Act shall not be construed to prevent or impede activities under the surface of lands designated as wilderness by this Act to operate, maintain, repair, or replace the Alva B. Adams Tunnel of the Colorado-Big Thompson Project. Repeals provisions authorizing the Bureau of Reclamation to enter and utilize for flowage or other purposes areas within the Park which may be necessary for the development and maintenance of a Government reclamation project.

	</summary>
</bill>
