<bill session="103" type="h" number="4366" updated="2010-04-19T10:31:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to establish a minority graduate mentor program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400438"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="404503" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="402750" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1994-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1994-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Small Business"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on SBA Legislation and the General Economy.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="SBA Legislation and the General Economy" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/5/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a minority graduate mentor program under which a small business concern that is a graduate of the small business and capital ownership development program (graduate concern) may serve as a mentor to small business concerns that are in the developmental stage of such program (developmental stage concern). Makes a participating graduate concern eligible to receive certain contracts upon agreeing to subcontract between 20 and 49 percent of the value of the contract to one or more developmental stage concerns. Requires program regulations to contain, at a minimum: (1) application requirements; (2) selection criteria; (3) procedures for establishing partnerships between graduate concerns and developmental stage concerns; (4) a description of the types of assistance that a graduate concern will provide to a developmental stage concern; (5) monitoring methods to be used by the Administrator to prevent abuse, including a requirement that all participants submit a financial capability statement at least every two years; and (6) procedures to permit a graduate concern and a developmental stage concern to terminate their partnership upon the completion of a contract.

	</summary>
</bill>
