<bill session="103" type="h" number="4378" updated="2010-04-19T10:33:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Hospital Survival Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to equalize the labor and non-labor portions of the standardized amounts used to determine the amount of payment made to rural and urban hospitals under part A of the medicare program for the operating costs of inpatient hospital services, to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the capacity of rural hospitals to provide health services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402657"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1994-05-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3193-3195)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.R.3600.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3600" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Family medicine"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical technology"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural hospitals"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Programs of Health Care Financing Administration Subtitle A: Medicare Program Subtitle B: Other Programs Title II: Programs of Public Health Service Title III: Antitrust Provisions Title IV: Commission on Reducing the Burden of Regulations and Paperwork on Small Rural Hospitals Rural Hospital Survival Act of 1994 - Title I: Programs of Health Care Financing Administration - Subtitle A: Medicare Program - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act regarding guidelines for determining a national adjusted DRG (diagnosis-related group) prospective payment rate to instruct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to compute, for rural hospital discharges, beginning FY 1995, the portion of the average standardized amount attributable to wages and wage-related costs. States that the portion of such amount not attributable to wages and wage-related rural hospital costs shall be equal to such portions of such amount for hospitals in another urban area. Requires the Secretary to adjust the proportion of hospitals' costs taking into account only costs attributable to wages and salaries, employee benefits, and professional fees. (This eliminates payment differentials between urban and rural hospitals.) Expresses the sense of the Congress that payment reductions made to providers under Medicare should be adjusted to reduce their disproportionate impact upon providers in rural areas. Subtitle B: Other Programs - Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987 to extend through FY 1997 the authorization of appropriations for rural health transition grants. Title II: Programs of Public Health Service - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary to make grants to public and private entities for demonstration projects for: (1) telecommunications which make medical advice and technologies available to rural area health professionals; and (2) increased access of rural populations to primary health services. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Antitrust Provisions - Provides antitrust exemption guidelines for certain rural hospitals. Title IV: Commission on Reducing the Burden of Regulations and Paperwork on Small Rural Hospitals - Establishes the Advisory Commission on Reducing the Burden of Regulations and Paperwork on Small Rural Hospitals to analyze and report to the Secretary and the Congress on the impact on such hospitals of governmental regulations and paperwork.

	</summary>
</bill>
