<bill session="103" type="h" number="4382" updated="2010-04-19T10:34:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (Superfund) to provide for the clean up of municipal waste landfill Superfund sites, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400585" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1994-05-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-27"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Natural gas"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to authorize States to submit to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for approval programs for the remediation of qualified municipal waste landfills. Defines a &quot;qualified municipal waste landfill&quot; as a landfill on the National Priorities List (NPL) which is owned by a municipality or a county or is a privately-owned site which has a record of receiving municipal waste. Makes CERCLA provisions inapplicable to releases or threatened releases at landfills covered under approved programs. Directs the President to promulgate regulations governing response actions for State programs that provide for a presumptive remedy based on streamlined site characterization using EPA's Model Municipal Landfill Remedial Investigation and Feasibility Study Guidance and for closure of the site consistent with Subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Includes within such remedy: (1) waste consolidation where feasible if multiple discrete disposal sites can be more economically contained in one unit; (2) final cover; (3) landfill gas and surface water controls; (4) control of leachate where feasible; (5) groundwater monitoring or treatment under specified conditions; (6) controls to prevent future exposure to waste; (7) site security to prevent access; and (8) a post-closure care plan that ensures the integrity of the remedy. Authorizes additional protections as necessary to protect human health and the environment. Provides for reimbursement from the Hazardous Substance Superfund for remediation expenses incurred by a State with an approved program at one qualified municipal waste landfill selected by the State each year. Limits total reimbursement to $2.5 billion. Permits reimbursement for remediation commenced before approval of a program if activities were not completed before January 1, 1994, and the remediation provides protection equivalent to that specified by this Act. Exempts any person who is otherwise liable under CERCLA or other Federal law with respect to a release of a hazardous substance from liability if the State has an approved remediation program. Bars such exemption in cases where: (1) remediation was completed before January 1, 1994; or (2) a person violated any Federal, State, or local law relating to the generation, transportation, or disposal of solid waste which is present at the facility concerned.

	</summary>
</bill>
