<bill session="103" type="h" number="4408" updated="2010-04-19T10:38:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-11">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-08-11" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Russian River Fisheries and Riverbed Restoration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect and restore the anadromous fish habitat in the Russian River of Northern California and its tributaries, and to provide for a pilot project to test and demonstrate the benefits of main stem river channel restoration.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404978"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1994-05-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E923)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Management.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from EPA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Management Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-08-11"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Fisheries Management" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water"/>
		<term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Flood control"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="River regulation"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Shore protection"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1994--Introduced.
Russian River Fisheries and Riverbed Restoration Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct one or more pilot projects on the main channel of the Russian River in California which may be identified in the Russian River Resource Enhancement Plan, to demonstrate measures to reestablish a channel and floodway in dynamic equilibrium with the River and to prevent the down cutting of the River bed. Requires the Chief of the Soil Conservation Service, working through the Resource Conservation Districts and with the California Department of Fish and Game, to carry out high priority fish habitat restoration projects on the River's tributaries or watershed restoration projects that are identified in and are consistent with the objectives of the Program Plan. Directs the Secretary of the Army, in consultation with the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, to review the effects of the operation and water release schedule of the Coyote Dam in Mendocino County on bank erosion problems, river channel down cutting, decreases in groundwater supplies and scour of riparian habitat. Requires the Secretary to review the effects that the operation of Warm Springs Dam in Sonoma County will have on fish habitat in Dry Creek and downstream reaches of the River, including potential effects that the project will have on the middle reach of the River when fully operational. Establishes the Russian River Basin Advisory Committee to advise and assist the Administrator and the Chief regarding the implementation and monitoring of the activities authorized by this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
