<bill session="103" type="h" number="4414" updated="2010-04-19T10:39:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Independence for Families Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Fairness for Main Street Business Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reconnect welfare families to the world of work, make work pay, strengthen families, require personal responsibility, and support State flexibility.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407399"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404503" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="407465" joined="1994-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="407124" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="408109" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="408556" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="407838" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="409442" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400377" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="408364" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400548" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="401446" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400395" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="406625" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="401153" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="406920" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="403190" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400591" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="406024" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400599" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="405258" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="401774" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="411488" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1994-05-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations and Nutrition.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Department Operations and Nutrition" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public welfare"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Automobiles"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Black lung"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business education"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Child nutrition"/>
		<term name="Child support"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="College costs"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Court records"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Custody of children"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Day care centers for the aged"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Dropout prevention"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational finance"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Employment agencies"/>
		<term name="Employment subsidies"/>
		<term name="Employment tax credits"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Fathers"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Food stamps"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Gambling"/>
		<term name="Garnishment"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Grandparents"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Group homes"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Housing finance"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Incest"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Job creation"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Local taxation"/>
		<term name="Lotteries"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Oregon"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Parents"/>
		<term name="Paternity"/>
		<term name="Payroll deductions"/>
		<term name="Pensions"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Probate law and practice"/>
		<term name="Profit"/>
		<term name="Property"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Public service employment"/>
		<term name="Rape"/>
		<term name="Real property"/>
		<term name="Sales tax"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="School lunch program"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Sex education"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Social services"/>
		<term name="Sports"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Student aid"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Students"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Technical education"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Temporary employment"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education"/>
		<term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
		<term name="Wealth"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Welfare fraud"/>
		<term name="Wisconsin"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Workers' compensation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Time-Limited Transitional Assistance Title II: Make Work Pay Subtitle A: Health Care Subtitle B: Earned Income Tax Credit Subtitle C: Child Care Subtitle D: AFDC Work Disregards Subtitle E: AFDC Asset Limitations Title III: The Work First Program Subtitle A: AFDC Subtitle B: Targeted Jobs Tax Credit Title IV: Family Responsibility and Improved Child Support Enforcement Subtitle A: Enhancement of Ability to Identify and Locate Noncustodial Parents Subtitle B: Paternity Establishment Subtitle C: Improvement of Child Support Order Establishment Process Subtitle D: Child Support Enforcement Title V: Teen Pregnancy and Family Stability Subtitle A: Federal Role Subtitle B: State Role Title VI: Program Simplification Subtitle A: Increased State Flexibility Subtitle B: Coordination of AFDC and Food Stamp Programs Subtitle C: Fraud Reduction Title VII: Financing Subtitle A: Ineligibility of certain Aliens for certain Social Services Subtitle B: Other Provisions Relating to Aliens Subtitle C: Limitation on Emergency Assistance Expenditures Subtitle D: Family Day Care Homes Program Improvements Subtitle E: Collection of Certain State and Local Taxes on Out-of-State Sales Title VIII: Effective Date Independence for Families Act of 1994 - Title I: Time-Limited Transitional Assistance - Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) require States opting below to have work first programs to make ineligible for AFDC any family with a member who has participated in such work program for two years; (2) condition eligibility for AFDC on participation in job search activities except during unsubsidized full-time private sector employment; (3) provide transitional child care for families cut off AFDC after two years; and (4) direct the Secretary of Health and Human Service (Secretary) to establish a database of work first and community service programs participants for use by States opting to have work first programs. Title II: Make Work Pay - Amends SSA titles XIX (Medicaid) and IV part A (AFDC), as well as the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) and other specified Federal law, to make various specified changes with regard to, among others, extended Medicaid enrollment for former AFDC recipients, increased AFDC earned income disregards, limited AFDC income and resource disregards of savings for education, first time home or automobile purchase, microenterprise initiatives, increased child care funding and transitional benefits for two parent families, and refundable tax credits for dependent care and other expenses connected with gaining employment in order to enable AFDC recipients to become self-sufficient. (Sec. 229) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the Child Care Development and Block Grant Act should be reauthorized to allow States greater flexibility to use their funds to strengthen child care; and (2) States should institute a child care voucher system to enable families on AFDC to purchase child care services, create Consumer Information Centers for providing information on eligible child care providers, and loosen their regulations to allow for reimbursement of certain provider costs. Title III: The Work First Program - Amends SSA title IV to: (1) replace the current Job Opportunities and Basic Skills Training Program under part F with a new Work First Program that allows participating States to establish work programs similar to those operated by Riverside County, California and the State of Oregon; (2) add a new part G (Community Service Program); (3) include a work supplementation component under each such program that provides for subsidized private sector or State or local government jobs; (4) give States the option of having such programs; and (5) require States exercising such option to provide participants with the necessary case management services to ensure integrated benefits and services provided under such programs. (Sec. 311) Amends IRC to provide for an increase in the minimum period of employment required to receive a targeted jobs tax credit. Title IV: Family Responsibility And Improved Child Support Enforcement - Amends SSA title IV parts A and D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) to make specified changes with regard to AFDC recipient cooperation in establishing paternity of illegitimate children, locate services for enforcing child support orders, parenting services for new fathers, and distribution of child support proceeds. (Sec. 411) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) certain actions pursuant to a child support order, such as the denial of visitation rights, should be treated as irrelevant in actions brought to enforce other provisions of the order; (2) the Secretary should investigate accessing certain Federal data banks not linked to the Parent Locator Service; (3) the national network established under this title for handling locate requests should be used to access State records only through the agency administering the State part D plan; (4) social services should be provided in hospitals to women whose pregnancy results from rape or incest; and (5) States should implement methods for verifying locate information and develop programs like the State of Wisconsin's program for noncustodial parents unable to meet support obligations. (Sec. 421) Establishes the National Child Support Guidelines Commission to: (1) study and develop a national child support guideline if one proves advisable; and (2) submit a report on the study's results to the President and the Congress. (Sec. 431) Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a system for enabling child support information to be obtained at the workplace via W-4 form reporting by employees. Amends IRC to require employers to: (1) deduct and withhold child support obligations from employee wages; (2) pay withholdings to the appropriate payee; and (3) include withheld obligations on the employee's W-2 form. Makes various other specified changes to SSA title IV part D involving: (1) State procedures for comparing information in the national registry of child support orders (NR) established under this title with information obtained above from W-4 form reporting, and for imposing monetary penalties on employees who fail to report support obligations; (2) development of uniform withholding orders; (3) garnishment of certain Federal benefits and seizure of lottery winnings and other payouts to satisfy support arrearages; (4) State reporting of support obligations to credit bureaus; and (5) liability of grandparents for financial support of children of their minor children. Title V: Teen Pregnancy and Family Stability - Amends SSA title IV part A (AFDC) with respect to Federal and State roles in reducing teenage pregnancy and promoting family stability; by: (1) requiring States to deny AFDC for additional children (except those born as a result of rape or incest) of AFDC families unless the State plan explicitly provides for such additional children; and (2) providing for unmarried minors who are pregnant or who have children to live under adult supervision in order to receive AFDC. (Sec. 503) Directs the Secretary of Education to establish a task force to reduce teenage pregnancy. (Sec. 511) Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) children should be educated about the risks of early parenthood; (2) reproductive family planning and education should be made available to potential parents; and (3) States should use SSA title XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services) funds to provide comprehensive services to high-risk youth and work with schools for early identification and referral of such children. Title VI: Program Simplification - Amends SSA titles IV part A and XI, as well as the Food Stamp Act of 1977, to give States increased flexibility in providing AFDC benefits (including restoring those wrongfully terminated) through, among other means, use of electronic benefit transfers, quicker action on waiver requests, and coordination with food stamp rules. (Sec. 631) Expresses the support of the Congress for certain efforts by the Social Security Administration to reduce fraud and abuse in the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) Program under SSA title XVI. (Sec. 632) Requires the Secretary to study and report to the Congress on the feasibility of issuing a single counterfeit-resistant ID card to replace the current social security card and any health security card issued under health reform legislation. Title VII: Financing - Amends the SSA, the IRC, and the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to make certain aliens ineligible for AFDC, SSI, Medicaid, food stamps, and the earned income tax credit. (Sec. 711) Sets forth special rules concerning aliens and general public assistance. (Sec. 714) Authorizes appropriations for financial assistance to States for assistance to resident aliens. Specifies the annual allocation of such Federal financial assistance for each State and the District of Columbia through FY 1988. (Sec. 721) Amends SSA title IV part A (AFDC) to revise: (1) the definition of &quot;emergency assistance to needy families with children&quot;; and (2) the limitation on State expenditures for such assistance. (Sec. 731) Amends the National School Lunch Act to: (1) modify family and group day care home reimbursement provisions under the child and adult care food program; and (2) provide grants to States for making grants to family and day care homes. Tax Fairness for Main Street Business Act of 1994 - States that the Congress: (1) recognizes that some States will be adversely affected by provisions of this Act which deny immigrants certain public assistance; (2) pledges to help those States offset the potential cost shift; and (3) encourages States, in authorizing them below to require out-of-State companies to collect sales taxes on certain purchases, to use increased revenues resulting from such collections to offset such cost shift and design assistance programs addressing special needs of immigrants. (Sec. 744) Authorizes a State or local jurisdiction to require certain out-of-State businesses to collect sales taxes on tangible personal property sold to residents of the State or local jurisdiction. (Sec. 745) Provides an in-lieu fee rate where local taxes are not uniform. (Sec. 746) Prohibits a State from requiring out-of-State businesses to file reporting returns more than once every calendar quarter. (Sec. 749) Requires a State to establish toll-free information services to provide such businesses with necessary forms and instructions. Title VIII: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
