<bill session="103" type="h" number="4411" updated="2010-04-19T10:38:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Environmental Training and Employment Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish national programs to provide for environmental response training and employment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400591"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="1994-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1994-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1994-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400300" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1994-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400502" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400417" joined="1994-08-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="402626" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="1994-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400595" joined="1994-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1994-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1994-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="1994-07-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E914)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Accidents"/>
		<term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Asbestos"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fire fighters"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Health surveys"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor unions"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Lead"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Military discharges"/>
		<term name="Military personnel"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Occupational retraining"/>
		<term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
		<term name="Physical examinations"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Veterans' employment"/>
		<term name="Veterans' organizations"/>
		<term name="Vocational guidance"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women's employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Environmental Response Training Program Subtitle A: Certification, Training, and Accreditation Program Subtitle B: Health and Safety Program Title II: National Environmental Response Employment Program Title III: Federal Environmental Coordination Committee and Related Provisions Title IV: Administration and Enforcement National Environmental Training and Employment Act of 1994 - Provides for training, health and safety, employment opportunities, and certification for environmental response employees and employers, emergency responders, and environmental training providers. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the various titles of this Act. Allows other funds to be used to carry out this Act from appropriations for programs, projects, or activities administered by the Departments of Defense, of Energy, of Housing and Urban Development, of the Interior, of Labor, and of Health and Human Services (HHS), and the Environmental Protection Agency. Title I: National Environmental Response Training Program - Subtitle A: Certification, Training, and Accreditation Program - Directs the Secretary of Labor (the Secretary) to establish a National Environmental Training Program to: (1) certify environmental response employers (through a National Certification Program in the Department of Labor); (2) train and certify environmental response employees and emergency responders; and (3) accredit environmental training providers. Subtitle B: Health and Safety Program - Directs the Secretary to establish a national safety and health program covering environmental response employees and emergency responders. Allows such program to be implemented and managed, at the Secretary's discretion, by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health. Requires such program to include minimum standard medical examination protocols, a medical surveillance program, and a national injury/illness/fatality surveillance system. Title II: National Environmental Response Employment Program - Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a program to ensure employment of minorities and women in activities covered by this Act; and (2) in cooperation with the Secretary of Defense, a program to ensure availability of training and employment in activities covered by this Act for displaced military personnel. Directs the Secretary to provide grants to: (1) public agencies and nonprofit employee organizations qualifying as accredited providers to train environmental emergency responders; (2) joint labor-managed training trust funds and labor organizations accredited as providers for training and related activities for environmental workers subject to this Act; (3) nonprofit veterans' organizations for recruitment and counseling services for recently separated members of the military and other veterans, in connection with environmental response training; and (4) nonprofit minority and women's organizations for recruitment and counseling services for minority and female applicants, in connection with environmental response training. Title III: Federal Environmental Coordination Committee and Related Provisions - Establishes the Federal Environmental Coordination Committee, including the heads of the aforementioned Federal departments and agencies. Provides for: (1) enforcement of this Act through Federal contracting procedures; (2) cooperation with States; (3) accreditation and certification/licensure fees; and (4) environmental workforce research and studies. Title IV: Administration and Enforcement - Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to seek judicial relief and civil penalties for failure to comply with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
