<bill session="103" type="h" number="4410" updated="2010-04-19T10:38:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bipartisan Health Security Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for universal affordable access to health care and health insurance through tax and savings incentives, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405939"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400567" joined="1994-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1994-05-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Coinsurance"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Insurance rates"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Medically uninsured"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Self-insurance"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Smoking"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendments of Internal Revenue Code of 1986 Subtitle A: Tax Incentives for Purchase of Health Care Coverage Subtitle B: Medical Care Savings Accounts Subtitle C: Expansion of COBRA Continuation Coverage Title II: Insurance Reform Subtitle A: Employer Insurance Protections Subtitle B: Guaranteeing Portability of Health Insurance for Individuals Subtitle C: Assuring Health Insurance Coverage for Uninsurable Individuals Title III: Medicaid Reform Title IV: Medical Charge Disclosure Bipartisan Health Security Reform Act of 1994 - Title I: Amendments of Internal Revenue Code of 1986- Subtitle A: Tax Incentives for Purchase of Health Care Coverage - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individuals a refundable credit of 30 percent of the amount paid for: (1) the purchase of health care coverage for the taxpayer, the spouse, and dependents; and (2) contributions to a medical care savings account if the individual is covered under a high deductible health plan or by a health maintenance organization. Repeals the deduction for health insurance costs of self-employed individuals. Subtitle B: Medical Care Savings Accounts - Provides for the establishment of medical care savings accounts. Makes the account beneficiary the owner of the account and includes distributions in the beneficiary's gross income. Sets forth uses and limitations for such accounts. Excludes health benefit payments made by employers from employment taxes. (Sec. 112) Allows the transfer of unused amounts in flexible spending accounts of cafeteria plans to medical savings accounts. Subtitle C: Expansion of COBRA Continuation Coverage - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Public Health Service Act to make the continuation coverage requirements for group health plans inapplicable to employers of fewer than four employees (currently, 20 employees). Extends the required period of coverage to 36 months (currently, 18 months). Title II: Insurance Reform - Subtitle A: Employer Insurance Protections - Prohibits a health benefit insurer that provides or offers a small group health benefit plan from: (1) cancelling or non-renewing an individual small employer group because of high claims costs or the health of the group; or (2) refusing to provide coverage to such a group based solely on the nature of the employer's business or industry. Places limitations on increases in premium rates and variations in premiums across and within classes of businesses. (Sec. 202) Provides for continued health benefit coverage for individuals who change employers. (Sec. 204) Imposes an excise tax on the failure of an insurer or group health plan to meet the requirements of this title. Makes such tax nondeductible. Subtitle B: Guaranteeing Portability of Health Insurance for Individuals - Provides continued coverage and portability protections for eligible individuals or families applying for an individual health benefit plan. Subtitle C: Assuring Health Insurance Coverage for Uninsurable Individuals - Requires each State, beginning in 1997, to establish, administer, and fund a high-risk health insurance pool that assures the availability of qualified health insurance coverage to uninsurable individuals. Provides funding for such high-risk programs through: (1) premiums, with limitations; (2) surcharges for avoidable health risks, such as smoking; and (3) other means specified under State law. Title III: Medicaid Reform - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to grant States the authority to provide an eligible individual the option to receive medical assistance through enrollment in a private health plan. Title IV: Medical Charge Disclosure - Requires providers of medical services to visibly post maximum charges and costs for services.

	</summary>
</bill>
