<bill session="103" type="h" number="4419" updated="2010-04-19T10:39:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the supplemental security income program under title XVI of the Social Security Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300085"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400197" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400574" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400401" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300151" joined="1994-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400567" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400205" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="407817" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400382" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400544" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400369" joined="1994-05-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Alcoholism"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Blind"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug testing"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Welfare fraud"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Restrictions for Aliens Title II: Restrictions for Drug Addicts and Alcoholics Title III: Benefits for Children Title IV: Fraud Title I: Restrictions For Aliens - Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to make certain aliens ineligible for SSI benefits. Amends SSA title IV part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) to require State AFDC plans to require the State agency to provide the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) with identifying information on any unlawful alien with any children who are U.S. citizens. Title II: Restrictions for Drug Addicts and Alcoholics - Amends SSA title XVI, among other things, to: (1) suspend SSI benefits for certain recipients who test positive for illegal drugs or alcohol until such time that the recipient tests negative; and (2) make various specified representative payee changes, including requiring SSI disability payments based on substance abuse to be paid through representative payees. Title III: Benefits for Children - Amends SSA title XVI to: (1) replace the current cash benefit with a medical voucher for children below 18 to use for items associated with treating child blindness or disability the costs of which are not covered under SSA title XIX (Medicaid); and (2) require disability reviews for SSI recipients upon reaching 18. Title IV: Fraud - Amends SSA title XVI to add additional requirements for: (1) foreign language translation under provisions for filing of applications and furnishing of information; (2) preventing fraud in the SSI program, for example, by establishing civil monetary penalties and assessments, and by making SSI fraud a felony; and (3) developing profiles of cases involving a high probability of fraud. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to request INS and the Centers for Disease Control to provide any relevant medical information for determining alien eligibility for SSI. Directs the Secretary to report annually to appropriate congressional committees on reviews of SSI cases.

	</summary>
</bill>
