<bill session="103" type="h" number="4425" updated="2012-07-17T06:02:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-23T12:19:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-05-23T12:19:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize major medical facility construction projects for the Department of Veterans Affairs for fiscal year 1995, to revise and improve veterans' health programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409442"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409205" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400504" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407838" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400389" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1994-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="405313" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="408556" joined="1994-05-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-05-17"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19T18:38:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 103-518.</text></action>
		<calendar number="287" datetime="1994-05-19T18:38:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 287.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T12:11:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Montgomery moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T12:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3798-3802"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T12:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-05-23T12:19:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T12:19:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="2277" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Clinics"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Day care centers for the aged"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Earthquakes"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Health services administration"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Medical centers"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Military construction operations"/>
		<term name="Nurses"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Oregon"/>
		<term name="Parents"/>
		<term name="Philippines"/>
		<term name="Public utilities"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
		<term name="South Carolina"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="West Virginia"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/16/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Construction Authorization Title II: Health Care Planning and Programs Title III: Medical Facilities Acquisition Title IV: State Home Program Title V: Miscellaneous Title I: Construction Authorization - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out the major medical facility (MMF) projects and leases for the Department of Veterans Affairs for which funds are requested in the President's budget for FY 1995, with the exception of the construction of research additions at Huntington, West Virginia, and Portland, Oregon. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out additional MMF projects, in specified amounts, and additional MMF projects for which funds were appropriated in the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act of 1994. Authorizes FY 1995 appropriations for such purposes. Title II: Health Care Planning and Programs - Directs the Secretary to: (1) prescribe a specific, detailed statement of the mission of, and the clinical programs to be operated at, each Department health care facility; (2) review current Department health care missions; and (3) report on mission implementation timetables. (Sec. 202) Extends through FY 1997 (currently FY 1994) the pilot program for determining noninstitutional alternatives to nursing home care. Extends eligibility for such pilot program to all veterans eligible for nursing home care. (Currently, there are further requirements of being treated for, or having a certain degree of, a service-connected disability.) Extends certain report deadlines under the Department of Veterans Affairs Nurse Pay Act of 1990. Title III: Medical Facilities Acquisition - Specifies additional information to be included within a prospectus of a proposed medical facility to be acquired by the Department for use in providing veterans' medical care. (Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary to review the Department methodology for establishing the priority for major construction projects under consideration. Requires such methodology to be revised to give additional weight to projects intended to expand long-term care and ambulatory care programs. Requires a report. (Sec. 303) Directs the Secretary to submit semiannually to the veterans' committees a report showing the current Department priorities for major medical construction projects, with the highest 20 projects specifically identified. (Sec. 304) Includes within the definition of a major medical facility project a project for providing additional ambulatory care involving a total expenditure of more than $5 million. Title IV: State Home Program - Directs the Secretary to pay to each State a per diem amount for each veteran receiving adult day health care in a State home if the veteran is eligible to receive such care in a Department facility. Provides the rate for such care and increases the per diem rate for domiciliary, nursing home, and hospital care (currently authorized). (Sec. 402) Includes the construction of adult day health care facilities in the provision by the Department of financial assistance to States for the construction of medical facilities for veterans. Title V: Miscellaneous - Designates specified veterans' research advisory committees that the Secretary may not terminate unless determined to be no longer needed, with a 120-day prior notification of such a finding to the veterans' committees by way of a report. (Sec. 502) Authorizes the Secretary to provide for the operation of child care centers at Department facilities. Provides a priority for such services to employees of the Department, followed by employees of other Federal departments and agencies. Allows the Secretary to provide child care services to members of the public when necessary to assure the center's financial success. Directs the Secretary to establish reasonable charges for such services with the proceeds to be used by such centers for staffing and other expenses. Outlines related authority of the Secretary with respect to establishing and operating such centers. (Sec. 503) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into contracts for the provision of utilities to the Audie L. Murphy Memorial Hospital in San Antonio, Texas; (2) during the period from February 28 through June 1, 1994, contract with facilities in the Republic of the Philippines other than the Veterans Memorial Medical Center to furnish hospital care and medical services to veterans for nonservice-connected disabilities if such veterans are unable to defray the cost of such care; and (3) undertake an administrative reorganization of the Department medical center in Sepulveda, California, without regard to a required waiting period.

	</summary>
</bill>
