<bill session="103" type="h" number="4431" updated="2010-04-19T10:41:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Free Health Clinic Expansion Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize demonstration grants for the renovation of facilities and the purchase of equipment for existing free health clinics that exclusively serve individuals who are without health insurance.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400569"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Family medicine"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Free clinics"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medically uninsured"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/1994--Introduced.
Free Health Clinic Expansion Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to nonprofit private health clinics that do not impose charges for the provision of health services if the clinic agrees that the grant will not be expended for any purpose other than the renovation of facilities and the purchase of equipment for providing health services through the clinic. Limits each grant to a maximum of $4 million. Sets the following conditions for grant awards: (1) the clinic gives priority to the provision of primary care; (2) the clinic does not impose any charges; (3) the clinic's services are available only to individuals who are without health insurance and whose income does not exceed 125 percent of the official poverty line; (4) none of the health care providers of the clinic receives compensation for the provision of services through the clinic; (5) not more than one individual among the clinic staff receives compensation for the provision of services to the clinic; and (6) the clinic agrees to continue operating in accordance with such conditions. Considers an individual to be without health insurance if the individual is not covered under: (1) any health insurance policy or plan; and (2) any Government program that entitles the individual to receive health services.

	</summary>
</bill>
