<bill session="103" type="h" number="4442" updated="2010-04-19T10:43:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide consultations for the development of Articles of Relations and Self-Government for insular areas of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee On Insular and International Affairs Prior to Referral.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-11"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee On Insular and International Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular and International Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3715" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="American Samoa"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="National self-determination"/>
		<term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Puerto Rico"/>
		<term name="Referendum"/>
		<term name="Virgin Islands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/1994--Introduced.
Authorizes the President and the government of an insular area (American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or the Virgin Islands) to develop and submit to the Congress proposed measures to enable insular area citizens to exercise greater powers of self-government or greater participation in the Federal system. Directs the President, upon request, to designate a personal representative who, together with representatives designated by the government of the area, shall consult in good faith and develop Articles of Relations and Self-Government. Declares that, upon enactment by the Congress of a resolution approving the proposed Articles, they shall be submitted to the citizens of the insular area in a local government-organized plebiscite and shall take effect if ratified by a majority vote.

	</summary>
</bill>
