<bill session="103" type="h" number="4440" updated="2010-04-19T10:43:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Performance Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for performance accountability in the government of the District of Columbia.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407400"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E956)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fiscal Affairs and Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House District of Columbia" subcommittee="Fiscal Affairs and Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Federal-city relations"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Management audit"/>
		<term name="Municipal officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Personnel management"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Promotions"/>
		<term name="Rating of employees"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/1994--Introduced.
District of Columbia Performance Accountability Act - Requires the District of Columbia to develop and submit to specified congressional committees and subcommittees a Performance Accountability Plan and a Performance Accountability Report covering all departments, agencies, and programs of the District government. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the content of the Plan; (2) performance measures; (3) goals; and (4) the content of the Report. Requires a District management employee who is designated in such Report as being directly responsible for the achievement of one or more performance measurement goals: (1) the majority of whose goals in such Report does not achieve a designation of at least an acceptable level of performance to be either removed from employment by the District or demoted to a nonmanagerial position; (2) all of whose goals in such Report do not achieve a designation of at least an acceptable level of performance to not receive any increase in pay for the subsequent year, including but not limited to merit increases, cost-of-living adjustments, and promotions; and (3) the majority of whose goals in such Report do not achieve a designation of at least a superior level of performance to not receive a promotion or performance bonus during the subsequent year. Allows additional limitations and regulations to be applied to such promotions, performance bonuses, and increases in pay. Requires the District, subject to the approval of the Office of Management and Budget, to amend its management and personnel laws and regulations to be in conformance with this Act. Directs the General Accounting Office to audit the Performance Accountability Reports of the District, including the District's compliance with the personal accountability provisions in this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
