<bill session="103" type="h" number="4467" updated="2010-04-19T10:47:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Government Bonus Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to eliminate the existing Federal employee bonus and incentive award programs and establish a program for incentive awards for Federal employees only for suggestions, inventions, or other personal efforts which cause a demonstrable monetary savings to the Government.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405939"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="1994-07-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1000)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23"><committee name="House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" subcommittee="Compensation and Employee Benefits" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Fringe benefits"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Waste in government spending"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1994--Introduced.
Federal Government Bonus Reform Act of 1994 - Amends Federal civil service law to eliminate the existing Federal employee bonus and incentive award programs. Establishes a new incentive program for Federal employees under which the President may pay a cash award (up to $1,500) to an employee who by a suggestion, invention, superior accomplishment, or other personal effort: (1) contributes to the efficiency, economy, or other improvement of Government operations or achieves a significant reduction in paperwork; and (2) by such contribution causes a demonstrable savings to the Government. Provides for such awards to deceased or separated employees. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
