<bill session="103" type="h" number="4490" updated="2010-04-19T10:51:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-29">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-06-29" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the Administrative Conference of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401947"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Subcommittee on Administrative Law Forwarded an Original Measure to Full Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-29"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-29"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T21:00:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 103-854.</text></action>
		<calendar number="471" datetime="1994-10-07T21:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 471.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative Conference of the U.S."/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Constitution"/>
		<term name="Constitutional law"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1994--Reported to House amended. Amends Federal law to authorize appropriations for and extend the Administrative Conference of the United States through FY 1998. Revises the Conference Chairman's compensation to set it at level III of the Executive Schedule. Declares that Conference members shall participate in Conference activities solely as private individuals without official responsibility on behalf of the U.S. Government and, therefore, shall not be considered to hold an office of profit or trust for purposes of the eighth clause of Section 9 of Article I of the Constitution (thus permitting them, without the consent of the Congress, to accept any present, emolument, office, or title of any kind whatever from any king, prince, or foreign state). Declares that a majority of the members of the Conference shall constitute a quorum with regard to final actions taken by the Conference Assembly.

	</summary>
</bill>
