<bill session="103" type="h" number="4519" updated="2010-04-19T10:55:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Insurance Choice Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase access to health insurance for employees of small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400252"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404503" joined="1994-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1994-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="406768" joined="1994-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1994-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1994-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="1994-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="1994-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="408476" joined="1994-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400012" joined="1994-06-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1103-1104)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-03"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.R.3600.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3600" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Antitrust actions"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Competition"/>
		<term name="Continuum of care"/>
		<term name="Contracts"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Self-insurance"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/26/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Improved Access to Affordable Health Care Subtitle A: Increased Availability and Continuity of Health Coverage for Employees and Their Families Subtitle B: Preemption of Scope of State Regulation Subtitle C: Health Deduction Fairness Title II: Removing Anti-Trust Impediments Small Business Health Insurance Choice Act - Title I: Improved Access to Affordable Health Care - Subtitle A: Increased Availability And Continuity of Health Coverage of Health Coverage for Employees and their Families - Prohibits a group health plan limiting coverage or excluding from coverage based on a pre-existing condition if: (1) the condition was not diagnosed within three months before coverage; (2) the limitation or exclusion extends over more than six months after coverage; (3) the limitation or exclusion applies to an individual who, as of the date of birth, was covered; or (4) the limitation or exclusion relates to pregnancy. Sets forth continuity of coverage provisions. Prohibits a plan from cancelling coverage or denying renewal, except for such reasons as nonpayment of premiums, fraud, or because the plan no longer provides coverage in a geographic area. Provides for enforcement by the Department of Labor for employers and group health plans. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on the failure of an insurer to comply with the requirements of the preceding paragraph. Provides for an exception to the tax if a State has adequate sanctions. Subtitle B: Preemption of Scope of State Regulation - Prohibits a State or local law from: (1) requiring coverage of one or more specific benefits, services, or categories of health care, or services of any class or type of provider; and (2) prohibiting two or more employers from obtaining coverage under an insured multiple employer health plan. Preempts for five years provisions of State law concerning: (1) restrictions on reimbursement rates or selective contracting; and (2) restrictions on differential financial incentives. Subtitle C: Health Deduction Fairness - Extends permanently and increases to 100 percent the health insurance tax deduction for self-employed individuals. Permits the deduction of uncompensated health insurance costs without regard to the adjusted gross income threshold for individuals who are not eligible to participate in any subsidized health plan maintained by either an employer or spouse. Title II: Removing Antitrust Impediments - Provides for a program which permits a health care joint venture to apply for a limited exemption from the antitrust laws, Permits a health care joint venture to apply for a certificate of public advantage. Directs the Attorney General to issue the certificate if: (1) the benefits of issuance are likely to outweigh the reduction in competition; and (2) the reduction in competition is reasonably necessary to obtain the desired benefit. Establishes the Interagency Advisory Committee on Competition, Antitrust Policy, and Health Care to evaluate competition and antitrust policy with respect to the performance of health care markets and to report recommendations to the Congress.

	</summary>
</bill>
