<bill session="103" type="h" number="4528" updated="2010-04-19T10:57:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Entitled the &quot;Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400509" joined="1994-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1994-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="402750" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400106" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="1994-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="411350" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="1994-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="1994-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="409627" joined="1994-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1994-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="1994-07-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1096)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-27"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1949" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Cadmium"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer goods"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Electric batteries"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Lead"/>
		<term name="Manganese"/>
		<term name="Mercury"/>
		<term name="Nickel"/>
		<term name="Packaging"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Zinc"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/26/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act Title II: Mercury Containing Battery Management Act Mercury-Containing and Rechargeable Battery Management Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to provide information on the proper handling and disposal of used regulated batteries and rechargeable consumer products with nonremovable batteries. Defines a &quot;regulated battery&quot; as a rechargeable battery that contains a cadmium or lead electrode or other electrode chemistries as determined by the Administrator. Establishes civil penalties for violations of this Act. Sets forth recordkeeping requirements and establishes inspection and access authorities for the Administrator. Authorizes appropriations. Title I: Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act - Rechargeable Battery Recycling Act - Prohibits any person from selling to an end user for use in the United States a regulated battery or rechargeable consumer product manufactured on or after 12 months after this Act's enactment date unless: (1) the battery is easily removable from the product, is contained in a battery pack that is easily removable, or is sold separately; and (2) the rechargeable consumer product and the battery are labeled in accordance with this Act. Sets forth labeling requirements, including that the label contain a statement that the battery must be recycled or disposed of properly. Requires retail establishments that sell such batteries or products to post notices informing consumers that regulated batteries must be recycled or disposed of properly. Authorizes the Administrator, upon determining that other rechargeable batteries having electrode chemistries different from regulated batteries are toxic and may cause substantial harm if discarded for land disposal or incineration, to promulgate: (1) labeling requirements for such batteries and related products; and (2) easily-removable design requirements for rechargeable consumer products designed to contain such batteries or battery packs. Provides for exemptions from this Act's requirements under certain conditions. Title II: Mercury Containing Battery Management Act - Mercury-Containing Battery Management Act - Prohibits the sale or offering for sale or promotional purposes of: (1) alkaline-manganese batteries manufactured on or after January 1, 1996, with a mercury content that was intentionally introduced (limits the content in alkaline-manganese button cells to 25 milligrams of mercury per button cell); (2) zinc carbon batteries manufactured on or after January 1, 1995, that contain mercury that was intentionally introduced; (3) button cell mercuric-oxide batteries on or after January 1, 1995; and (4) any mercuric-oxide battery on or after January 1, 1997.

	</summary>
</bill>
