<bill session="103" type="h" number="453" updated="2010-04-19T00:11:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ed-Flex</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Educational Reform and Flexibility Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national demonstration program providing increased flexibility for schools in order to promote improved educational achievement for all students.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="404083" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400023" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400390" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="406554" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400537" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="1993-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-03-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Education of handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational innovations"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Homeless children"/>
		<term name="Migrant education"/>
		<term name="Performance based education"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/1993--Introduced.
Educational Reform and Flexibility Act of 1993 (Ed-Flex) - Amends the General Education Provisions Act to establish a program for flexibility and accountability in education and related services. Directs the Secretary of Education to assist projects for elementary and secondary schools and other service providers to improve achievement of all students and other participants, but particularly disadvantaged individuals, by authorizing a limited number of waivers by which the performance of schools and programs can be improved by increasing their flexibility in use of resources while holding them accountable for achieving educational gains. Limits such waivers to not more than: (1) six States which have implemented comprehensive regulatory reform plans; and (2) 50 LEAs within each SEA of such States. Authorizes the Secretary to only waive a statutory or regulatory requirement applicable to a program under specified Federal laws relating to elementary, secondary, and vocational education and disadvantaged or homeless students. Authorizes other Federal agency heads, with the Secretary's agreement, to make similar waivers of such requirements applicable to an elementary, secondary, or youth vocational training program administered by such agencies. Limits duration of projects and associated waivers. Requires each project that involves elementary or secondary schools to include participation of an LEA and at least two schools. Requires, to the extent possible, project participation by each grade and academic program in a participating school. Sets forth application and planning requirements. Prohibits waiver of requirements: (1) in awarding new competitive grants to a service provider within the LEA or other applicant participating in such a project; (2) relating to maintenance of effort, comparability, or equitable participation of private school students; and (3) under specified provisions of specified Federal laws relating to individuals with disabilities. Sets forth requirements for reports, evaluations, budget neutrality, and a sunset provision.

	</summary>
</bill>
