<bill session="103" type="h" number="4542" updated="2010-04-19T10:59:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Persian Gulf War Veterans Health and Services Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide an improved system of health-related information for Persian Gulf War veterans and to extend the availability of certain health care for Persian Gulf War Veterans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406277"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400126" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="407838" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="401854" joined="1994-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="405524" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="1994-06-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-26"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Marriage counseling"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Persian Gulf War"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/8/1994--Introduced.
Persian Gulf War Veterans Health and Services Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to maintain an information system involving the use of a toll-free telephone number to provide Persian Gulf War veterans and their families (and members of the public at the Secretary's discretion) with information regarding: (1) the Persian Gulf War Veterans Health Registry; (2) access to Department of Veterans Affairs health services and benefits; (3) compensation and benefits relating to disabilities resulting from service in the Persian Gulf War (War); and (4) significant developments in research related to health consequences from such service. Amends the Persian Gulf War Veterans' Health Status Act to direct the Secretary to notify such veterans, or, if deceased, the veteran's surviving spouse, children, or parents at least quarterly concerning research findings, compensation and benefits, and other appropriate matters relating to service by veterans in the War. Extends through December 31, 1998, the authority of the Department to provide hospital, nursing home, and outpatient care to veterans of the War. Amends the Veterans' Medical Program Amendments of 1992 to extend through December 31, 1998, the authority of the Secretary to furnish marriage and family counseling to such veterans. Extends through FY 1999 the authorization of appropriations for such counseling.

	</summary>
</bill>
