<bill session="103" type="h" number="4553" updated="2010-04-19T11:01:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fusion Energy Research Authorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the fusion energy research, development, and demonstration program at the Department of Energy, to direct the participation of the United States in the International Thermonuclear Experimental Reactor, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400572"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1166-1168)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4908" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Nuclear energy"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Commercialization"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Cost accounting"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Electric power distribution"/>
		<term name="Electric power production"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International cooperation in science"/>
		<term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear fusion"/>
		<term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology assessment"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Test facilities"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/9/1994--Introduced.
Fusion Energy Research Authorization Act of 1994 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to implement a Fusion Energy Research Program to demonstrate the technical and economic feasibility of producing safe, environmentally sound, and affordable energy from fusion. Prescribes program goals and elements. Directs the Secretary to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review various magnetic fusion technologies and alternative fusion concepts with respect to their commercial viability. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) submit a comparisons study to the Congress regarding the siting of the International Thermonuclear Experimental Reactor (ITER); (2) seek to reach an agreement with international partners to select a host country for ITER; (3) initiate a process to identify candidate sites for ITER within the United States; and (4) provide within a certain time period a detailed estimate to the Congress of final ITER project costs. Directs the Secretary to submit reports to the Congress on: (1) a parallel design effort on the Tokamak Physics Experiment; (2) the Fusion Energy Research Program; and (3) resource sharing with the Secretary of Defense to enhance the civilian energy applications of the Defense Inertial Confinement Fusion Program. Repeals the five-year fusion energy program established under the Energy Policy Act of 1992. Directs the Secretary to form a new University Radiation Science and Technology Program comprised of: (1) the Nuclear Engineering Research and Education Program; (2) the University Research Reactor Program; and (3) the University Reactor Fuel Assistance Program. Directs the Secretary to establish a fee collection program for certain ITER purposes and the Tokamak Physics Experiment. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) the Alternative Fusion Research Program; (2) the Tokamak Physics Experiment; and (3) the University Radiation Science and Technology Program. Sets limitations upon funding for ITER construction and for magnetic fusion facilities.

	</summary>
</bill>
