<bill session="103" type="h" number="4585" updated="2010-04-19T11:06:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom and Fairness Restoration Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote freedom, fairness, and economic opportunity for families by reducing the power and reach of the Federal establishment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400551"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400174" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406431" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="1994-08-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="406863" joined="1994-08-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1994-08-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="409423" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400382" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400586" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400601" joined="1994-08-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1994-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public finance"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Balanced budgets"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business income tax"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional sessions"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Cost accounting"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Economic growth"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Elasticity (Economics)"/>
		<term name="Eminent domain"/>
		<term name="Entitlements"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal budget process"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Flat-rate tax"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Prices"/>
		<term name="Public health"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Regulatory reform"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Social work"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Sunset legislation"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Tax reform"/>
		<term name="Tax simplification"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Reduction and Simplification Title II: Spending Restraint and Budget Process Reform Subtitle A: Joint Budget Resolution Subtitle B: Zero Based Budgeting and Decennial Sunsetting Subtitle C: Spending Caps on the Growth of Entitlements for Fiscal Years 1995 Through 2000 Subtitle D: Balanced Budget by Fiscal Year 2000 Title III: Regulatory Relief Subtitle A: Private Property Rights Protection and Compensation Subtitle B: Measuring Costs of Federal Regulations Subtitle C: Risk Assessment and Cost/Benefit Analyses and Reports Freedom and Fairness Restoration Act of 1994 - Title I: Tax Reduction and Simplification - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a 20 percent tax (17 percent after December 31, 1996) on the taxable earned income of every individual. Bases such amount on the standard deduction. (Replaces current income tax procedures for individuals.) Increases the basic standard deduction for individuals and includes an additional standard deduction for dependents, with inflation adjustments. (Sec. 102) Replaces the current tax on corporations with a tax on every person engaged in a business activity equal to 20 percent (17 percent after December 31, 1996) of the business taxable income of such person. Makes the person engaged in the business activity liable for the tax. (Sec. 103) Repeals income tax withholding. Title II: Spending Restraint and Budget Process Reform - Subtitle A: Joint Budget Resolution - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to reform the budget process by requiring a joint resolution on the budget instead of the concurrent resolution on the budget. Subtitle B: Zero Based Budgeting and Decennial Sunsetting - Terminates spending authority for unearned entitlements and high-cost discretionary spending programs for FY 1994, and discretionary spending programs (not including high-cost programs) for FY 1995, unless such spending is reauthorized after the date of enactment of this Act. (Sec. 212) Establishes a point of order against legislation that appropriates funds, which may be waived by a three-fifths vote of each House of Congress. (Sec. 213) Requires the reauthorization of discretionary spending authority and unearned entitlements every ten years beginning in the first decennial census year after 2000. Subtitle C: Spending Caps on the Growth of Entitlements for Fiscal Years 1995 Through 2000 - Declares that for FY 1995 through 2000 the total level of entitlement and mandatory spending, excluding social security, shall not exceed the total level for the previous fiscal year increased by the consumer price index and growth in eligible population. Requires sequestration as necessary to reduce spending. Provides for making uniform reductions with limitations. Lists programs and activities exempt from sequestration and provides exceptions, limitations, and special rules. Establishes a point of order against entitlement programs which may be waived by a three-fifths vote of each House. Subtitle D: Balanced Budget by Fiscal Year 2000 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act to revise the budget enforcement process. (Sec. 231) Establishes maximum spending amounts for FY 1995 through 1999 and revises sequestration procedures for enforcement. (Sec. 233) Establishes a point of order against exceeding permissible total spending. Title III: Regulatory Relief - Subtitle A: Private Property Rights Protection and Compensation - Declares that a private property owner is entitled to receive compensation for any reduction in the value of property of the owner that is: (1) a consequence of a limitation on an otherwise lawful use of the property imposed by a final agency action; and (2) measurable and not negligible. Subtitle B: Measuring Costs of Federal Regulations - Requires the Office of Management and Budget to report annually to the President, and the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to report annually to the Congress, on projections of costs of complying with Federal mandates. (Sec. 322) Requires the President to make annual recommendations to the Congress to ensure that such costs do not exceed their corresponding baseline costs. Subtitle C: Risk Assessment and Cost/Benefit Analyses and Reports - Includes in CBO reports on the cost of legislation: (1) an estimate of private sector compliance costs in the effective fiscal year and the next four fiscal years; (2) an estimate of the risks to the public health and safety which would result from any significant bill or resolution; and (3) an estimate of the effects of any significant bill or resolution on the economy, including the rate of gross domestic product growth, job loss, and price stability.

	</summary>
</bill>
