<bill session="103" type="h" number="4580" updated="2010-04-19T11:05:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Geno Baroni Commemorative Neighborhood Policy Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Geno Baroni Commission on Neighborhoods and provide for a White House Conference on Neighborhoods, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400211"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400542" joined="1994-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1994-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1994-06-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSBA-04" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Urban areas"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Community development banking"/>
		<term name="Community development corporations"/>
		<term name="Community life"/>
		<term name="Community organization"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Enterprise zones"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hate crimes"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="National service"/>
		<term name="Neighborhood government"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Property tax"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Social services"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Urban crime"/>
		<term name="Urban problems"/>
		<term name="Urban renewal"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="White House conferences"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/14/1994--Introduced.
Geno Baroni Commemorative Neighborhood Policy Act - Establishes the Geno Baroni Commission on Neighborhoods (GBCN) to assess: (1) progress made in the United States in carrying out the recommendations made by the National Commission on Neighborhoods (NCN) (established under title II of the Supplemental Housing Authorization Act of 1977); (2) factors arising since the termination of the NCN that prevent or interfere with efforts for neighborhood revitalization, including escalation of the influence of crime, illegal drug use, and racial violence in neighborhoods; and (3) the impact, influence, roles, and needs of Federal, State, and local, and other policies, entities, programs, and efforts in revitalizing neighborhoods, implemented or originated since the termination of the NCN. Requires the GBCN to: (1) assist the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development in carrying out responsibilities with respect to a White House Conference on Neighborhoods; and (2) update the NCN's report entitled &quot;People Building Neighborhoods.&quot; Requires the President, by November 30, 1996, to convene a White House Conference on Neighborhoods to: (1) facilitate the transfer of knowledge and sharing of experience among the broad range of neighborhood self-help organizations throughout the United States; (2) acknowledge the accomplishments of such organizations; (3) develop recommendations for additional research and public policy recommendations and actions in the field of neighborhood preservation and revitalization; and (4) disseminate the report of, and information obtained by, the GBCN and exhibit its materials and works. Requires the GBCN to report to the President and the chief executive officers of the States on the activities of the Conference. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
