<bill session="103" type="h" number="4591" updated="2010-04-19T11:07:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Safety and Licensing Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a system for regulating and licensing the distribution of firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400350"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/1994--Introduced.
Public Safety and Licensing Act of 1994 - Amends the Federal criminal code to increase the fee for engaging in the business of importing, manufacturing, or dealing in firearms or importing or manufacturing ammunition. Provides for the annual expiration of dealers' licenses. Prohibits dealing in firearms from a private residence, with exceptions. Repeals prohibitions against recording firearms records at, or transferring such records to, a public facility and establishing a system for registration of firearms, firearms owners, or firearms dispositions. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) establish recordkeeping requirements for dealers selling firearms from personal collections; and (2) revoke the license of any dealer who has violated (currently, willfully violated) specified provisions, rules, or regulations. Requires applicants seeking to engage in the business of dealing in firearms to have obtained a license, permit, or other document required under State or local law. Authorizes the Secretary to revoke a dealer's license for violation of any State or local firearms law. Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations requiring the secure storage of firearms by licensed dealers.

	</summary>
</bill>
