<bill session="103" type="h" number="459" updated="2010-04-19T00:12:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nationwide Banking and Branching Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for nationwide banking and branching.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405507"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400596" joined="1993-01-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-01"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Bank capital"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank holding companies"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Bank mergers"/>
		<term name="Branch banking"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Credit"/>
		<term name="Deposit insurance"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Financial institutions"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Interstate banking"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/1993--Introduced.
Nationwide Banking and Branching Act of 1993 - Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to authorize the Federal Reserve Board to approve an application by a bank holding company or foreign bank to acquire voting shares or interests in additional insured depository institutions or bank holding companies located in any State (notwithstanding State law to the contrary). Repeals the requirement that such acquisitions be expressly authorized by State statute. Amends Federal banking law to authorize the Comptroller of the Currency to approve interstate branching applications by national banks, subject to the bank's rating under the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977. Authorizes States to elect to either permit or deny interstate branching if the law: (1) applies equally to national and State banks; (2) expressly prohibits all out-of-State banks from establishing or acquiring branches located in the host State; and (3) was enacted within a specified time frame. Permits the States to authorize interstate branching at a later time subsequent to an initial denial and to coordinate their examination and regulatory activities. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to authorize interstate branching by insured State banks. Amends the International Banking Act of 1978 to prescribe guidelines under which foreign banks may establish interstate banking operations. Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 and specified Federal banking law to authorize the interstate consolidation or merger of bank holding company subsidiary banks, subject to prescribed guidelines. Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to require the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency to prepare written State-by-State evaluations of the performance records of financial institutions with interstate branches. Requires such agency to promulgate regulations establishing guidelines to ensure that each interstate branch meets the credit needs of the community and market area in which it operates.

	</summary>
</bill>
