<bill session="103" type="h" number="4602" updated="2012-07-17T05:59:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1994-09-30" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Appropriations bill FY95, Interior</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Interior Department FY95 Appropriations bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of the Interior and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1995, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411947"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Interior.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Interior"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-11"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Interior"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Interior"/><text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Interior"/><text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-09"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations" subcommittee="Interior"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-17T16:49:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-551, by Mr. Yates.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-17"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-17"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Ordered to be Reported.</text></calendar>
		<calendar number="305" datetime="1994-06-17T16:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 305.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21T16:41:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 458 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4602. All points of order against provisions of the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI are waived except on page 80, line 10 through line 19. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T11:00:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 458 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T11:00:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4789-4852"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T11:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Yates moved to resolve into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T11:01:00-04:00"><text>Pending the foregoing motion, Mr. Yates asked unanimous consent that the time for general debate on the bill be limited to one hour, equally divided. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T11:01:00-04:00"><text>On motion to resolve into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T11:02:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Dan Glickman to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T11:02:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T12:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Pombo amendment, equally divided and controlled.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T13:29:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, further debate on the Allard amendment and all amendments thereto was limited to not to exceed 40 minutes, equally divided and controlled.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T14:43:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Yates asked unanimous consent that the time for debate on the amendment, and all amendments thereto, be limited to not to exceed 50 minutes, equally divided and controlled. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T14:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 50 minutes of debate on the Duncan amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T16:40:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Vento raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Vento stated that the language on page 80, lines 11 through 14 providing salaries and expenses for the Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation contains material not authorized. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T16:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment and all amendments thereto, equally divided and controlled.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22T17:49:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4602 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T10:37:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4889-4915"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T10:38:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T10:40:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate equally divided and controlled.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T11:37:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Stearns amendment and all amendments thereto.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T13:10:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to clause 2(d) of rule XXIII the Committee rises.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4602 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T13:11:00-04:00"><text>RE-VOTE ON COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE AMENDMENT - As Chairman of the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, Mr. Glickman, pursuant to clause 2(d) of rule XXIII, reported to the House that during consideration of the bill H.R. 4602 in the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, the votes cast by the Delegates and the Resident Commissioner were decisive on a recorded vote on the amendment offered by Mr. Yates to the amendment offered by Mr. Bachus of Alabama.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T13:12:00-04:00"><text>Under the rule, the question on agreeing to the amendment offered by Mr. Yates must be put de novo before the full House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T13:35:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T13:36:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T13:36:00-04:00"><text>STATEMENT BY CHAIRMAN OF COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE - When the Committee of the Whole rose, the amendment offered by Mr. Yates to the Bachus substitute had been adopted on a recorded vote on which the votes cast by the Delegates and the Resident Commissioner were decisive. That result was subsequently reversed by the House. Accordingly, the Yates amendment to the Bachus substitute was not agreed to.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T14:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Klug amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:06:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - By unanimous consent, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Rahall amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:16:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Yates moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:16:00-04:00"><text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:17:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4602.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:17:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:18:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Myers moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Myers motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion require the Appropriations Committee to report the bill back to the House with an amendment to reduce the Land Acquisition account for the Forest Service by $1 million, from $62,131,000 to $61,131,000.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:18:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:18:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4914"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:18:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to the foregoing motion to recommit with instructions, Mr. Yates reported the bill back to the House with an amendment.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="272" datetime="1994-06-23T15:43:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 338 - 85 (Roll no. 272).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:44:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23T15:44:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4602.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-24"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="House Committee on Appropriations"/><text>Subcommittee on Interior. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-28" ><text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Byrd with amendments. With written report No. 103-294.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="498" datetime="1994-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 498.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9588-9641"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2382 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2382 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2383 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2383 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2384 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2384 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2385 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2385 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2386 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2386 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2387 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator Burns.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2387 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2388 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2388 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2389 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2389 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2390 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator DeConcini.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2390 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2391 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator Dorgan.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2391 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2392 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator Kassebaum.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2392 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2393 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator Murray.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2393 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2394 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator Stevens.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2394 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2395 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2396 proposed by Senator Helms.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2397 proposed by Senator Jeffords.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2395 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 92-0. Record Vote No: 229.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Proposed amendment SP 2397 withdrawn in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Motion to table SP 2396 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49-42. Record Vote No: 230.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2398 proposed by Senator Baucus.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2398 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2399 proposed by Senator McCain.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2399 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 89-0. Record Vote No: 231.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Amendment SP 2400 proposed by Senator Bumpers.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Proposed amendment SP 2400 withdrawn in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9664-9697, S9699-9722"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2401 proposed by Senator Bradley.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2402 proposed by Senator Byrd.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2402 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2403 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator Wofford.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2403 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Motion to table SP 2401 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 63-37. Record Vote No: 232.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2405 proposed by Senator Hutchison.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2405 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Motion to table the Committee amendment on page 49, lines 12-14, rejected by Yea-Nay Vote. 43-56. Record Vote No: 233.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2406 proposed by Senator Moseley-braun.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2406 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2407 proposed by Senator Wallop.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2407 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2408 proposed by Senator Byrd for Senator Leahy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2408 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2409 proposed by Senator Murkowski.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2410 proposed by Senator Murkowski.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2410 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2409 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2411 proposed by Senator Bingaman.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2411 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2412 proposed by Senator Domenici.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Amendment SP 2412 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1994-07-26" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><text>Senate insists on its amendments asks for a conference, appoints conferees Byrd; Johnston; Leahy; DeConcini; Bumpers; Hollings; Reid; Murray; Nickles; Stevens; Cochran; Domenici; Gorton; Hatfield; Burns.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9722"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-29"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T14:09:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Dicks asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T14:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9108"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T14:12:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Regula moved that the House instruct conferees.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T14:14:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Regula motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion require the managers on the part of the House to insist on the House position on Senate amendments Nos. 67 and 68. The House position imposes a one-year moratorium on the patenting of hardrock mining claims, that is, the transfer of ownership of lands covered by a mining claim from the Federal Government to the claimholder for a small fee, as provided in the 1872 General Mining Law. The Senate version of the bill contains no comparable provision.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T14:47:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T15:09:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 318 - 64 (Roll no. 421).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9108-9114"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T15:09:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13T15:09:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Yates, Murtha, Dicks, Bevill, Skaggs, Coleman, Obey, Regula, McDade, Kolbe, and Packard.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-21"><text>Conference held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22T14:00:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Dicks asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on Sept. 22 to file a conference report on H.R. 4602. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22"><text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22T19:04:00-04:00"><text>Conference report H. Rept. 103-740 filed. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text><reference label="text of conference report" ref="CR H9536-9539"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-26T19:17:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 547 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 4602. All points of order against the conference report and against it's consideration shall be waived.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T13:32:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 547 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T13:33:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Yates brought up conference report H. Rept. 103-740 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 547.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T13:36:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T13:59:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T14:00:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Myers moved to recommit to the conference committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T14:01:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T14:02:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit to conference committee Failed by voice vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9797"/></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="conference" datetime="1994-09-27T14:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9786-9797"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27T14:03:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28"><text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="311" datetime="1994-09-28" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 92-7. Record Vote No: 311.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S13548"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1994-09-28" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident datetime="1994-09-30" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1994-09-30" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-332" type="public" datetime="1994-09-30"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-332.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral, Markup" />
		<committee code="HSAP-06" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="Interior" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Interior and Related Agencies" activity="Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="458" />
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="547" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Africa"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Alabama"/>
		<term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
		<term name="American Samoa"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Arkansas"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Army posts"/>
		<term name="Arts"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
		<term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
		<term name="Biological research"/>
		<term name="Black colleges"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Cattle"/>
		<term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Clinics"/>
		<term name="Coal"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Colleges"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
		<term name="Community colleges"/>
		<term name="Competition"/>
		<term name="Concessions"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Cultural centers"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Disasters"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Elephants"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Endangered animals"/>
		<term name="Endangered species"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Fire fighters"/>
		<term name="Fire prevention"/>
		<term name="Fish culture"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Forest clearcutting"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Forest fires"/>
		<term name="Forest management"/>
		<term name="Forest roads"/>
		<term name="Forestry research"/>
		<term name="Forests and forestry"/>
		<term name="Fossil fuels"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
		<term name="Geology"/>
		<term name="Government aircraft"/>
		<term name="Government consultants"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Government vehicles"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health facilities"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Horses"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Illinois"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Indian economic development"/>
		<term name="Indian housing"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Indian medical care"/>
		<term name="Indian water rights"/>
		<term name="Insect control"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International education"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Irrigation"/>
		<term name="Islands"/>
		<term name="Ivory"/>
		<term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
		<term name="Kansas"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Landscape architecture"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Lumber trade"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Medical centers"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Micronesia"/>
		<term name="Military history"/>
		<term name="Mine safety"/>
		<term name="Mineral industries"/>
		<term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
		<term name="Mining leases"/>
		<term name="Mining royalties"/>
		<term name="Minnesota"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Missouri"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
		<term name="Museums"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
		<term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National monuments"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Nevada"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="New York City"/>
		<term name="North America"/>
		<term name="North Dakota"/>
		<term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
		<term name="Ohio"/>
		<term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution control"/>
		<term name="Oil shales"/>
		<term name="Oklahoma"/>
		<term name="Old growth forests"/>
		<term name="Oregon"/>
		<term name="Owls"/>
		<term name="Palau Islands"/>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
		<term name="Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation"/>
		<term name="Pest control"/>
		<term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
		<term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
		<term name="Prospecting"/>
		<term name="Psychologists"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public housing"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Railroad land grants"/>
		<term name="Range management"/>
		<term name="Reclamation of land"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Reforestation"/>
		<term name="Rent"/>
		<term name="Rental housing"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Reptiles"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Restaurants"/>
		<term name="Roosevelt Administration"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Strategic materials"/>
		<term name="Streets"/>
		<term name="Strip mining"/>
		<term name="Submarine oil well drilling"/>
		<term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
		<term name="Surveying"/>
		<term name="Surveys"/>
		<term name="Sustainable development"/>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Timber sales"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Trees"/>
		<term name="Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="U.S. Holocaust Memorial Council"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Urban planning"/>
		<term name="Utah"/>
		<term name="Virgin Islands"/>
		<term name="Volcanoes"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
		<term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
		<term name="Zoos"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h660"/>
		<amendment number="h661"/>
		<amendment number="h662"/>
		<amendment number="h663"/>
		<amendment number="h664"/>
		<amendment number="h665"/>
		<amendment number="h666"/>
		<amendment number="h667"/>
		<amendment number="h668"/>
		<amendment number="h669"/>
		<amendment number="h670"/>
		<amendment number="h671"/>
		<amendment number="h672"/>
		<amendment number="h673"/>
		<amendment number="s2382"/>
		<amendment number="s2383"/>
		<amendment number="s2384"/>
		<amendment number="s2385"/>
		<amendment number="s2386"/>
		<amendment number="s2387"/>
		<amendment number="s2388"/>
		<amendment number="s2389"/>
		<amendment number="s2390"/>
		<amendment number="s2391"/>
		<amendment number="s2392"/>
		<amendment number="s2393"/>
		<amendment number="s2394"/>
		<amendment number="s2395"/>
		<amendment number="s2396"/>
		<amendment number="s2397"/>
		<amendment number="s2398"/>
		<amendment number="s2399"/>
		<amendment number="s2400"/>
		<amendment number="s2401"/>
		<amendment number="s2402"/>
		<amendment number="s2403"/>
		<amendment number="s2405"/>
		<amendment number="s2406"/>
		<amendment number="s2407"/>
		<amendment number="s2408"/>
		<amendment number="s2409"/>
		<amendment number="s2410"/>
		<amendment number="s2411"/>
		<amendment number="s2412"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/1994--Conference report filed in House. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of the Interior Title II: Related Agencies Title III: General Provisions Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1995 - Title I: Department of the Interior - Makes appropriations for FY 1995 operation of the Department of the Interior. Sets forth the uses and limitations for such appropriations, including use of Bureau of Indian Affairs school system funds. Title II: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 1995 for the Department of Agriculture for the Forest Service. Makes appropriations for the Department of Energy for, among other things, fossil energy research and development, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), and the SPR Account. Makes appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services for the Indian Health Service for Indian health services and facilities. Appropriates funds to: (1) the Department of Education for the Office of Elementary and Secondary Education for Indian education; (2) the Office of Navajo and Hopi Relocation; (3) the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; (4) the Smithsonian Institution; (5) construction and improvements at the National Zoological Park; (6) restoration and repair of buildings owned or occupied by the Smithsonian Institution; (7) the National Gallery of Art; (8) the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts; and (9) the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars. Makes appropriations for: (1) the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities; (2) the Institute of Museum Services; (3) the Commission of Fine Arts; (4) National Capital arts and cultural affairs; (5) the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; (6) the National Capital Planning Commission; (7) the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Commission; (8) the Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation; and (9) the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Council. Sets forth uses and prohibitions on such funds. Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth uses and limitations of funds appropriated by this Act. (Sec. 307) Requires expenditures under this Act to comply with the Buy American Act. Expresses the sense of the Congress that entities receiving Federal assistance should purchase only American-made equipment and products. Prohibits Federal contracts with persons found to have falsely labeled a product with a &quot;Made in America&quot; inscription.

	</summary>
</bill>
