<bill session="103" type="h" number="4607" updated="2010-04-19T11:09:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Vancouver National Heritage Area Partnership Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Vancouver National Heritage Area, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411040"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1269)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Prior to Referral.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-30"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.5044.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="5044" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Army posts"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="General aviation aircraft"/>
		<term name="Helicopters"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Humanities"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Museums"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/1994--Introduced.
Vancouver National Heritage Area Partnership Act of 1994 - Establishes: (1) the Vancouver National Heritage Area in the State of Washington; and (2) the Vancouver National Heritage Area Partnership to oversee the protection, enhancement, and development of the Area. (Sec. 5) Requires the Partnership to: (1) be a forum for cooperation and coordination between the public agencies represented in the Area; (2) minimize staffing, development, and operational costs to each member agency; (3) promote the coordinated protection, use, and interpretation of the cultural, recreational, and educational resources of the Area; (4) identify additional opportunities for public use and enjoyment of the Area; (5) develop and implement the management plan required for the lands included in the Area; and (6) be formalized by the compact described in this Act. (Sec. 8) Requires the Partnership to prepare, sign, and submit to the Secretary of the Interior for approval a compact, prepared with public participation, that shall function as a memorandum of agreement between Partnership members. (Sec. 9) Requires the Partnership: (1) to develop and submit a management plan for the Area to the Secretary for review and approval; and (2) every five years, to submit a revised plan to the Secretary upon evaluating the progress made in implementing the original one. (Sec. 10) Requires the management plan to permit general aviation at Pearson Airpark to continue, provided that: (1) Pearson Field and Air Museum shall be operated by the city of Vancouver; (2) Vancouver pays the National Park Service (NPS) a fee of $1 per year for the continued use and occupancy of the Airpark and Air Museum on NPS property; (3) all nonhistoric, aviation-related buildings and devices shall be removed by Vancouver from NPS property by the year 2003, except those necessary for navigation and safety; (4) Vancouver shall not be compensated for historic buildings remaining on NPS property, but shall be liable and responsible for continued use and maintenance of these structures; (5) approval of the NPS is required for all structural improvements and structural additions to the Air Museum for its structures and facilities located on NPS property; (6) helicopters shall not be based at Pearson Airpark except as necessary to accommodate emergency, disaster, or national security needs; (7) the total number of airworthy aircraft based at the Airpark shall be determined by the Pearson economic plan in agreement with the Partnership; and (8) the Partnership shall prepare the Pearson Airpark economic viability and mitigation plan as part of the management plan. (Sec. 11) Authorizes the Secretary to provide financial and technical assistance in preparing and developing the compact and management plan. (Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
