<bill session="103" type="h" number="4627" updated="2010-04-19T11:12:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prisoner Transfer Equity Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the negotiation of prisoner transfer treaties in order to relieve overcrowding in Federal and State prisons.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402325"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/1994--Introduced.
Prisoner Transfer Equity Act of 1994 - Urges the President to begin to negotiate prisoner transfer treaties and renegotiate existing treaties with countries that currently have more prisoners in U.S. prisons than there are U.S. citizens in their prisons in order to relieve overcrowding in Federal and State prisons, focusing on the transfer of illegal aliens who are serving in U.S. prisons. Requires the President to report to the Congress on the progress of such negotiations. Specifies that, if such a report indicates that no progress has been made in negotiations with a foreign country, that such country is unwilling to proceed with serious negotiations, and that the United States has a greater number of prisoners who are citizens of that country than the number of prisoners in that country who are U.S. citizens, not less than one percent nor more than ten percent of U.S. assistance allocated for such country, as determined by the President, shall be withheld until the President certifies to the Congress that progress has been made in negotiations with that country to carry out the purpose of this Act. Authorizes the President to waive such provision if withholding assistance would jeopardize the relationship between the United States and that foreign country and that would not be in the national interest. Requires the President, if exercising such waiver authority, to submit a statement in writing to the Congress setting forth the justification for the exercise of such waiver. Urges the President to use such diplomatic and other efforts as may be necessary to ensure progress in negotiating prisoner transfer treaties to carry out the purpose of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
