<bill session="103" type="h" number="4640" updated="2010-04-19T11:14:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf of Maine Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Gulf of Maine Council to promote the economic development and ensure the environmental quality of the Gulf of Maine, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400885"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410496" joined="1994-06-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4885-4886)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-05"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-05"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-05"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Management.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-05"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-05"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce, EPA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-08"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-08"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA-07" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere Affairs" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Fisheries Management" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Economic Development" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="2241" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="2241" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
		<term name="Estuarine ecology"/>
		<term name="Estuarine oceanography"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="International fishery management"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Maine"/>
		<term name="Marine ecology"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="New Hampshire"/>
		<term name="Ocean"/>
		<term name="Regional planning"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Sustainable development"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Underemployment"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Waterways"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/23/1994--Introduced.
Gulf of Maine Act of 1994 - Establishes a Gulf of Maine Council to promote the environmental and economic health of the Gulf of Maine. Requires the Council to: (1) facilitate the coordination of governmental and nongovernmental activities related to the Gulf; (2) establish a Gulf of Maine Advisory Group to advise the Council, the Governors of Maine, Massachusetts, and New Hampshire, and the Premiers of Nova Scotia and New Brunswick on the implementation of this Act; and (3) adopt a Gulf of Maine Agreement for the protection, assessment, management, and sustainable development of the Gulf. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Council to establish an Economic Development Board to implement a long-term plan for coordinating environmentally sound economic assistance for the Gulf region. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to provide planning and local technical assistance grants to the Council for related projects. Makes a cooperative agreement available through the Economic Development Administration for planning programs to retain or create full-time permanent jobs and income for individuals who are unemployed or underemployed as a result of Federal fishery management regulations. Authorizes appropriations. Permits the Council to submit recommendations to the New England Fishery Management Council (Management Council) on fishery management plans if recommendations are necessary to make such plans reflect the goals and priorities of the Agreement. Requires the Secretary, if in concurrence with such recommendations, to issue a finding that the Management Council review such plans in light of the Council's recommendations. Establishes an Environmental Management and Assessment Program for the Gulf region and provides for a plan for improved environmental management and assessment. Authorizes grants to the Council for such purposes. Authorizes appropriations. Permits the Regional Marine Research Board for the Gulf of Maine, with the Secretary's approval, to revise schedules for the development of research plans under the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to ensure coordination with activities under this Act. Authorizes the Council to establish a Gulf of Maine Research Advisory Group. Authorizes appropriations. Permits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to award grants to the St. Croix International Waterway Commission to support its activities. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
