<bill session="103" type="h" number="4659" updated="2010-04-19T11:17:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Health Care Liability Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To impose certain requirements on health care liability claims.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400504"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1332)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-18"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Civil procedure"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Malpractice"/>
		<term name="Medical associations"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Products liability"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/27/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Health Care Liability Reform Subtitle A: Reform Described Subtitle B: Requirements for State Alternative Dispute Resolution Systems (ADR) Federal Health Care Liability Reform Act of 1994 - Title I: General Provisions - Applies this Act to any health care liability claim or action in State or Federal court, except for vaccine or medical product injuries. Preempts State laws, subject to limitations. Title II: Health Care Liability Reform - Subtitle A: Reform Described - Requires initial resolution under an alternative dispute resolution system (ADR) of State or Federal health care liability actions and claims against the United States. Sets a time limit for commencement of actions. Limits contingent attorney's fees to percentages of the amount recovered (including any periodic payments projected to life expectancy). Requires payment by the contesting party of attorney's fees and costs if the award amount is not adjusted at least a specified percentage in favor of the contesting party. Limits noneconomic damages for an injury to a specified dollar amount regardless of the number of defendants or the number of actions. Requires, if requested by either party, that future expense payments over a certain amount be paid on a periodic basis. Mandates collateral source payment offsets. Regulates punitive damages with regard to the standard of proof, medical products subject to premarket approval, pleadings, separate proceedings, and amount. Permits several but not joint liability. Allows injunctions prohibiting violations of this title. Authorizes State agencies responsible for health care practitioner disciplinary actions to make agreements with professional societies to participate in health care practitioner licensing and to review malpractice actions and allegations. Subtitle B: Requirements for State Alternative Dispute Resolutions Systems (ADR) - Sets forth requirements for State ADRs, including requiring that State ADRs apply to all health care liability claims in that State's courts. Provides for annual Federal certification of State ADRs and mandates an alternative Federal ADR for claims in uncertified States. Requires uncertified States to reimburse the United States for costs and prohibits payments under the Public Health Service Act to those States, their local governments, or any entity in those States.

	</summary>
</bill>
