<bill session="103" type="h" number="4664" updated="2010-04-19T11:18:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide relief from antidumping and countervailing duty orders in cases of short supply.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405855"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408661" joined="1994-06-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Antidumping"/>
		<term name="Countervailing duties"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to require the administering authority, whenever it has determined upon the filing of a short-supply petition that a short-supply situation exists with respect to a particular product within the same class or kind as merchandise that is the subject of an antidumping duty order or finding, or a countervailing duty order, to authorize the importation of additional quantities of such merchandise free of duties, estimated duty deposits, reporting requirements, and other restrictions, unless it determines that such imports will erode the pricing structure of domestic merchandise comparable to the class or kind of merchandise that is subject to such order or finding. Requires the administering authority, whenever it finds that a short-supply petition contains adequate information, to determine: (1) if a short-supply situation exists in the United States with respect to a product; and (2) if an affirmative determination is made, the quantity of the product, if any, that may be imported into the United States without regard to the applicable antidumping or countervailing duty order. Requires the administering authority, if it determines that a short-supply situation does not exist because a U.S. producer states that it will supply the product in the quantity requested, and such producer fails to supply such product as promised, to grant a short-supply allowance for the quantity such producer failed to supply.

	</summary>
</bill>
