<bill session="103" type="h" number="4678" updated="2010-04-19T11:20:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Budget Resolution Accountability Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide more program specificity during consideration of concurrent resolutions on the budget, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408364"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional Record"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Legislative amendments"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/29/1994--Introduced.
Budget Resolution Accountability Act of 1994 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Budget Committee report accompanying the concurrent resolution on the budget to include each specific deviation from the President's budget by program and amount. Prohibits the offering of amendments in the House of Representatives or the Senate that increase or decrease spending in any functional category unless a statement has been inserted in the Congressional Record that identifies the specific program, project, or activity that is to be increased or decreased. Expresses the sense of the House that during consideration of a concurrent resolution on the budget in the Committee of the Whole, the Committee on Rules should allow specific amendments to increase or decrease particular functional categories and not only amendments in the nature of a substitute.

	</summary>
</bill>
