<bill session="103" type="h" number="4687" updated="2010-04-19T11:22:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Health Equity Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to prohibit a State from requiring any child with special health care needs to receive services under the State's plan for medical assistance under such title through enrollment with a capitated managed care plan until the State adopts pediatric risk adjustment methodologies to take into account the costs to capitated managed care plans of providing services to such children, and to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop model pediatric risk adjustment methodologies for such purpose.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300068"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5457, E1395-1396)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-22"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/30/1994--Introduced.
Children's Health Equity Act of 1994 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to prohibit a State from requiring any child with special health care needs to receive services under the State's Medicaid plan through enrollment with a capitated managed care plan, unless the State adopts pediatric risk adjustment methodologies under which the State adjusts the payment rates for such plans to take into account the financial risks of enrolling such children. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and report to the Congress on model pediatric risk adjustment methodologies for such purpose.

	</summary>
</bill>
