<bill session="103" type="h" number="4715" updated="2010-04-19T11:26:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain lands administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400176"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-06"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-30"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Forest roads"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National monuments"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/30/1994--Introduced.
Applies Federal provisions governing the conveyance of certain parcels and road rights-of-way of National Forest System lands administered by the Secretary of Agriculture to lands administered by the Secretary of the Interior. Revises such provisions to: (1) authorize the appropriate Secretary to convey such lands by patent, if appropriate; (2) increase the maximum value of lands that may be so conveyed to $250,000; (3) provide for conveyance of parcels of 40 acres or less (currently, ten acres or less) subject to specified encroachment, or of tracts of parcels of any size involving adjacent parcels subject to similar encroachment; (4) authorize conveyances of qualified tracts of lands within the National Wilderness Preservation System, National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, National Trails System, national monuments, or national recreation areas by cash sale only, at fair market value, with the proceeds to be accumulated into a restricted fund for purchase of additional private lands within or adjacent to such special areas; and (5) authorize boundary adjustments within such specially designated areas in order to resolve encroachments which existed before the time of designation.

	</summary>
</bill>
