<bill session="103" type="h" number="4745" updated="2010-04-19T11:31:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Derivatives Dealers Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a framework for Securities and Exchange Commission supervision and regulation of derivatives activities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400253"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410589" joined="1994-07-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1469-1471)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Securities"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Brokers"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Capital"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Derivative securities"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Financial statements"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government securities"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Risk management"/>
		<term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
		<term name="Securities fraud"/>
		<term name="Securities industry"/>
		<term name="Securities regulation"/>
		<term name="Stock exchanges"/>
		<term name="Trade associations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/13/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Derivatives Dealers Title II: Broker-Dealer Oversight Reforms Derivatives Dealers Act of 1994 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (the Act) to define &quot;derivatives dealer,&quot; &quot;material associated person,&quot; and &quot;person associated with a derivatives dealer&quot; so as to include derivatives dealers affiliated with securities and insurance firms. Title I: Derivatives Dealers - Sets forth: (1) registration and notice requirements for derivatives broker/dealers and material associated persons of such broker/dealers; (2) Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) rulemaking authority over derivatives dealers; and (3) membership requirements in a registered securities association for derivatives dealers. Title II: Broker-Dealer Oversight Reforms - Authorizes national securities exchanges and registered securities associations to prescribe internal rules and enforcement guidelines for members engaged in derivatives transactions and for material associated persons. Requires SEC financial responsibility rules to include maintenance of sufficient capital levels taking into account selected activities of any registered derivatives dealer that is a material associated person of a broker or dealer. Includes within SEC risk assessment guidelines the derivatives transactions of government and municipal securities broker/dealers, and of registered broker/dealers.

	</summary>
</bill>
