<bill session="103" type="h" number="4741" updated="2010-04-19T11:30:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Guam War Restitution Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Organic Act of Guam to provide for restitution to the people of Guam who suffered atrocities such as personal injury, forced labor, forced marches, internment and death during the occupation of Guam in World War II, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400516"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="403314" joined="1994-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5645-5650)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Late Referral to the Subcommittee on Insular and International Affairs (Nov 30, 94).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7293-7297)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-20"><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee On Insular and International Affairs Prior to Referral.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-04"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held and Forwarded to Full Committee by the Subcommittee On Insular and International Affairs Prior to Referral by Voice Vote.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular and International Affairs" activity="Hearings, Markup" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
		<term name="Concentration camps"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Housing finance"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Japan"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Military history"/>
		<term name="Military occupation"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Probate law and practice"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="World War II"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/13/1994--Introduced.
Guam War Restitution Act - Amends the Organic Act of Guam to apply this Act to Guamanians who did not meet the one-year time limitation for filing of death or personal injury claims specified in a certain Act or who suffered other compensable injuries if such Guamanians, their heirs, or next of kin meet the eligibility, time limitation for filing, and other criteria set forth in this Act. Defines &quot;compensable injury&quot; as one of the three following categories of injury incurred during, or as a result of, World War II: (1) death; (2) personal injury; or (3) forced labor, forced march, or internment. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to render final decisions concerning claims for awards and benefits under this Act. Sets forth eligibility requirements. Makes awards available to Guamanians who personally received the compensable injury or to their heirs or next of kin in claims for death. Makes benefits available to Guamanians who are heirs or next of kin of the decedent Guamanian who received the compensable injury and who died after September 2, 1945. Requires payment of the award or benefit relating to death to be prorated among the heirs or next of kin claiming for the same death, as provided in the Guam probate laws. Establishes the Guam Restitution Claims Fund, the Guam Restitution Trust Fund, and the Guam Restitution Trust Fund Board of Directors. Permits the Board to make disbursements from the Trust Fund only: (1) to sponsor research and public educational activities relating to Guamanian wartime experiences; (2) to disburse funds as benefits to eligible claimants through a revolving fund for purposes such as post-secondary scholarships and first-time home ownership loans; and (3) for administrative expenses. Limits any remuneration on account of services rendered on behalf of any claimant in connection with any claim to five percent of the amount paid on such claim. Prescribes penalties for violations of such limit. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
