<bill session="103" type="h" number="4756" updated="2010-04-19T11:33:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to take into account the health of a primary caregiver in determining whether an item of durable medical equipment is considered medically necessary and appropriate under part B of the medicare program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Caregivers"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/1994--Introduced.
Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, when determining whether an item of durable medical equipment (DME) is reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury or to improve the functioning of a malformed body member with respect to an ill or injured individual, to consider the effect of a denial of payment for the DME item on the health of the individual's live-in primary caregiver. Defines the primary caregiver as one who assists the ill or injured individual without monetary compensation in the performance of such activities of daily living as eating, bathing, dressing, toileting, and transferring in and out of a bed or a chair.

	</summary>
</bill>
