<bill session="103" type="h" number="4750" updated="2010-04-19T11:32:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Policy and Conservation Act Amendments of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to manage the Strategic Petroleum Reserve more effectively, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409793"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.4751.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>For Further Action See H.R.4752.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4751" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4752" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Energy law and legislation"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Antitrust actions"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Coal"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Eminent domain"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy supplies"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Fuel allocation"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Natural gas"/>
		<term name="Petroleum"/>
		<term name="Petroleum industry"/>
		<term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
		<term name="Petroleum storage"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Strategic materials"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/13/1994--Introduced.
Energy Policy and Conservation Act Amendments Act of 1994 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to repeal the loan guarantee program for development of underground coal mines. Transfers the Strategic Petroleum Reserve Office from the Federal Energy Administration to the Secretary of Energy. Repeals the mandates for: (1) a Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) Plan (while retaining authority for a one billion barrel Reserve); (2) an Early Storage Reserve; (3) a minimum fill rate; and (4) Utility, Coal, and Remote Crude Oil and Natural Gas Reserves. Makes the Regional Petroleum Reserve part of the SPR. Revises SPR operation and maintenance guidelines affecting expansion, drawdown, and distribution plans. Revises SPR drawdown and distribution guidelines, including: (1) a repeal of the Secretary's allocation authority; and (2) a mandate that the Secretary sell SPR petroleum at public sale to the highest bidder. Revises: (1) SPR annual reporting requirements; and (2) guidelines governing the obligation of funds from the SPR Petroleum Account. Extends the authorities relating to the SPR through FY 1999. Repeals general emergency authorities for energy conservation, rationing, and related contingency plans. Revises guidelines governing: (1) international voluntary agreements affecting emergency responses; (2) the applicability of the Defense Production Act of 1950; and (3) antitrust defenses applicable to international voluntary agreements. Extends through FY 1999 the authorization of appropriations for interagency working groups to promote export of renewable energy and energy efficiency products and services. Extends emergency energy authorities through FY 1999. Extends authorizations of appropriations through FY 1999 for: (1) State energy conservation programs; and (2) the energy conservation program for schools and hospitals. Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to extend through FY 1999 the authorization of appropriations for the weatherization assistance program for low-income persons.

	</summary>
</bill>
