<bill session="103" type="h" number="4769" updated="2010-04-19T11:35:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the treatment of long-term care insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1472)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Accident insurance"/>
		<term name="Accounting"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
		<term name="Brain diseases"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Caregivers"/>
		<term name="Chronically ill"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Consumer complaints"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Critically ill"/>
		<term name="Day care centers for the aged"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Endorsements in advertising"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grandparents"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Insurance agents"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Parents"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Pensions"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Respite care"/>
		<term name="Sales promotion"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Students"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Tax Treatment of Long-Term Care Insurance Title II: Establishment of Federal Standards for Long-Term Care Insurance Title III: Deduction for Certain Expenses for Dependents with Alzheimer's Disease or Related Organic Brain Disorders Title IV: Dependent Care Credit Expanded and Made Refundable Title I: Tax Treatment of Long-Term Care Insurance - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the treatment of qualified long-term care insurance or plans as accident and health insurance or plans for purposes of insurance company taxation. (Sec. 102) Excludes from gross income benefits provided under a long-term care insurance contract. Includes in gross income employer-provided coverage for long-term care services. (Sec. 103) Allows a tax credit for a percentage of eligible long-term care premiums. (Sec. 104) Includes amounts paid for qualified long-term care services as medical expenses for individual itemized deductions. Includes any parent or grandparent as a dependent for purposes of such expenses. (Sec. 105) Requires long-term care insurance contracts to use a one-year full preliminary term tax reserve method. (Sec. 106) Excludes from gross income certain amounts withdrawn from individual retirement accounts and certain employer cash or deferred arrangements to pay long-term care premiums. (Sec. 107) Provides for the exclusion as a death benefit of any amount paid or advanced to an individual under a life insurance contract because such individual is terminally ill, chronically ill, or has been permanently confined to a qualified facility. (Sec. 108) Allows insurance companies to issue accelerated death benefit riders on life insurance contracts. (Sec. 109) Permits long-term care insurance contracts to be offered in cafeteria plans. Title II: Establishment of Federal Standards for Long-term Care Insurance - Amends the Public Health Service Act to mandate the establishment of model Federal standards for long-term care insurance. Prohibits the offering of a long-term care insurance policy in a State unless the State has a regulatory program meeting the requirements of this Act or the policy has been certified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Authorizes grants to States for demonstration programs to improve enforcement of the standards. Authorizes appropriations. Imposes on agents selling long-term policies a duty of good faith and fair dealing. Prohibits twisting, high pressure tactics, and cold lead advertising. Mandates minimum financial standards, including income and asset criteria, for advising individuals considering the purchase of a long-term policy. Prohibits sales: (1) to an individual eligible for assistance under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act; (2) of duplicate service policies; and (3) of policies that reduce, limit, or coordinate benefits on the basis of eligibility for other coverage or benefits. Provides for: (1) criminal and civil penalties; and (2) agent training and certification. Sets forth additional carrier responsibilities relating to refunding of premiums, mailing of policies, providing information on denials of claims, and reporting of information. Prohibits cancellation or nonrenewal of a long-term care policy except for nonpayment of premium or material misrepresentation. Sets forth continuation and conversion rights for group policies, regulating premiums for converted policies. Requires guaranteed issuance to an individual if the individual meets the minimum medical requirements of the policy. Mandates standards regarding upgraded benefits. Limits cancellation for nonpayment by an incapacitated individual. Requires: (1) subject to exceptions, uniform language and definitions, a uniform format, and at least one standard benefit package; and (2) disclosure of certain matters, including an outline of coverage. Mandates recommendations by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) regarding informing consumers on the long-term economic viability of long-term care insurance carriers. Limits certain conditions on benefits. Requires, if benefits are provided for home health care or community-based services, that certain minimum benefits be provided. Prohibits treating cognitive or mental impairments (including Alzheimer's disease and mental illness) differently from other medical conditions. Limits preexisting condition requirements. Requires: (1) each claimant to have a functional assessment by an individual or entity meeting NAIC qualifications and unconnected to the policy issuer; (2) inflation protection, unless rejected in writing by a policyholder; (3) disclosure of certain premium increases; and (4) nonforfeiture benefits. Prohibits a carrier from contesting a policy or claim based on fraud or misrepresentation unless notice is provided within a time period set by NAIC. Establishes the right of a purchaser to return a policy within a specified period. Defines &quot;long-term care insurance policy,&quot; excluding: (1) any basic Medicare supplemental policies; (2) other insurance offered primarily to provide specified types of coverage; and (3) certain life insurance policies. Authorizes grants for programs to provide information, counseling, and assistance regarding the procurement of long-term insurance. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Deduction for Certain Expenses for Dependents with Alzheimer's Disease or Related Organic Brain Disorders - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual an income tax deduction for qualified home health care and adult day and respite care expenses with respect to a dependent who: (1) resides with the taxpayer; (2) suffers from Alzheimer's disease or a related organic brain disorder; and (3) is physically or mentally incapable of self- care. Title IV: Dependent Care Credit Expanded and Made Refundable - Repeals the Internal Revenue Code's nonrefundable income tax credit for employment- related dependent care expenses, replacing it with a corresponding refundable 50 percent credit, reduced (but not below 20 percent) as the taxpayer's adjusted gross income exceeds $15,000 (adjusted for inflation). Includes within the scope of the new credit up to $1,200 ($2,400 in the case of more than one qualifying individual) of respite care expenses incurred in the care of: (1) a dependent of the taxpayer who is at least 13 years old; or (2) a spouse or other dependent who is physically or mentally incapable of self-care.

	</summary>
</bill>
