<bill session="103" type="h" number="4760" updated="2010-04-19T11:33:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">High Seas Fisheries Licensing Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To implement the Agreement to Promote Compliance with International Conservation and Management Measures by Fishing Vessels on the High Seas, adopted by the Conference on the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations on November 24, 1993.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="407141" joined="1994-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Fisheries Management" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fishery agreements"/>
		<term name="Fishing boats"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International fishery management"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/1994--Introduced.
High Seas Fisheries Licensing Act of 1994 - Prohibits a high seas vessel from engaging in harvesting operations on the high seas unless the vessel has on board a valid license issued under this Act. Makes any U.S. vessel eligible to receive such a license unless the vessel was previously authorized to be used for fishing on the high seas by a foreign nation and: (1) such nation suspended such authorization because the vessel undermined the effectiveness of international conservation and management measures; or (2) such nation, within the last three years preceding application for a license, withdrew such authorization because the vessel undermined the effectiveness of international conservation and management measures. Makes such restriction inapplicable in cases where the Secretary of Commerce determines that issuing a license would not subvert the Agreement to Promote Compliance with International Conservation and Management Measures by Fishing Vessels on the High Seas. Sets forth application and fee provisions. Directs the Secretary to maintain a record of high seas fishing vessels issued licenses under this Act and to notify the flag State if a foreign fishing vessel has engaged in activities undermining the effectiveness of international conservation and management measures. Sets forth enforcement and penalty provisions.

	</summary>
</bill>
