<bill session="103" type="h" number="4767" updated="2010-04-19T11:34:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the welfare system.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400256"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="1994-08-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400354" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="411947" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="407672" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1994-08-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1994-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1994-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1994-08-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="1994-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1478-1479)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-20"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations and Nutrition.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-08"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>See H.R.5252.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Department Operations and Nutrition" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="5252" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public welfare"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Black lung"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Caregivers"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Child support"/>
		<term name="Child welfare"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Citizenship"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Compensatory education"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Domestic relations"/>
		<term name="Driver licenses"/>
		<term name="Dropout prevention"/>
		<term name="Dropouts"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
		<term name="Drugs and youth"/>
		<term name="Due process of law"/>
		<term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Elementary school students"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Food stamps"/>
		<term name="Garnishment"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal services"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Management audit"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Marriage"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle registration"/>
		<term name="National service"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Oaths"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Parents"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Paternity"/>
		<term name="Payroll deductions"/>
		<term name="Pensions"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public records"/>
		<term name="Public service employment"/>
		<term name="Puerto Rico"/>
		<term name="Real property"/>
		<term name="Residence requirements"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Safety measures"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Secondary school students"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Single-parent families"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Social services"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State courts"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="Student aid"/>
		<term name="Student employment"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Tax administration"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
		<term name="Unmarried fathers"/>
		<term name="Unmarried mothers"/>
		<term name="Vaccination"/>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
		<term name="Virgin Islands"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Workers' compensation"/>
		<term name="Youth"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
		<term name="Youth services"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Promotion of Work and Self-Sufficiency Subtitle A: Expansion of Funding for, and Participation in, the JOBS Program Subtitle B: Job Creation, Job Placement and Development, and Work Requirements Subtitle C: Support for Working Families Subtitle D: Child Care Title II: Strengthening Parental Responsibility and Family Stability Subtitle A: Federal Responsibilities Subtitle B: Paternity Establishment Subtitle C: Enforcement Subtitle D: State Responsibilities Subtitle E: Demonstrations Subtitle F: Miscellaneous Title III: Teen Parents and Welfare Reform Subtitle A: Family Subtitle B: Education and Employment Subtitle C: Case Management Subtitle D: Demonstration Projects Title IV: Waivers Title V: Improving Government Assistance Subtitle A: AFDC Amendments Subtitle B: Food Stamp Act Amendments Title VI: Effective Date Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 1994 - Title I: Promotion of Work and Self-Sufficiency - Subtitle A: Expansion of Funding for, and Participation in, the JOBS Program - Amends title IV (Aid to Families With Dependent Children) (AFDC) to increase funding and the matching rate for the Job Opportunities and Basic Skills (JOBS) program. Revises JOBS participation requirements. (Sec. 104) Requires State plans to provide for a preliminary assessment of a family's self-sufficiency needs within 30 days after approval of an AFDC application. Subtitle B: Job Creation, Job Placement and Development, and Work Requirements - Authorizes any State to establish a public jobs creation program providing AFDC-eligible individuals with employment in the public sector or in private nonprofit organizations. (Sec. 112) Revises job placement, job development, and job retention activities retirements to provide for their expansion. (Sec. 113) Requires establishment of self-employment programs. Subtitle C: Support for Working Families - Eliminates the dollar-for-dollar &quot;work penalty&quot; in determining the amount of an AFDC recipient's earned income disregard. (Sec. 122) Raises the limitation on total family income. (Sec. 123) Allows a State the option to extend Medicaid enrollment for former AFDC recipients for one additional year after they have obtained employment. (Sec. 124) Revises treatment of two-parent families. (Sec. 125) Increases the stepparent income disregard. Subtitle D: Child Care - Increases child care funding. (Sec. 132) Sets forth a formula for payments to encourage the use of an entire State allotment for at-risk child care. Limits the carryforward of unused allotments. (Sec. 134) Requires a State agency to pay a family at most 75 percent of the actual local cost of child care (or a higher maximum, as the State may establish). (Sec. 135) Requires a State to set aside a specified portion of Federal funds for the improvement of the quality of services and the building of infrastructure to serve low-income children. (Sec. 136) Revises requirements with respect to child care for working AFDC parents. (Sec. 137) Revises child care health and safety standards and continuity of care requirements. (Sec. 138) Requires a State agency to ensure: (1) periodic identification of child care needs; (2) family understanding of child care alternatives; and (3) reimbursement mechanisms meeting family needs. (Sec. 140) Revises &quot;seamless services facilitation&quot; requirements for the provision of child care assistance to families who cease to receive AFDC benefits. (Sec. 141) Allows States to continue child care assistance without interruption during breaks between otherwise allowable activities, and for a reasonable time after loss of employment, to ensure continuity of child care arrangements. (Sec. 142) Requires States to guarantee child care whether or not a caretaker relative is receiving AFDC. (Sec. 143) Grants States the option to extend transitional child care benefits, and provide them to families who have received AFDC for less than three months. (Sec. 145) Limits at-risk child care to families ineligible for recipient or transitional child care. (Sec. 146) Repeals the requirement that a family receiving transitional child care benefits include a dependent child. (Sec. 148) Requires a State to ensure continued provision of child care with respect to a family of an individual in dispute resolution with the State over the individual's qualification for such care. (Sec. 149) Grants a State agency the option to enter agreements for consolidation of State responsibility for child care. Title II: Strengthening Parental Responsibility and Family Stability - Subtitle A: Federal Responsibilities - Adds to present uses of the Federal Parent Locator Service: (1) establishing parentage, or establishing, modifying, and enforcing child support obligations; and (2) providing safeguards to prevent the disclosure of information in case that would jeopardize the safety of the custodial or noncustodial parent or any child of either such parent. (Sec. 202) Requires the Federal Parent Locator System to include information on an absent parent's income and assets. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) (the Secretary) to provide the System with prompt access to all Federal income tax returns. Directs the Secretary to expand the Parent Locator Service to establish a national network based on the comprehensive statewide child support enforcement systems developed by the States in order to give each State access to records of other States. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary to establish a Federal registry of all child support orders recorded in State registries. Requires the Federal registry to compare information on W-4 forms with information in child support orders. (Sec. 204) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a system of reporting by requiring employers to provide a copy of every employee's W-4 form to the Federal child support order registry. (Sec. 205) Increases the base matching rate for Federal payments for State child support enforcement activities. (Sec. 206) Revises requirements for performance-based incentives and penalties. (Sec. 207) Provides for increased Federal financial participation for States with unified child support enforcement programs. (Sec. 208) Directs the Secretary to promulgate criteria and standards for a new child support audit process. (Sec. 209) Establishes the National Child Support Guidelines Commission to develop a national child support guideline for congressional consideration based on a study of various guideline models, the benefits and efficiencies of such models, and any needed improvements. (Sec. 210) Directs the Secretary to establish a Child Support Audit Advisory Committee. Subtitle B: Paternity Establishment - Revises requirements for paternity establishment procedures. Requires States to provide for new outreach programs to encourage voluntary paternity acknowledgement. Sets forth an administrative penalty of AFDC recuctions for children for whom paternity is not established promptly. Subtitle C: Enforcement - Requires States to establish procedures for: (1) obtaining access to financial records maintained by any financial institution doing business in the State, for the purpose of establishing, modifying, or enforcing a child support obligation; and (2) requiring courts or administrative agencies to issue final orders in a child support or parentage case requiring each party to file addresses, telephone numbers, social security numbers, driver's license numbers, and other specified information. (Sec. 223) Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to allow a State agency administering an AFDC program to use consumer credit reports to establish, modify, or enforce a child support award. (Sec. 224) Amends Federal law to make Federal death, black lung, veterans, and workers' compensation benefits subject to garnishment for child support. (Sec. 225) Requires State and Federal holds on granting of certain occupational, professional, and business licenses for a noncustodial parent with a child support delinquency. (Sec. 226) Requires State procedures to: (1) deny driver's licenses and vehicle registrations to persons failing to appear in child support cases; and (2) systematically place liens on all nonexempt real and titled personal property for child support arrearages. (Sec. 228) Requires State procedures requiring a rebuttable presumption that, in any case related to child support, any transfer of property for significantly less than its fair market value by an individual who owes a child support arrearage is made with the intent to avoid payment of the arrearage. (Sec. 229) Revises from $1,000 to the monthly support obligation the minumum threshold for a State at its option to report child support arrearage information to a credit bureau. (Sec. 230) Authorizes the Secretary of State to refuse, revoke, restrict, or limit a passport to noncustodial parents subject to State arrest warrants for nonpayment of child support. (Sec. 231) Requires State procedures permitting enforcement of any child support order until the child attains age 30. (Sec. 232) Provides for State certification to the Secretary of the Treasury of a child support obligation for Internal Revenue Service collection. Subtitle D: State Responsibilities - Requires procedures under which a State child support enforcement agency shall establish an automated central child support order registry. (Sec. 241) Requires a State to transmit a wage withholding order to the employer of any individual upon the imposition of a child support obligation. (Sec. 242) Requires the Secretary to develop a uniform abstract of a child support order with specified contents. (Sec. 243) Requires States to enact the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act. (Sec. 244) Revises requirements for expedited processes, administrative procedures, and due process. (Sec. 246) Requires State plans to provide for an ongoing program of outreach to eligible persons. (Sec. 247) Requires States to: (1) ensure cost-of-living adjustments for child support awards; (2) establish a simplified process for review and adjustment of certain child support orders; and (3) ensure that the State does not provide to any noncustodial parent representation relating to review or adjustment of a child support order, unless the State makes such provision outside the State agency. (Sec. 250) Directs the Secretary to conduct and complete staffing studies for each State child support enforcement program, including each agency and court involved in the child support process. Requires specified reductions in AFDC payments to a State that has not met performance standards and has not implemented the staffing levels recommended in the report to the Congress on such studies. (Sec. 251) Requires States to develop and implement a program of annual training to all personnel performing functions under the State plan. (Sec. 252) Sets priorities for the distribution of collected child support. (Sec. 253) Grants States the option to waive temporarily the right to collect child support obligations of teen noncustodial parents participating in a State educational or employment preparation program. Subtitle E: Demonstrations - Directs the Secretary to make grants to up to six States to conduct demonstration projects for establishing or improving a system of assured minimum child support payments. Subtitle F: Miscellaneous - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to make a technical correction to the definition of medical child support order. Title III: Teen Parents and Welfare Reform - Subtitle A: Family - Requires a State plan to provide that, with specified exceptions, no AFDC benefits shall be provided to an individual under age 18 who has never married but has a dependent child in his or her care or is pregnant and eligible for AFDC if the individual's case manager determines that the individual is not residing in the home of the individual's parent, legal guardian, or other adult relative, or in a foster home, maternity home, or other adult-supervised supportive living arrangement. (Sec. 302) Requires a State plan to provide for a $50 increase in the monthly benefit to a family including an individual under age 20 who is the parent of a child whose paternity has been established or with respect to which a child support order is in effect. Subtitle B: Education and Employment - Sets forth schooling and employment requirements for any AFDC recipient who is under age 20 and is a custodial parent or is pregnant. (Sec. 312) Allows a State to increase AFDC payments by a certain amount to any qualified participant in certain appropriate summer educational or other activities. (Sec. 313) Provides for bonus payments to States which meet specified goals for teen participation in Job Opportunities and Basic Skills (JOBS) program activities. (Sec. 314) Allows States the option to provide child care for certain non-AFDC teen parents. Subtitle C: Case Management - Requires a State plan to provide for assignment of a case manager to each AFDC recipient who is under age 20 and is a custodial parent or is pregnant. Subtitle D: Demonstration Projects - Directs the HHS Secretary, the Secretary of Education, and the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service to jointly make grants to eligible entities for the development of intensive and sustained school-linked and school-based pregnancy prevention programs for adolescents and their families in areas of high poverty or high unmarried adolescent birth rates. Directs the HHS Secretary to approve between five and seven demonstration projects to provide comprehensive services to prevent adolescent pregnancy in high-risk communities. Title IV: Waivers - Provides for funding of waivers that are not cost neutral. Title V: Improving Government Assistance - Subtitle A: AFDC Amendments - Establishes a requirement that needs standards reflect the cost of essential items. (Sec. 502) Requires a State plan to provide that the maximum amount of AFDC payable to a family for any month shall not be reduced below the level in effect for October 1994 to a family of the same size. (Sec. 503) Allows States to supplement benefits for families subject to retrospective budgeting. (Sec. 504) Revises income disregards with respect to elementary or secondary students under age 20, including training stipends, lump-sum income, educational assistance, and in-kind income. (Sec. 505) Increases the resource limit for families eligible for AFDC from $1,000 to $2,000 (or, in the case of a family with a member who has attained 60 years of age, $3,000). Revises requirements for exclusions from resources, including cash value of life insurance policies, real property which must be disposed of, earned income tax credit payments, lump-sum payments for medical expenses or replacement of lost resources, and certain resources for self-employment. (Sec. 508) Requires States to require, as a condition of eligibility, that adult family members applying for such aid declare in writing that each family member is a U.S. citizen or eligible alien. (Sec. 509) Sets forth payment limits for Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam. Subtitle B: Food Stamp Act Amendments - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 with respect to inconsequential income, educational assistance, training stipends and allowances, income from on-the-job training programs, earned income tax credits, resources necessary for self-employment, and lump-sum payments for medical expenses or replacement of lost resources. Title VI: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
