<bill session="103" type="h" number="4781" updated="2010-04-19T11:36:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-11-02">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1994-11-02" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Antitrust Enforcement Assistance Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">International Antitrust Enforcement Assistance Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">International Antitrust Enforcement Assistance Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate obtaining foreign-located antitrust evidence by authorizing the Attorney General of the United States and the Federal Trade Commission to provide, in accordance with antitrust mutual assistance agreements, antitrust evidence to foreign antitrust authorities on a reciprocal basis; and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401837"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404097" joined="1994-07-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1496)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-08"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-29"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-29"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03T12:00:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 103-772.</text></action>
		<calendar number="420" datetime="1994-10-03T12:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 420.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03T12:21:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Brooks moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03T12:21:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10453-10456"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03T12:21:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-10-03T12:27:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03T12:27:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03"><text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1994-10-08" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S15021-15022"/></vote>
		<topresident datetime="1994-10-08" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<action datetime="1994-10-12"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1994-10-24" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1994-11-02" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-438" type="public" datetime="1994-11-02"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-438.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="2297" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Antitrust actions"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Privileges and immunities"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/3/1994--Passed House amended. International Antitrust Enforcement Assistance Act of 1994 - Authorizes the Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to provide, in accordance with an antitrust mutual assistance agreement in effect under this Act, antitrust evidence to assist a foreign antitrust authority in: (1) determining whether a person has violated, or is about to violate, any of the foreign antitrust laws administered or enforced by the authority; and (2) enforcing any of such laws. Requires a request for such investigative assistance to be made to the Attorney General, who may deny the request in whole or in part. Authorizes the Attorney General and the FTC to conduct investigations to obtain and provide to the authority evidence relating to a possible violation of such laws, regardless of whether the conduct investigated violates Federal antitrust law. Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to grant the FTC the power to conduct investigations of possible violations of such laws. Authorizes the U.S. district court for the district in which a person resides, is found, or transacts business, upon application of the Attorney General made in accordance with such an agreement, to order such person to give testimony or a statement, or to produce a document or other thing, to the Attorney General to assist the authority in making its determination or in enforcing any of such laws (but prohibits compelling such person to do so in violation of any legally applicable right or privilege). Sets forth provisions regarding the contents of the order, the preservation of rights and privileges, and voluntary conduct. Makes this Act inapplicable with respect to antitrust evidence that is: (1) received by the Attorney General or the FTC under provisions of the Clayton Act regarding a premerger notification and waiting period; (2) a matter occurring before a grand jury with respect to which disclosure is prevented by Federal law, with exceptions; (3) specifically authorized by executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy; and (4) classified under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954. Permits disclosure of antitrust evidence obtained under the Antitrust Civil Process Act in accordance with such an agreement. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) publication requirements; (2) implementation of such agreements; (3) limitations on judicial review; (4) preservation of authority; and (5) reporting requirements. Authorizes the Attorney General and the FTC to receive from a foreign antitrust authority, or from the foreign state or regional economic integration organization represented by such authority, reimbursement for costs incurred in conducting an investigation, applying for an order, or providing antitrust evidence to such authority.

	</summary>
</bill>
