<bill session="103" type="h" number="4788" updated="2010-04-19T11:38:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Health Care Eligibility Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to reform and simplify criteria for eligibility for health care provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400504"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="406768" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400127" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400028" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="1994-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300151" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400329" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400056" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400610" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409219" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1994-08-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5782, E1491-1492)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSVR-03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Continuum of care"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Nursing homes"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/19/1994--Introduced.
Veterans' Health Care Eligibility Reform Act of 1994 - Defines &quot;continuum of health care&quot; and &quot;noninstitutional long-term care&quot; under veterans' health care provisions. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide a continuum of health care to veterans eligible for veterans' benefits. (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary to provide institutional nursing home care to certain disabled veterans or those in receipt of a veterans' pension. Allows for recovery of nursing home care costs by the Secretary if the veteran is also eligible for such care through a State plan under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act. Designates a Department of Veterans Affairs facility as a Medicare provider for purposes of any program administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act. Declares a Department medical center as a Medicare HMO. Directs the HHS Secretary to reimburse a Department facility or medical center for providing services as a Medicare provider in the case of care for a non-service-connected disability of a veteran eligible for Medicare benefits. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to develop a plan to implement the provision of institutional long-term care for veterans who: (1) have a service-connected disability of less than 50 percent; (2) have an annual income below a formulated amount; (3) have a catastrophic nonservice-connected disability; or (4) require such care as a follow-up to inpatient care. Outlines, with respect to such care, provisions concerning: (1) premiums and copayments for covered veterans; (2) the issuance of a long-term care insurance contract; and (3) a report from the Secretary to the Congress on the costs of the plan and the insurance contract and legislation required for plan implementation. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to administer a program of health insurance known as the VA Group Health Plan as a managed-care plan meeting specified requirements. Allows any eligible veteran and his or her spouse or child to be enrolled in the Plan. Provides Plan enrollment requirements. Prohibits the Plan from imposing a limitation or exclusion of benefits relating to treatment for certain preexisting conditions. Directs the Secretary to administer the Plan so that no appropriated funds are required for Plan operation. Requires an annual report to the Congress by the Secretary on Plan operation, as well as an initial report. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to administer the health programs of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) through use of a managed care medical practice model, with limitations. Directs the Secretary to organize the VHA health care delivery and resources into geographic regions known as veterans service areas. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary for FY 1995 through 1999 for: (1) acquiring medical equipment to relieve existing medical equipment backlogs in Department facilities; and (2) infrastructure improvement, patient care amenities, primary care services and personnel, and medical facility construction projects.

	</summary>
</bill>
