<bill session="103" type="h" number="4815" updated="2010-04-19T11:42:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that pay for Members of Congress shall be reduced whenever total expenditures of the Federal Government exceed total receipts in any fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300055"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400298" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400165" joined="1994-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400611" joined="1994-07-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Balanced budgets"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Record votes"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/22/1994--Introduced.
Congressional Fiscal Responsibility Act of 1994 - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to reduce the annual salary of a Member of Congress by five percent for FY 1998 and ten percent for FY 1999 through 2001 if the total expenditures of the Federal Government exceed its total receipts for a fiscal year. Requires the reductions to be cumulative and prohibits their total from exceeding 35 percent. Requires such reductions in salary to be disregarded effective as of the first pay period beginning on or after the date the Congress receives a report indicating that total receipts of the Federal Government are greater than or equal to its total expenditures for a fiscal year. Requires restoration of the Member's salary to the level which would then be in effect without enactment of this Act. Mandates such pay adjustments before any other adjustment scheduled to take effect on the same day for the same position. Makes it out of order for the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any bill or resolution increasing the salary for Members of Congress, with specified exceptions, unless the bill or resolution deals with no subject matter other than a pay increase for members. Requires a recorded vote by the House or Senate in the passage or adoption of such bill or resolution.

	</summary>
</bill>
