<bill session="103" type="h" number="4810" updated="2010-04-19T11:41:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Integrated Child Health Care Network Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from granting a waiver under the medicaid program to permit a State to require children enrolled in the program to receive medical assistance under the program through managed care plans unless such assistance is provided through an integrated child health care network, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409627"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1994-08-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="1994-08-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="406729" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400537" joined="1994-09-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1525)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1586-1587)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/21/1994--Introduced.
Integrated Child Health Care Network Act of 1994 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from granting a waiver under the Medicaid program to permit a State to require children enrolled in the program to receive medical assistance through managed care plans, unless such assistance is provided through an integrated child health care network. Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities over a three-year period for the establishment and operation of such networks using different payment models, including grants to demonstrate the operation of networks (including State-initiated networks) applying a separate capitated payment rate with respect to children enrolled with the network.

	</summary>
</bill>
