<bill session="103" type="h" number="4821" updated="2010-04-19T11:43:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Honey Springs National Battlefield and Washita Battlefield National Historic Site Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Honey Springs National Battlefield and Washita Battlefield National Historic Site in the State of Oklahoma, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410589"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400247" joined="1994-07-25" withdrawn="1994-09-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2590)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1537-1538)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1553)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Late Referral to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands (Nov 30, 94).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-29"><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Prior to Referral.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Black history"/>
		<term name="Black military personnel"/>
		<term name="Civil war"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Indians"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Military history"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Oklahoma"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/25/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Honey Springs National Battlefield Title II: Washita Battlefield National Historic Site Honey Springs National Battlefield and Washita Battlefield National Historic Site Act of 1994 - Title I: Honey Springs National Battlefield - Establishes the Honey Springs National Battlefield in Oklahoma to provide for the preservation and interpretation of a Civil War battlefield. Provides for cooperative agreements with, and grants to, specified entities for protection, maintenance, interpretation, and rehabilitation of the battlefield. Directs the National Park Service to submit a management plan for the battlefield to specified congressional committees. Establishes the Honey Springs National Battlefield Advisory Commission. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Washita Battlefield National Historic Site - Establishes the Washita Battlefield National Historic Site in Oklahoma to provide for the preservation and interpretation of the Battle of the Washita. Sets forth provisions parallel to those in title I concerning cooperative agreements and grants and the submission of a management plan for the battlefield. Establishes the Washita Battlefield National Historic Site Advisory Commission. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
