<bill session="103" type="h" number="4849" updated="2010-04-19T11:47:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Chemical Weapons Convention Implementation Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To implement the obligations of the United States under the Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production, Stockpiling and Use of Chemical Weapons and on Their Destruction, known as &quot;the Chemical Weapons Convention&quot; and opened for signature and signed by the United States on January 13, 1993.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404996"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400307" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="410567" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400536" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="1994-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-18"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Law, Immigration, and Refugees.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Chemical industries"/>
		<term name="Chemical weapons"/>
		<term name="Chemicals"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Military law"/>
		<term name="Military personnel"/>
		<term name="Riot control agents"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Subpoena"/>
		<term name="Weapons systems"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Authority Title II: Application of Convention Prohibitions to Natural and Legal Persons Title III: Declarations by Chemical Industry Title IV: Inspections Chemical Weapons Convention Implementation Act of 1994 - Title I: National Authority - Directs the President to establish the United States National Authority to serve as the focal point for liaison with the Organization for the prohibition of Chemical Weapons and other States Parties to the convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production, Stockpiling and Use of Chemical Weapons and on Their Destruction opened for signature on January 13, 1993. Title II: Application of Convention Prohibitions to Natural and Legal Persons - Amends the Federal criminal code to impose criminal penalties on anyone who knowingly develops, acquires, stockpiles, transfers, uses, owns, or possesses any chemical weapon, assists any other person in doing so, or attempts to do so. Makes such provision inapplicable to the retention, ownership, or possession of any chemical weapon that is permitted by the Convention, pending the weapon's destruction, by any Federal agency. (Sec. 201) Sets forth provisions regarding seizures and forfeitures of chemical weapons. Imposes criminal penalties upon persons who knowingly use riot control agents as a method of warfare or assist another person in doing so. Subjects members of the armed forces who engage in such activity to military penalties. (Sec. 203) Makes it unlawful for any person or any U.S. national located outside the United States to produce, acquire, transfer, or use a chemical listed on Schedule 1 of the Annex on Chemicals of the Convention unless: (1) the chemicals are applied to research, medical, pharmaceutical, or protective purposes; (2) the types and quantities of chemical are strictly limited to those that can be justified for such purposes; and (3) the amount of such chemicals per person at any given time for such purposes does not exceed a limit to be determined by the United States National Authority or, in any case, one metric ton. Makes it unlawful for any person or U.S. national located outside the United States to: (1) produce, acquire, transfer, or use Schedule 1 chemicals outside the territories of the States Parties to the Convention or to transfer such chemicals to any person outside of the United States except as provided for in the Convention for transfers to persons located in other State Parties; and (2) transfer a chemical on Schedule 2 of the Annex to any person outside the territory of a State party or to receive such a chemical from any person outside a State Party. Title III: Declarations by Chemical Industry - Requires the Department of Commerce to establish recordkeeping and reporting requirements for persons who produce, process, consume, export, or import chemical substances subject to the Convention or who propose to engage in such activities. (Sec. 303) Makes it unlawful to fail to comply with recordkeeping and reporting requirements. Title IV: Inspections - Authorizes members of inspection teams of the Technical Secretariat of the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons to inspect plants, plant sites, or other locations in the United States subject to inspection under the Convention. (Sec. 401) Sets forth additional provisions regarding notice, time frame, and scope of inspections. (Sec. 403) Makes it unlawful to fail or refuse to permit entry or inspection or to disrupt or impede an inspection. (Sec. 404) Provides for civil penalties for specified violations of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
