<bill session="103" type="h" number="4854" updated="2010-04-19T11:48:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Aquaculture Development Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Aquaculture Act of 1980 to promote the development of the aquaculture industry in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410496"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1994-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1598-1599)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01"><committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Management.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Commerce, Interior.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAG-03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Fisheries Management" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agricultural credit"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural education"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Aquaculture"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Commercialization"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Libraries"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1994--Introduced.
National Aquaculture Development Act of 1994 - Amends the National Aquaculture Act of 1980 to require the National Aquaculture Development Plan to clearly outline and define the authorities of the Departments of Agriculture, Interior, and Commerce and other relevant Federal agencies with respect to the development, promotion, and regulation of all aquaculture in the United States. Requires the interagency aquaculture coordinating group to report to the Congress a report on an evaluation of actions taken under the Plan. (Sec. 4) Authorizes (current law requires) the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to: (1) establish within the National Agricultural Library a National Aquaculture Information Center; and (2) assign new aquaculture programs to the appropriate Federal agencies. (Sec. 5) Provides for coordination with the aquaculture industry. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretaries to: (1) implement a national strategy for private aquaculture; (2) implement an Aquaculture Strategy; and (3) treat private aquaculture as a form of agriculture. Directs the coordinating group to coordinate strategies, policies, and programs for private aquaculture. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretaries, through the coordinating group, to: (1) study Federal and State regulations and permits applicable to the United States aquaculture industry; (2) publish a compendium of requirements applicable to marine and fresh water aquaculture operations; and (3) recommend to the Secretaries and the Congress a framework for more consistent regulations on aquaculture operations. (Sec. 8) Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to direct the Secretary to provide disaster assistance to eligible aquaculture farmers for weather-related losses. (Sec. 9) Authorizes the Secretary to establish aquaculture education programs in secondary and postsecondary vocational schools. (Sec. 10) Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to make aquaculture farmers eligible for farm credit assistance. (Sec. 11) Amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to authorize the Secretary to establish an international aquaculture information and data collection program. (Sec. 12) Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress with respect to aquaculture information network enhancement. (Sec. 13) Authorizes FY 1994 through 1996 appropriations for aquaculture programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
