<bill session="103" type="h" number="4856" updated="2010-04-19T11:48:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Safety Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the Nation's health care by creating a comprehensive medical malpractice prevention program through the creation of independent, publicly accountable State medical boards and more stringent licensing and discipline procedures; to empower health consumers by mandating reporting of certain information regarding health care providers and professionals and by enhancing informed individual choice regarding health care services by providing certain information to consumers; and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400289"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-17"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Consumer complaints"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugstores"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forensic scientists"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Malpractice"/>
		<term name="Medical ethics"/>
		<term name="Medical malpractice insurance"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medication abuse"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
		<term name="Quality of care"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State politics and government"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Creation of Independent and Effective State Medical Boards Title III: Requirements for Health Care Professionals and Providers Title IV: Public Access to Practitioner Data Bank Patient Safety Act of 1994 - Title I: General Provisions - Declares that the purpose of this Act is to create a national program of medical malpractice prevention. Title II: Creation of Independent and Effective State Medical Boards - Requires each State medical board to create a consumer assistance unit to deal directly with complainants. Requires the board to disclose information received from complaints to the national practitioner data bank. Establishes guidelines for investigations, disciplinary hearings, and disciplinary actions. Provides for the Secretary of Health and Human Services to assume responsibilities of this Act in cases where a State medical board does not meet requirements. Title III: Requirements for Health Care Professionals and Providers - Requires health care professionals and health care providers to renew their medical licenses every two years. Sets forth reporting requirements for health care professionals and providers and medical examiners. Requires licensed health care professionals to be reexamined every six years as a condition of licensure. Requires State medical boards to perform audits of the office-based practices of licensees to assess performance and to improve practices. Requires an audit of pharmacies to detect illegal drug diversion and other misuse of controlled substances. Requires health care professionals and providers to maintain malpractice insurance. Directs the Secretary to conduct a national interdisciplinary study of medical negligence. Title IV: Public Access to Practitioner Data Bank - Amends the Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 to require the Secretary to make specified information on health practitioners available to the public.

	</summary>
</bill>
