<bill session="103" type="h" number="4882" updated="2010-04-19T11:52:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lead Exposure Reduction Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to reduce the levels of lead in the environment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410567"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Birds"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business intelligence"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Cadmium"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Container industry"/>
		<term name="Electric batteries"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fishing"/>
		<term name="Game and game birds"/>
		<term name="Glass and glass industry"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Industrial standards"/>
		<term name="Inventories"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Lead"/>
		<term name="Lead poisoning"/>
		<term name="Manganese"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Mercury"/>
		<term name="Metals"/>
		<term name="Nickel"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Packaging"/>
		<term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
		<term name="Petroleum"/>
		<term name="Printing"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Sports"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Surveys"/>
		<term name="Toys"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Zinc"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Lead Abatement Title II: Miscellaneous Title III: Authorization of Appropriations Lead Exposure Reduction Act of 1994 - Title I: Lead Abatement - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit the processing or distribution in commerce of certain products containing more than a specified percentage of lead. (Sec. 103) Prohibits the sale or distribution in commerce of packaging or products if they include any additive to which lead has been intentionally introduced. Exempts certain products from lead content requirements, including products used for medical purposes, radiation protection or shielding, or in the mining industry to determine the presence of noble metals. (Sec. 104) Requires the Administrator to promulgate a list of lead-containing products that may present a health or environmental risk, specify the maximum concentration of lead found in such products, and promulgate labeling requirements. (Sec. 106) Prohibits: (1) placing in a landfill or incinerating lead-acid batteries; and (2) the disposal of such batteries other than by recycling in accordance with this Act. Requires used batteries to be delivered to specified entities and establishes battery acceptance requirements. Makes it unlawful to sell a battery that does not bear a label setting forth lead content and recycling information. Prohibits any person from selling at retail for use in the United States a regulated battery or rechargeable consumer product introduced into interstate commerce on or after one year after this Act's enactment date unless: (1) the battery is easily removable from the product, is contained in a battery pack that is easily removable, or is sold separately; and (2) the rechargeable consumer product and the battery are labeled in accordance with this Act. Sets forth labeling requirements, including that the label contain a statement that the battery must be recycled or disposed of properly. Requires retail establishments that sell such batteries or products to post notices informing consumers that regulated batteries must be recycled or disposed of properly. Authorizes the Administrator, upon determining that other rechargeable batteries having electrode chemistries different from regulated batteries are toxic and may cause substantial harm if discarded for land disposal or incineration, to promulgate: (1) labeling requirements for such batteries and related products; and (2) easily-removable design requirements for rechargeable consumer products designed to contain such batteries or battery packs. Provides for exemptions from rechargeable battery requirements under certain conditions. Prohibits the introduction into commerce or offering for introduction or promotional purposes of: (1) alkaline-manganese batteries manufactured on or after January 1, 1996, with a mercury content that was intentionally introduced (limits the content in alkaline-manganese button cells to 25 milligrams of mercury per button cell); (2) zinc carbon batteries manufactured on or afer January 1, 1995, that contain mercury that was intentionally introduced; (3) button cell mercuric-oxide batteries on or after January 1, 1995; and (4) any mercuric-oxide battery on or after January 1, 1997. Sets forth enforcement provisions. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 107) Directs the Administrator to study and report to the Congress on the environmental and public health effects of burning used oil. Requires the Administrator to appoint a Coordinator for Lead Activities to coordinate activities relating to the prevention of lead poisoning, the reduction of lead exposure, and lead abatement. Title II: Miscellaneous - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Administrator should finalize no rule or regulation that requires a nationwide prohibition of the manufacture, sale, or use of fishing sinkers, jigs, or lures containing lead, brass, or zinc until the Administrator gives priority consideration to alternative means of reducing the risk to waterfowl from lead fishing sinkers. Title III: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
