<bill session="103" type="h" number="4900" updated="2010-04-19T11:55:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Boxing Labor Standards Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of an occupational safety and health standard applicable to boxing under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411677"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-16"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Sports"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Athletes"/>
		<term name="Boxing"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	
8/4/1994--Introduced.
Boxing Labor Standards Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish an advisory council to make recommendations concerning an occupational safety and health standard for boxing. Directs the Secretary to promulgate such a standard for boxing under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970. Provides that more effective State standards enforceable by State boxing commissions shall not be preempted if States submit inspection programs for certification by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to establish the Office of Boxing Standards Compliance, within the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, to enforce such standard, including the authority to conduct inspections and investigations and establish a passport system of boxer registration and tracking.

	</summary>
</bill>
