<bill session="103" type="h" number="4917" updated="2010-04-19T11:58:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Freedom of Information Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), to provide for public access to information in an electronic format, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300018"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400505" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="404083" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="409829" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1994-08-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1676-1677)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-12"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Information, Justice, Transportation and Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Information, Justice, Transportation, and Agriculture" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="1782" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Computers and government"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Due process of law"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Electronic publishing"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Public records"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/8/1994--Introduced.
Electronic Freedom of Information Improvement Act of 1994 - Amends the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to: (1) direct agencies to publish electronically by computer telecommunications (or by other electronic means if computer telecommunications means are unavailable) all information required to be published in the Federal Register, and make certain items available for public inspection and copying by such electronic means as well (including a list of all records made available to any person); (2) include among such required information an index of all information stored in an electronic form by the agency, a description of any new database, and a list of all statutes authorizing the agency to withhold information under such Act; (3) enable requesters to receive records in the format in which such records are maintained; (4) require reasonable efforts by the agency to provide records in an electronic format even when such records are not usually maintained in such format; (5) credit to agencies which have been found to be responsive to FOIA requests a percentage of the fees collected from such requests to offset compliance costs, at an agency's request; (6) provide for Government payment of the requester's out-of-pocket expenses in any case in which the agency has failed to comply with the FOIA request within prescribed time limits; (7) lengthen from ten to 20 days the period for agency decision to comply with a request for information; (8) preclude treatment of predictable workload (including any ongoing agency backlog) as unusual circumstances warranting extension of time limits; (9) require denial notifications to specify the total number of denied records and pages considered in responding to the FOIA request; (10) mandate agency regulations governing FOIA requests for expedited access, including a multitrack first-in, first-out processing policy for simple and complex requests); (11) require the extent of deletions to be indicated on the released portion of the record where they were made; and (12) define &quot;record&quot; to include all information or documentary materials regardless of physical form or characteristics, and &quot;search&quot; to include an automated examination to locate records.

	</summary>
</bill>
