<bill session="103" type="h" number="4927" updated="2010-04-19T11:59:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Marianas Delegate Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a nonvoting delegate to the House of Representatives to represent the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400516"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="1994-08-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="403314" joined="1994-08-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="408052" joined="1994-08-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1994-08-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400615" joined="1994-08-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1701)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee On Insular and International Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular and International Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
		<term name="Political representation"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/10/1994--Introduced.
Northern Marianas Delegate Act - Requires the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands to be represented in the Congress by the Resident Representative authorized by the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States of America. Provides that the Resident Representative shall be a nonvoting Delegate to the House of Representatives. Sets forth requirements for the election of the Delegate. Requires a candidate for the office of Delegate to: (1) be at least 25 years of age on the date of the election; (2) have been a U.S. citizen for at least seven years prior to the date of the election; (3) be an inhabitant of the Northern Mariana Islands; and (4) not be a candidate for any other office. Grants the Delegate the same compensation, allowances, and benefits as a Member of the House and entitles the Delegate to privileges and immunities granted to nonvoting House of Delegates.

	</summary>
</bill>
