<bill session="103" type="h" number="4929" updated="2010-04-19T11:59:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women and Children's Health Outreach and Education Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a program of demonstration projects to provide outreach services regarding the utilization of health benefits under Federal, State, and local programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-30"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Infant mortality"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
		<term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/10/1994--Introduced.
Women and Children's Health Outreach and Education Act of 1994 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities to carry out demonstration projects for: (1) identifying individuals who may be eligible for, but who are not participating in, Federal, State, or local programs that provide health services to residents of eligible communities (whose residents include a significant number of medically underserved individuals, a health professional shortage area, or communities whose infant mortality rate is significantly above the national rate); (2) assisting individuals in establishing eligibility for the benefits of the programs; (3) educating individuals on obtaining and utilizing the benefits; and (4) providing transportation, child care, translation, and other specified services to enable individuals to utilize the benefits. Authorizes the Secretary to make such grants only if: (1) the applicant agrees that project services involved will be provided in the language and cultural context most appropriate for the individuals served; and (2) an application is submitted in such form and manner, and contains such agreements, assurances, and information, as the Secretary determines to be necessary. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
