<bill session="103" type="h" number="4931" updated="2010-04-19T12:00:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf of Maine Conservation and Cooperation Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen protection of the natural resources of the Gulf of Maine through greater cooperation and coordination between Federal agencies and the Gulf of Maine Council on the Marine Environment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1694-1695)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Environment and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Maine"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="New Hampshire"/>
		<term name="Regional planning"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Sustainable development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/10/1994--Introduced.
Gulf of Maine Conservation and Cooperation Act of 1994 - Requires the President to establish a Gulf of Maine Inter-Agency Task Force to provide for improved interagency cooperation, efficiency, and effectiveness with respect to Federal activities concerning the conservation and sustainable development of the natural resources of the Gulf of Maine. Requires Federal officials who appoint members of the Task Force to cooperate and coordinate their activities related to natural resources of the Gulf with the Gulf of Maine Council on the Marine Environment. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to enter into agreements and memoranda of understanding with the Council to enhance efforts to conserve the Gulf's natural resources. Authorizes the Secretary to work with others to develop a sustainable development strategy for the Gulf. Permits Federal officials who appoint Task Force members to make grants to the Council for programs related to the conservation of the Gulf's natural resources or to sustainable economic development in the Gulf region. Limits the total amount of annual grants. Directs the Regional Marine Research Board for the Gulf of Maine region to cooperate with the Council and the States bordering the Gulf in efforts to promote the environmental and economic health of the region. Authorizes the Board, subject to the Secretary's approval, to revise schedules for the development of research plans under the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to ensure the coordination of such plans with activities under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
