<bill session="103" type="h" number="4934" updated="2010-04-19T12:00:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Reduction Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To restore immigration to traditional levels by curtailing illegal immigration and imposing a ceiling on legal immigration.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400567"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="407899" joined="1994-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="1994-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1994-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="1994-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="1994-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="404068" joined="1994-09-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Law, Immigration, and Refugees.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-18"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-18"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="International Law, Immigration, and Refugees" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Child support"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Citizenship"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Customs administration"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="English language"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigrants"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Local officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Naturalization"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public health"/>
		<term name="Public works"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="Vital statistics"/>
		<term name="Voting"/>
		<term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/10/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Immigrants and Refugees Title II: Border Control Title III: Interior Enforcement Title IV: Document Reform Title V: State and Local Responsibilities Title VI: Public Benefits Abuse Title VII: Strengthening Citizenship Title VIII: Immigration and Naturalization Service Immigration Reduction Act of 1994 - Title I: Immigrants and Refugees - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise immigration levels with respect to: (1) the worldwide level of backlogged family-sponsored immigrants; and (2) allocations for priority-worker immigrants. (Sec. 102) Limits the number of refugees who may be admitted to the United States for special humanitarian concerns. (Sec. 103) Authorizes the granting of asylum to aliens who will be threatened in their country based upon race, religion, nationality, or political opinion. Prohibits such persons from receiving any preference or priority or from being discriminated against in the granting or termination of asylum based on race, sex, religion, or nationality. (Sec. 104) Repeals the authority to grant temporary protected status to aliens. Prohibits an alien who is excludable or deportable from remaining in the United States or engaging in employment in the United States. (Sec. 105) Prohibits the Attorney General from paroling into the United States groups or classes of aliens. Prohibits such aliens from being authorized to work in the United States. Limits the number of such parolees. Title II: Border Control - Increases the number of full-time border patrol personnel in the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS). Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 through 1999. (Sec. 202) Imposes a land border and port of entry user fee on persons entering the United States. Title III: Interior Enforcement - Increases the number of full-time investigative personnel in INS. (Sec. 302) Restores the authority of immigration officers and employees to conduct searches without warrants. (Sec. 303) Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to make available to the Attorney General defense facilities suitable for the detention of aliens. (Sec. 304) Grants the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit exclusive jurisdiction over immigration cases. (Sec. 305) Imposes a penalty on aliens for unlawful presence in the United States. Authorizes the seizure of certain property of deportable aliens. (Sec. 308) Requires the Attorney General to inform an alien who is departing voluntarily of the date and time such departure must be accomplished. Title IV: Document Reform - Revises provisions concerning the examination of work eligibility documents of aliens, including social security cards and identification cards issued by INS. (Sec. 402) Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to modify the Social Security data base to provide for an electronic verification system of information on aliens. (Sec. 403) Directs the Secretary to establish a national electronic network linking the vital statistics records of State agencies. (Sec. 404) Requires aliens who have not lawfully immigrated to the United States to be employed to obtain a visa for nonimmigrant status that explicitly contemplates employment. Title V: State and Local Responsibilities - Makes a State or local government or agency that does not cooperate with Federal immigration authorities ineligible for any Federal funds or assistance relating to law enforcement, education, public health, transportation, or public works. (Sec. 502) Requires State law enforcement agencies to notify the appropriate INS district office of alien arrests. (Sec. 503) Requires confidentiality of immigration-related communications. (Sec. 504) Authorizes the Attorney General to deputize state law enforcement officers to assist Federal officers in the apprehension of aliens in violation of immigration laws. Title VI: Public Benefits Abuse - Prohibits the payment of: (1) direct Federal financial or social insurance benefits to illegal aliens; or (2) unemployment benefits to aliens without employment authorization. (Sec. 603) Revises the requirements for immigrant sponsors with respect to their financial responsibilities. Title VII: Strengthening Citizenship - Prohibits automatic citizenship to persons born in the United States of parents who are not citizens. (Sec. 702) Restricts the voting privilege to citizens of the United States. (Sec. 703) Increases from 50 years to 60 years the age for which elderly aliens are exempt from English language requirements for naturalization. Declares that the commission of a fraud upon the INS shall be conclusive evidence that an alien lacks good moral character for purposes of naturalization requirements. (Sec. 704) Authorizes a State to commence a civil suit against the head of a Federal agency for immigration law violations. Title VIII: Immigration and Naturalization Service - Establishes INS as an agency of the Federal government outside of the Department of Justice.

	</summary>
</bill>
