<bill session="103" type="h" number="4932" updated="2010-04-19T12:00:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require the Secretary of Commerce to prepare conservation and management measures for the northeast multispecies (groundfish) fishery under negotiated rulemaking procedures.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1700)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-16"><committee name="House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" subcommittee="Fisheries Management" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Fishes"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="New England"/>
		<term name="North Atlantic Ocean"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/10/1994--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Commerce to begin preparing under the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act a fishery management plan, or an amendment to an existing plan under the Act, and proposed regulations to implement such plan or amendment (plan), which establish conservation and management measures for the northeast multispecies (groundfish) fishery. Requires the Secretary, in preparing such plan, to comply with specified procedures for negotiated rulemaking, with exceptions, including by establishing a negotiated rulemaking committee and publishing notice within 60 days. Specifies that if a negotiated rulemaking committee reaches a consensus on a plan, the Secretary may submit the plan to the New England Fishery Management Council (and if the Secretary submits the plan, it shall be treated as having been prepared by the Secretary) under the Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
