<bill session="103" type="h" number="4947" updated="2010-04-19T12:02:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28, United States Code, to establish additional requirements regarding appointment of an independent counsel.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401947"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government attorneys"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Special prosecutors"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/12/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Federal judicial code to establish additional requirements regarding the appointment of an independent counsel. Requires the division of the court to appoint as independent counsel an individual who is without any real or apparent personal, financial, or political conflict of interest. Directs that any communication with the division of the court or any member of such division regarding the qualifications or suitability of an individual to serve as independent counsel be made in writing. Prohibits any member of such division from engaging in oral communication regarding such matters with anyone other than an individual who is a member, or on the staff, of such division or who is being considered for such appointment. Requires such division to make any such written communication a part of the proceedings and available for review by the public.

	</summary>
</bill>
