<bill session="103" type="h" number="495" updated="2010-04-19T00:18:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend subtitle C of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the preparation of a community information statement for new hazardous waste treatment or disposal facilities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402657"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="1993-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="1993-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="410589" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406920" joined="1993-06-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E135)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E151)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to require the preparation of a community information statement as part of the permitting process applicable to any new off-site hazardous waste treatment or disposal facility. Requires such statement to describe: (1) the effects of the proposed facility on the host community; (2) the types of waste expected to enter the facility, the types of releases expected from the facility, and the human health impacts associated with such wastes and releases; (3) the alternatives for mitigating impacts on the community; (4) the demographic characteristics of the community; (5) the presence in the community of an existing solid waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility or site in which a hazardous substance release has occurred, and the extent to which the site has been remediated; and (6) the permit applicant's compliance with State and Federal environmental regulations and laws.

	</summary>
</bill>
