<bill session="103" type="h" number="4961" updated="2010-04-19T12:04:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coeur d'Alene Basin and Spokane River Restoration Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Coeur d'Alene Basin Restoration Corporation and authorize the Corporation to undertake all actions necessary for the cleanup of mining wastes and the restoration of natural resources in the watershed encompassing the Coeur d'Alene River, Coeur d'Alene Lake, and its tributaries, and the Spokane River in northern Idaho and western Washington.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406605"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8046-8047)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-25"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-06"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSPW-02" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Liability for water pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Mine wastes"/>
		<term name="Mineral industries"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Stream conservation"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/12/1994--Introduced.
Coeur d'Alene Basin and Spokane River Restoration Act of 1994 - Establishes the Coeur d'Alene Basin Restoration Corporation and the Coeur d'Alene Basin Advisory Committee. Directs the Board of the Corporation to adopt a Basin Restoration Plan for the Coeur d'Alene Basin, Idaho, and the Spokane River, Idaho and Washington State. Requires the Plan to: (1) identify all sources of mining waste and other discharges into the Basin and River; (2) inventory existing projects and activities to restore, remediate, or prevent damages from mining waste and other pollution; and (3) identify additional projects needed to carry out such activities. Preempts any conflicting Federal, State, or local laws. Exempts the Corporation from liability for the costs of removing or remediating releases of hazardous materials, including liability under provisions of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA or Superfund) Prohibits a project from proceeding until the Board determines that the project meets all requirements under Federal, or more stringent State and tribal, environmental laws. Funds the Corporation's activities through congressional appropriations and private contributions from companies that have been involved with mining activities in the Basin. Establishes the Coeur d'Alene Basin Restoration Fund. Authorizes appropriations. Expresses the intent of the Congress that the mining companies of the Basin that contributed to the release of hazardous materials should: (1) contribute a fair portion of the cost of restoring natural resources; and (2) upon payment of a fair contribution, be assured that no further liability for response costs or natural resource damages may be imposed upon them. Deems such companies to have satisfied liability that may otherwise be imposed by CERCLA if they contribute at least 25 percent of the amount appropriated by the Congress to carry out this Act. Grants such companies an offset against liabilities if they contribute less than the required amount. Authorizes the Corporation, the State of Idaho, the Coeur d'Alene Tribe, and the United States to pursue all actions under CERCLA unless the companies satisfy their liabilities regardless of whether the Basin Restoration Plan is implemented. Tolls all statutes of limitation for cost recovery and natural resource damage actions against the mining companies until January 1, 2018.

	</summary>
</bill>
