<bill session="103" type="h" number="5000" updated="2010-04-19T12:11:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of the Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve in Kansas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404602"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1994-08-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409966" joined="1994-08-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1994-08-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1782-1783)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Grassland ecology"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Kansas"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/19/1994--Introduced.
Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Act of 1994 - Establishes the Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve to provide for the preservation, restoration, and interpretation of the Spring Hill Ranch area of the Flint Hills of Kansas. Considers the Preserve a designated unit of the National Park System, including for purposes of charging entrance and admission fees under specified provisions of the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a general management plan for the Preserve. Authorizes the acquisition of real property and improvements thereon, and rights-of-way on roads that are not owned by Kansas, within the boundaries of the Preserve. Prohibits: (1) such property from being acquired without the owner's consent; and (2) U.S. acquisition of fee ownership of any lands within the Preserve other than these lands. Establishes the Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Advisory Committee to advise the Secretary and the Director of the National Park Service on the development, management, and interpretation of the Preserve. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
