<bill session="103" type="h" number="5024" updated="2010-04-19T12:14:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Training Center for Minority Museum, Archives and Historic Preservation Professionals Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require that the Director of the National Park Service construct a National Training Center at the National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410407"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1994-09-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1813)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Culture"/>
		<term name="Black education"/>
		<term name="Black history"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Cultural centers"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Humanities"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Museums"/>
		<term name="Ohio"/>
		<term name="Professional education"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/12/1994--Introduced.
National Training Center for Minority Museum, Archives, and Historic Preservation Professionals Act - Requires the Director of the National Park Service: (1) to construct, jointly with the State of Ohio, a National Training Center at the National Afro-American Museum and Cultural Center to prepare professionals for our Nation's museums, archives, and historic preservation offices; and (2) through the Board of Governors of the Museum (established by this Act), to provide for the operation and maintenance of, and technical assistance to, the Museum. Requires the Secretary of Education, acting through the Board, to: (1) contract with a consortium of institutions of higher education to implement a graduate degree program to train minorities in museum, archives, and historic preservation studies at the Museum; (2) offer annual seminars in museum, archival, and historic preservation practices and periodic workshops, in conjunction with the African American Museums Association and other professional organizations, to serve the needs of minority museums professionals; and (3) provide scholarships and loans for students and professionals in such studies. Authorizes the Secretary and the Director to establish jointly with Ohio a Board of Governors of the Museum which meets specified requirements and has the authority to carry out the duties, responsibilities, and authorities set forth in this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
