<bill session="103" type="h" number="5057" updated="2010-04-19T12:19:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Nuclear Waste Responsibility Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to clarify the obligation of the Federal Government to take title to and possession of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel and establish an interim spent nuclear fuel storage facility, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400414"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1918)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF-03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy and Power" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="5061" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Nuclear energy"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/19/1994--Introduced.
Federal Nuclear Waste Responsibility Act of 1994 - Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act to instruct the Secretary of Energy to: (1) take title to certain high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel by a specified deadline; (2) take possession of such waste and spent fuel in accordance with the Federal Integrated Spent Nuclear Fuel Management Program; (3) establish an interim spent nuclear fuel storage facility at one or more Federal sites; and (4) notify the Congress within 30 days if the deadline cannot be met. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit issuance of either a construction permit or combined construction and operating license for a utilization facility used for the generation of electricity for commercial sale, unless: (1) there is in existence a federally licensed facility for the interim storage or permanent disposal of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel generated by the utilization facility; and (2) the Secretary has certified that the facility will have an adequate capacity to accept all such waste and spent nuclear fuel generated during its lifetime.

	</summary>
</bill>
