<bill session="103" type="h" number="5075" updated="2010-04-19T12:22:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Insurance Sales and Underwriting Consumer Protection Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that sellers and underwriters of insurance are qualified and subject to consumer protection requirements.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400110"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402763" joined="1994-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="406284" joined="1994-10-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1914)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Insurance"/>
		<term name="Insurance agents"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Interstate commerce"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marketing"/>
		<term name="Reinsurance"/>
		<term name="Sales promotion"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/1994--Introduced.
Insurance Sales and Underwriting Consumer Protection Act of 1994 - Prohibits selling or soliciting the purchase of insurance without qualifying under and complying with all insurance regulatory requirements applicable in the State in which the sale or solicitation of insurance takes place (including qualifying for and maintaining a license to sell or solicit the purchase of insurance if such license is required by the State insurance regulatory authority and complying with all State consumer protection requirements that apply to the marketing of insurance). Prohibits underwriting insurance without complying with all insurance regulatory requirements applicable in the State in which the insurance is underwritten (including qualifying for and maintaining a license to underwrite insurance if such license is required by the State insurance regulatory authority and complying with all State consumer protection requirements that apply to underwriting insurance and, if a license is not required by such authority, otherwise meeting any applicable financial or other requirements imposed by such State). Specifies that the sales, solicitations, and underwriting covered includes any insurance sold, solicited, underwritten, or reinsured by an entity that operates in interstate commerce or is part of an entity any part of which operates in interstate commerce. Specifies that this Act does not alter or affect the provisions of the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986. Authorizes the Department of Justice (DOJ) to file a civil action if the appropriate State does not take action against a violation of this Act. Specifies that: (1) the determination of whether an act constitutes a violation shall be made pursuant to the insurance laws and regulations of the applicable State; and (2) in such an action, DOJ may ask for either an order prohibiting that person from engaging in the prohibited conduct, a civil fine of up to $1,000 for each violation, or both.

	</summary>
</bill>
