<bill session="103" type="h" number="5085" updated="2010-04-19T12:24:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the disclosure of lobbying activities to influence the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401947"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-11"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Charitable contributions"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Computers and government"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional travel"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Financial disclosure"/>
		<term name="Financial statements"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="International propaganda"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Lobbying Disclosure Title II: Congressional Gift Rules Title I: Lobbying Disclosure - Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1994 - Declares that, not later than 30 days after a lobbyist first makes a lobbying contact with a covered legislative or executive branch official (or, if it happens earlier, is employed or retained to make such a contact), such lobbyist (or the organization employing such lobbyist) shall, with certain exceptions, register with the Office of Lobbying Registration and Public Disclosure (OLRAPD). Requires any organization with one or more employees who are lobbyists to file a single registration on behalf of such employees for each client on whose behalf the employees act as lobbyists. Specifies the information that such registration shall contain. (Sec. 103) Defines &quot;lobbyist&quot; as any individual who is employed or retained by a client for financial or other compensation for services that include one or more lobbying contacts, other than an individual whose lobbying activities constitute less than ten percent of the time engaged in the services provided by such individual to that client. (Sec. 104) Provides that, in the case of a registrant making more than one lobbying contact for the same client, the registrant shall file a single registration covering all such lobbying contacts. Provides for separate registration filing in the case of a registrant making lobbying contacts on behalf of more than one client. (Sec. 105) Requires registrants to file with OLRAPD a semiannual report on lobbying activities, with a separate report for each client, with certain exceptions. (Sec. 106) Prohibits lobbyists, lobbying firms, and registered agents of foreign principals from providing certain gifts, directly or indirectly, to any covered legislative branch official. (Sec. 107) Establishes the OLRAPD as an executive agency, whose duties include: (1) prescribing regulations, penalty guidelines, and forms to carry out this title; (2) reviewing registrations and reports; (3) making registrations and reports public; and (4) transmitting annual reports to the Congress and President. (Sec. 108) Establishes procedures for: (1) initial determination of alleged violations; (2) determination of violations where information provided to OLRAPD indicates that a violation may exist; and (3) disclosure of certain information to the public. (Sec. 111) Provides for judicial review of certain OLRAPD decisions. (Sec. 113) Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to: (1) eliminate references to political propaganda and, in certain cases, replace such references with references to informational materials; and (2) modify the registration exemption for lawyers providing legal representation to disclosed foreign principals to apply such exemption to judicial proceedings and criminal or civil law enforcement inquiries, investigations, or proceedings. (Sec. 114) Revises limitations on use of appropriated funds to influence certain Federal contracting and financial transactions, removing obsolete reporting requirements, among other changes. (Sec. 115) Repeals the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act. (Sec. 116) Repeals provisions under the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act and the Housing Act of 1949 relating to lobbyist activities. (Sec. 118) Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 119) Provides for the identification of clients and covered officials. (Sec. 121) Requires the Comptroller General to review interim reporting by registrants of lobbying expenditures for a report to the Congress. Title II: Congressional Gift Rules - Amends the Standing Rules of the Senate, the Rules of the House of Representatives, the Ethics in Government Act, and the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 with regard to gifts and travel.

	</summary>
</bill>
