<bill session="103" type="h" number="5128" updated="2010-04-19T12:30:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-05">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-10-05" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Mandates Relief for State and Local Government Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Mandate and Community Assistance Reform Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Private Sector Legislative Analysis Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the partnership between the Federal Government and State, local, and tribal governments, to end the imposition, in the absence of full consideration by the Congress, of Federal mandates on State, local, and tribal governments without adequate funding in a manner that may displace other essential governmental priorities, to better assess both costs and benefits of Federal legislation and regulations on State, local, and tribal governments, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="1994-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="402657" joined="1994-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="407124" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="408109" joined="1994-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1994-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1994-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="1994-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="1994-10-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-04"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-10-05"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 35 - 4.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Subcommittee on Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations Discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2215)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Human Resources and Intergovernmental Relations" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4771" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional Record"/>
		<term name="Congressional voting"/>
		<term name="Cost accounting"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative amendments"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Regulatory reform"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Legislative Accountability and Reform Title II: Regulatory Accountability and Reform Title III: Judicial Review Title IV: Baseline Study Title V: Limitation on Implementation of Federal Mandates; Review and Monitoring of Unfunded Federal Mandates and Implementation of Act Title VI: Private Sector Costs Federal Mandates Relief for State and Local Government Act of 1994 - Title I: Legislative Accountability and Reform - Provides that when an authorization committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate reports a public bill or joint resolution including any Federal mandate, the committee shall identify such mandate to the Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) and issue a report along with the legislation containing, among other things, statements of: (1) the expected direct costs to States and local and tribal governments required to comply with the mandate; (2) the Federal sources available for assisting such entities to meet direct mandate costs, as well as the amount, if any, of new or increased appropriations provided by the legislation; and (3) the possible benefits anticipated from the mandate and whether or not preemptions of State, local, or tribal law will occur because of such mandate, along with the reasons for enacting such preemptions. Requires that, as early as practicable in each new Congress, any congressional committee which anticipates considering proposed legislation establishing, amending, or reauthorizing any Federal program likely to have a significant budgetary impact on State, local, or tribal governments request the CBO Director to study such proposed legislation to develop information that may be useful in analyzing the costs of any Federal mandates, especially unfunded Federal mandates, that may be included in it. Requires the Director to prepare and submit to the appropriate committee estimates for each public bill or joint resolution reported by an authorization committee of the costs of all mandates in the particular legislation. Authorizes appropriations to CBO to carry out this Act. Sets forth guidelines for congressional consideration of measures reported by authorization committees, making it out of order, for example, to consider legislation containing a Federal mandate which does not contain funding for it, subject to waiver under certain conditions. Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives with regard to voting for measures containing mandates, adding requirements for a seven-day layover for certain measures. Title II: Regulatory Accountability and Reform - Requires each agency to assess the effects of Federal regulations on States, and local and tribal governments, including the specific availability of resources to carry out any mandates in those regulations, and seek to minimize those burdens that uniquely or significantly affect such governmental entities, consistent with achieving statutory and regulatory objectives. Requires each agency to: (1) develop an effective process to permit elected officials and other representatives of such governments to provide meaningful and timely input in the development of regulatory proposals containing significant Federal mandates; and (2) develop a plan for providing appropriate notice to, seeking views from, and advising small governments on compliance with any regulatory requirements that might significantly or uniquely affect them before establishing such requirements. Authorizes appropriations. Requires agencies to prepare certain cost-benefit and other statements before promulgating any final rule that includes any Federal mandates upon States or local or tribal governments that may result in expenditures by them in excess of a certain amount in any one year, and before promulgation of any general notice of proposed rulemaking likely to result in promulgation of any such rule. Requires the OMB Director to: (1) collect from agencies the statements prepared under this subtitle and provide copies to the CBO Director promptly after promulgation of the general notice of proposed rulemaking or of the final rule for which the statement was prepared; and (2) establish certain pilot programs to test approaches for reducing reporting and compliance burdens on small governments. Title III: Judicial Review - Disallows judicial review of any action or noncompliance committed under this Act. Title IV: Baseline Study - Requires the Director of the Bureau of the Census to study certain issues involved in calculating the total costs and benefits to State, local, and tribal governments of compliance with Federal law. Authorizes appropriations. Title V: Limitation on Implementation of Federal Mandates; Review and Monitoring of Unfunded Federal Mandates and Implementation of Act - Federal Mandate and Community Assistance Reform Act - Requires the Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations to: (1) investigate and review on a regular basis the role of unfunded Federal mandates in intergovernmental relations and their impact on local, State, and Federal Government objectives and responsibilities; (2) study and make certain recommendations to the President and the Congress regarding, among other things, flexibility for State and local government compliance with specific unfunded Federal mandates for which terms of compliance are unnecessarily rigid or complex; and (3) monitor and evaluate the implementation of this Act. Authorizes appropriations. Title VI: Private Sector Costs - Private Sector Legislative Analysis Act of 1994 - Requires that, at the beginning of each Congress, the majority leader of the Senate and the Speaker of the House prepare for the CBO Director a list of major legislative proposals that they believe are likely to have a significant economic impact and be considered for enactment. Requires that House and Senate leadership review for modification each proposal in such list before adjournment of the first session of each Congress. Requires the Director, upon receiving such a list, to initiate a study of each of the major proposals, topics, and areas of interest in the list for purposes of studying and estimating its economic impact, comparing congressional committee and Federal agency estimates of the impacts of such proposals, topics, or areas. Provides for guidelines for congressional consideration of any bill or joint resolution that is included on such a list.

	</summary>
</bill>
