<bill session="103" type="h" number="5143" updated="2012-07-17T04:36:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-05T19:03:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-10-05T19:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="without objection" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FBI Counterintelligence Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide for disclosures by consumer reporting agencies to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for counterintelligence purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400023"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05T19:03:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05T19:03:00-04:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10943-10944"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05T19:03:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Kennedy asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text></action>
		<vote how="without objection" type="vote" datetime="1994-10-05T19:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05T19:03:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Bank accounts"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Counterintelligence"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Financial institutions"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/30/1994--Introduced.
FBI Counterintelligence Act of 1994 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require a consumer reporting agency (agency) to furnish to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) the names and addresses of all financial institutions at which a consumer maintains or has maintained an account, to the extent that such information is in the agency's files, when presented with a written request signed by the Director of the FBI which certifies compliance with this Act. Permits the Director to make such certification only upon determining in writing that: (1) such information is necessary for the conduct of an authorized foreign counterintelligence investigation; and (2) there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the consumer is a foreign power or an official of a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power engaging in international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities involving a violation of U.S. criminal statutes (clandestine activities). Requires an agency to furnish certain identifying information respecting a consumer to the FBI when presented with such a written request. Authorizes a court to issue an order ex parte directing an agency to furnish a consumer report to the FBI if requested in writing by the Director upon a showing in camera that: (1) the consumer report is necessary for the conduct of an authorized foreign counterintelligence investigation; and (2) there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the consumer whose consumer report is sought is an agent of a foreign power and is engaging or has engaged in international terrorism or clandestine activities. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) confidentiality; (2) payment of fees; (3) limits on dissemination; (4) reporting requirements; (5) damages; (6) disciplinary actions for violations; (7) a good-faith exception (for an agency relying upon an FBI certification); (8) limitation of remedies; and (9) injunctive relief and costs. Terminates this Act five years after its enactment.

	</summary>
</bill>
