<bill session="103" type="h" number="5146" updated="2010-04-19T12:33:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">OSHA Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400174"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2005-2006)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-26"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Industrial accidents"/>
		<term name="Industrial relations"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Management audit"/>
		<term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/30/1994--Introduced.
OSHA Reform Act of 1994 - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA) to repeal provisions for: (1) inspections, investigations, and recordkeeping; (2) citations; (3) enforcement procedures; (4) judicial review; and (5) civil and criminal penalties. Requires a continuing comprehensive economic analysis of the costs and benefits of each OSHA standard. Directs the Secretary of Labor to consider the number of workers exposed to the toxic material or harmful physical agent, the nature and severity of the potential impairment, and the likelihood of such impairment, in determining the priority for establishing standards dealing with such materials or agents. Provides that employee safety and health participation committees are not prohibited under the National Labor Relations Act or the Railway Labor Act. Establishes a small business assistance and training program, including: (1) technical assistance and consultative services for employers and employees, targeted at small businesses and the most hazardous industries; and (2) certain consultative services to employers provided under cooperative agreements between the States and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration. Requires that at least one-fourth of the annual appropriation to carry out OSHA be expended for such assistance and training program. Directs the Secretary of Labor to periodically make an award to companies and other organizations which have implemented particularly effective approaches to occupational safety and health, including those providing for effective employee involvement.

	</summary>
</bill>
