<bill session="103" type="h" number="5186" updated="2010-04-19T12:39:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Prisons Community Services Projects Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to the Bureau of Prisons.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405775"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-11"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-11"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property and Judicial Administration" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Charities"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Prison labor"/>
		<term name="Social services"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State politics and government"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/5/1994--Introduced.
Bureau of Prisons Community Services Projects Act of 1994 - Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize the Chief Executive Officer of a Federal penal or correctional facility, as part of an inmate work program, to provide products or services to private, nonprofit organizations or to a component of a State government or political subdivision thereof. Specifies that such: (1) products shall be of minimal cost and constructed in substantial part through the use of excess property and shall not be resold by the recipient; and (2) services shall be used only for the benefit of the recipient entity and not for the benefit of any other individual or organization and shall not displace or result in a reduction in hours, wages, or employment benefits of any employee of the recipient. Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to specify that nothing in such Act shall impair or affect any authority of the Federal Bureau of Prisons or Federal Prison Industries with respect to the disposal of property used to produce such products. Makes this Act inapplicable to provisions of the Federal criminal code regarding transportation or importation of prison-made goods.

	</summary>
</bill>
