<bill session="103" type="h" number="5205" updated="2010-04-19T12:42:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide Federal assistance for compliance with Federally-mandated motor vehicle inspection and maintenance requirements and employee trip reduction requirements in effect under the Clean Air Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407153"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2138-2139)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Air pollution"/>
		<term name="Automobile inspection"/>
		<term name="Automobile repair"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Car pools"/>
		<term name="Commuting"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide grants to each State carrying out a vehicle inspection and maintenance program under the Clean Air Act. Requires grants to be used to provide assistance to enable vehicle owners to perform repair and maintenance as is necessary for such vehicles to comply with program requirements. Directs States to use grants to make payments for qualified repair and maintenance costs incurred by owners. Establishes a payment schedule that provides for covering: (1) up to 60 percent of qualified repair and maintenance costs that do not exceed $200; and (2) up to 80 percent of such costs between $200 and $400. Authorizes the Administrator to provide grants to each State carrying out employee trip reduction requirements for nonattainment areas under title I of the Clean Air Act. Requires grants to be used by States to provide assistance to enable employers to comply with such requirements.

	</summary>
</bill>
