<bill session="103" type="h" number="5204" updated="2010-04-19T12:42:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Employee Partnership Reward Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for awards to an employee under a performance-based reward plan and to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a program to promote implementation of performance-based reward plans and employee decision making participation programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2138)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-14"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Economic research"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Employee motivation"/>
		<term name="Employee ownership"/>
		<term name="Employees' representation in management"/>
		<term name="Fringe benefits"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Industrial relations"/>
		<term name="Job creation"/>
		<term name="Labor productivity"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Profit sharing"/>
		<term name="Rating of employees"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax expenditures"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Refundable Income Tax Credit for Nondeferred Distributions from Performance-Based Reward Plans Title II: Establishment of Program to Promote Performance-Based Reward Plans and Employee Decisionmaking Participation Programs Employee Partnership Reward Act of 1994 - Title I: Refundable Income Tax Credit for Nondeferred Distributions from Performance-Based Reward Plans - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow eligible employees a refundable income tax credit for nondeferred distributions from performance-based reward plans. Allows employers an additional deduction for performance-based rewards. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and report to the Congress on the effect of such credit in stimulating productivity and full employment. Directs the Secretary of Labor and the Director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service each to: (1) collect statistics on the extent of performance-based reward plans in the United States; and (2) prepare studies describing the nature and terms of these plans. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to publish annual estimates of annual tax expenditures for deferred profit-sharing plans and employee stock ownership plans. Title II: Establishment of Program to Promote Performance-Based Reward Plans and Employee Decisionmaking Participation Programs - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish and carry out an Employee Partnership Pilot Program. Directs the Administrator to make five-year program grants to up to five eligible entities to promote implementation of performance-based reward plans and employee decisionmaking participation programs. Requires a matching non-Federal share.

	</summary>
</bill>
