<bill session="103" type="h" number="5203" updated="2010-04-19T12:42:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Export Enhancement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve small business export assistance.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-17"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Export finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State politics and government"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade fairs"/>
		<term name="Waste in government spending"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Small Business Export Enhancement Act of 1994 - Authorizes appropriations to provide: (1) grants to qualified entities under the Market Development Cooperator Program to promote the export of goods and services of U.S. small businesses; and (2) assistance to U.S. small businesses to increase their participation in U.S. trade shows that bring together foreign governments seeking to buy their goods and services. Directs the International Trade Administration (ITA) to establish a grant program to provide financial support, on a shared basis, for State-run foreign trade missions designed primarily for participation by small and medium-sized businesses. (Sec. 4) Directs the ITA, in order to better promote the export of the goods and services of small- and medium-sized businesses in particular, to make it a priority to expand financial support for State-based enhancement activities by using discretionary funds. (Sec. 5) Requires Federal agencies that administer controls and regulations with respect to the export of U.S. goods and services to establish a plan to: (1) consolidate, and make easily accessible to small businesses that export, information regarding rules and restrictions on exports; and (2) create an outreach program to inform such businesses of such rules and restrictions and provide technical assistance for complying with them. (Sec. 6) Directs the ITA to submit to the Congress a plan to consolidate or eliminate programs that provide similar export assistance services or provide such assistance to similar recipients. Requires such plan to realize savings of not less than $100 million per year through improved efficiency, streamlining, and targeting of resources to sectors with high export potential.

	</summary>
</bill>
