<bill session="103" type="h" number="5222" updated="2010-04-19T12:45:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Products Safe Testing Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for nonanimal acute toxicity testing by the Federal Government.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400585" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="410567" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="407141" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="401310" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="405524" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400572" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400291" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400223" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="410565" joined="1994-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2210)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Evaluation"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Laboratory animals"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Protection of animals"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Consumer Products Safe Testing Act - Requires each Federal department or agency (department) head to: (1) evaluate any regulation, guideline, or recommendation issued by that department which requires, recommends, or encourages the use of the Draize or other animal acute toxicity test (animal test) to evaluate the safety of a regulated product; (2) evaluate nonanimal alternatives with the potential for partial or full replacement of such test; and (3) promulgate regulations, guidelines, or recommendations that specify a nonanimal acute toxicity test or battery of tests that should be used instead of an animal test unless the nonanimal test is less likely to predict the acute health effects of a product on humans. Directs the appropriate Federal department, if a determination is made that no nonanimal test is as likely to predict the human reaction to the regulated product as the animal test, to publish in the Federal Register an explanation of all options considered and the justification for continuing the animal test, which shall be subject to public comment. Requires each Federal department head, at least every two years (beginning three years after this Act's enactment date), after considering the most recent technological advances available, to determine whether continued use of any animal test is justified (and if the department head determines that such use is justified, such head shall publish an explanation and justification for such continued use in the Federal Register, which shall be subject to public comment). Makes this Act inapplicable to regulations, guidelines, or recommendations related to medical research.

	</summary>
</bill>
