<bill session="103" type="h" number="5233" updated="2010-04-19T12:46:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Workplace Religious Freedom Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 with respect to religious accommodation in employment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400289"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400306" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1994-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2157)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-26"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Seniority in employment"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Workplace Religious Freedom Act of 1994 - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to modify the definition of &quot;religion&quot; to include all aspects of religious observance, practice, and belief unless an employer demonstrates that it is unable to reasonably accommodate an employee's or prospective employee's religious observance or practice without undue hardship on the conduct of the employer's business (as under current law) after initiating and engaging in an affirmative and bona fide effort. Provides that an accommodation by the employer shall not be deemed to be reasonable if: (1) such accommodation does not remove the conflict between employment requirements and the employee's religious observance or practice; or (2) the employee demonstrates to the employer the availability of an alternative accommodation less onerous to the employee that may be made by the employer without undue hardship on the conduct of the employer's business and the employer refuses to make such accommodation. Specifies that it shall not be a defense to a claim of unlawful employment practice for failure to provide a reasonable accommodation that such accommodation would be in violation of a bona fide seniority system if, in order for the employer to reasonably accommodate such observance or practice: (1) an adjustment is made in the employee's work hours (including an adjustment that requires the employee to work overtime to avoid working at a time that abstention from work is necessary to satisfy religious requirements), shift, or job assignment that would not be available to any employee but for such accommodation; or (2) the employee and any other employee voluntarily exchange shifts or job assignments or make some other arrangement. Defines &quot;undue hardship&quot; as an action requiring significant difficulty or expense (taking into account the identifiable cost of the accommodation in relation to the size and operating cost of the employer and the number of individuals who will need a particular accommodation to a religious observance or practice). Specifies that an employer shall not be required to pay premium wages for work performed during hours to which such premium wages would ordinarily be applicable if work is performed during such hours only to accommodate religious requirements of an employee.

	</summary>
</bill>
