<bill session="103" type="h" number="5231" updated="2012-07-17T06:04:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-07T16:42:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-10-07T16:42:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the management of portions of the Presidio under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400314"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Late Referral to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands (Nov 21, 94).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T02:53:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 576 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5231 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. All points of order against the bill and against its consideration are waived. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:36:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 576 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:36:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 576.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11279-11283"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:36:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5231 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. All points of order against the bill and against its consideration are waived. Measure will be considered read.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:37:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:42:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-10-07T16:42:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:43:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="576" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3433" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1639" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Army posts"/>
		<term name="Arts"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Charities"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Construction workers"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Cultural relations"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International education"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Public works"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Scientific education"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Transportation research"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to utilize the resources of the Presidio in California to provide for and support programs and activities that foster research, education, or demonstration projects and that relate to the environment, energy, transportation, international affairs, arts and cultural understanding, health, and science. Grants the Secretary authority to: (1) negotiate and enter into specified interagency agreements and leases for the use of property within the Presidio; and (2) retain the proceeds from leases under this Act and from concession and other use authorizations and services provided by the Golden Gate National Recreation Area for five years or until the leased property is transferred to the Presidio Trust (established by this Act). Establishes within the Department of the Interior the Presidio Trust to manage the leasing, maintenance, rehabilitation, repair, and improvement of property within the Presidio which is transferred to the Trust by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to transfer to the Trust, subject to specified requirements, a leasehold in the Letterman-LAIR complex, Fort Scott, Main Post, Cavalry Stables, Presidio Hill, Wherry Housing, East Housing, the structures at Crissy Field, and such other properties within the Presidio as the Secretary and the Trust deem appropriate. Requires the Trust to obtain such competition as is practicable in the circumstances, maintain liaison with the Golden Gate National Recreation Area Advisory Commission, and meet with the Commission at least annually. Authorizes appropriations. Prohibits an entity from expending funds appropriated pursuant to this Act unless it complies with the Buy American Act. Expresses the sense of the Congress that only American-made equipment and products should be purchased by entities receiving financial assistance under this Act. Requires the head of each Federal agency to notify each such recipient of this congressional statement. Provides that if a court or Federal agency determines that any person intentionally affixed a &quot;Made in America&quot; label to any product sold or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States, such person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract made with funds provided under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
