<bill session="103" type="h" number="5266" updated="2010-04-19T12:51:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Occupational Safety and Health Compliance Incentive Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to assist small business in compliance with such Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405258"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400580" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="410529" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400397" joined="1994-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400389" joined="1994-10-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2163-2164)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-26"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Industrial accidents"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1994--Introduced.
Small Business Occupational Safety and Health Compliance Incentive Act - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA) to revise provisions relating to small businesses' compliance with such Act. Increases the Federal share of a grant for administration and enforcement for States that demonstrate their meeting State plan requirements. Requires the State to use such additional amount to carry out a consultation program to: (1) enable employers to consult with the State or the Secretary of Labor respecting their responsibilities under OSHA; and (2) provide education and training to employers respecting such responsibilities, including methods of hazard identification and mitigation. Directs the Secretary to provide technical and other assistance to States to establish and operate such consultation programs. Exempts any employer with less than 100 employees from being subject under OSHA to: (1) any fee, if the employer solicits such consultation services and has not been found in violation of OSHA within the previous 12 months; (2) certain inspections, if the employer requests a consultation visit and the consultant entity later determines that its recommendations have been implemented; or (3) a civil penalty of more than $1,000, if the employer abates a non-willful hazard in what the consultant entity deems a reasonable period of time and if a subsequent inspection finds that any such hazard no longer exists. Bases the amount of such penalty on the employer's cooperation and due diligence in abating the hazard.

	</summary>
</bill>
