<bill session="103" type="h" number="5308" updated="2010-04-19T12:58:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-11-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-11-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-11-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Payment Equity Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for a limitation on payment during any year of old-age, wife's, and husband's insurance benefits, based on the work record of an individual with higher levels of income for such year, if total payments of such benefits have exceeded prior contributions plus interest, and to adjust the gradual increase in retirement age so as to commence with calendar year 1996 and to reach age 68 for those who would attain age 65 in or after calendar year 2031.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400382"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-11-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-12-06"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Retirement"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/29/1994--Introduced.
Social Security Payment Equity Act of 1994 - Amends title II (Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) to set limits on payment of OASDI benefits during any year, based on the work record of an individual with higher levels of income for such year, if total payments of such benefits have exceeded prior contributions plus interest. Specifies schedules of benefit reductions from ten percent to 100 percent for single and for married individuals. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security to provide annual social security account statements to eligible individuals with respect to such benefit limitations. Adjusts the gradual increase in retirement age from 65 to 68 so as to commence with calendar year 1996 and reach age 68 for those who would attain age 65 in or after calendar year 2031.

	</summary>
</bill>
