<bill session="103" type="h" number="5304" updated="2010-04-19T12:57:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-11-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-11-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-11-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to modify provisions relating to the redesignation of areas and motor vehicle inspection and maintenance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400591"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-11-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Air pollution"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Air quality"/>
		<term name="Business"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Consumers"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/29/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to provide that if a State Governor submits a redesignation of an area from nonattainment to attainment and such designation is based upon attainment of the relevant national ambient air quality standard for three consecutive years, such redesignation shall become effective immediately upon receipt by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. Requires the Office of Technology Assessment to study methods for implementing enhanced inspection and maintenance programs. Includes within such study an evaluation of the cost effectiveness of such methods. Directs the Administrator to republish the motor vehicle inspection and maintenance guidance document and incorporate the study's findings. Grants States one year from the study's publication date to submit or revise implementation plans with respect to the enhanced motor vehicle inspection and maintenance program.

	</summary>
</bill>
