<bill session="103" type="h" number="530" updated="2010-04-19T00:24:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To condition the closure of a military medical facility in the United States or a reduction in the level of care provided at a military medical facility in the United States upon a determination by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the military department concerned that the closure or reduction is cost effective for the Federal Government.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408457"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E113)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military hospitals"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Prohibits the Secretary of a military department from closing, or reducing the level of care provided at, a military medical facility in the United States until determining that the closure or reduction will be cost effective. Bases a determination of cost-effectiveness on whether the cost to the Federal Government of providing such care exceeds the cost of providing equivalent care at other health facilities as a consequence of closure or reduction. Applies this Act to any closure or reduction, including pursuant to a base closure law.

	</summary>
</bill>
