<bill session="103" type="h" number="534" updated="2010-04-19T00:25:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that a special census shall be conducted, without charge to a requesting State, county, or other unit of government, if necessary to correct a significant undercount in a decennial census which is due, in whole or in part, to a natural disaster or similar situation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408457"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Census, Statistics and Postal Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16"><committee name="House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from OMB,, Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" subcommittee="Census, Statistics and Postal Personnel" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Statistics"/>
		<term name="Census"/>
		<term name="Disasters"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Population statistics"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of Commerce to conduct a special census for the government of a State, the District of Columbia, a U.S. territory or possession, or a political subdivision thereof without charge to such government, if: (1) the special census is necessary to correct a significant undercount which occurred in the most recent decennial census of population; (2) a natural disaster or other emergency affecting such area, as declared by the President, was a major factor contributing to the undercount; and (3) a request for such census is made by such government within such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe, except that the deadline for such a request may not be before the end of the 18-month period beginning on the most recent decennial census date.

	</summary>
</bill>
