<bill session="103" type="h" number="59" updated="2010-04-18T23:09:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Depository Institution Burden Relief Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the amount of credit available to fuel economic growth by reducing the regulatory burden imposed upon depository institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400023"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="402657" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400197" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="410529" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="407676" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="406431" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="407320" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400085" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400322" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="404296" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400104" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400552" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400165" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400603" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="408556" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="406863" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300151" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="411725" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="405758" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400037" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400225" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="408092" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400374" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="409423" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="408553" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="408618" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400115" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="401153" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400594" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400568" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300097" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400604" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="405560" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="404068" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400079" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400544" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400012" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="1993-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="411178" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="405258" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300096" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="409052" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="406790" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="403864" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400236" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1993-01-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-14"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-14"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-14"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H278)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H364)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSBA-04" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Deposit Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Automated teller machines"/>
		<term name="Bank capital"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank holding companies"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Bank mergers"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Branch banking"/>
		<term name="Checking accounts"/>
		<term name="Checks"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Credit cards"/>
		<term name="Credit unions"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Deposit insurance"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Financial deregulation"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Money"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
		<term name="Settlement costs"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Supervisory Reforms Title II: Nonsupervisory Reforms Subtitle A: Expedited Funds Availability and Electronic Transfers Subtitle B: Amendments to the Truth in Lending Act Subtitle C: Homeownership Amendments Depository Institution Burden Relief Act of 1993 - Title I: Supervisory Reforms - (Secs. 101-105) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to modify the guidelines governing: (1) the coordination of Federal and State examinations and reporting requirements for insured depository institutions; (2) the consolidation of requisite reports by a depository institution holding company for its capital-efficient insured depository institution subsidiaries; (3) the non-applicability to capital-efficient depository institutions of certain financial status reports for the early identification of needed improvements; and (4) the submission of duplicative information to Federal banking supervisory agencies. (Sec. 106) Prohibits a Federal banking agency from requiring an insured depository institution to submit information unrelated to either its safety or soundness, its insured deposits, or its reserve requirements. (Sec. 107) Limits the information that a capital-efficient insured depository institution must include in its federally required financial status report. (Secs. 108-109) Exempts from certain regulatory standards capital-efficient insured depository institutions and insured depository institutions which received an &quot;outstanding rating for meeting community credit needs&quot;. (Sec. 110) Sets forth guidelines for each Federal banking agency to review and report to the Congress on needless burdens imposed by the Federal banking regulatory scheme. (Sec. 111) Amends the Federal Reserve Act to repeal the statutory scheme with respect to interbank liabilities. (Sec. 112) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to set forth expedited approval procedures under which capital-efficient State banks may engage in specified activities. (Sec. 113) Amends the Community Reinvestment Act (CRA) to set forth self-certification procedures for certain regulated financial institutions in good standing. Permits Federal financial supervisory agencies to accept in satisfaction of CRA requirements State examinations conducted pursuant to comparable community reinvestment laws. Declares that a comprehensive examination of performance shall only be conducted if a Federal regulatory agency is not satisfied that credit is being extended throughout the community in a nondiscriminatory manner. (Sec. 114) Exempts specified banks from the purview of the CRA. (Sec. 115) Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to modify the assessment base guidelines for deposit insurance premiums. (Sec. 116) Mandates that certain Federal banking regulations be accompanied with a detailed statement about their economic impact upon small banks and savings associations. (Sec. 117) Mandates that each Federal banking regulatory agency establish a separate Office of Regulatory Quality to monitor its examination activities. (Sec. 118) Limits the frequency of routine examinations of insured depository institutions except those for safety and soundness. (Secs. 119-121) Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to modify the guidelines for: (1) certain reorganizations of banks into holding companies; and (2) certain bank holding companies seeking approval to engage in specified nonbanking activities. (Sec. 122) Amends Federal law regarding monetary instruments transactions to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) review annually all regulations pertaining to monetary instruments transaction requirements seeking public comment; and (2) publish all written rulings interpreting such law, as well as staff commentaries. (Sec. 123) Amends the Federal Reserve Act to modify the aggregate limits on insider lending for specified small banks. Title II: Nonsupervisory Reforms - Subtitle A: Expedited Funds Availability and Electronic Transfers - (Sec. 201) Amends the Expedited Funds Availability Act to: (1) modify the availability schedules for both depository institution accounts and new accounts; and (2) authorize the Board to establish rules for losses and liability among the States and their political subdivisions in connection with any aspect of the payment system. Subtitle B: Amendments to the Truth in Lending Act - (Sec. 211) Amends the Truth in Lending Act to: (1) exempt from its purview credit transactions involving consumers whose income or net worth exceeds specified thresholds; and (2) modify its information disclosure guidelines. Subtitle C: Homeownership Amendments - (Sec. 221) Amends the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 to modify the total assets criterion used to exempt depository institutions from its purview. (Sec. 222) Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to repeal its homeownership debt counseling notification requirements. (Sec. 223) Forbids a Federal banking agency from requiring any institution under its purview to engage in data collection practices pursuant to the requirements of the Fair Housing Act other than data required under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975.

	</summary>
</bill>
