<bill session="103" type="h" number="612" updated="2010-04-19T00:37:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">House of Representatives Election Campaign Reform Act of 1990</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform campaign practices for elections to the House of Representatives by limiting contributions from political action committees, establishing tax credits for individual campaign contributions, providing matching funds for individual small contributions, limiting the use of personal funds in a campaign, offsetting independent expenditures, encouraging the use of longer campaign commercials, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400210"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Campaign contributors"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Checkoff"/>
		<term name="Congressional candidates"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
		<term name="Political advertising"/>
		<term name="Radio in politics"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Television in politics"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1993--Introduced.
House of Representatives Election Campaign Reform Act of 1990 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 with respect to House of Representatives election campaign financing. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require broadcast stations to offer their lowest rates for certain campaign commercials to House candidates who agree to limit personal spending. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a full tax credit for small individual contributions to a House candidate. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish in the Treasury the House of Representatives Campaign Trust Fund.

	</summary>
</bill>
