<bill session="103" type="h" number="623" updated="2010-04-19T00:39:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Reorganization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Social Security Administration as an independent agency, which shall be headed by a Social Security Board, and which shall be responsible for the administration of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program under title II of the Social Security Act and the supplemental security income program under title XVI of such Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407320"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-29"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-29"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Ombudsman"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Establishment of the Social Security Administration Title II: Miscellaneous Provisions and Conforming Amendments Title III: Effective Dates and Transitional Rules Social Security Reorganization Act of 1993 - Title I: Establishment of the Social Security Administration - Amends title VII (Administration) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish the Social Security Administration as an independent executive agency to be governed by a Social Security Board. Provides that it shall be the duty of the Board to administer the Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance (OASDI) program and the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) program under SSA titles II and XVI. Requires the Board to establish in the Administration an Office of the Beneficiary Ombudsman, to be headed by a Beneficiary Ombudsman who shall represent the interest and views of OASDI and SSI beneficiaries. Transfers to the Board all functions carried out by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pertaining to such programs. Title II: Miscellaneous Provisions And Conforming Amendments - Sets forth a contributor and beneficiary bill of rights. Makes conforming amendments to SSA titles II and XVI. Requires the Board to report to the Congress within 120 days after the beginning of each regular session on its administration under SSA. Requires the Secretary to study and make recommendations on the most effective methods of providing economic security and on the administrative policy for the programs. Sets forth rules of construction. Title III: Effective Dates and Transitional Rules - Sets forth effective dates and transitional rules.

	</summary>
</bill>
