<bill session="103" type="h" number="638" updated="2010-04-19T00:41:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, regarding sentencing for capital offenses.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410529"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Civil and Constitutional Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Air piracy"/>
		<term name="Assassination"/>
		<term name="Bank robberies"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Correctional personnel"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Juries"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Presentence investigation reports"/>
		<term name="Presidential protection"/>
		<term name="Prison violence"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Protection of foreign officials"/>
		<term name="Protection of officials"/>
		<term name="Rape"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Treason"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to establish criteria for the imposition of the death penalty for Federal crimes. Requires the Government, for any offense punishable by death, to serve notice upon the defendant a reasonable time before trial or acceptance of a plea that it intends to seek the death penalty, as well as notice of the aggravating factors upon which it will rely. Requires a separate sentencing hearing before a jury, or the court upon motion by the defendant, when the defendant is found guilty or pleads guilty to an offense punishable by death. Provides that no presentence report shall be prepared in such cases. Allows the defendant and the Government to present any information relevant to sentencing, but permits information to be excluded where its probative value is substantially outweighed by the danger of unfair prejudice, confusion of the issues, or misleading of the jury. Specifies mitigating and aggravating factors. Allows the death penalty to be imposed for: (1) the murder of foreign officials, Federal judges, Federal law enforcement officers, or Federal penal or correctional employees; and (2) an offense of kidnapping resulting in the death of any person. Eliminates the death penalty for the crime of rape. Imposes the death penalty or a life sentence without the possibility of parole for any Federal prisoner who commits murder. Authorizes the death penalty for the crime of attempting to kill the President of the United States if the attempt results in bodily injury to the President or otherwise comes dangerously close to causing his death. Establishes procedures for appeal from a death sentence.

	</summary>
</bill>
