<bill session="103" type="h" number="648" updated="2010-04-19T00:43:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide that, in determining whether an individual applying for or receiving benefits based on disability is engaging in substantial gainful activity, a portion of the cost of acquiring a van which is specially equipped for the individual's disability and which the individual needs for transportation to work shall be excluded from amounts treated as such individual's earnings, and to make conforming changes in title XVI.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405939"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-01"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-01"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Commuting"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Transportation and the physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide that, in determining an individual's ability to engage in substantial gainful activity by reason of the individual's earnings, for purposes relating to disability benefits, there shall be excluded from such individual's earnings the costs of modifying a van which the individual needs for transportation to work to specially equip it for the individual's disability, plus the lesser of 50 percent of the remaining cost of the van or $12,000. Amends SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) to make conforming changes.

	</summary>
</bill>
