<bill session="103" type="h" number="650" updated="2010-04-19T00:43:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIV of the Public Health Service Act (the Safe Drinking Water Act) to clarify that review by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under section 1424(e) is mandatory, to improve interagency coordination in the protection of sole or principal drinking water source aquifers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404634"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E203-204)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Natural gas"/>
		<term name="Oil well drilling"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to review all projects concerning underground injection wells referred by Federal agencies to determine if they may contaminate any sole or principal drinking water source aquifer through a recharge zone so as to create a significant public health hazard. Requires Federal agencies to: (1) designate officials to be responsible for compliance with project requirements; and (2) forward to the Administrator, before financial assistance is committed, a description of each project, an assessment of whether the project poses a risk to the sole source aquifer concern, and documentation supporting assessment.

	</summary>
</bill>
