<bill session="103" type="h" number="670" updated="2012-07-17T06:02:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-25T13:54:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-03-25T13:54:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="107"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Abortion Counseling bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family Planning Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Family Planning Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that pregnant women receiving assistance under title X of the Public Health Service Act are provided with information and counseling regarding their pregnancies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400425"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and the Environment"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and the Environment"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and the Environment"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-02-04"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04T17:30:00-05:00"><text>RULES COMMITTEE ANNOUNCEMENT - Mr. Moakley notified the House that the Rules Committee intended to meet for the purpose of fashioning a rule providing for the consideration of H.R. 670. Members wishing to have amendments made in order to that legislation should submit 55 copies of said amendments to the Committee on Rules no later than 12 noon on February 16, 1993.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16T12:24:00-05:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 103-14.</text></action>
		<calendar number="3" datetime="1993-02-16T12:25:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 3.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16T16:36:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 81 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 670 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-23T17:19:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 138 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 670 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in the report accomanying this resolution. Each amendment shall be offered in the order, manner, and debatable as specified in the report. Amendments shall not be subject to further amendment, except as specified. The amendment in the form of a motion to strike specified in the report, to be offered by Rep. Bartlett, shall not be in order if the text proposed to be stricken has been rewritten by a previous amendment. Upon adoption of this resolution, H. Res. 81 shall be laid upon the table.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T14:39:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 138 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T15:18:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 138.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1570-1587"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T15:18:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 670 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in the report accomanying this resolution. Each amendment shall be offered in the order, manner, and debatable as specified in the report. Amendments shall not be subject to further amendment, except as specified. The amendment in the form of a motion to strike specified in the report, to be offered by Rep. Bartlett, shall not be in order if the text proposed to be stricken has been rewritten by a previous amendment. Upon adoption of this resolution, H. Res. 81 shall be laid upon the table.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T15:20:00-05:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 138 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T15:20:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Louise McIntosh Slaughter to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T15:20:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T16:16:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 138, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the DeLay amendment and the Waxman perfecting amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T17:17:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 138, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 15 minutes of debate on the Waxman amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T17:58:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Waxman moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T18:17:00-05:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by recorded vote: 287 - 119 (Roll no. 98).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24T18:18:00-05:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 670 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T11:32:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1602-1615"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T11:32:00-05:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T11:34:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 138, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the DeLay amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T12:18:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 138, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T12:25:00-05:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 670.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T12:25:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T13:05:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Bliley moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T13:05:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Bliley motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion require the Committee on Energy and Commerce to report the bill back with an amendment which would require Title X clinics that also provide abortion services with non-federal funds to notify a parent or guardian before performing an abortion on a minor. The parental notification requirement could be waived in three instances: if the minor's physician certifies that the abortion is necessary to prevent her death, and that there is insufficient time to provide the required notice; the minor declares that her pregnancy resulted from incest by her parent or legal guardian; or, that the Title X grant recipient complies with a state or local parental notification law which is at least as stringent as the federal standard established in the Bliley amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T13:17:00-05:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T13:37:00-05:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 179 - 243 (Roll no. 106).</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="107" datetime="1993-03-25T13:54:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 273 - 149 (Roll no. 107).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T13:55:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Waxman moved to reconsider the vote by which the bill was passed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T13:55:00-05:00"><text>Mrs. Unsoeld moved to table the motion to reconsider.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T14:13:00-05:00"><text>On motion to table the motion to reconsider. Agreed to by recorded vote: 274 - 142 (Roll no. 108).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T14:13:00-05:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 670.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-26"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-05-05" ><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy without amendment. With written report No. 103-84.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="129" datetime="1993-07-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 129.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="81" />
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="138" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Abortion"/>
		<term name="Abortion counseling"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Childbirth"/>
		<term name="Condoms"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Foster home care"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Population growth"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Quality of products"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h23"/>
		<amendment number="h24"/>
		<amendment number="h25"/>
		<amendment number="h26"/>
		<amendment number="h27"/>
		<amendment number="h28"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/25/1993--Passed House amended. Family Planning Amendments Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require family planning grant and contract recipients to provide nondirective counseling and referrals regarding: (1) prenatal care and delivery; (2) infant care, foster care, and adoption; and (3) termination of pregnancy. Allows a provider who objects, on religious or moral grounds, to providing such counseling and referrals to refer the woman to another provider. Requires recipients to: (1) comply with State parental notification or consent laws; and (2) distribute only those condoms meeting current quality and labeling requirements and provide information regarding condom use benefits and risks. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes appropriations for grants and contracts concerning: (1) training to provide family planning services; and (2) informational and educational materials regarding family planning and population growth. Declares the sense of the Congress regarding buying American with financial assistance under title X (Population Research and Voluntary Family Planning Programs) of the Public Health Service Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
