<bill session="103" type="h" number="689" updated="2010-04-19T00:50:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Labor Relations Fair Elections Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Labor Relations Act to provide for fair and expeditious representation elections.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400306"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-19"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Collective bargaining unit"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Labor union elections"/>
		<term name="Labor union organization and administration"/>
		<term name="National Labor Relations Board"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
National Labor Relations Fair Elections Act - Amends the National Labor Relations Act to direct the National Labor Relations Board to provide for fair and expeditious employee representation elections. Directs the Board to investigate expeditiously certain situations involving designation or election of individuals or labor organizations as employee representatives. Sets forth deadlines for the Board to conduct such investigations, as well as elections, tallies, and certifications of employee representatives. Allows employees or labor organizations to petition for such Board actions by alleging certain conditions, such as: (1) 75 percent of the employees in a collective bargaining unit having signed authorization cards designating their representative; or (2) a majority of the employees in such a unit having designated their representative, which the employer declines to recognize. Requires, in any case where the Board directs such an election to be held, that the election and tally be carried out within specified deadlines, and any objections to election results be resolved expeditiously.

	</summary>
</bill>
