<bill session="103" type="h" number="695" updated="2010-04-19T00:51:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women's Health Research Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish an Office of Research on Women's Health, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E202)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Clinical trials"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Geriatrics"/>
		<term name="Gynecology"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Menopause"/>
		<term name="Obstetrics"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Women physicians"/>
		<term name="Women scientists"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Women's Health Research Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish within the Office of the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) the Office of Research on Women's Health (Office). Establishes in the Office the Coordinating Committee on Research on Women's Health and the Advisory Committee on Research on Women's Health. Directs the Secretary to: (1) determine the extent to which women are represented among senior physicians and scientists of the national research institutes and among physicians and scientists conducting research with funds provided by such institutes; and (2) carry out activities, as appropriate, to increase the extent of such representation. Requires the NIH Director to establish a data system for the collection, analysis, and dissemination of information regarding research on women's health conducted or supported by the national research institutes, including a registry of clinical trials of experimental treatments. Requires the NIH Director to establish and operate a program to provide information on research and prevention activities of the the national research institutes that relate to research on women's health. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that NIH resources are sufficiently allocated for projects of research on women's health.

	</summary>
</bill>
