<bill session="103" type="h" number="696" updated="2010-05-20T22:00:16-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Kingpin Death Penalty Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Entitled the &quot;Drug Kingpin Death Penalty Act&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="410147"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Civil and Constitutional Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Correctional personnel"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugs and youth"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Judicial officers"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Juries"/>
		<term name="Lawyers"/>
		<term name="Legal assistance to prisoners"/>
		<term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Right to counsel"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State courts"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Drug Kingpin Death Penalty Act - Provides for imposition of the death penalty upon those: (1) subject to mandatory life imprisonment for committing a Federal drug felony as part of a continuing criminal enterprise; (2) convicted of committing such a felony as part of a continuing criminal enterprise where the defendant is a principal administrator, organizer, or leader of such an enterprise and, in order to obstruct the investigation or prosecution of the enterprise, attempts or conspires to kill any public officer, juror, witness, or family or household member of such a person; and (3) who, intending to cause death or acting with reckless disregard for human life, engage in a Federal drug felony resulting in the death of another person. Sets forth mitigating and aggravating factors. Establishes procedures for a special hearing to determine whether a sentence of death is justified. Requires the court to: (1) instruct the the jury that, in considering whether a sentence of death is justified, it shall not consider the race, color, religious beliefs, national origin, or sex of the defendant or any victim; and (2) impose a sentence of death if the jury (or if there is no jury, the court) returns a recommendation of the death penalty. Sets forth procedures for review and implementation of a sentence of death. Provides for appointment of counsel in Federal capital cases for indigent defendants. Sets standards for competence of counsel. Specifies that appointment of counsel in the Federal habeas corpus review of State capital cases is discretionary.

	</summary>
</bill>
