<bill session="103" type="h" number="711" updated="2010-04-19T00:54:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to ensure that handguns are available only to persons with demonstrated knowledge and skill in their safe use, maintenance, and storage.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404634"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="407153" joined="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="406082" joined="1993-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E236-237)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Safety measures"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/2/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the possession of a handgun by an individual who does not have a Federal firearms license unless the individual has been issued a handgun permit pursuant to this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations providing for the issuance of a handgun permit only to individuals who: (1) have successfully completed a course of instruction in the safe use, maintenance, and storage of handguns offered by a Federal or State law enforcement agency or designated entity; (2) have attained age 21; (3) are not otherwise prohibited from possessing a handgun by Federal, State, or local law; and (4) have not willfully violated any Federal firearms provision. Prescribes penalties.

	</summary>
</bill>
