<bill session="103" type="h" number="725" updated="2010-04-19T00:56:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to create a new part under such title to provide access to services for medically underserved populations not currently served by federally qualified health centers, by providing funds for a new program to allow federally qualified health centers and other qualifying entities to expand such centers' and entities' capacity and to develop additional centers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407044"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="407351" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1993-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="1993-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1993-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1993-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical centers"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/2/1993--Introduced.
Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to establish a part B (Health Services Access) to fund grants to federally-qualified health centers (FQHCs) and other entities for the expansion and development of primary health care service programs for medically underserved populations. Sets forth grant eligibility criteria and the requirements grant applications must meet. Outlines limitations on the use of grant funds. Establishes priorities for the awarding of grants, with the highest priority for those FQHCs and other entities proposing to expand operations to serve medically underserved populations with the highest degree of unmet need in the most efficient manner. Requires entities receiving program funds to return excess revenues to the Secretary. Requires termination of grants to entities failing to meet certain requirements. Directs the Secretary to study and report to the Congress on the relationship between community health centers and hospitals in providing such services. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
