<bill session="103" type="h" number="731" updated="2010-04-19T00:57:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Patriots of Peace Service Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the cost of operating the military service academies, to establish a program of college scholarships to assist the education of students in exchange for service in the Federal Government, and to increase Montgomery GI Bill benefits.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400306"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-08"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Forces and Personnel.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-08"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-09"><committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education, Training and Employment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received from DOD.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSAS-02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Forces and Personnel" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Education, Training and Employment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Civil-military relations"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational finance"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government internships"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Military education"/>
		<term name="Military pay"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Service academies"/>
		<term name="Summer employment"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/2/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Reduction in the Costs of Operating the Military Service Academies Title II: Patriots of Peace Scholarships Title III: Montgomery GI Bill Benefits for Enlisted Men and Women Patriots of Peace Service Act of 1993 - Title I: Reduction in the Costs of Operating the Military Service Academies - Requires the Secretary of Defense to reduce the costs of providing an education at U.S. military academies so that, by January 1, 1995, the average cost per student of operating each service academy is: (1) approximately equal; and (2) not more than ten percent greater than the average cost per nonacademy student at the ten top-ranked institutions of higher education in the United States. Requires the Secretary to further reduce such operating costs for each fiscal year to achieve a reduction in expenditures equal to 50 percent of the cost for that year of providing scholarships under title II of this Act. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to achieve such cost reductions, to reduce the number of appointments made to the service academies. Expresses the sense of the Congress that savings achieved as the result of such cost reductions should be used for the title II scholarship program. Title II: Patriots of Peace Scholarships - Directs the Secretary to establish a program of national security scholarships to assure an adequate supply of college graduates for civilian employee positions with the Department of Defense (DOD) and other Federal agencies involved in education or other activities related to national security. Designates each scholarship recipient as a National Security Scholar (Scholar). Outlines eligibility requirements for selection as a Scholar. Places a $50,000 annual family income limitation on eligible individuals. Provides the total number of scholarships to be awarded for FY 1994 through 1996. Allows a Scholar to use such scholarship at any institution of higher education offering a course of instruction in: (1) the complete workings of the three branches of Government; (2) DOD operations; (3) the relationship of DOD with other Federal agencies, the Congress, and the judicial branch; and (4) the relationship of DOD with State and local governments. Requires each individual selected to sign a written contract for six years of service in exchange for financial assistance. Makes all such assistance contingent upon the appropriation of funds for such scholarships. Directs the Secretary, in disseminating contract forms for scholarships, to include a fair summary of rights and liabilities of a recipient. Requires pro rata reimbursement from a Scholar to the United States for failure to complete the educational requirements or the required employment. Waives any repayment requirement if the Scholar terminates the agreement and withdraws before the start of the third school year. Title III: Montgomery GI Bill Benefits for Enlisted Men and Women - Amends the Montgomery GI Bill educational assistance program to: (1) eliminate a required $100 monthly reduction in basic pay for enlisted military personnel entering into active duty after June 30, 1985, for participation in the program; (2) eliminate provisions which allow such members an election of whether to participate in the program; and (3) increase annually the authorized amount of monthly educational assistance provided under the program on a pro rata basis to reflect the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index. Increases from 36 to 48 the number of authorized monthly payments of educational assistance under the program.

	</summary>
</bill>
