<bill session="103" type="h" number="763" updated="2010-04-19T01:02:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the establishment of free trade areas between the United States and certain Pacific Rim countries.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400085"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400104" joined="1994-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400112" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="404520" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400601" joined="1993-07-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-09"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E357)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1467-1468)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1616-1620)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Australia"/>
		<term name="Brunei Darussalam"/>
		<term name="Customs unions"/>
		<term name="Dumping"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="Export subsidies"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Free trade"/>
		<term name="Hong Kong"/>
		<term name="Indonesia"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="Japan"/>
		<term name="Malaysia"/>
		<term name="New Zealand"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Pacific area"/>
		<term name="Philippines"/>
		<term name="Singapore"/>
		<term name="South Korea"/>
		<term name="Taiwan"/>
		<term name="Thailand"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/3/1993--Introduced.
Directs the President to initiate consultations with each Pacific Rim country (Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, Brunei, Australia, New Zealand, Taiwan, South Korea, Japan, or Hong Kong) to determine the feasibility of negotiating the elimination of tariffs and nontariff barriers, including barriers to investment, trade in services, and protection of intellectual property rights, through a bilateral free trade agreement. Requires the President, at each ministerial meeting convened for such consultations, to recommend establishment of a council to review and report on the existing bilateral relationship and the prospects for negotiating a free trade agreement. Authorizes the President to enter into such agreements after expiration on June 1, 1993, of &quot;fast track&quot; authority which provides procedures for their congressional passage under the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 and the Trade Act of 1974. Requires the President to achieve specified negotiating objectives with each country, including: (1) improving bilateral relationships through trade expansion and greater economic efficiency; (2) removing trade barriers, particularly in agricultural products and manufactured components in an effort to reduce government subsidies and injurious dumping practices; (3) providing mechanisms for the development of rules in nontraditional areas such as services, trade-related investment, and the protection of intellectual property rights; (4) encouraging U.S. firms to take greater advantage of opportunities in Pacific Rim countries and to compete more effectively there; and (5) improving market access in such countries.

	</summary>
</bill>
