<bill session="103" type="h" number="811" updated="2010-04-19T01:11:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-10T14:58:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-02-10T14:58:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Counsel Reauthorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Independent Counsel Reauthorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Independent Counsel Reauthorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the independent counsel law for an additional 5 years, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401837"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="1993-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="411040" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1993-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="401947" joined="1993-02-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E331-332)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-03-24"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06T21:27:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 103-224.</text></action>
		<calendar number="125" datetime="1993-08-06T21:28:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 125.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08T18:43:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 352 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 811 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Points of order against the committee amendment for failure to comply with provisions of the Budget Act shall be waived. Only those amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution shall be in order, to be considered in the manner specified in the report and not subject to further amendment except as specified. All points of order against the amendments shall be waived. After passage of the bill, it shall be in ...</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T15:06:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 352 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T15:06:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 352.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H378-389"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T15:07:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 811 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the Committee of the Whole. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Points of order against the committee amendment for failure to comply with provisions of the Budget Act shall be waived. Only those amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution shall be in order, to be considered in the manner specified in the report and not subject to further amendment except as specified. All points of order against the amendments shall be waived. After passage of the bill, it shall be in ...</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T15:07:00-05:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 352 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T15:07:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Robert G. Torricelli to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T15:07:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T16:12:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 352, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brooks amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T16:21:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 352, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fish amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T16:30:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 352, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fish amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T16:34:00-05:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 811 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T11:00:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H419-439"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T11:00:00-05:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T11:00:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 352, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Ramstad amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T11:34:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 352, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with twenty minutes of debate on the Hyde amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T11:53:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 352, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with thirty minutes of debate on the Gekas amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T12:27:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Bryant substitute to the Gekas amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T13:27:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 352, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the Hyde amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:24:00-05:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 811.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:25:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:25:00-05:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:26:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Gekas moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:26:00-05:00"><text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Gekas motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment which would provide for mandatory coverage of Members of Congress under the independent counsel law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:32:00-05:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:50:00-05:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 183 - 230 (Roll no. 22).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H440"/></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="23" datetime="1994-02-10T14:58:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 356 - 56 (Roll No. 23).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T14:58:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10T15:00:00-05:00"><text>Laid on the table. See S. 24 for further action.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="352" />
		<bill relation="superseded" session="103" type="s" number="24" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="24" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Ethics"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="General Services Administration"/>
		<term name="Government attorneys"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="Official secrets"/>
		<term name="Physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Removal of officials"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
		<term name="Special prosecutors"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h430"/>
		<amendment number="h431"/>
		<amendment number="h432"/>
		<amendment number="h433"/>
		<amendment number="h434"/>
		<amendment number="h435"/>
		<amendment number="h436"/>
		<amendment number="h437"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/10/1994--Passed House amended. Independent Counsel Reauthorization Act of 1994 - Amends the Federal judicial code to reauthorize the independent counsel law for an additional five years. Requires an independent counsel to: (1) conduct all activities with due regard for expense, authorize only reasonable and lawful expenditures, and (promptly upon taking office) assign to a specific employee the duty of certifying that expenditures of the independent counsel are reasonable and made in accordance with law; and (2) comply with the established policies of the Department of Justice (DOJ) regarding expenditures of funds, except to the extent that compliance would be inconsistent with the purposes of the Act. Directs: (1) the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to provide administrative support and guidance to each independent counsel; and (2) the Administrator of General Services to provide office space for each independent counsel. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) independent counsel per diem expenses; (2) independent counsel employee pay comparability; (3) ethics enforcement; (4) compliance with DOJ policies; (5) publication of reports; (6) annual reports to the Congress; (7) periodic reappointment of independent counsel; and (8) audits by the Comptroller General. Authorizes the Attorney General to conduct a preliminary investigation upon the receipt of information sufficient to constitute grounds to investigate whether a Member of Congress may have violated any Federal criminal law, other than a violation classified as a Class B or C misdemeanor or an infraction, when the Attorney General determines that it would be in the public interest. Includes as grounds for removal of an independent counsel physical or mental disability consistent with prohibitions on discrimination otherwise imposed by law (current law includes physical disability and mental incapacity). Requires an independent counsel to comply with guidelines and procedures used by DOJ in the handling and use of classified materials.

	</summary>
</bill>
