<bill session="103" type="h" number="812" updated="2010-04-19T01:11:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Advisory Commission on Amateur Boxing Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Professional Boxing Prohibition Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Congressional Advisory Commission on Amateur Boxing and to amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the participation in and promotion of professional boxing.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404634"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E298)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-11"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime and Criminal Justice.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-19"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-10" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor Standards, Occupational Health and Safety" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSJU-08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Criminal Justice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Sports"/>
		<term name="Accident insurance"/>
		<term name="Boxing"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Physical examinations"/>
		<term name="Professional sports"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Congressional Advisory Commission on Amateur Boxing Title II: Prohibition of Professional Boxing Title I: Congressional Advisory Commission on Amateur Boxing - Congressional Advisory Commission on Amateur Boxing Act of 1993 - Establishes the Congressional Advisory Commission on Amateur Boxing to conduct studies and make legislative recommendations to the Congress for the establishment of Federal standards for amateur boxing matches. Requires the Commission to report to the Congress its findings and conclusions, together with any legislative recommendations concerning: (1) licensing requirements for boxers, promoters, physicians, and ring officials; (2) health and medical requirements for the examination of boxers; (3) safety and performance standards for equipment and facilities; (4) bonding requirements for promoters; (5) health, life, and accident insurance requirements for boxers; (6) training programs and standards for ring officials; (7) standards for ranking boxers; (8) a national data base of information on the health, background, and records of boxers; and (9) fines and penalties for violations of standards. Terminates the Commission 60 days after it submits the report. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Prohibition of Professional Boxing - Federal Professional Boxing Prohibition Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to make it a Federal offense to promote a boxing match or to participate in a professional boxing match in any capacity, including participation as a coach, fighter, judge, physician, referee, or timekeeper. Sets forth penalties for violation of this prohibition.

	</summary>
</bill>
