<bill session="103" type="h" number="855" updated="2010-04-19T01:18:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Land Use Notification Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of General Services, the Director of the National Park Service, the Architect of the Capitol, and the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution to provide notice to the District of Columbia before carrying out any activity affecting property located in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E292)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17"><committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Libraries and Memorials.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-19"><committee name="House Committee on Public Works + Transportation"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Grounds.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-26"><committee name="House Committee on District of Columbia"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Operations and Metropolitan Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House District of Columbia" subcommittee="Government Operations and Metropolitan Affairs" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Administration" subcommittee="Libraries and Memorials" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Public Works and Transportation" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Grounds" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="General Services Administration"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Real property"/>
		<term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
		<term name="Stadiums"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/1993--Introduced.
District of Columbia Land Use Notification Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to prohibit the Administrator of General Services, the Architect of the Capitol, the National Park Service, and the Smithsonian Institution from carrying out any activity that affects real property located in the District of Columbia (including transferring excess property or disposing of surplus property) unless the following individuals are notified with an opportunity to comment: (1) the Mayor of the District of Columbia; (2) the Chair of the Council of the District; and (3) the Chair of the Advisory Neighborhood Commission in whose neighborhood such property is located. Prohibits an event from being held at the William H.G. Fitzgerald Tennis Center at Rock Creek Park without the prior approval of the Director of the National Park Service and the Mayor of the District of Columbia. Authorizes the Administrator to waive the requirements of this Act if compliance would jeopardize public safety or national security interests: (1) upon certifying such finding to such individuals; and (2) providing the individuals with a notice and an opportunity to comment.

	</summary>
</bill>
