<bill session="103" type="h" number="860" updated="2010-04-19T01:19:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the National Park Service to provide funding to assist in the restoration, reconstruction, rehabilitation, preservation, and maintenance of the historic buildings known as &quot;poplar Forest&quot; in Bedford County, Virginia, designed, built, and lived in by Thomas Jefferson, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408556"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/1993--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to provide assistance under the Historic Sites, Buildings, and Antiquities Act to nonprofit organizations to be used to: (1) restore, preserve, and maintain the historic buildings designed, built, and lived in by Thomas Jefferson known as Poplar Forest in Bedford County, Virginia; (2) preserve and maintain related sites; (3) provide and maintain public access to such buildings and related sites; (4) design and plan activities necessary to carry out this Act; and (5) acquire lands and interests in lands to provide for the preservation and interpretation of such buildings and related sites. Prohibits funds made available pursuant to this Act from exceeding 50 percent of the total cost of the project to be funded.

	</summary>
</bill>
