<bill session="103" type="h" number="873" updated="2012-07-17T05:11:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1993-10-01" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Entitled: &quot;Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411677"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E292)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-23"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-03-31"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06T15:40:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 103-82, Part I.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Agriculture for a period ending not later than May 7, 1993 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(a), rule X.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-07"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-07T16:22:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="39" datetime="1993-05-07T16:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 39.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11T13:31:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Vento moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11T13:32:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2363-2368"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11T13:32:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11T13:57:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Burton objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11T15:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2417-2418"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11T15:42:00-04:00"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 262 - 140 (Roll no. 158).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11T15:42:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 171 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 873 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T12:42:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 171 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T12:42:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 171.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T12:42:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 873 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T12:42:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 171 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T12:42:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lynn Schenk to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T12:43:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T13:30:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 873.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T13:31:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T13:31:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T13:31:00-04:00"><text>Mr. DeLay moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T13:32:00-04:00"><text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the DeLay motion to recommit with instructions. The motion directs that the bill be recommitted to Natural Resources with instructions that that Committee reconsider the bill and report back promptly.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T13:39:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2650-2660"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T14:00:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 128 - 287 (Roll no. 174).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2658-2660"/></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="175" datetime="1993-05-20T14:15:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 317 - 101 (Roll no. 175).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T14:16:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20T14:17:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-24"><text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-07-21" ><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported in lieu of S. 489 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-122.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="180" datetime="1993-08-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 180.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><text>Amendment SP 771 proposed by Senator Kennedy for Senator Baucus.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><text>Amendment SP 771 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1993-08-04" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10463"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-13T13:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Vento moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-13T13:06:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="pingpong" datetime="1993-09-13T13:13:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-09-13T13:13:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1993-09-13" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident datetime="1993-09-21" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1993-10-01" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-91" type="public" datetime="1993-10-01"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-91.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Specialty Crops and Natural Resources" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="171" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="489" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Easements"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Lumber trade"/>
		<term name="Mineral reserves"/>
		<term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
		<term name="Mining claims"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h64"/>
		<amendment number="s771"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/4/1993--Passed Senate amended. Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire: (1) by exchange from the Big Sky Lumber Company, specified lands and interests north of Yellowstone National Park, including land in and adjacent to the Hyalite-Porcupine-Buffalo Horn Wilderness Study Area, the Scapegoat Wilderness Area, and other lands in the Gallatin National Forest; and (2) by purchase or exchange from the Company, lands and interests in the Porcupine Area, the Taylor Fork Area, and the Gallatin Area. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to convey National Forest System lands as part of such exchange. Sets forth conditions for such exchange with respect to leases and easements. Provides for the continuation of grazing on the North Bridger Range lands and requires timber harvest practices on such lands to be in accordance with the laws of the State of Montana. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture, pursuant to an agreement with Burlington Resources, Incorporated, to acquire mineral interests owned by Burlington underlying surface lands owned by the United States and located within the Clearwater-Monture Area and the Gallatin Area. Requires such acquisition to be made through exchange to Burlington of other federally owned mining interests that the parties may agree to. Requires consultation with the Secretary of the Interior in the negotiation of such exchange. Requires all lands conveyed to the United States under this Act to be added to and administered as part of the Gallatin National Forest. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
