<bill session="103" type="h" number="880" updated="2010-04-19T01:22:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">California Military Lands Withdrawal and Overflights Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To withdraw certain Federal lands in the State of California for military purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400612"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406729" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1993-02-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E294-295)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-03"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, Navy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Provisions of Measure Included in H.R.518.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Air routes"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Deserts"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Fire prevention"/>
		<term name="Geothermal resources"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Horses"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Military aviation"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
		<term name="Naval bases"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/1993--Introduced.
California Military Lands Withdrawal and Overflights Act of 1993 - Withdraws from appropriation under public land laws, and reserves for military training, research, and development activities by the Secretary of the Navy, specified lands in California known as the China Lake Naval Weapons Center and Chocolate Mountain. Withdraws the China Lake lands from the mining and mineral leasing laws and withdraws the Chocolate Mountain lands from the mining, mineral, and geothermal leasing laws. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage such lands pursuant to the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, permitting the continuation of grazing, the protection of wildlife, the control of animals, recreation, the prevention of brush and range fires, and geothermal leasing (for China Lake only). Directs the Secretary of the Interior to develop a plan for the management of each area withdrawn. Directs the Secretary of the Navy to prevent and suppress brush and range fires occurring on such lands as a result of military activities. Authorizes such land to be used for other defense-related purposes. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to assign management responsibility for the China Lake area to the Secretary of the Navy, who shall submit specified reports and manage the wild horses and burros on such lands. Terminates such land withdrawals under this Act after 15 years. Requires an environmental impact statement. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to: (1) maintain a decontamination program for such lands; and (2) notify the Secretary of the Interior on whether an extension of withdrawal shall be requested and on the extent that such lands are contaminated with hazardous materials. Requires the decontamination of any such lands. Exempts the United States from liability for injuries or damages resulting from nonmilitary activity on withdrawn lands. Authorizes an extension of the Navy's use of the El Centro Ranges in California through 1993, terminating all military uses of such lands on January 1, 1994. States that nothing in this Act or the California Desert Protection Act of 1991 shall preclude low-level overflights by military aircraft, the designation of new airspace, or military flight training routes over the new units of the National Park or National Wilderness Preservation Systems designated by either Act. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to monitor the effect of aircraft overflights on the resources and values of such units, and prevent, minimize, or eliminate the derogation of such resources and values.

	</summary>
</bill>
