<bill session="103" type="h" number="89" updated="2010-04-18T23:13:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Technology Education Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize a program of grants to States and establish a technology agency within the Department of Education to improve the use of technology in elementary and secondary schools.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400216"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Educational technology"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Technology Education Assistance Act of 1993 - Title I: State Grants and National Programs - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to States to strengthen teacher skills and improve instruction regarding use of technology in the classroom. Authorizes appropriations. Sets forth formulas for allocation to States and for in-State allocation to: (1) local education agencies, for training projects and grants projects for individual teachers; and (2) higher education training programs for teachers. Sets forth State and local application and program evaluation requirements. Directs the Secretary to submit a summary of State evaluations of programs to the Congress biennially. Title II: Technology Agency - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to direct the Secretary to: (1) establish an Education Technology Agency (ETA) within the Department of Education; and (2) appoint a ETA Director and a Technology Board. Sets forth ETA functions. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
