<bill session="103" type="h" number="903" updated="2010-04-19T01:26:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Federal Purchases Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title III of the Act of March 3, 1933, commonly known as the Buy American Act, to require Federal agencies to increase domestic procurement in times of economic recession, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400286"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400210" joined="1993-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1993-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="405775" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="1993-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="404220" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400591" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="410889" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="407044" joined="1993-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="402762" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-03-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-19"><committee name="House Committee on Government Operations"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Business cycles"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Gross national product"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Unemployment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/1993--Introduced.
Fairness in Federal Purchases Act of 1993 - Amends the Buy American Act to require Federal agency heads, upon notification in the Federal Register that the unemployment rate was five percent or higher or that the gross national product (GNP) declined during the preceding fiscal quarter, to determine whether: (1) the amount the agency spent on foreign government goods and services exceeded the amount such foreign governments spent on similar domestic goods and services during the preceding fiscal year and, if so, adjust spending on procurement from domestic versus foreign sources to eliminate any imbalance; and (2) less than 35 percent of the agency procurement spending went to small businesses and, if so, increase small business procurement spending to equal or exceed that amount. Provides that the lowest acceptable domestic product prices shall be considered unreasonable if they exceed the lowest acceptable foreign prices by more than specified amounts. Terminates such spending requirements after: (1) three years; or (2) specified shorter periods following publication of an unemployment rate of less than five percent for the preceding quarter or of a stable or increasing GNP for two consecutive quarters.

	</summary>
</bill>
