<bill session="103" type="h" number="908" updated="2010-04-19T01:27:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To disqualify any individual or business concern who violates a Federal environmental law, or who holds a beneficial business interest in a person who has violated such a law, from being eligible to receive certain benefits from the Environmental Protection Agency for a period of 10 years.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408553"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/1993--Introduced.
Denies Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) benefits for ten years to any person: (1) convicted of violating a Federal environmental law; or (2) found to have held a beneficial business interest in a business concern required to be listed on a disclosure statement under this Act and convicted of violating a Federal environmental law. Prohibits the EPA Administrator from denying benefits to any person who demonstrates that he has been rehabilitated. Requires the following persons to file disclosure statements with the Administrator: (1) Federal environmental permit applicants; (2) applicants for EPA loans, grants, or other benefits; or (3) persons submitting contract bids or competitive proposals to EPA. Provides for enforcement of this Act through EPA examination of disclosure statements and access to business sites and records. Grants persons declared to be ineligible for EPA benefits the opportunity for a hearing. Provides for public access to disclosure statements and business records, with the exception of confidential information.

	</summary>
</bill>
