<bill session="103" type="h" number="91" updated="2010-04-18T23:14:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Workplace Education and High Performance Workforce Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to States for the purpose of providing workplace services to small businesses.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400216"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400534" joined="1993-05-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-19"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education and Training.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education and Training" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Adult education"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Industrial engineering"/>
		<term name="Industrial productivity"/>
		<term name="Industry-university relations"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Literacy programs"/>
		<term name="Mathematics"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/1993--Introduced.
Workplace Education and High Performance Workforce Act of 1993 - Authorizes appropriations. Title I: Office of Workplace Education and High Performance Work - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish in the Employment and Training Administration an Office of Workplace Education and High Performance Work to provide workplace education and other services for small businesses. Requires the establishment of standards for workforce specialists, research on implementation of workplace education, and dissemination of information on the introduction of new technologies and the reorganization of work by small businesses. Requires annual reports. Title II: Workplace Education and Workforce Grant Program - Requires the Secretary to make grants to States to establish workplace service programs to improve the productivity of small businesses in such States. Requires each State receiving such a grant to establish a State office of workplace education and high performance work. Requires such State office to: (1) establish workplace service districts throughout the State; (2) hire workforce specialists; and (3) place one of them, including necessary support staff, in one of the institutions of higher education located in each district. Requires the State office to make supplemental grants to eligible small businesses. Sets forth limitations on grants and on administrative costs. Requires grant allocations to States to be based on population, but limits the percentage of funds which may go to any one State. Sets forth maintenance of effort requirements. Requires annual grant program reports and evaluations by States.

	</summary>
</bill>
