<bill session="103" type="h" number="915" updated="2010-04-19T01:28:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Support Economic Security Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the collection of child support.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409650"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406466" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="406873" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400532" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="401494" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="404013" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400524" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400106" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400143" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400417" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="411947" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="406729" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400265" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400269" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400615" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="404190" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="406554" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400314" joined="1993-03-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E335)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-23"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-10"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>See H.R.2264.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Human Resources" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2264" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Alimony"/>
		<term name="Bankruptcy"/>
		<term name="Child support"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Court records"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Divorce"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Garnishment"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Insurance"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Lotteries"/>
		<term name="Marriage"/>
		<term name="Paternity"/>
		<term name="Property"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Separation (Law)"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="State courts"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Support of dependents"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Child Support Enforcement Amendments Title II: Bankruptcy Amendments Relating to Child Support, Alimony, and Property Settlement Agreements Child Support Economic Security Act of 1993 - Title I: Child Support Enforcement Amendments - Amends the Social Security Act to provide that, in order to satisfy Federal grant eligibility criteria, a State plan for child and spousal support must provide for the designation of a single, separate, organizational unit at the State level to administer the plan under uniform State rules. Requires a State to have in effect specified statutory procedures. Mandates that State absent parent locator programs include response deadlines for information requests from other States. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue regulations establishing standards and procedures governing the processing by States of cases involving the enforcement of child support obligations against parents in other States, including a deadline by which prosecutions must commence. Increases the amount the Secretary shall pay quarterly to each State for the operation of a State plan for child and spousal support. Repeals the mandate for Federal incentive payments to the States for cost-effective enforcement of child support payments. Makes a prerequisite for approval of any State plan that it have in effect a law identical to the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act. Establishes the Commission on Child Support Guidelines. Title II: Bankruptcy Amendments Relating to Child Support, Alimony, and Property Settlement Agreements - Amends Federal bankruptcy law to declare that the filing of a petition in bankruptcy does not operate as an automatic stay of actions for establishment of paternity or concerning certain debts for child and spousal support and maintenance. Includes among priority claims and expenses those for certain child and spousal support and maintenance. Precludes a trustee in bankruptcy from avoiding a transfer if it was a bona fide payment of a debt for child or spousal support, maintenance, or alimony. Amends the guidelines for what constitutes the property of the bankrupt estate of either a family farmer or an individual with regular annual income. Declares, for such debtors, that the court shall confirm a bankruptcy plan if the debtor has paid all allowable claims arising after the order for relief for debts for child and spousal support, maintenance, or alimony. Permits representatives of child support creditors to appear in court without charge and without meeting any special local court rule requirement for attorney appearances in any judicial bankruptcy proceeding if such representatives file information detailing the child support debt, status, and other characteristics.

	</summary>
</bill>
