<bill session="103" type="h" number="935" updated="2010-04-19T01:32:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Earthquake, Volcanic Eruption, and Hurricane Hazards Insurance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a Federal program of insurance against the risk of catastrophic earthquakes, volcanic eruptions, and hurricanes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400554"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400509" joined="1993-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400596" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="1993-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400511" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="407772" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="403364" joined="1993-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="411350" joined="1993-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400615" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="406554" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400516" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403776" joined="1993-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404067" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="1993-04-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E345-346)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space and Technology.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-22"><committee name="House Committee on Science, Space and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Science.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSSY-14" name="House Science, Space and Technology" subcommittee="Science" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Disasters"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Building laws"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Disaster insurance"/>
		<term name="Earthquake insurance"/>
		<term name="Earthquakes"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Fire prevention"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Hurricanes"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Insurance rates"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Mobile homes"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Reinsurance"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tsunamis"/>
		<term name="Volcanoes"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/17/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Participation by States in Adoption of Hazard Reduction Measures Title II: Primary Insurance Program Title III: National Earthquake, Volcanic Eruption, and Hurricane Excess Loss Reinsurance Program Earthquake, Volcanic Eruption, and Hurricane Hazards Insurance Act of 1993 - Title I: Participation by States in Adoption of Hazard Reduction Measures - Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (Director of FEMA) to identify earthquake-prone, volcanic eruption-prone, and hurricane-prone States and areas. Establishes the Earthquake, Volcanic Eruption, and Hurricane Loss Mitigation Advisory Committee. Requires development of loss-reduction criteria for State and local land use and management ordinances, building codes, and other measures. Requires that a percentage of the annual hurricane, earthquake, and volcanic eruption insurance and excess reinsurance premiums collected under the Primary Insurance program be deposited in a Self-Sustaining Mitigation Fund to support specified hazard reduction activities. Provides State assistance for development and implementation of mitigation plans. Prohibits making, increasing, extending, or renewing any federally-related mortgage loan secured by: (1) residential property in an earthquake-prone, volcanic eruption-prone, or hurricane-prone State unless the property is covered by earthquake and volcanic eruption insurance coverage under this Act or equivalent private insurance; or (2) improved real estate or a mobile home located in an earthquake-prone or volcanic eruption-prone State if the State is not in compliance with the loss-reduction criteria of this Act and the property does not meet minimum mitigation criteria. Title II: Primary Insurance Program - Requires the Director of FEMA to establish a Primary Insurance Program to provide national coverage for residential property (and related personal property) losses in earthquake-prone, volcanic eruption-prone, or hurricane-prone States. Establishes: (1) the Earthquake, Volcanic Eruption, and Hurricane Insurance and Reinsurance Advisory Committee; and (2) the Residential Property Insurance Fund in the Treasury. Title III: National Earthquake, Volcanic Eruption, and Hurricane Excess Loss Reinsurance Program - Requires the Director of FEMA to make reinsurance and excess reinsurance available to private insurers participating in the Program and their reinsurers. Provides for the excess reinsurance liability of the insurance industry and the Federal Government. Establishes in the Treasury the Reinsurance Fund to carry out the excess loss reinsurance program. Requires the Director of FEMA, to the extent that the Reinsurance Fund is insufficient to pay claims and expenses, to issue to the Secretary of the Treasury obligations to cover the insufficiency.

	</summary>
</bill>
