<bill session="103" type="h" number="963" updated="2010-04-19T01:37:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Government Interstate Waste Control Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize local governments and Governors to restrict receipt of out-of-State municipal solid waste.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400078" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400571" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1993-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="407351" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="1993-09-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400397" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="408109" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="405377" joined="1993-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="402890" joined="1994-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400578" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="402750" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400527" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="409578" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400386" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400340" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="407141" joined="1993-11-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400614" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="1993-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400572" joined="1993-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="409966" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="409400" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400513" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400526" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1993-02-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E368-369)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-01"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Transportation and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/18/1993--Introduced.
Local Government Interstate Waste Control Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit owners or operators of landfills, incinerators, or other waste disposal facilities from receiving municipal solid waste generated outside their State unless they obtain authorization from the affected local government. Exempts from such prohibition: (1) landfills that, as of this Act's enactment date, complied with State laws relating to design and location standards, leachate collection, groundwater monitoring, and financial assurance for closure and post-closure care and corrective action and, during 1991, accepted municipal solid waste generated outside the State or, before this Act's enactment date, obtained authorization to accept such waste; (2) persons planning to own or operate a landfill, incinerator, or other waste disposal facility who obtained authorization to accept such waste before this Act's enactment; and (3) incinerators that accepted such waste during 1991 or obtained authorization before this Act's enactment. Considers expansions of landfills, incinerators, or waste disposal facilities to be separate facilities requiring authorization. Exempts owners or operators of such facilities from the requirement to obtain additional authorizations if: (1) at the time they obtained authorization, they possessed an option to purchase the land on which the expansion is proposed to occur; and (2) the area of expansion was indicated in documents filed with the affected local government before obtaining authorization; or (3) with respect to facilities exempted from authorization requirements, they possessed an option to purchase the land for the expansion during 1991. Authorizes State Governors to prohibit local government authorizations if the disposal of out-of-State waste is using solid waste management capacity required to be used for waste generated within the local government's region. Permits a Governor, if requested by an affected local government and local solid waste planning unit, to limit the amount of out-of-State waste received at landfills exempted from authorization requirements. Makes this Act inapplicable after 1996 unless each operating landfill in a State: (1) meets design and location standards applicable to landfills constructed on and after October 1993; or (2) is on an enforceable schedule to stop receiving waste by 2000 and to implement a closure plan.

	</summary>
</bill>
