<bill session="103" type="h" number="980" updated="2010-04-19T01:40:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to require dependency as a condition of a stepchild's eligibility for child's insurance benefits, thereby preventing an insured individual's stepchildren from qualifying for such benefits on the insured individual's wage record (and thereby reducing the benefits of the insured individual's natural children) if the stepchildren are being supported by a natural parent, and to provide for termination of an individual's child's insurance benefits, based on the work record of a stepparent, upon the remarriage of the child's natural parent after such natural parent's divorce from such stepparent.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405939"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Divorce"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Remarriage"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/18/1993--Introduced.
Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to eliminate as a basis of a stepchild's eligibility for child's insurance benefits the fact that such child is living with his or her stepfather or stepmother. (Continues the requirement that the child receive at least half of his or her support from the stepparent.) Provides for termination of a child's insurance benefits based on the work record of a stepparent upon the remarriage of the child's natural parent after divorce from such stepparent. Sets forth circumstances in the case of existing entitlements where a child shall be deemed as not dependent on the stepparent (hence ineligible for insurance benefits).

	</summary>
</bill>
