<bill session="103" type="hc" number="179" updated="2010-04-18T21:28:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Concerning the case of Joseph Occhipinti.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400611"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2988, E3003-3005)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E3026)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E140-141)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E174-175)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E220)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E269-270)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E356)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E376-377)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E401-402)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E465-466)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E614)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2281-2284)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Private legislation"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Introduced.
Requires the Attorney General to appoint a special prosecutor to investigate all allegations of a drug cartel inspired conspiracy against a named individual and to determine whether or not such individual's conviction was justified or if there was perjured testimony, organized crime coercion of witnesses, and possible prosecutorial misconduct. States that the President should grant the individual a full and complete pardon and restore him to his position within the Immigration and Naturalization Service if the investigation finds that he was unjustly convicted.

	</summary>
</bill>
