<bill session="103" type="hc" number="203" updated="2010-04-18T21:32:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress that information regarding the conviction of child-related sex offenses should be available to employers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400055"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-15"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-09"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-02" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Civil and Constitutional Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and criminals"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Child molesting"/>
		<term name="Children"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Foster home care"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Group homes for children"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="School personnel"/>
		<term name="Teachers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/1994--Introduced.
Calls for: (1) criminal background checks for all prospective employees or volunteers of State-licensed or tax-funded organizations that interact with children; (2) an adult convicted of, or a child adjudicated as a delinquent for, a child-related sex offense to register a current address with the local law enforcement agency (LEA); (3) courts to require such persons to register with a local LEA as a condition of probation; (4) criminal penalties for failing to register and for violating confidentiality requirements regarding the release of information obtained through such registration; (5) LEAs to submit information on individuals convicted of such offenses to the national criminal history background check system and to access the Federal Bureau of Investigation database for criminal background checks on employees, or volunteers in State-licensed or federally funded organizations that interact with children; (6) the police, upon request, to release information on whether a person has been convicted of an offense if the convicted person lives in the same county as the person making the request; (7) a child care institution, foster family home, group home, or child placing agency to be prohibited from hiring an employee or utilizing a volunteer convicted of such an offense; (8) anyone applying for employment with a school to undergo a mandatory criminal history check; (9) a school to be prohibited from hiring or retaining a person known to have committed such an offense; (10) the State board of education to be prohibited from issuing a teaching license to a person convicted of an offense and to revoke a teacher's license permanently if the teacher is convicted of such an offense; and (11) in the case of an arrest or filing of charges for such offense, an LEA or prosecuting attorney to be required to notify the school superintendent regarding the arrest or filing of charges for such an offense against a person known to be employed by such school.

	</summary>
</bill>
