<bill session="103" type="hc" number="240" updated="2010-04-18T21:38:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to intellectual property protection.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400585"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409423" joined="1994-04-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-19"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22"><committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Tariff preferences"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/1994--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) intellectual property protection should continue to be among the principal U.S. trade policy objectives; (2) the United States should pursue further strengthened levels of intellectual property protection, even after implementation of the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights (TRIPS Agreement) through bilateral, regional, and multilateral negotiations; (3) the level of such protection should be a determinant of eligibility for participation in future free trade agreements, and the provisions of law relating to existing preferential programs such as the Caribbean Basin Initiative, the General System of Preferences, and the Andean Trade Preferences, should be strengthened to encourage accelerated implementation of the TRIPS Agreement; and (4) non-trade law statutes should be clarified to ensure that they may be used in support of strong intellectual property protection abroad.

	</summary>
</bill>
