<bill session="103" type="hc" number="267" updated="2010-04-18T21:42:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the Federal Government should develop a comprehensive program regarding natural disasters, require individuals and businesses in disaster prone areas to purchase insurance for natural disasters, and create a Federal reinsurance program to minimize the associated risks to insurance companies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400055"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-30"><committee name="House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Credit and Insurance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Consumer Credit and Insurance" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Disasters"/>
		<term name="Disaster insurance"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Earthquake insurance"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Flood insurance"/>
		<term name="Hurricanes"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Reinsurance"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/19/1994--Introduced.
Declares that it is the sense of the Congress that the Federal Government should: (1) with assistance from State and local officials, develop and implement a comprehensive program to prevent further exorbitant spending on assistance relating to natural disasters; (2) require individuals and businesses in areas that have a high risk of experiencing natural disasters to purchase comprehensive insurance to cover the high cost of damages resulting from such disasters as flooding, earthquakes, and hurricanes; and (3) create a Federal reinsurance program that would minimize the financial risk incurred by insurance companies that provide insurance in areas that have a high risk of experiencing natural disasters.

	</summary>
</bill>
