<bill session="103" type="hc" number="265" updated="2010-04-18T21:42:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the issuance under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 of administrative guidelines applicable to religious harassment in employment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400502"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04"><committee name="House Committee on Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education and Civil Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSED-04" name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Select Education and Civil Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/12/1994--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that for the purpose of issuing final regulations under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 in connection with proposed guidelines published by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission: (1) the category of religion should be withdrawn from the proposed guidelines; (2) any new guidelines should be drafted to make clear that symbols or expressions of religious belief consistent with the First Amendment and the Religious Freedom Act of 1993 are not to be restricted and do not constitute proof of harassment; (3) the Commission should hold public hearings on such new proposed guidelines; and (4) the Commission should receive additional public comment before issuing similar new guidelines.

	</summary>
</bill>
