<bill session="103" type="hc" number="300" updated="2010-04-18T21:47:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the commonwealth option presented in the Puerto Rican plebiscite of November 14, 1993.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2008-2009)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee On Insular and International Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular and International Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="sc" number="75" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Puerto Rico"/>
		<term name="Referendum"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/30/1994--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the changes to the political relationship between Puerto Rico and the United States described in the commonwealth option of the Puerto Rico plebiscite of November 14, 1993, would provide to U.S. citizens who are residents of Puerto Rico the Federal benefits of U.S. citizens living in the States without the concomitant responsibilities; (2) the commonwealth formula presented in such plebiscite is not an economically or politically viable alternative to the current self-governing, unincorporated territorial status of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and (3) the unalterable bilateral pact that such formula purposes as the vehicle for the permanent union of Puerto Rico with the United States is not a constitutionally viable alternative to the current status of that Commonwealth.

	</summary>
</bill>
