<bill session="103" type="hc" number="64" updated="2012-06-27T12:16:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
	<status><conference datetime="1993-04-01" where="s" result="pass" how="roll" roll="94"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal years 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, and 1998.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400354"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-15T13:59:00-05:00" state="INTRODUCED"><text>The House Committee on The Budget reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-31, by Mr. Sabo.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-03-15T13:59:00-05:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 15.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16T14:56:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 131 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 64 with 10 hours of general debate. All points of order against the concurrent resolution shall be dispensed with. After the conclusion of general debate the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion. No further consideration of the concurrent resolution shall be in order except pursuant to a subsequent order of the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T12:21:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 131 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T15:11:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 131.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1325"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T15:11:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 64 with 10 hours of general debate. All points of order against the concurrent resolution shall be dispensed with. After the conclusion of general debate the Committee of the Whole shall rise without motion. No further consideration of the concurrent resolution shall be in order except pursuant to a subsequent order of the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T15:11:00-05:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 131 and Rule XXIII.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T15:11:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jose E. Serrano to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T15:12:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 131, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 hours of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T23:22:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Mfume moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T23:23:00-05:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T23:23:00-05:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 64 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T23:24:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1325-1392"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T23:28:00-05:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T23:28:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17T23:34:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 133 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 64. Previous question shall be considered as ordered. Upon adoption of this resolution the Speaker may declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole for the further consideration of the concurrent resolution. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution. Said amendments shall be offered and debated as specified in the report and shall not be subject to amendment except as specified. All points of order against the amendments shall be waived. If more than one amendment in the nature of a substitute is adopted, only the last to been adopted shall be considered as finally adopted and reported to the House. At the conclusion of consideration of the resolution and a final 20 minute period of general debate, the Committee shall rise and repor...</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T01:25:00-05:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H. Con. Res. 64 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T13:24:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 133 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T14:02:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 133.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1392-1411, H1428-1496"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T14:03:00-05:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T14:05:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 64. Previous question shall be considered as ordered. Upon adoption of this resolution the Speaker may declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole for the further consideration of the concurrent resolution. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. No amendment shall be in order except those printed in the report accompanying this resolution. Said amendments shall be offered and debated as specified in the report and shall not be subject to amendment except as specified. All points of order against the amendments shall be waived. If more than one amendment in the nature of a substitute is adopted, only the last to been adopted shall be considered as finally adopted and reported to the House. At the conclusion of consideration of the resolution and a final 20 minute period of general debate, the Committee shall rise and repor...</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T14:08:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 133, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with two hours of debate on the Kasich amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T16:47:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 133, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Solomon amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T18:19:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant the provisions of H. Res. 133, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the Mfume amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T19:08:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Burton moved to strike the resolving clause.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T19:35:00-05:00"><text>On motion to strike the resolving clause Failed by recorded vote: 122 - 302 (Roll no. 83).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T19:35:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed debate on the Mfume amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T20:21:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 133, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T20:49:00-05:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H. Con. Res. 64.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18T20:49:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="85" datetime="1993-03-18T21:11:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 243 - 183 (Roll no. 85).</text></vote>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="43" datetime="1993-03-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 43.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S3699-3700"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S.CON.RES. 18 amended.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="83" datetime="1993-03-25" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES"><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate in lieu of S.CON.RES. 18 with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 54-45. Record Vote No: 83.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25"><text>Senate insists on its amendment asks for a conference, appoints conferees Sasser; Hollings; Johnston; Domenici; Grassley.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T14:18:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Sabo asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T14:19:00-05:00"><text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T14:19:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Kasich moved that the House instruct conferees.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T14:21:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Kasich motion to instruct conferees. The motion requires that the managers on the part of the House at the conference be instructed to agree to the highest level of deficit reduction, the lowest levels of budget outlays, and the lowest level of revenues within the scope of the conference without resorting to higher taxes on social security beneficiaries.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T15:08:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T15:31:00-05:00"><text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 413 - 0 (Roll no. 109).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T15:31:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25T15:32:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Sabo, Gephardt, Kildee, Beilenson, Berman, Wise, Bryant, Stenholm, Frank (MA), Slaughter, Kasich, McMillan, Kolbe, Shays, Snowe, and Herger.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30"><text>Conference held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30T16:59:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Sabo asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on March 30 to file a conference report on H. Con. Res. 64. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31T15:05:00-05:00"><text>Conference report H. Rept. 103-48 filed.</text><reference label="text of conference report" ref="CR H1747-1761"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31T15:36:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 145 Reported to House. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read. The conference report shall be debatable for one hour. The chairman of the Committee on the Budget may submit for printing in the Congressional Record not later than April 1, 1993 the allocations required by section 602(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31T17:48:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 145 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31T17:49:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Sabo brought up conference report H. Rept. 103-48 for consideration under the provisions of H. Con. Res. 145.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31T17:49:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31T19:05:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="127" datetime="1993-03-31T19:26:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 184 (Roll no. 127).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31T19:26:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31"><text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="94" datetime="1993-04-01" where="s" result="pass" ><text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 55-45. Record Vote No: 94.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="131" />
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="133" />
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="145" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hj" number="174" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hj" number="174" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="sc" number="18" />
		<bill relation="supersedes" session="103" type="sc" number="18" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="sc" number="18" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="sc" number="18" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural machinery"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Barges"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Child nutrition"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation in crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Community policing"/>
		<term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections"/>
		<term name="Conversion of industries"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Diesel motor"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Economic growth"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational innovations"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Entitlements"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="Family policy"/>
		<term name="Farms"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal budget process"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Food relief"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Free trade"/>
		<term name="Fuel"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government property"/>
		<term name="Government securities"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Heating"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Inflation"/>
		<term name="Inland water transportation"/>
		<term name="Item veto"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Mining royalties"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Petroleum"/>
		<term name="Police"/>
		<term name="Police-community relations"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Presidential powers"/>
		<term name="Privatization"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Space programs"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="h20"/>
		<amendment number="h21"/>
		<amendment number="h22"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/1993--Conference report filed in House. Establishes the budget for FY 1994 and sets forth appropriate budgetary levels for FY 1995 through 1998. Sets forth recommended budgetary levels of Federal revenues, new budget authority, budget outlays, deficits, public debt, and credit activity. Sets forth the increase in the public debt subject to limitation. Displays Federal retirement trust fund balances. Sets forth Social Security trust fund revenues and outlays for Senate enforcement purposes. Sets forth funding levels for each major functional category. Requires the House Committee on Ways and Means and the Senate Committee on Finance to report reconciliation legislation to their respective Houses containing recommendations to change laws to increase the statutory limit on the public debt to not more than a specified amount. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the Government should sell assets from time to time; and (2) the amounts realized from such sales will not recur on an annual basis and do not reduce the demand for credit. Allows budget authority and outlay allocations for legislation that increases funding for certain purposes when legislation has been reported that will not, if enacted, increase the deficit for FY 1994 through 1998. Describes such purposes as funding: (1) to improve the health and nutrition of children and to provide for services to protect children and strengthen families; (2) for economic growth initiatives for unemployment compensation and related programs; (3) to make continuing improvements in ongoing health care programs and comprehensive health care reform; (4) to improve educational opportunities for individuals at the early childhood, elementary, secondary, or higher education levels, or to invest in America's children; (5) to preserve and rebuild the United States maritime industry; (6) to reform the financing of Federal elections; and (7) to implement trade-related legislation. Limits the levels of social security outlays and revenues for this resolution to the current services levels. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that legislation enacting tax increases called for in this budget resolution provide that net revenues shall not be counted for the purposes of calculating any deficit increase. Establishes Senate enforcement procedures to extend the system of discretionary spending limits to budget resolutions for FY 1996 through 1998 and enforce pay-as-you-go spending. Expresses the sense of the Senate with respect to the barge tax, social security taxes, home heating fuel rates, relief from the energy tax for the agriculture industry, the effects of inflation on national defense, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, grazing fees, hardrock mining royalty fees, the Head Start program, education reform and initiatives, defense conversion programs, medical research, Federal health care costs and reform, the Women, Infants, and Children program, the community policing program, drug supply reduction programs, debt limit in reconciliation, the establishment of a deficit reduction account, line item veto authority, and savings from Government streamlining.

	</summary>
</bill>
