<bill session="103" type="hc" number="78" updated="2010-04-18T21:12:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Establishing a commission to study compensation and other personnel policies and practices in the legislative branch.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E877-878)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><committee name="House Committee on House Administration"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Personnel and Police.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Administration" subcommittee="Personnel and Police" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Equal pay for equal work"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government consultants"/>
		<term name="Libraries"/>
		<term name="Pay equity"/>
		<term name="Personnel management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
Establishes the Commission on Employment Discrimination in the Legislative Branch to: (1) employ a nongovernmental consultant, with expertise in job evaluation, to study and compare the compensation paid within and between job classifications in the Library of Congress and to analyze its personnel policies and practices; (2) evaluate such compensation system and personnel policies and practices for compliance with title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and make recommendations to the Congress (other than one that would reduce the salary of any position) for necessary action to achieve such compliance; (3) develop a comprehensive plan that applies the principles of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 throughout the legislative branch; and (4) make recommendations to the Congress for improvement of personnel policies and practices in the legislative branch.

	</summary>
</bill>
