<bill session="103" type="hj" number="284" updated="2010-04-18T22:36:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">War Powers Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the War Powers Resolution.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="1993-11-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="404375" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="404978" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400243" joined="1993-10-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2557-2558)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional sessions"/>
		<term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
		<term name="Declaration of war"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Military intervention"/>
		<term name="Presidents"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/27/1993--Introduced.
War Powers Amendments of 1993 - Amends the War Powers Resolution to permit the introduction of the armed forces into hostilities or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated only: (1) pursuant to a declaration of war by the Congress; (2) in accordance with a specific statutory authorization; (3) to contend with an armed attack on the United States or the armed forces; or (4) under certain circumstances to protect U.S. nationals while evacuating them from a situation that threatens their lives or liberty. Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds for any such introduction of the armed forces except as described under this Act. Requires the President to consult with the Congress before the armed forces are introduced into hostilities and before they are introduced into the territory, airspace, or waters of a foreign country: (1) while equipped for combat, except for deployments which relate solely to supply, replacement, repair, or training of such forces; or (2) in which there are already armed forces equipped for combat if such introduction would substantially enlarge the number of armed forces equipped for combat or increase the military capabilities of such forces. Declares that the President must ask Members of Congress for their advice and opinions before the decision is made to introduce the armed forces in order to satisfy the consultation requirement. Directs the President, within 48 hours after the armed forces are introduced into hostilities or situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated, to report to the Speaker of the House and the president pro tempore of the Senate on: (1) the circumstances necessitating the introduction; (2) the constitutional and legislative authority under which the introduction took place; and (3) the estimated scope and duration of the hostilities or the involvement of the armed forces. Provides for continuing reports at least every six months. Prohibits funding for continued involvement of the armed forces 60 days after their introduction unless the Congress has provided specific statutory authorization and other conditions have been met. Sets forth expedited congressional procedures for the consideration of a privileged resolution authorizing the introduction of the armed forces into hostilities. Authorizes Members of Congress to bring actions for declaratory judgment and injunctive relief for failures by the President to comply with this resolution. Provides for removal of the armed forces from hostilities by court order if the court finds that this resolution has been violated.

	</summary>
</bill>
