<bill session="103" type="hj" number="74" updated="2010-04-18T22:02:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Balanced Budget Amendment</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Constitution of the United States to provide for balanced budgets and elimination of the Federal indebtedness.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405939"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic and Commercial Law.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>See H.J.Res.103.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Economic and Commercial Law" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hj" number="103" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Balanced budgets"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Deficit financing"/>
		<term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
		<term name="Record votes"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1993--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Directs the Congress to assure that total fiscal year Federal outlays do not exceed receipts and that Federal indebtedness is eliminated. Presents a mandatory six fiscal year timetable for achieving a balanced budget. Permits waiver of these balanced budget requirements (not to exceed a ten percent receipt to outlay deficit) in times of national emergency, but only by roll call vote of three-fourths of the total membership of both Houses. Requires a surplus budget with total Government receipts exceeding outlays by two and one-half percent of Federal indebtedness during the 40 fiscal years following achievement of a balanced budget. Requires that any indebtedness ensuing after an emergency waiver shall be extinguished within three fiscal years of being incurred.

	</summary>
</bill>
