<bill session="103" type="hr" number="149" updated="2010-04-19T13:21:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-28T17:02:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-04-28T17:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="144"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 1578) to amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for the expedited consideration of certain proposed rescissions of budget authority.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403403"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01T22:46:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-52, by Mr. Derrick.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01T22:46:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1578 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for consideration of the bill in the Committee of theWhole. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part 1 of the report accompanying this resolution. Only those amendments printed in part 2 of the report shall be in order, to be offered and debatable in the manner specified and not subject to amendment except as specified. All points of order against the amendments shall be waived.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-04-01T22:46:00-05:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 27.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02T12:06:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1867-1875"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02T12:08:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02T14:11:00-05:00"><text>WITHDRAWAL OF MEASURE - Mr. Derrick, on behalf of the Committee on Rules, withdrew the resolution from floor consideration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T15:22:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2067-2078"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T15:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T16:33:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="144" datetime="1993-04-28T17:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 212 - 208 (Roll no. 144).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-04-28T17:02:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1578" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1578" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 1578 (amending the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 regarding rescissions of budget authority).

	</summary>
</bill>
