<bill session="103" type="hr" number="197" updated="2010-04-19T13:29:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-16T12:38:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-06-16T12:38:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="226"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 2333) to authorize appropriations for the Department of State, the United States Information Agency, and related agencies, to authorize appropriations for foreign assistance programs, and for other purposes, and for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 2404) to authorize appropriations for foreign assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400538"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15T21:08:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-132, by Mr. Hall (OH).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15T21:08:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2333 and H.R. 2404. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. For the consideration of H.R. 2333, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Foreign Affairs now printed in the bill, modified by the amendments printed in part 1 of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. For both H.R. 2333 and H.R. 2404, all specified amendments made in order by the rule must be offered in the order and mannner specified in the report accompanying the rule. For both H.R. 2333 and H.R. 2404, all points of order against the amendments made in order by the rule are ...</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-15T21:08:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 51.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16T10:57:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3599-3613"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16T10:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16T12:15:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="226" datetime="1993-06-16T12:38:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 294 - 129 (Roll no. 226).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16T12:38:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2333" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2333" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2404" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1993--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of: (1) H.R. 2333 (authorizing appropriations for the Department of State, the United States Information Agency, related agencies, and foreign assistance programs); and (2) H.R. 2404 (authorizing appropriations for foreign assistance programs).

	</summary>
</bill>
