<bill session="103" type="hr" number="190" updated="2010-04-19T13:28:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to reform the House, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300003"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400091" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400581" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412001" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400083" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400568" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300085" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1994-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1993-06-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8514-8515)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Botanical gardens"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congressional Record"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee chairmen"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
		<term name="Congressional information resources"/>
		<term name="Congressional publications"/>
		<term name="Congressional voting"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative amendments"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Libraries"/>
		<term name="Library of Congress"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="Political parties"/>
		<term name="Public meetings of legislative bodies"/>
		<term name="Record votes"/>
		<term name="Special days"/>
		<term name="Special months"/>
		<term name="Special weeks"/>
		<term name="Special years"/>
		<term name="Sunset legislation"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/9/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to make it out of order to consider any primary expense resolution for the second session of the 103d Congress until the Committee on House Administration has reported and the House has adopted a resolution establishing an overall ceiling for committee staff for that year. Limits the overall ceiling for committee staff for the second session of the 103d Congress to 75 percent of the staff employed at the end of the 102d Congress. Requires the membership of each standing, select, or conference committee and each subcommittee thereof, except for the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct and the bipartisan Subcommittee on Administrative Oversight of the Committee on House Administration, to reflect the ratio of majority to minority party Members of the House. Requires the ratio of the majority staff to minority staff of each committee to be the same as the ratio of majority party members to minority party members on that committee. Prohibits proxy voting by any committee or subcommittee member. Directs the Speaker to refer legislation initially to one committee as the committee of principal jurisdiction. Requires that at least one-half (currently one-third) of the members of a committee (except the Committees on Appropriations, Budget, and Ways and Means) must be present in order to constitute a quorum for taking any action other than the reporting of a measure or recommendation. Requires the chair to order a roll call vote on a motion to report any public bill or resolution at the request of a member of the committee. Limits a Member's service as chairman of a committee to three Congresses. Requires an affirmative vote of two-thirds of the members of a committee or subcommittee before all or part of its meeting can be closed to the public because of national security, personnel information, or a criminal investigation. Calls for a two-thirds' vote by the members of the Committee on Rules before provisions can be waived with respect to: (1) the report on a bill being made available to Members at least three days before it is considered; (2) filing and printing of a conference report and its accompanying statement in the Congressional Record at least three calendar days before the report is considered and a copy of them being made available to Members at least two hours before the consideration; and (3) reporting any rule or order that contains a nongermane amendment or reporting of an unauthorized appropriation in a general appropriation bill or an amendment thereto. Prohibits the Committee on Rules from reporting any rule or order preventing minority party members from offering at least four amendments to any appropriation bill or resolution or to a concurrent resolution on the budget. Makes it out of order to consider any bill or resolution providing for the designation of a commemorative day or other commemorative period. Requires the appropriate House committees with jurisdiction to report legislation requiring periodic reauthorization, for a maximum five-year period, of the: (1) Architect of the Capitol; (2) United States Botanical Garden; (3) Congressional Budget Office; (4) Government Printing Office; (5) General Accounting Office; (6) Library of Congress; (7) Copyright Royalty Tribunal; and (8) Office of Technology Assessment. Directs the Committee on House Administration to establish a toll-free (800) telephone number and a data base to provide public access to information on the substance and present status of each bill and resolution that is before the House.

	</summary>
</bill>
