<bill session="103" type="hr" number="198" updated="2010-04-19T13:29:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-14">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-07-14" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Requesting the President to furnish to the House of Representatives certain documents concerning the response of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to allegations of criminal conduct in the White House travel office.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400192"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402657" joined="1993-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="407676" joined="1993-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-06-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-07-14"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported Adversely.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20T12:52:00-04:00"><text>Reported adversely by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 103-183.</text></action>
		<calendar number="68" datetime="1993-07-20T12:52:00-04:00" calendar="House" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 68.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Campaign contributors"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive privilege"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Government and the press"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="Presidential records"/>
		<term name="Public corruption"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Travel"/>
		<term name="Travel agents"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/1993--Introduced.
Requests the President to provide to the House of Representatives certain documents related to the Federal Bureau of Investigation's (FBI) examination of allegations of criminal conduct in the White House travel office, including documents concerning: (1) authorization of the Associate Counsel to the President, William Kennedy, to initiate the examination; (2) the decision to retain the accounting firm of KPMG Peat Marwick to audit the travel office; (3) the FBI's decision to investigate the travel office; (4) actions taken against the travel office employees and their current status; (5) involvement of the FBI's Inspector in Charge of the Office of Public and Congressional Affairs, John Collingwood, in the investigation; (6) the press statement issued to confirm that the investigation was underway; (7) any interest of workers on, and contributors to, the President's campaign in, respectively, assuming control of, or obtaining contracts with, the travel office; (8) the employment of Penny Sample in the travel office, the employment status of Harry Thomason, and conflict of interest considerations; and (9) any consideration of the appointment of the Director of the FBI, William Sessions, to other Federal positions and any determination regarding his tenure as Director.

	</summary>
</bill>
