<bill session="103" type="hr" number="208" updated="2010-04-19T13:31:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-28T13:28:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-06-28T13:28:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="274"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving certain points of order against the bill (H.R. 2491) making appropriations for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and for sundry independent agencies, boards, commissions, corporations, and offices for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400378"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:51:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-159, by Ms. Slaughter.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24T18:51:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2491. Waiving all points of order against provision in the bill for failure to comply with clause 2 or 6 of rule XXI shall be waived, except as specified by this resolution. Where points of order are waived against only part of a paragraph, a point of order against matter in the balance of the paragraph may be applied only within the balance of the paragraph. Debate on the amendment specified in the report accompanying this resolution to be offered by Rep. Roemer, and on any amendments thereto, shall not exceed two hours. The amendments en bloc specified in the report to be offered by Rep. Bereuter and by Rep. Solomon may amend portions of the bill not yet read for amendment, shall be considered as read, and shall not be subject to a division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-24T18:51:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 59.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-06-28T12:21:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-28T12:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-28T13:07:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="274" datetime="1993-06-28T13:28:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 206 - 132 (Roll no. 274).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-06-28T13:28:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2491" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/24/1993--Introduced.
Waives certain points of order against the consideration of H.R. 2491 (Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development and independent agencies appropriations).

	</summary>
</bill>
