<bill session="103" type="hr" number="231" updated="2010-04-19T13:34:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the acceptance of travel and related expenses by Members of Congress.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400300"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Business and politics"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional travel"/>
		<term name="Food"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Political action committees"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1993--Introduced.
Amends rule XLIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit a Member of the House from accepting payment of travel and related expenses (food and beverage, lodging, entertainment, hospitality) with respect to attendance at any conference, meeting, or similar function from: (1) any corporation, company, firm, partnership, or other for-profit business enterprise, or any submit or affiliated organization thereof; (2) any organization or corporation that maintains a political action committee; (3) any organization or corporation registered under the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act of 1946 or any successor statute, or any organization or corporation that employs or retains a registered lobbyist. Makes provisions of this Act inapplicable to travel expenses provided: (1) by organizations described in the Internal Revenue Code under charitable contribution provisions; (2) in connection with a fact-finding event directly related to official duties in the Member's home State; or (3) in connection with a speaking engagement of an individual Member, at a meeting organized for that purpose or at which that individual is a principal speaker.

	</summary>
</bill>
