<bill session="103" type="hr" number="254" updated="2010-04-19T13:38:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-28T13:08:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-09-28T13:08:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="459"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for further consideration of the bill (H.R. 2401) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1994 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400143"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22T18:19:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-252, by Mr. Frost.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22T18:19:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2401. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. After the adoption of this resolution, the Speaker may declare the House resolved into the Committee of teh Whole House for the further consideration of the bill. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. No further amendments to the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be in order except the amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution and amendments en bloc described in sec. 3 of this resolution, to be offered in the order and manner specified.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-09-22T18:20:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 88.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-09-27T16:14:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7028-7034"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-27T16:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-27T17:05:00-04:00"><text>Further proceedings on the bill were postponed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T12:40:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7062-7064"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T12:40:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House continued with debate on the resolution which was pending as unfinished business from Monday, Sept. 27, 1993.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T12:47:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="459" datetime="1993-09-28T13:08:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 182 (Roll no. 459).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-09-28T13:08:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2401" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/1993--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the further consideration of H.R. 2401 (Department of Defense authorization of appropriations).

	</summary>
</bill>
