<bill session="103" type="hr" number="274" updated="2010-04-19T13:41:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-13T14:18:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-10-13T14:18:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 1804) to improve learning and teaching by providing a national framework for education reform; to promote the research, consensus building, and systemic changes needed to ensure equitable educational opportunities and high levels of educational achievement for all American students; to provide a framework for reauthorization of all Federal education programs; to promote the development and adoption of a voluntary national system of skill standards and certifications; and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403403"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T19:20:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-288, by Mr. Derrick.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-12T19:20:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1804 with 1 hour and 20 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of H.R. 3210. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-10-12T19:20:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 99.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13T13:46:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7735-7739"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13T13:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13T14:18:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-10-13T14:18:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-10-13T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1804" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/12/1993--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 1804 (national education reform).

	</summary>
</bill>
