<bill session="103" type="hr" number="293" updated="2010-04-19T13:44:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-08T16:20:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-11-08T16:20:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="548"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 170) directing the President pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution to remove United States Armed Forces from Somalia by January 31, 1994.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400538"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T17:50:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-328, by Mr. Hall (OH).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-04T17:50:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Con. Res. 170. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Foreign Affairs now printed in the concurrent resolution shall be considered as adopted. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the concurrent resolution, as so amended, to final adoption without intervening motion except for two amendments made in order by this resolution and a motion to recommit. Specified amendments are in order. If more than one of the amendments printed in the report is adopted, only the last amendment adopted shall be considered as finally adopted. The provisions of sec. 7 of the War Powers Resolution shall not apply during the remainder of the 1st session of the 103rd Congress with respect to Somalia.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-04T17:50:00-05:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 111.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08T13:39:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8903-8912"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08T13:39:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08T14:05:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08T14:05:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED ROLL CALL VOTE - At the conclusion of debate, the previous question was ordered and the question of agreeing to the resolution was put by the Chair. The Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered, but postponed until no earlier than 4 p.m. today.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08T16:01:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="548" datetime="1993-11-08T16:20:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 390 - 8 (Roll no. 548).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08T16:20:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hc" number="170" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/4/1993--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H. Con. Res. 170 (directing the President, pursuant to the War Powers Resolution, to remove U.S. armed forces from Somalia by January 31, 1994).

	</summary>
</bill>
