<bill session="103" type="hr" number="291" updated="2010-04-19T13:44:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that a Presidential commission should be established to investigate whether there has been any measurable depletion of stratospheric ozone beyond that caused by natural phenomena, whether it has been proven that the use of chloroflourocarbons damages stratospheric ozone, and whether the phaseout of chloroflourocarbons will have any effect on stratospheric ozone.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400113"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400398" joined="1994-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400197" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300151" joined="1994-11-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400609" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400567" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="1994-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="1994-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1994-08-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-11-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400504" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400083" joined="1994-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="1994-06-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-03"><committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Fluorocarbons"/>
		<term name="Ozone layer depletion"/>
		<term name="Presidential commissions"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/28/1993--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) a presidential commission should be established to investigate whether there has been any measurable depletion of stratospheric ozone beyond the seasonal variations caused by natural phenomena; (2) such commission should investigate whether it has been proven that the use of man-made chlorofluorocarbons damages stratospheric ozone and whether the phaseout of chlorofluorocarbons will have any effect on ozone levels in the stratosphere; and (3) the membership of the commission should be equally apportioned between representatives from the scientific community whose published research shows that chlorofluorocarbons have a negligible effect on ozone depletion and representatives whose research makes contrary claims.

	</summary>
</bill>
