<bill session="103" type="hr" number="331" updated="2010-04-19T13:50:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-16T12:12:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-03-16T12:12:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="59"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 103) proposing an amendment to the Constitution to provide for a balanced budget for the United States Government and for greater accountability in the enactment of tax legislation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400389"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="408556" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="406277" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="410084" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="1994-01-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E17)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24T10:05:00-05:00"><text>Motion to Discharge Committee filed by Mr. Stenholm. Petition No: 103-14.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24T18:22:00-05:00"><text>Motion to discharge the Committee on Rules filed by Mr. Stenholm. Assigned to the Discharge Calendar, Calendar No. 2.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-11T14:51:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Stenholm asked unanimous consent That business in order pursuant to Clause 3 of Rule XXVII on Monday, March 14, 1994, be dispensed with, and that it be in order on Wednesday, March 16 for Rep. Stenholm or his designee to call up H. Res. 331 for consideration under the same terms as if discharged from the Committee on Rules pursuant to Clause 3 of Rule XXVII, and, further, that the period of general debate provided for in H. Res. 331 be reduced to six hours, to be equally divided and controlled by Reps. Brooks, Fish, and Stenholm, or their designees. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16T11:04:00-05:00"><text>Considered by order of the House of March 11.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16T11:04:00-05:00"><text>Consideration initiated by order of the House of March 11.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1352-1357"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16T11:05:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16T11:48:00-05:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="59" datetime="1994-03-16T12:12:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 387 - 22 (Roll no. 59).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16T12:12:00-05:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hj" number="103" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Public finance"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/25/1994--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.J. Res. 103 (proposing an amendment to the Constitution to provide for a balanced budget).

	</summary>
</bill>
