<bill session="103" type="hr" number="356" updated="2010-04-19T13:54:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-09T19:24:00-05:00">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-02-09T19:24:00-05:00" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving a requirement of clause 4(b) of rule XI with respect to consideration of a certain resolution reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401310"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T19:24:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-421, by Mr. Beilenson.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09T19:24:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 3759. Waiving the requirement for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to a resolution reported on or before February 11, 1994, providing for the consideration or disposition of the bill, any amendment thereto, any conference report thereon, or any amendment thereto, any amendment reported in disagreement from a conference thereon.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-02-09T19:24:00-05:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 134.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3759" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/9/1994--Introduced.
Waives provisions of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives that require a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to resolutions reported by such Committee on or before February 11, 1994, to provide for the consideration or disposition of H.R. 3759 (emergency supplemental appropriations for FY 1994), including any amendment, conference report, or any amendment reported in disagreement from conference thereon.

	</summary>
</bill>
