<bill session="103" type="hr" number="36" updated="2010-04-19T13:04:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mandate for Change in the People's House</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend House Rules and direct certain committees to report legislation to reform the House, restore its committee system, and make the legislative process more rational, deliberative, representative and accountable.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407676"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="410147" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400596" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="1993-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400104" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400192" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400551" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="408553" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="404068" joined="1993-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="407669" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="411997" joined="1993-11-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H150)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H319)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
		<term name="Congressional legal counsel"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
		<term name="Congressional voting"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Legal services"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative amendments"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Oaths"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Mandate for Change in the People's House - Amends rule V of the House of Representatives to abolish the office of the Doorkeeper and incorporates the Doorkeeper's duties into those of the Sergeant-at-Arms. Amends rule X to require each standing committee to submit to the Committee on House Administration its oversight plans for that Congress. Prohibits the consideration of any committee expense resolution, or any amendment to it, if that committee has not submitted its oversight plans. Requires the membership of each committee or other subunit to reflect the ratio of majority to minority party Members of the House at the beginning of the Congress. Exempts the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico and the Delegates to the House in determining such party ratio. Revises limits on the number of subcommittees allowed to House committees. Prevents any member from serving on more than four House subcommittees at any one time. Amends rule XI to repeal the general permission, subject to certain conditions, for proxy voting by a member of any committee or subcommittee. Makes it out of order to consider any primary expense resolution unless the Committee on House Administration has reported and the House has adopted a resolution establishing an overall ceiling for House committee statutory and investigative staff personnel for that year. Provides that the overall ceiling for committee staff in a resolution reported by the committee or contained in any amendment for the 103d Congress and the first session of the 104th Congress shall not exceed 90 percent of the total committee staff personnel employed the previous session of the Congress. Applies committee expense resolution requirements and personnel ceilings to the Committees on Appropriations and Budget. Requires a report from the Committee on Appropriations accompanying any appropriation bill to list all appropriations contained in the bill for any expenditure not previously authorized by law. Amends rule XXI to prohibit the consideration in the House of any bill or joint resolution which authorizes enactment of new budget authority for a fiscal year unless such measure is reported in the House on or before May 15 preceding the beginning of such fiscal year. Amends rule XLIII to require a specified oath to be administered to Members or House employees before they are granted access to classified information. Directs the House Committees on Rules and on Government Operations by a certain date to report legislation granting the President enhanced rescission authority with respect to any discretionary budget authority not authorized by law. Directs the Joint Committee on the Organization of Congress to report to the House on the feasibility of converting to a biennial budget-appropriations process and corresponding multiyear authorizations. Provides for a study of the House and Senate committees on realignment of Committee jurisdictions. Abolishes specified select committees. Directs the Committee on House Administration to report a resolution providing for the consideration of a Federal election and campaign reform bill under an open amendment process. Amends rule VI to create a Chief Financial Officer of the House. Establishes the Office of the General Counsel in the House to provide legal assistance to Members and employees of the House on matters directly related to their duties, with specified exceptions. Repeals certain amendments to the Rules of the House of the 102d Congress.

	</summary>
</bill>
