<bill session="103" type="hr" number="407" updated="2010-04-19T14:02:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 3266) to provide for automatic downward adjustments in the discretionary spending limits for fiscal year 1994 set forth in the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 equal to the amount of rescissions contained in this Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411997"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="1994-04-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2589)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2845)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2944)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3017)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04T18:45:00-04:00"><text>Motion to Discharge Committee filed by Mr. Zeliff. Petition No: 103-16.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3061)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3232)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3758)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3895)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4100-4101, E1084, E1113-1114)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4171)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5472-5473)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/1994--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 3266 (providing for automatic downward adjustments in the discretionary spending limits for FY 1994 equal to specified rescissions).

	</summary>
</bill>
