<bill session="103" type="hr" number="419" updated="2011-02-25T20:08:54-05:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">House Administration Reform Resolution of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide for certain changes in the bipartisan administrative oversight of House functions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407676"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="404587" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400401" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="406863" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400117" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400568" joined="1994-05-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional information resources"/>
		<term name="Congressional leadership"/>
		<term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Democratic Party"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
		<term name="Printing"/>
		<term name="Republican Party"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Teleconferencing"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/5/1994--Introduced.
House Administration Reform Resolution of 1994 - Transfers specified functions and entities to the Director of Non-Legislative and Financial Services of the House of Representatives. Requires the House Information Systems (HIS), upon transfer to the Director, to be responsible for video teleconferencing, INTERNET access, and related technology services. Directs the Committee on House Administration (Committee) to provide for implementation of recommendations contained in a certain report of the House Task Force on Printing (regarding review of the majority and minority print facilities), provided that such operations are used only for official purposes and are eliminated as soon as practicable or as otherwise directed by the House Subcommittee on Administrative Oversight (Subcommittee). Transfers such operations to the Director. Provides for the elimination of such operations by January 22, 1997. Transfers responsibility for the operation of the Democratic and Republican cloakrooms to the Speaker of the House and the Republican leader, respectively. Amends Rule VI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the Director to report to the Subcommittee on all matters (currently, the Director is subject to the policy direction and oversight of the Committee) and makes the Director responsible for simultaneous bipartisan notification of subcommittee members. Requires the Director to review, on a continuing basis, the implementation of employment standards and to report any violation to the Subcommittee. Makes employment and other administrative decisions of the Director final unless otherwise directed by a majority of Subcommittee members. Directs the Committee to conduct a comprehensive, bipartisan review of Committee regulations and eliminate ambiguities and obsolete provisions. Requires the Subcommittee to provide for transfers of functions and entities to the Director as necessary for the improvement of non-legislative and financial services in the House. Deems any action taken by the Subcommittee with regard to any functions and entities within its jurisdiction to be taken on behalf of the full committee, except in the case of proposals to report to the House. Expresses the sense of the House that the changes in public law necessary to delineate the authorities affected by this resolution should be enacted as soon as possible.

	</summary>
</bill>
