<bill session="103" type="hr" number="436" updated="2010-04-19T14:06:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to investigate allegations pertaining to the House Post Office.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406431"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400197" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="1994-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="1994-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H3956)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-24T21:05:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to rule IX of the Rules of the House, Mr. Klug gave formal notice of his intention to call up H. Res. 436 as a privileged resolution within two legislative days.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4143)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26T17:07:00-04:00"><text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Klug notified the House formally of his intention to call up the privileged resolution, H. Res. 436, on either Wednesday, June 8, 1994, or Thursday, June 9, 1994. Mr. Klug further asked unanimous consent that the text of the resolution be printed in the Congressional Record of today as if read. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Campaign funds"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Embezzlement"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="Postage stamps"/>
		<term name="Postal service"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/1994--Introduced.
Instructs the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to: (1) immediately investigate any alleged violation by any Member, officer, or employee of the House of Representatives of the Code of Official Conduct or of any other standard of conduct that is related to activities described by, or referred to in, documents that it received on July 22, 1992, from the Committee on House Administration pertaining to the Committee's Task Force to Investigate the Operation and Management of the House Post Office investigation; (2) report to the House periodically on the status of this investigation; and (3) report to the House by September 30, 1994, on its findings of fact and recommendations on possible disciplinary actions.

	</summary>
</bill>
