<bill session="103" type="hr" number="443" updated="2010-04-19T14:07:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-25T15:40:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-05-25T15:40:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="203"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 4426) making appropriations for foreign operations, export financing, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1995.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400538"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25T13:27:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4426 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit. Waiving all points of order against the bill and against its consideration. Measure will be read by section. Specified amendments are in order. After general debate, the pending question shall be the adoption of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Appropriations now printed in the bill. The amendment shall be debatable for 10 minutes. All points of order against the amendment and against the bill, if amended, shall be waived. No further amendment to the bill shall be in order except as specified by the report accompanying this resolution, and debatable as specified. All points of order against said amendments shall be waived. The chairman of the Committee of the Whole may postpone a request for a recorded vote on any amendme...</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25T14:00:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-530, by Mr. Hall (OH).</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-05-25T14:01:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 169.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25T14:01:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4022-4032"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25T14:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25T15:21:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 191 (Roll no. 202).</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="203" datetime="1994-05-25T15:40:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 181 (Roll no. 203).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25T15:40:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4426" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1994--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.R. 4426 (making FY 1995 appropriations for foreign operations, export financing, and related programs).

	</summary>
</bill>
