<bill session="103" type="hr" number="511" updated="2010-04-19T14:18:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayers' Right to Know Resolution</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a rollcall vote on passage of any measure making appropriations, providing revenue, or increasing the statutory limit on the public debt, and in certain other instances.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300085"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Balanced budgets"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Congressional voting"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
		<term name="Record votes"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/8/1994--Introduced.
Taxpayer's Right to Know Resolution - Amends rule XV of the Rules of the House of Representatives to make it out of order in the House or in the Committee of the Whole to pass or adopt except by a rollcall vote, a quorum being present, and the yeas and nays being considered as ordered any bill, joint resolution, or conference report: (1) making or continuing an appropriation; (2) increasing the statutory limit on the public debt; (3) amending the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 or changing the congressional budget process; (4) providing revenue; (5) establishing, extending, or raising any user fee; or (6) authorizing the enactment of new budget authority. Makes it out of order in any committee to report such legislation except by a rollcall vote, approved by a majority of the members voting, a quorum being present.

	</summary>
</bill>
