<bill session="103" type="hr" number="526" updated="2010-04-19T14:20:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-21T17:02:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-08-21T17:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="414"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving points of order against a further conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 3355) to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to allow grants to increase police presence, to expand and improve cooperative efforts between law enforcement agencies and members of the community to address crime and disorder problems, and other wise to enhance public safety.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403403"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-21T15:00:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-713, by Mr. Derrick.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-21T15:00:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 3355 with 1 hour and 20 minutes of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit. Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider a further conference report to accompany the bill. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration shall be waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-08-21T15:02:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 217.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-08-21T15:26:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8957-8968"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-21T15:29:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-21T16:44:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="414" datetime="1994-08-21T17:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 189 (Roll no. 414).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-08-21T17:02:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3355" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/21/1994--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of a further conference report to accompany H.R. 3355 (crime control).

	</summary>
</bill>
