<bill session="103" type="hr" number="549" updated="2010-04-19T14:24:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should work to achieve a clearly defined agreement which establishes a multilateral export control regime to stem the proliferation of militarily critical products, technology, and advanced strategic weapons to rogue regimes that jeopardize international peace and the national security of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400536"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1960)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-11"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Policy, Trade and Environment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-11"><committee name="House Committee on Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Security, International Organizations and Human Rights.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy, Trade, and Environment" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Security, International Organizations, and Human Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Advanced weapons"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Iran"/>
		<term name="Iraq"/>
		<term name="Libya"/>
		<term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="North Korea"/>
		<term name="Peace"/>
		<term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Weapons systems"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/1994--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the President should work to achieve a clearly defined agreement which establishes a multilateral export control regime to stem the proliferation of militarily critical products and technology and advanced strategic weapons to rogue regimes that jeopardize international peace and the national security of the United States and its allies; and (2) no country should qualify for membership unless it has begun to implement effective export controls, adheres to the control list and guidelines of the existing multilateral regimes, adheres to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons and the existing biological and chemical weapons conventions, and has stopped providing advanced strategic weapons to Iran, Iraq, Libya, and North Korea.

	</summary>
</bill>
