<bill session="103" type="hr" number="578" updated="2010-04-19T14:29:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to apply certain laws to the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400600"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T20:24:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 579 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 578. Upon the adoption of this resolution, H. Res. 578 shall be considered to be also adopted.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T21:33:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 579 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T21:33:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 579, H. Res. 578 is considered passed House.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="579" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hr" number="579" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Age and employment"/>
		<term name="Age discrimination"/>
		<term name="Aged"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Civil rights"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Conflict of interests"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional Record"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional privileges and immunities"/>
		<term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Demography"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employee selection"/>
		<term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
		<term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grievance procedures"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Older workers"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Parental leave"/>
		<term name="Party affiliation"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Polygraphs"/>
		<term name="Promotions"/>
		<term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
		<term name="Public records"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of the mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of the physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Sick leave"/>
		<term name="Statistics"/>
		<term name="Subpoena"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
		<term name="Vital statistics"/>
		<term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to add rule LII to establish an Office of Compliance to apply the following laws to the House of Representatives: (1) the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938; (2) Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964; (3) the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990; (4) the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967; (5) Titles I and V of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993; (6) the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970; (7) specified provisions of Federal law relating to Federal labor-management relations; (8) the Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (except with respect to the Capitol Police); (9) the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act; and (10) the Rehabilitation Act of 1973. Applies any provision of Federal law that relates to the terms and conditions of employment of employees to the House. Prohibits lobbyists, Members of Congress, and congressional employees from being on the Office Board of Directors. Requires the Board of Directors to study and report to the House on how the laws under rule LII should apply. Directs the Office to: (1) carry out a program of education for House Members and other House employing authorities respecting such laws and a program to inform individuals of their rights; (2) compile specified statistics, including those on the use of the Office by House employees, reasons for contact, and complaints filed; and (3) develop a system for the collection of demographic data respecting the composition of House employees and for collection of information on employment practices. Sets forth procedures for consideration of alleged violations of such laws consisting of the following steps: (1) counseling; (2) mediation; and (3) formal complaint and hearing by a hearing board. Declares that any intimidation of, or reprisal against, any House employee because of the exercise of a right under this Act constitutes an unlawful employment practice that may be remedied in the same manner under this Act as a violation of a law made applicable under rule LII. Directs the Office to study and report to the House on the application to the House of the Freedom of Information Act and the Privacy Act of 1974. Requires the House General Counsel to study further changes in House rules to provide House employees the ability to bring civil actions in Federal district court for alleged violations that relate to terms and conditions of employment until the statutory provisions contained in H.R. 4822, as passed by the House, are enacted.

	</summary>
</bill>
