<bill session="103" type="hr" number="570" updated="2010-04-19T14:27:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-06T17:20:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-10-06T17:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="495"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for further consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 416) providing limited authorization for the participation of United States Armed Forces in the multinational force in Haiti and providing for the prompt withdrawal of United States Forces from Haiti.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400538"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06T00:13:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 103-840, by Mr. Hall (OH).</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06T00:13:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 416 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the further consideration of the joint resolution in the Committee of the Whole. Upon adoption of this resolution all time for general debate under terms of the previous special order shall be considered as expired, and an additional period of 2 hours shall be available for general debate. Specified amendments are in order. The amendments printed in part one of the report accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. No further amendment shall be in order except those printed in part 2 of said report, if offered in the order and manner specified, and not subject to further amendment except as specified, and debatable for one hour each. All point...</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-10-06T00:14:00-04:00"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 244.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06T15:53:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11034-11037, H11059-11065"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06T15:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06T16:59:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="495" datetime="1994-10-06T17:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 182 (Roll no. 495).</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06T17:20:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="hj" number="416" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule for the further consideration of H.J. Res. 416 (U.S. armed forces' participation in the multinational force in Haiti).

	</summary>
</bill>
