<bill session="103" type="hr" number="588" updated="2010-04-19T14:30:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-11-29">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-11-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-11-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide for transition salary continuation for certain committee staff.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407772"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-11-29"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-11-29"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/29/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to direct the Clerk of the House to notify the Committee on House Administration of the name of each displaced staff member (i.e., an individual employed by a committee or subcommittee for at least 183 days whose service as a House employee is terminated solely and directly as a result of a change in the political party of the chairman or ranking minority member of a committee). Directs that each displaced staff member continue to be paid for a period not to exceed 60 days following the staff member's date of termination or until the staff member becomes otherwise gainfully employed. Specifies that a statement in writing by any such employee that he or she was not gainfully employed during the period for which payment is claimed shall be accepted as prima facie evidence that he or she was not so employed. Makes funds necessary to carry out this Act available from the contingent fund of the House.

	</summary>
</bill>
