<bill session="103" type="s" number="1001" updated="2012-07-17T05:00:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Sanctions Enforcement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen United States laws to enforce economic embargoes against foreign countries pursuant to a declaration of national emergency or United Nations Security Council measures, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6273)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Aviation agreements"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Embargo"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Libya"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Trading with the enemy"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
International Sanctions Enforcement Act of 1993 - Authorizes the President to prohibit U.S. persons from procuring, importing, selling, or exporting goods or services to or from any foreign person who has knowingly violated United Nations Security Council Resolution 748 imposing sanctions against Libya. Urges the President to initiate consultations with foreign governments with jurisdiction over such persons with respect to the imposition of sanctions. Requires the President to impose the sanctions unless he certifies to the Congress that a government has taken actions to terminate the involvement of a person in such activities. Exempts the procurement of vital defense articles by the U.S. Government and medical or other humanitarian items from sanctions under this Act. Aplies sanctions for at least 12 months and terminates sanctions only if the President certifies to the Congress that a person has ceased to, and will not in the future, violate the Resolution. Permits the President to waive sanctions after such period if he certifies to the Congress that continued imposition would have a serious adverse effect on U.S. interests. Applies enforcement authorities and penalty provisions of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to sanctions and violations under this Act. Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act to authorize the issuance of residence visas for protection purposes to up to 25 aliens (per fiscal year) who furnish information concerning acts of international terrorism against U.S. persons or property. Increases criminal penalties for the misuse of passports. Directs the President to certify to the Congress whenever he determines that a country is not complying with the Resolution. Suspends service of such countries' air carriers to or from the United States and authorizes the revocation of their rights to engage in air transportation to or from the United States. Amends the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to regulate or prohibit the importation or exportation of informational materials containing technical or commercial data of value to the economy of a foreign country whose transactions are otherwise regulated or prohibited. Increases the amount of civil penalties authorized for violations of such Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
