<bill session="103" type="s" number="1016" updated="2012-07-17T05:45:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Grandparents Raising Grandchildren Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to recognize grandparents who serve as the primary caregivers to their grandchildren and to provide assistance to such grandparents under certain programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402727"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6452-6453)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Caregivers"/>
		<term name="Census"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Custody of children"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Foster home care"/>
		<term name="Grandparents"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Households"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Old age assistance"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Population statistics"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1993--Introduced.
Grandparents Raising Grandchildren Assistance Act of 1993 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to qualify grandchildren for social security benefits based only on their dependency on social security recipients. Sets special rules if one of a grandchild's natural or adoptive parents is living. Provides for suspension of such benefits in the event the grandchild reunites with a natural or adoptive parent. Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of SSA title IV to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a model procedure for States to use in notifying relatives before the placement of a child in foster care. Directs the Secretary, if the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) has not done so by a specified deadline, to develop model standards for the coverage of dependents under health insurance policies. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to expand the data collection efforts of the Bureau of the Census to enable it to collect statistically significant data on the growing trend of grandparents who are the primary caregivers for their grandchildren. Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to direct the Commissioner on Aging to make grants to or enter contracts with one eligible entity to establish and operate the National Resource Center for Grandparents to serve as a central source of information and assistance to older individuals who: (1) raise their grandchildren; (2) encounter problems obtaining visitation access to their grandchildren; or (3) need financial, legal, emotional, or informational assistance regarding their relationship with their grandchildren.

	</summary>
</bill>
