<bill session="103" type="s" number="1024" updated="2012-07-17T05:15:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Innovation and Coastal Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a demonstration program to develop new techniques to prevent coastal erosion and preserve shorelines.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401709"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6466-6467)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Beach erosion"/>
		<term name="Flood damage"/>
		<term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
		<term name="Flood insurance"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Insurance rates"/>
		<term name="Shore protection"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1993--Introduced.
Local Innovation and Coastal Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to make grants ($500,000 maximum with matching fund requirements) from the Coastal Erosion Control Fund (established by this Act) to States and qualifying communities for an erosion mitigation demonstration program. Gives grant priority to projects that: (1) have multiple location applicability; (2) broaden existing erosion control techniques; or (3) rely on natural designs rather than structural alterations. Authorizes appropriations. Establishes in the Treasury the Coastal Erosion Control Fund. Requires the Director to: (1) assess an annual five-dollar flood insurance premium mitigation surcharge to be paid into such Fund, unless the Fund's balance exceeds $15 million; (2) evaluate and publish a list of the most effective erosion mitigation measures; and (3) provide flood insurance rate incentives for erosion mitigation efforts.

	</summary>
</bill>
