<bill session="103" type="s" number="1025" updated="2012-07-17T05:46:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Manufacturers' Renewal and Training Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote technology transfer to small manufacturers by providing for engineering students to work as interns with small manufacturers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300026"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404219" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6468-6469)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Employment subsidies"/>
		<term name="Engineering"/>
		<term name="Engineers"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Mathematics"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Scientific education"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology policy"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Women engineers"/>
		<term name="Women's education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1993--Introduced.
Small Manufacturers' Renewal and Training Act of 1993 - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to carry out the Small Manufacturers Renewal and Training Program for awarding grants to manufacturing outreach centers to give undergraduate engineering students the opportunity to work as interns with small manufacturing companies. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) eligible entities; (2) grant duration and renewal; (3) grant priorities; and (4) funding limitations. Requires the: (1) Director to solicit and evaluate grant proposals from such centers, collect information regarding program performance, and coordinate Program activities with other Federal programs for manufacturing and technology extension; and (2) Secretary of Commerce to establish criteria for evaluating grant proposals. Sets forth provisions regarding the respective roles of manufacturing outreach centers, host companies, and interns in the Program. Requires the Director to solicit qualified engineering students from underrepresented groups for participation in the Program. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
