<bill session="103" type="s" number="1021" updated="2012-07-17T05:23:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Free Exercise of Religion Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assure religious freedom to Native Americans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403962" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1993-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6456-6457)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-10"><committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Eagles"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hawaiians"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Peyote"/>
		<term name="Plants"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Protection of Sacred Sites Title II: Traditional Use of Peyote Title III: Prisoners' Rights Title IV: Religious Use of Eagles and Other Animals and Plants Title V: Jurisdiction and Remedies Title VI: Miscellaneous Native American Free Exercise of Religion Act of 1993 - Title I: Protection of Sacred Sites - Requires Federal agencies to plan and manage their lands in ways that are consistent with Native American religious sites. Grants access to religious sites on Federal lands to Native American practitioners at all times, unless the President determines that national security interests are directly affected. Provides for the temporary closing of such areas to general public use in order to protect the privacy of religious or cultural activities. Directs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to identify lands with which an Indian tribe has historic or religious ties. Requires a Federal agency, before undertaking any activities on such land, to notify the Secretary and the affected tribe and refrain from such activities until the matter is resolved. (Sets forth a special rule for the Indian pueblos of New Mexico.) Provides for tribal authority over Native American religious sites on Indian lands. Establishes criminal sanctions for damaging Native American religious sites on Federal land. Title II: Traditional Use of Peyote - States that: (1) the use, possession, or transportation by an Indian of peyote for bona fide ceremonial use in a Native American religious activity is lawful and shall not be prohibited by the Federal Government or any State; (2) such activity may be reasonably regulated; and (3) specified provisions of Texas law shall remain applicable to such activity. Title III: Prisoners' Rights - Grants Native American prisoners access to traditional religious leaders, ceremonial materials, and religious facilities. Directs the Attorney General to establish the Commission on the Religious Freedom of Native American Prisoners. Title IV: Religious Use of Eagles and Other Animals and Plants - Requires the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to: (1) develop a plan for access to eagles and other animals and plants for use in Native American religious activities; and (2) consult with Regional Advisory Councils (established by this Act) in such matters. Title V: Jurisdiction and Remedies - Grants jurisdiction to U.S. district courts for actions to enforce the provisions of this Act. Title VI: Miscellaneous - Sets forth miscellaneous provisions.

	</summary>
</bill>
