<bill session="103" type="s" number="1035" updated="2012-07-17T04:39:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300082"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-05-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-05-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Civil procedure"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Gambling"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Oklahoma"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Video games"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/26/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to revise conditions for regulation of Class II and Class III gaming activities on Indian lands. Limits gaming to the specific forms of, and methods of play for, those gaming activities expressly authorized by the law of the State. Revises provisions with respect to Class II licensing of persons other than Indian tribes. Excludes video bingo from the definition of Class II gaming. Includes video bingo, and any other forms of electronic video games or devices, as well as slot machines, within the definition of Class III gaming. Shifts the burden of proof from a State to the United States in a compact negotiation action initiated by the United States on behalf of a tribe. Sets forth restrictions with respect to gaming on after-acquired lands (with a special provison for lands in Oklahoma). Subjects Indian gaming establishments to specified reporting and recordkeeping requirements. Requires the Attorney General to conduct specified background investigations of directors, financial backers, and key employees of Class III establishments. Amends Federal law to apply State gambling laws to Indian lands to the same extent that they apply to non-Indian lands. Grants the United States exclusive jurisdiction over related criminal prosecutions, with specified exceptions.

	</summary>
</bill>
