<bill session="103" type="s" number="103" updated="2012-07-17T06:05:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional and Presidential Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to fully apply the rights and protections of Federal civil rights and labor laws to employment by Congress.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300079"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1993-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1993-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="406256" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400558" joined="1993-07-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S541)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-29"><committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/><text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Age and employment"/>
		<term name="Age discrimination"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional ethics"/>
		<term name="Congressional privileges and immunities"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
		<term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Equal pay for equal work"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Older workers"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Senate"/>
		<term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Congressional and Presidential Accountability Act - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1991 to require Senate employees to be free from acts that: (1) are unlawful under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938; (2) constitute unfair labor practices under the National Labor Relations Act; or (3) constitute violations of duties and standards under the Occupational Health and Safety Act; and (4) are determined applicable to Senate employment. Requires the promulgation of rules to apply the rights and protections of such Acts to the Senate. Grants specified investigative powers authorized under such Acts, the Civil Rights Act of 1964, and the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to the Director of the Office of Senate Fair Employment Practices. Prescribes civil penalties, damages, or other remedies for violations concerning Senate employees under specified Acts. Authorizes aggrieved Senate employees and presidential appointees to file civil actions against the head of the employing office or the unit of the executive branch in which they are employed, as appropriate. Applies specified provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Revised Statutes, the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the National Labor Relations Act, or the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to such actions, based on the type of violation. Removes provisions concerning the standard of review to be used by courts and the application of Federal judicial review procedures to such actions. Authorizes presidential appointees to file complaints alleging violations with the Department of Labor, the National Labor Relations Board, or the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, as appropriate. Incorporates rule LI (employment practices) of the Rules of the House of Representatives into the Civil Rights Act of 1991. Revises rule LI to set forth requirements for the House that are parallel to those established for the Senate under this Act. Amends the Revised Statutes to prohibit a complainant in an employment discrimination action from recovering punitive damages against a government, government agency, or political subdivision except in accordance with title III of the Civil Rights Act (Government employee rights). (Current law prohibits recovery without such exception.)

	</summary>
</bill>
