<bill session="103" type="s" number="1045" updated="2012-07-17T05:19:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Self-Employment Opportunity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permit States to establish programs using unemployment funds to assist unemployed individuals in becoming self-employed.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411818"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="407786" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-05-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6759-6760)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s906"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/27/1993--Introduced.
Self-Employment Opportunity Act - Allows the Secretary of Labor to authorize a State self-employment program upon the State's application to participate and the Secretary's determination that the State program: (1) does not cost the Unemployment Trust Fund more than otherwise; (2) provides unemployment benefits only to those who would otherwise be entitled under State law; (3) targets those who have been permanently separated from or do not expect to be recalled to their jobs; (4) makes benefits available only to those likely to receive unemployment compensation for the maximum number of weeks under State law; (5) has an aggregate number of individuals receiving benefits which at no time exceeds five percent of the number receiving compensation under State law. Allows a State, if the Secretary authorizes its self-employment program, to use the State unemployment fund to provide cash unemployment benefits, exclusive of administrative expenses, to participants to help them become self-employed.

	</summary>
</bill>
