<bill session="103" type="s" number="1058" updated="2012-07-17T05:12:05-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Real Jobs for America Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create real jobs in America through investment and savings incentives, to pay for such incentives by decreasing Federal spending, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400565"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="411271" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1993-05-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6840-6841, S6846-6848)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Accounting"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Automobile parts"/>
		<term name="Boats and boating"/>
		<term name="Business losses"/>
		<term name="Capital gains tax"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="College costs"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Copyright royalties"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense procurement"/>
		<term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Eastern Europe"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational finance"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Employment tax credits"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid programs"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Fur trade"/>
		<term name="General aviation aircraft"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Helium"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Housing finance"/>
		<term name="Hurricanes"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
		<term name="Jewelry trade"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Leave of absence"/>
		<term name="Legal Services Corporation"/>
		<term name="Legal services"/>
		<term name="Louisiana"/>
		<term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Privatization"/>
		<term name="Real estate business"/>
		<term name="Rental housing"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
		<term name="Storms"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax exemption"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transportation and the physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/28/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Investment and Savings Incentives Subtitle A: Reductions in Cost of Capital and Tax Penalties on Investment Subtitle B: Investment in Business Subtitle C: Increased Savings Through Individual Retirement Accounts Subtitle D: Incentives for Private Businesses to Hire New Employees Title II: Deficit Reductions Subtitle A: Extension of the Caps on Discretionary Spending Subtitle B: Spending Cuts Real Jobs for America Act of 1993 - Title I: Investment and Savings Incentives - Subtitle A: Reductions in Cost of Capital and Tax Penalties on Investment - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require indexing of certain assets (corporate stock, certain tangible property, and a principal residence) that have been held for more than three years at the time of sale or other transfer, solely for the purpose of determining gain or loss. Modifies the method of determining the depreciation deduction for certain personal property placed in service after June 30, 1993. Eliminates the depreciation adjustment for computing adjusted current earnings for such property. Subtitle B: Investment in Small Business - Increases the dollar limitation, with an inflation adjustment, on the deduction for expensing depreciable business assets. Subtitle C: Increased Savings Through Individual Retirement Accounts - Removes the limitation on the retirement savings deduction for active participants in certain pension plans. Provides a cost-of-living adjustment for such deduction. Allows individuals to establish individual retirement plus accounts with tax treatment similar to that for individual retirement plans. Makes contributions to such accounts nondeductible. Allows distributions from certain retirement plans without penalty to purchase first homes, pay higher education expenses and financially devastating medical expenses, and assist certain unemployed individuals. Treats certain disaster victims as first-time homebuyers. Requires contributions to an individual retirement plan (other than an individual retirement plus account) to be held for five years prior to distribution. Subtitle D: Incentives for Private Businesses to Hire New Employees - Allows employers a refundable credit for the employment taxes paid on the qualified wages of new employees hired during July 1, 1993, and June 30, 1994. Repeals the luxury excise tax on passenger vehicles, boats, aircraft, jewelry, and furs. Exempts from such tax parts for accessories installed for use on passenger vehicles by disabled individuals. Provides for the treatment of rental and nonrental real estate activities under the limitation on losses from passive activities. Title II: Deficit Reductions - Subtitle A: Extension of the Caps on Discretionary Spending - Reduces discretionary spending limits for the defense, international, and domestic categories for FY 1993 through 1995. Establishes the level of such limits for FY 1996 through 1998. Subtitle B: Spending Cuts - Rescinds a specified amount of budgetary resources for Federal administrative expenses. Eliminates the lump sum retirement benefit for Federal employees unless such employees have a life-threatening affliction or other critical medical condition. Requires employers to report group health plan information on wage forms. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a data bank for the collection of information on Medicare secondary payer situations and health insurance information. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the reductions in discretionary spending required by this Act be achieved by reducing, modifying, eliminating, closing, or terminating specified Federal programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
