<bill session="103" type="s" number="1069" updated="2012-07-17T04:40:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children Registration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require any person who is convicted of a State criminal offense against a victim who is a minor to register a current address with law enforcement officials of the State for 10 years after release from prison, parole, or supervision.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403669"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6863-6864)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="324" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Child molesting"/>
		<term name="Child pornography"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Ex-offenders"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Personnel records"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Prostitution"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/28/1993--Introduced.
Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children Registration Act - Directs the Attorney General to establish guidelines for State programs requiring persons convicted of a criminal offense against a minor to register a current address with a designated State law enforcement agency for ten years after release from prison, parole, or being placed on supervised release. Sets forth requirements for an approved State registration program, including fingerprint cards and entry of information into the State law enforcement system and National Crime Information Center computer networks. Provides that the information provided under this Act is private and may be used for law enforcement purposes, including confidential background checks by child care service providers. Specifies that the allocation of Bureau of Justice Assistance grant funds under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 received by a State not complying with the provisions of this Act within three years shall be reduced by 25 percent. Requires such unallocated funds to be reallocated to the States in compliance with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
