<bill session="103" type="s" number="1074" updated="2012-07-17T06:13:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Environmental Trade Development Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the development and implementation of a national strategy to encourage and promote opportunities for the United States private sector to provide environmentally sound technology, goods, and services (especially source reduction and energy efficiency technology, goods, and services) to the global market, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-05-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6870-6872, S6874)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="American technical assistance"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Foreign service"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Peace Corps"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Sustainable development"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
		<term name="Waste reduction"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/28/1993--Introduced.
National Environmental Trade Development Act of 1993 - Directs the President to coordinate Federal export promotion programs to ensure implementation of the national strategy to increase environmental exports developed under this Act by the Environmental Trade Promotion Council (the Council). Directs the Secretary of Commerce (the Secretary) to: (1) ensure that Department of Commerce programs and policies implement such strategy; (2) establish an environmental technology export promotion one-stop shop at the Trade Information Center; and (3) ensure that Federal offices, including those of the Foreign Commercial Service, which function as one-stop shops for U.S. exporters, also function as environmental technology export promotion one-stop shops. Directs the President to establish an Environmental Trade Promotion Council to develop a national strategy and implementation plan to increase exports of environmental technology, goods, and services (especially in source reduction and energy efficiency). Prescribes guidelines for the establishment of Regional Environmental Business and Technology Cooperation Centers. Authorizes the Secretary to make matching grants to the Centers. Amends the Peace Corps Act to establish the Senior Environmental Service Corps to provide to requesting countries volunteers skilled in environmental management and technology (especially source reduction and energy efficiency), sustainable development, and coastal zone management. Authorizes the Secretary to establish American Business Centers, including Environmental Business Centers, in countries that offer new market possibilities for the export of U.S. environmental technology, goods, and services (especially in source reduction and energy efficiency). Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
