<bill session="103" type="s" number="1086" updated="2012-07-17T05:55:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Telecommunications Infrastructure Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to foster the further development of the Nation's telecommunications infrastructure through the enhancement of competition, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403171"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-06-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7023-7024)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Subcommittee on Communications. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-08"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Subcommittee on Communications. Hearings concluded. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-787.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="Communications" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Cable television"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Corporate mergers"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Electronic publishing"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
		<term name="Radio"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Rural conditions"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Telephone rates"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/9/1993--Introduced.
Telecommunications Infrastructure Act of 1993 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit State or local legal requirements from limiting, in a manner inconsistent with Federal legal requirements, the ability of any entity to provide interstate or intrastate telecommunications services. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to prescribe regulations requiring telecommunications carriers to provide to any entity seeking to provide telecommunications or information services, on reasonable terms and conditions: (1) interconnection to the carrier's telecommunications facilities at any technically feasible point within the carrier's network; (2) nondiscriminatory access to specified facilities, information, and network functions; and (3) telecommunications services and network functions without restrictions on the resale or sharing of such services and functions. Requires: (1) all telecommunications carriers to contribute to, and the States to ensure, the preservation and advancement of universal service; and (2) the States and the FCC to have as their goal directly assisting individuals or entities that cannot afford the cost of telecommunications service or equipment. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) telecommunications number portability; (2) reciprocal compensation agreements; (3) regulatory flexibility for competitive services; and (4) rules for foreign ownership. Directs the FCC to take action if State regulatory authorities fail to ensure that telecommunications carriers provide consumers in rural and noncompetitive markets with access to high quality telecommunications network facilities and capabilities meeting specified requirements. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) State regulatory incentives; and (2) network standards and planning. Revises provisions of such Act with respect to restrictions on ownership and control of cable television systems by telephone companies to prohibit a local exchange carrier or affiliate from: (1) acquiring more than a five percent interest in any cable system that is providing service within the carrier's telephone exchange service area and is owned by an unaffiliated person; or (2) entering into any joint venture or partnership with such cable system. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) interexchange services associated with cable service and relating to cellular mobile radio services; (2) requirements for the provision of information services by a Bell Telephone Company or an affiliate; (3) privacy of customer proprietary network information; and (4) limitations on State regulation of the offering of information services.

	</summary>
</bill>
