<bill session="103" type="s" number="1099" updated="2012-07-17T04:14:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the Department of State to carry out its authorities and responsibilities in the conduct of foreign affairs during the fiscal years 1994 and 1995, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7221, S7228-7234)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Afghanistan"/>
		<term name="Air piracy"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Arab countries"/>
		<term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="College students"/>
		<term name="Commercial blacklisting"/>
		<term name="Communication policy"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense burdensharing"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="Disasters"/>
		<term name="East-West trade"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Embassies"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Expert witnesses"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Foreign service"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Grievance procedures"/>
		<term name="Hostages"/>
		<term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Information policy"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Insurgency"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International courts"/>
		<term name="International economic relations"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="Israel"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Local taxation"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Offshore structures"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Pacific area"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Refugee policy"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
		<term name="Security measures"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Ships"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="Tax treaties"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication policy"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Torture"/>
		<term name="Transfer of employees"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="United Nations finances"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of State Title II: Department of State Organization Title III: Torture and Terrorism Offenses and Sanctions Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1994 and 1995 - Title I: Department of State - Part A: Authorization of Appropriations - (Secs. 101 through 105) Authorizes appropriations for FY 1994 and 1995 for: (1) the Department of State for the administration of foreign affairs; (2) international organizations, peacekeeping activities, and conferences; (3) international commissions; (4) migration and refugee assistance; (5) bilateral science and technology agreements; and (6) the Asia Foundation. (Sec. 106) Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds authorized by this Act for contracts with any firm that complies with the Arab League boycott of Israel or discriminates in the award of subcontracts on the basis of religion. Part B: Department of State Authorities and Activities - (Sec. 113) Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to authorize the Secretary of State to procure the services of experts for use in prosecuting a proceeding before an international tribunal or a claim by or against a foreign entity. Establishes an International Litigation Fund for meeting expenses related to such proceedings. (Sec. 121) Authorizes the Secretary to make grants and otherwise support activities to conduct research and promote international cooperation on environmental and scientific issues. Part C: Diplomatic Reciprocity and Security - (Sec. 131) Authorizes the admission into the United States for safety purposes of a limited number of aliens who provide information regarding international terrorism under a rewards program. Part D: Personnel - (Sec. 141) Amends the Federal Insurance Contributions Act to provide that service by a Government employee in an international organization shall constitute employment for purposes of employment tax provisions if such individual is entitled to retain certain Federal retirement benefits during such service. (Sec. 142) Permits the Secretary, if exceptional circumstances so warrant, to waive a limitation (up to a specified amount) on claims for losses incurred by Government personnel subject to a chief of mission in a foreign country in cases of a natural disaster or emergency evacuation. Makes such waiver retroactive to claims made as of October 31, 1988. (Secs. 143 and 144) Makes chiefs of mission salaries and performance pay subject to limitations on certain payments under Federal civil service provisions. Part E: International Organizations - (Sec. 151) Authorizes the President to bring into force the Agreement on State and Local Taxation of Foreign Employees of Public International Organizations. (Sec. 152) Permits the President to withhold 20 percent of the funds appropriated for the U.S. assessed contribution to the United Nations if the United Nations has failed to implement consensus-based decisionmaking procedures on budgetary matters which assure that sufficient attention is paid to the views of the United States and other states who are major financial contributors. (Sec. 154) Authorizes the President to maintain membership in the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation Organization. Part F: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 161) Authorizes the Secretary to determine that the publication of certain international agreements is not required if certain criteria are met. (Sec. 162) Amends the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 to raise the ceiling on the amounts of funds authorized to be appropriated for the Emergency Refugee Migration and Assistance Fund. Title II: Department of State Organization - (Sec. 201) Requires the Department of State to notify the Congress of its intention to abolish or create units at or above the bureau level. (Sec. 202) Revises the organization of the Department of State to eliminate certain positions and to transfer certain authorities from subordinate officials to the Secretary. Title III: Torture and Terrorism Offenses and Sanctions - (Secs. 301 through 305) Amends the Federal criminal code to establish penalties for: (1) performing or attempting an act of violence against a person at an airport serving international civil aviation which causes or is likely to cause serious injury or death; (2) destroying or seriously damaging the facilities of, or a civil aircraft not in service at, such airport; (3) disrupting the services of such airport, if such an act endangers safety; (4) committing acts of violence against maritime navigation and fixed platforms; (5) committing, or attempting to commit, torture outside the United States; and (6) providing material support to terrorists.

	</summary>
</bill>
