<bill session="103" type="s" number="1091" updated="2012-07-17T04:32:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Organized Crime Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to control international organized crime.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400565"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7093-7094, S7097-7098)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Child molesting"/>
		<term name="Child pornography"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Credit cards"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Extortion"/>
		<term name="Extradition agreements"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Gambling"/>
		<term name="Gangs"/>
		<term name="Hong Kong"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Misconduct in office"/>
		<term name="Money"/>
		<term name="Money laundering"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Police"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Prostitution"/>
		<term name="Public corruption"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="Secret service"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Taiwan"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/10/1993--Introduced.
International Organized Crime Control Act of 1993 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to conclude agreements with, and furnish assistance to, other countries to control international organized crime. Prohibits U.S. officers or employees from: (1) directly effecting arrests in foreign countries as part of foreign police actions to control such crime, except in exigent circumstances or, with the agreement of a country, in maritime law enforcement operations; and (2) interrogating or being present during the interrogation of any U.S. person arrested in a foreign country without such person's written consent. Withholds 50 percent of U.S. assistance allocated each fiscal year for each major organized crime source country. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. executive directors of specified international financial institutions to oppose funding for such countries. Releases assistance if the President certifies to the Congress that a country has taken steps to address law enforcement, narcotics control, money laundering, and public corruption issues. Amends the Federal criminal code to require the death penalty or life imprisonment for a death caused during a kidnapping. Directs the Attorney General to report to the Congress and the President on effors made to recruit and hire former Royal Hong Kong Police officers into Federal law enforcement positions. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report on Secret Service efforts to combat credit card counterfeiting with ties to the U.S. region. Directs the Attorney General and the Commissioner of the Immigration and Naturalization Service to report on the status of organized crime task forces, including proposed Asian Crime Task Forces. Provides increased penalties for passport and visa fraud. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for penalties against carriers delivering undocumented aliens into the United States. Requires the U.S. Sentencing Commission to promulgate or amend guidelines to provide for increased penalties for alien smuggling if certain circumstances (related to number of aliens or specified criminal activities) exist. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the United States should encourage the development of a United Nations Convention on Organized Crime.

	</summary>
</bill>
