<bill session="103" type="s" number="1098" updated="2012-07-17T05:58:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Brain Injury Rehabilitation Quality Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for optional coverage under State medicaid plans of case-management services for individuals who sustain traumatic brain injuries, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1993-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="403171" joined="1993-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-06-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7217-7218)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Brain"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Head injuries"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Patients' rights"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Trauma care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1993--Introduced.
Brain Injury Rehabilitation Quality Act of 1993 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to provide for optional Medicaid coverage of case-management services to Medicaid-eligible individuals who sustain traumatic brain injuries, reside in a State with a case-management program meeting specified requirements, and meet other specified criteria. Requires States electing to provide such coverage to appoint a State coordinator to establish policies and standards for providing services, make necessary reports, supervise and coordinate services for eligible persons, and perform other specified duties. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish standards for reporting data on traumatic brain injuries and operation of registries of traumatic brain injuries for use by State coordinators. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Administrator of the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research to study and report to the Congress on the effectiveness of traumatic brain injury interventions. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
