<bill session="103" type="s" number="1095" updated="2012-07-17T04:37:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals to direct that part or all of their income tax refunds be contributed to a trust fund established for the relief of domestic and international hunger, and to establish a commission to oversee the distribution of such conditions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7099-7100)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Charities"/>
		<term name="Checkoff"/>
		<term name="Child nutrition"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Food relief"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Hunger"/>
		<term name="Tax refunds"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/10/1993--Introduced.
Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust Act of 1993 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individuals to designate on their income tax returns a contribution of all or part of their tax refund to the Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust. Establishes in the Treasury the Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust to distribute hunger relief funds to qualified nonprofit hunger relief services organizations. Describes standards and procedures for the distribution of trust fund monies. Specifies a number of restrictions with respect to the activities of recipient organizations, including limitations on administrative expenses. Requires the Hunger Commission (established by this Act) to submit to specified congressional committees an annual report detailing trust fund expenditures. Establishes a Hunger Commission to administer the distribution of funds to qualified hunger relief services organizations on a matching grant basis. Permits a maximum award of $100,000 to any single qualified organization in any fiscal year. Requires that: (1) at least 50 percent of amounts received into the trust fund in any year be paid to qualified organizations; and (2) monies in the trust fund be distributed within 180 days of their receipt. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
