<bill session="103" type="s" number="1122" updated="2012-07-17T05:54:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Health Professionals Education Debt Reduction Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans' Affairs to carry out a program for repayment by the Secretary of certain education costs incurred by certain Veterans' Health Administration employees, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300073"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7496)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23"><committee name="Committee on Veterans"/><text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/17/1993--Introduced.
Department of Veterans Affairs Health Professionals Education Debt Reduction Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out the Department of Veterans Affairs Education Debt Reduction Program to assist Department health-care personnel serving in the Veterans Health Administration in reducing the amount of debt incurred in completing educational programs that qualify such personnel for such service. Makes eligible for such Program any individual other than a physician or dentist serving in a Department health care position and having an outstanding health education loan from a qualified educational institution. Provides certain assistance preferences. Limits the assistance to $4,000 for each full year served in a Department health-care position, up to a $12,000 maximum. Authorizes appropriations for the Program for FY 1994 through 1998.

	</summary>
</bill>
