<bill session="103" type="s" number="1120" updated="2012-07-17T04:29:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">World War II Cadet Nurse Civil Service Fairness Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that periods of training in the Cadet Nurse Corps during World War II be made creditable for Federal retirement purposes with respect to annuitants and certain other individuals not included under Public Law 99-638.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300089"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7383)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-25"><text>Senate Committee on Veterans discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-25"><text>Referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1968" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Civil service retirement"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Nurses"/>
		<term name="Nursing students"/>
		<term name="World War II"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/1993--Introduced.
World War II Cadet Nurse Civil Service Fairness Act - Includes service of at least one year but less than two years in the Cadet Nurse Corps during World War II as creditable service for purposes of civil service retirement. (Current law provides for individuals with two or more years of service.) Requires the retirement annuity of an affected individual to be redetermined upon the filing of an appropriate application with the Office of Personnel Management and the deposit of required amounts into the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.

	</summary>
</bill>
