<bill session="103" type="s" number="1140" updated="2012-07-17T04:16:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sewer and Water Fee Deductibility Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction for fees for sewer and water services to the extent such fees exceed 1 percent of adjusted gross income, and to offset the cost of such deduction by disallowing the deduction for amounts paid pursuant to settlements and for compensatory damages under certain environmental laws.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-06-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7620)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Business losses"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Sewage disposal"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Water rates"/>
		<term name="Water use"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/1993--Introduced.
Sewer and Water Fee Deductibility Act of 1993 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a deduction for fees imposed by a State or local government for water or sewer services in the same manner as local real property taxes. Limits such deduction to the extent that such fees exceed one percent of adjusted gross income. Disallows any corporate deduction for payments to the government under environmental settlement agreements or for compensatory damages relating to violations of environmental laws. Prohibits the net operating loss deduction from reducing taxable income to an amount less than such disallowed amount.

	</summary>
</bill>
