<bill session="103" type="s" number="1143" updated="2012-07-17T05:35:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Health Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the delivery of health care services in rural areas by creating an Assistant Secretary for Rural Health, to attend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide that medical assistance facilities be reimbursed based on reasonable cost, to establish a grant program for the use of interactive telecommunications systems, and to adjust the payments made for certain direct graduate medical education expenses.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="1993-06-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7627-7628)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5499-5500)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Medical residents"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Rural hospitals"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/1993--Introduced.
Rural Health Improvement Act of 1993 - Amends title VII (Administration) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to create within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) an Assistant Secretary for Rural Health to: (1) head an independent Office of Rural Health Policy; (2) report directly to the HHS Secretary on the implications of national health care reforms for rural areas; and (3) establish a program to provide grants to rural health care networks to enhance the delivery of health care in rural areas through the use of interactive telecommunications systems. Authorizes appropriations. Amends parts A (Hospital Insurance) and B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of SSA title XVIII (Medicare) to provide for coverage of, and payment for, medical assistance facility services. Provides for: (1) adjustments in Medicare graduate medical education payments for certain publicly funded family practice residency programs; and (2) preventive care services as part of the initial residency period under Medicare.

	</summary>
</bill>
