<bill session="103" type="s" number="1141" updated="2012-07-17T05:42:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Hospice Services Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 17 of title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans' Affairs to conduct a hospice care pilot program and to provide certain hospice care services to terminally ill veterans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-06-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7621-7622)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Hospices (Terminal care)"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/1993--Introduced.
Veterans' Hospice Services Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a pilot program to: (1) assess the feasibility and desirability of furnishing hospice care to terminally ill veterans; and (2) determine the most efficient and effective means of providing such care. Directs the Secretary to designate 15 to 30 Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities for hospice care demonstration projects. Allows such hospice care to be provided by Department medical facilities and personnel or by contract with a non-Department medical facility. Limits the amount paid for such care to amounts paid for hospice care programs under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act. Directs the Secretary, during the pilot program period of October 1, 1993, through December 31, 1998, to designate not fewer than ten Department medical facilities at which hospice care is being provided to furnish palliative care to such veterans. Provides for: (1) informing terminally ill veterans of their eligibility for hospice and palliative care; and (2) hospice program evaluation, assessment, and congressional reports by the Secretary and the Director of the Health Services Research and Development Service of the hospice care pilot program.

	</summary>
</bill>
