<bill session="103" type="s" number="1158" updated="2012-07-17T06:09:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family Unity Demonstration Project Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the National Institute of Corrections to make grants to States to carry out family unity demonstration projects, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403669"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-07-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8103)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee on Judiciary. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-668.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="569" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Community-based corrections"/>
		<term name="Correctional institutions"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/24/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Grants to States Title III: Family Unity Demonstration Project for Federal Prisoners Title I: General Provisions - Family Unity Demonstration Project Act of 1993 - Authorizes appropriations for State (80 percent) and Federal (20 percent) family unity demonstration projects that enable eligible prisoners to live in community correctional facilities with their children for purposes of alleviating harm to children and primary caretaker parents caused by separation due to incarceration, promoting policies to assign prisoners to correctional facilities for which they qualify closest to their family homes, reducing prison populations and recidivism rates, and reducing the cost of providing correctional services. Title II: Grants to States - Authorizes the Director of the National Institute of Corrections (NIC) to make grants to States to carry out such projects, giving preference to States providing assurances that: (1) the State corrections and health and human services agencies will participate and cooperate closely in the development and operation of the project; (2) public and nonprofit private community-based organizations will be integrally involved; (3) the State will target economically disadvantaged, incarcerated prisoners and their children for participation; (4) the State has a policy that provides for the placement of prisoners in correctional facilities for which they qualify that are located closest to their family homes; and (5) the State will follow specified guidelines in selecting prisoners to participate. Directs the NIC to make grants on a competitive basis to five eligible States geographically dispersed throughout the United States. Sets forth conditions for grant eligibility and State reporting requirements. Title III: Family Unity Demonstration Project for Federal Prisoners - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) carry out a family unity demonstration project that enables eligible prisoners to live in community correctional facilities with their children; (2) comply with preference and reporting requirements established under this Act; and (3) consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services regarding development and operation of such project.

	</summary>
</bill>
