<bill session="103" type="s" number="1167" updated="2010-04-19T17:32:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-25">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-06-25" where="s" result="pass" how="by Voice Vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Electrification Loan Restructuring Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to restructure the electric and telephone loan programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300065"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-25"><text>Committee on Agriculture. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Leahy. Without written report.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-06-25" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote. (consideration: CR 6/24/93 S8075-8077)</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29T11:11:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29T20:16:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3123" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
		<term name="Agricultural credit"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Drainage"/>
		<term name="Economic policy"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government consultants"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Liens"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Rural electrification"/>
		<term name="Sewage disposal"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/25/1993--Introduced.
Rural Electrification Loan Restructuring Act of 1993 - Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to prescribe guidelines under which the Rural Electrification Administrator (the Administrator) shall make insured electric and telephone loans (including hardship, municipal rate, and cost of money loans). Directs the Administrator to approve State telecommunications modernization plans if they meet specified requirements. Prescribes guidelines for loans made by the Governor of a telephone bank in the rural telephone bank loan program. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) electric hardship loans; (2) electric municipal rate loans; (3) telephone hardship loans; and (4) telephone cost-of-money loans. Expands the size of a &quot;rural area&quot; for such purposes. Prohibits the Administrator and the Governor of the telephone bank from imposing any charges not expressly provided for in this Act in connection with any loan or guarantee made under it. Specifies circumstances under which the Administrator may use consultants funded by the borrower. Prescribes guidelines for: (1) distribution borrower eligibility for loans, loan guarantees, and lien accommodations; and (2) administrative prohibitions applicable to electric borrowers. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to make loans to certain borrowers to whom a loan has been made under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 for water and waste disposal facilities serving certain rural residents. States that a borrower of a loan or loan guarantee under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 is eligible for assistance under all programs administered by the Rural Development Administration.

	</summary>
</bill>
