<bill session="103" type="s" number="1163" updated="2012-07-17T04:52:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Budget Deficit Reduction Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce spending and tax subsidies in order to reduce the budget deficit, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8111-8112, S8116-8117)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Acreage allotments"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
		<term name="Air traffic"/>
		<term name="Antisatellite weapons"/>
		<term name="Antisubmarine warfare"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Ballistic missile defenses"/>
		<term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Cotton"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Early retirement"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Engines"/>
		<term name="Executive orders"/>
		<term name="Farm production quotas"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fighter aircraft"/>
		<term name="Frigates"/>
		<term name="Goats"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Infantry"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Military discharges"/>
		<term name="Military pensions"/>
		<term name="Military personnel"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Military weapons"/>
		<term name="Mine warfare ships"/>
		<term name="Minesweeping"/>
		<term name="Mining claims"/>
		<term name="Mining royalties"/>
		<term name="Naval aviation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear energy research facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear submarines"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Retired military personnel"/>
		<term name="Rice"/>
		<term name="Rockets (Aeronautics)"/>
		<term name="Space exploration"/>
		<term name="Space stations"/>
		<term name="Space warfare"/>
		<term name="Superconductivity"/>
		<term name="Tactical nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Wool"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/24/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Agriculture and Related Programs Title II: Commerce, Science, and Transportation Title III: Energy and Natural Resources Title IV: Finance Title V: National Defense Title VI: General Provisions Budget Deficit Reduction Act of 1993 - Title I: Agriculture and Related Programs - Amends the National Wool Act of 1954 to eliminate the wool and mohair price support program. Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to eliminate: (1) the cotton price support and production adjustment programs; and (2) the rice price support and production adjustment programs. Title II: Commerce, Science, and Transportation - Terminates funding for the Advanced Solid Rocket Motor and the Space Exploration Initiative programs. Requires the Federal Communications Commission to initiate an auction process for licenses for the radio spectrum. Title III: Energy and Natural Resources - Eliminates funds for the Superconducting Super Collider. Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to require the establishment of annual domestic livestock grazing fees equal to fair market value. Abolishes grazing advisory boards. Requires the payment of annual holding fees or royalties for hardrock mining on Federal lands. Title IV: Finance - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require premiums to cover 100 percent of the costs for certain higher-income individuals. Increases the premium payments for such individuals. Title V: National Defense - Limits funding for: (1) Navy ballistic missile submarines and crews on patrol at sea concurrently; (2) Navy attack submarines; (3) Navy antisubmarine warfare weapons; (4) Army light infantry divisions; (5) Air Force tactical fighter wings; (6) weapons research and development and testing activities; and (7) the Strategic Defense Initiative and the Theater Missile Defense Initiative. Terminates: (1) the Navy MHC(V) coastal mine-hunting ship program; and (2) the Army Kinetic Energy Anti-Satellite Attack (ASAT) program. Requires the military departments to exercise early retirement authority to retire at least 60,000 members of the Armed Forces before October 1, 1994. Title VI: General Provisions - Transfers savings from this Act to the General fund of the Treasury.

	</summary>
</bill>
