<bill session="103" type="s" number="1166" updated="2012-07-17T04:04:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Nuclear Power Safety and Security Enhancement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 and the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to enhance the safety and security of nuclear power facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8119-8121)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Clean Air and Nuclear Regulation. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-28"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Subcommittee on Clean Air incorporated provisions of bill into S. 1162, as approved for full committee consideration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Clean Air and Nuclear Regulation" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Nuclear energy"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
		<term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
		<term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
		<term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
		<term name="Nuclear research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
		<term name="Radiation safety"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Sabotage"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
		<term name="Weapons"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/25/1993--Introduced.
Omnibus Nuclear Power Safety and Security Enhancement Act of 1993 - Amends the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 to require certain persons (including owners and operators) with information about a defect or safety violation at nuclear facilities regulated by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), including those leased by the United States Enrichment Corporation, to notify the NRC immediately if such defect or violation could create a substantial safety hazard. Authorizes the NRC to issue regulations requiring such persons to devise and implement notification compliance procedures. Mandates that the notification requirements be preeminently posted on the business premises of persons subject to this Act. Provides a civil penalty for non-compliance. Grants the NRC enforcement powers. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to establish civil penalties for violations of its licensing or certification strictures. Declares that each day of a continuing violation constitutes a separate violation for purposes of computing the civil penalty. Repeals the requirement that the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards submit an annual status report to the Congress on reactor safety research. Authorizes the NRC to: (1) permit its licensees to carry firearms while in the discharge of their official duties; and (2) issue regulations regarding the introduction of dangerous weapons or instrumentalities upon property within its licensing purview. Includes within the penalty guidelines for the sabotage of nuclear facilities those facilities subject to NRC licensing during their construction where the damage could affect public health and safety during the operation of the facility. Sets forth guidelines for the NRC to conduct warrantless searches, and to enter certain premises with a judicially approved administrative search warrant.

	</summary>
</bill>
