<bill session="103" type="s" number="1160" updated="2012-07-17T05:56:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Health Innovation Demonstration Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants to entities in rural areas that design and implement innovative approaches to improve the availability and quality of health care in such rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1993-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8104-8107)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2529" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Consumer cooperatives"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Medical centers"/>
		<term name="Medical malpractice insurance"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Mental health services"/>
		<term name="Nurses"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Rural hospitals"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/24/1993--Introduced.
Rural Health Innovation Demonstration Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize competitive grants for the development of networks among rural and urban health care providers to preserve and share health care resources and enhance the quality and availability of health care in rural areas. Allows the networks to be statewide or regional. Specifies the services for which grant amounts must be used. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes competitive grants to develop and administer cooperatives in rural areas that will establish an effective case management and reimbursement system designed to support the economic viability of essential public or private health services, facilities, health care systems, and health care resources. Involves the cooperative in matters such as third party reimbursement, employee health insurance, malpractice insurance, and managed care and practice standards. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes competitive grants to develop and implement a plan for mental health outreach programs in rural areas. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes grants to enable rural communities to provide stipends to physicians, nurses, or other health professional trainees to encourage such individuals to continue to provide health care services in such communities. Authorizes appropriations to carry out provisions relating to area health education centers.

	</summary>
</bill>
