<bill session="103" type="s" number="1173" updated="2012-07-17T06:26:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Japan Trade Equalizing Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a comprehensive reduction in the United States bilateral trade deficit with Japan, to assure mutually advantageous international trade in motor vehicles and motor vehicle parts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8244-8246)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Automobile engines"/>
		<term name="Automobile industry"/>
		<term name="Automobile parts"/>
		<term name="Automobile parts industry"/>
		<term name="Balance of payments"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Import quotas"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Japan"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/29/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Findings and Definitions Title II: Merchandise Trade Deficit Reduction United States-Japan Trade Equalizing Act of 1993 - Title I: Findings and Definitions - Sets forth congressional findings and purposes with respect to access to Japanese markets by U.S. manufacturers of motor vehicles and motor vehicle parts. Title II: Merchandise Trade Deficit Reduction - Sets forth annual merchandise trade deficit reduction targets with respect to Japan's trade deficit with the United States. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) compute annually whether the target has been met for each year; (2) publish in the Federal Register that the import restriction implementation period is in effect for the year following the year a target has not been met; and (3) compute annually and publish in the Federal Register the quantitative import restrictions for years in which import restrictions are effective. Prohibits the quantity of Japanese motor vehicles and parts that may be entered into the United States in: (1) the first year in which a restriction is in effect from exceeding the quantity of such vehicles and parts entered during 1993, reduced by 20 percent; and (2) subsequent years from exceeding the quantity entered during the most recent year for which a restriction was in effect, reduced by 20 percent. Authorizes the Secretary to impose temporary quantitative import restrictions on such motor vehicles and parts during the first three months of an import restriction implementation period in order to prevent surging. Expresses the sense of the Congress that representatives of the U.S. and Japanese Governments should undertake continuing discussions regarding the measures to be selected by the Japanese Government to achieve the merchandise trade deficit reduction targets.

	</summary>
</bill>
