<bill session="103" type="s" number="1178" updated="2012-07-17T04:21:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to coordinate and promote Great Lakes activities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404598"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8254)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2566" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/29/1993--Introduced.
Great Lakes Federal Effectiveness Act - Establishes a Great Lakes Research Council to: (1) advise and promote the coordination of Federal research activities to avoid unnecessary duplication and ensure greater effectiveness in achieving ecosystem protection of the Great Lakes through the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement; (2) prepare and provide to interested parties a document which includes an assessment of research activities needed to fulfill the goals of the Agreement and of existing Federal expertise in such activities and recommendations for research priorities; (3) identify topics for and participate in workshops and conferences on Great Lakes research issues; (4) make recommendations for the uniform collection of data for enhancing research and management protocols relating to the Great Lakes ecosystem; (5) advise and cooperate in the establishment of a multi-media data base for such ecosystem; and (6) ensure that findings and information regarding such research are disseminated in a timely manner.

	</summary>
</bill>
