<bill session="103" type="s" number="1183" updated="2012-07-17T04:56:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Clean Water Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide for confined soil disposal facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-06-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8357-8358)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Clean Water, Fisheries. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Clean Water, Fisheries and Wildlife" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2651" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Dredging"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Sediment control"/>
		<term name="Sedimentation"/>
		<term name="Storm drains"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Waste reduction"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/30/1993--Introduced.
Great Lakes Clean Water Amendments Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to make it unlawful, after 1994, to dispose of dredge spoil in Great Lakes waters other than at a confined disposal facility unless the disposal is consistent with guidelines established under this Act. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop guidelines for the disposal of sediment material in the open waters of the Great Lakes. Prescribes civil penalties for violations concerning such disposal. Prohibits the Secretary of the Army from establishing, expanding, or modifying any confined spoil disposal facility in Great Lakes waters unless the facility is consistent with such guidelines. Directs the Administrator to implement management plans for such facilities. Requires the Secretary to develop remediation plans for confined disposal facilities that are at risk of exceeding water or sediment quality standards or interfering with the protection and propagation of a balanced, indigenous population of fish and wildlife. Terminates the use of facilities for which plans are not implemented by January 1, 1999. Requires persons who dispose of dredge spoil at confined spoil disposal facilities to obtain permits. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop tributary sediment transport models for each major river system that deposits sediment into a Great Lakes federally authorized commercial harbor, channel maintenance project site, or area of concern; (2) develop an analytical method to project the effectiveness of sediment source reduction approaches; and (3) use such method to conduct sediment load reduction analyses for the models. Requires the Secretary to transfer funds to EPA for making grants to States for projects to reduce erosion that contributes to the sedimentation of such areas. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Great Lakes National Program Office to conduct demonstration projects of promising technologies to remedy contaminated sediments. Establishes: (1) a Great Lakes Pollution Prevention Demonstration Program; (2) a Great Lakes Pollution Prevention Clearinghouse; and (3) a Great Lakes Research Council. Sets deadlines for the publication of final and proposed Lakewide Management Plans for specified Great Lakes. Authorizes appropriations for the Great Lakes water quality program.

	</summary>
</bill>
