<bill session="103" type="s" number="1189" updated="2012-07-17T05:36:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Professional Boxing Corporation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Professional Boxing Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400565"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="1993-07-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8453, S8457-8458)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8639-8640)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13129-13132)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2607" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Sports and recreation"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Athletes"/>
		<term name="Boxing"/>
		<term name="Bribery"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Extortion"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Professional sports"/>
		<term name="Right of petition"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
Professional Boxing Corporation Act of 1993 - Establishes the Professional Boxing Corporation to work with State boxing authorities to establish uniform regulations for the protection of the health and safety of professional boxers. Requires the Corporation to be administered by an Executive Director appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Establishes a Professional Boxing Advisory Board. Sets forth the functions of the Corporation, which include: (1) providing a national computer source for certain boxing information; (2) licensing and certifying boxers, judges, referees, persons serving in a professional role in boxing, sanctioning organizations, promoters, matchmakers, managers, trainers, physicians, and cut men; and (3) charging licensing and registration fees. Requires States that regulate professional boxing to submit boxing plans that meet certain requirements to the Corporation. Establishes in the Treasury the Professional Boxing Corporation Trust Fund. Authorizes State boxing authorities to submit to specified congressional committees a petition: (1) stating that this Act is unnecessary because it has established a similar organization; and (2) requesting a delay of the effective date or repeal of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
