<bill session="103" type="s" number="1181" updated="2012-07-17T04:41:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-06-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-06-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-06-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Film Disclosure Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Act entitled &quot;An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes&quot;, enacted July 5, 1946 (commonly known as the Lanham Act), to require certain disclosures relating to materially altered films.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409923"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-06-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8353)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Patents, Copyrights and Trademarks.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Patents, Copyrights and Trademarks" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Trademarks"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Artists"/>
		<term name="Authors and authorship"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Motion pictures"/>
		<term name="Trade regulation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/30/1993--Introduced.
Film Disclosure Act of 1993 - Amends the Lanham Act to require that each public exhibition of a materially altered motion picture (and each copy of such film offered to the public through sale or rental) bear a label which conspicuously discloses the fact of: (1) the film's material alteration from the form in which it was first released to the public; (2) the nature of such alteration; and (3) any objections raised by the artistic authors with reference to such alteration. Delineates the compliance procedure for: (1) distributors or networks that propose to exploit a materially altered film; and (2) motion pictures intended for home use through either retail purchase or rental. Grants an artistic author the right to seek injunctive relief in U.S. district courts to prevent violation of his or her rights under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
