<bill session="103" type="s" number="1195" updated="2012-07-17T05:49:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wetlands Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to further the protection of wetlands, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8465-8466)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="350" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Charitable contributions"/>
		<term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Dredging"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Farm lands"/>
		<term name="Hydrology"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Maps"/>
		<term name="Navigation"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetland ecology"/>
		<term name="Wetlands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Amendments to the Federal Water Pollution Control Act Title II: Improved Wetlands Permitting; Revisions to Wetlands Delineation Procedures Title III: Wetlands Restoration Program Title IV: Tax Incentives for Wetlands Conservation Wetlands Reform Act of 1993 - Title I: Amendments to the Federal Water Pollution Control Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to make any pollutant discharge or alteration of navigable waters unlawful. Authorizes the issuance of permits for other alterations of navigable waters. Prohibits the issuance of permits if there is a practical alternative to the proposed activity that would have less adverse impact on navigable waters. Title II: Improved Wetlands Permitting; Revisions to Wetlands Delineation Procedures - Directs the Comptroller General to submit to the Congress an analysis of needs of the Corps of Engineers and Environmental Protection Agency for additional personnel, administrative resources, and funding to improve implementation of the wetlands permit program. Requires funds to be used for specified wetlands delineation and education programs. Requires the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service to use funds for wetlands mapping and for the delineation of wetlands in watersheds and ecosystems for which the need for delineation is particularly acute. Prohibits revisions to or clarifications of any Federal manual for identifying and delineating jurisdictional wetlands or regulations related to the definition, delineation, or identification of wetlands until a specified National Academy of Sciences study has been completed. Title III: Wetlands Restoration Program - Directs the Secretary of the Army to initiate a pilot program of wetlands restoration. Title IV: Tax Incentives for Wetlands Conservation - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to designate a nonprofit organization to be a Wetlands Stewardship Trust if such organization conforms to certain regulations, and includes among its primary purposes the acquisition of interests in wetlands, former wetlands, and associated real property for preservation purposes. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to set forth special rules for charitable contributions of wetlands to such trusts. Excludes from gross income amounts received by the owner of wetlands for allowing any person to use such lands in a compatible use (one that does not degrade the functions or values of such lands).

	</summary>
</bill>
