<bill session="103" type="s" number="1199" updated="2012-07-17T04:21:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide for coastal protection, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407786"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-07-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8479-8481)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Biodegradation"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
		<term name="Estuarine pollution"/>
		<term name="Eutrophication"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health surveys"/>
		<term name="Industrial pollution"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marine pollution"/>
		<term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
		<term name="Microbiology"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
		<term name="Ships"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Storm drains"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Territorial waters"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
Coastal Protection Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) submit a coastal environment toxics release strategy to the Congress; and (2) prepare an annual assessment of the extent and environmental effect of certain industrial discharges into marine waters. Extends the authorization of appropriations for the National Estuary Program. Directs the Administrator to list each marine water that does not support the protection and propagation of a balanced, indigenous population of fish and wildlife and allow for recreational activities in and on the water. Requires the Administrator, with respect to such waters, to: (1) implement certain ocean discharge criteria requirements when issuing a permit for point source discharges; (2) consider prohibiting the use of such waters as disposal sites or restricting their use; (3) prohibit the discharge of sewage from vessels; (4) implement a management program for the watershed areas; and (5) enforce programs for the pretreatment of industrial waste discharges. Requires States to adopt standards for any pollutant for which the Administrator has established criteria if the pollutant is likely to be present in such waters. Directs the Administrator to establish a national program to provide information and technical assistance to owners of marine land. Makes it unlawful to discharge sewage: (1) into waters designated under this Act; and (2) that has not been treated by a marine sanitation device. Directs the Administrator to submit a five-year plan for the development, review, and revision of criteria for pollutants found in marine waters to the Congress. Requires each State that borders on marine waters to establish marine and numerical water quality standards. Conditions the issuance of permits for discharges into the territorial sea, the waters of the contiguous zone, the oceans, or waters designated under this Act on the protection of fish and wildlife and recreational activity and the attainment of marine water quality standards. Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to provide financial assistance to local governments for the construction of facilities for the control of overflows from combined storm and sanitary sewers to marine waters. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress on Federal activities that may result in degradation of marine waters. Directs Federal agencies to minimize degradation and to consider alternative actions to avoid adverse effects on marine waters. Sets forth study and reporting requirements for specified issues, including: (1) health impacts of marine pollutants and shellfish consumption; (2) economic impacts of degradation; (3) toxic algal blooms; (4) the use of microorganisms to degrade pollutants; and (5) unregulated pollutants in marine waters.

	</summary>
</bill>
