<bill session="103" type="s" number="12" updated="2012-07-17T04:40:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Infrastructure Growth and Employment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to make grants to States and local governments for the construction of projects in areas of high unemployment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-05-11" withdrawn="1994-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-02-17" withdrawn="1993-07-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S359)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public works"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Capital investments"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Construction workers"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Economic growth"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Indian economic development"/>
		<term name="Industrial parks"/>
		<term name="Industrial research"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Local finance"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Public service employment"/>
		<term name="Research and development facilities"/>
		<term name="School districts"/>
		<term name="State finance"/>
		<term name="Underemployment"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
		<term name="Unemployment"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Infrastructure Growth and Employment Act of 1993 - Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Economic Development Administration, to make grants to States or local governments for construction, renovation, repair, or other improvement of local public works projects (including projects for which Federal funding is authorized under other laws). Sets the Federal share at 80 percent of project cost. Terminates the making of such grants after the earlier of: (1) any three-consecutive-month period during which the national unemployment rate remained below six percent; or (2) September 30, 1994. Allocates funds among the States on the basis of a formula involving relative numbers of unemployed persons, average unemployment rates, and severity of unemployment. Reserves funds for projects of Indian tribes and Alaskan Native villages, minimum State allotments, and development and administration of each project. Requires that at least ten percent of total grant funds be set aside for grants to local governments with populations under 10,000. Sets project priority and preference requirements. Requires giving priority to applications from States or local governments with unemployment rates in excess of the national rates. Requires State and local prioritization of projects in their applications. Requires localization of unemployment rate determinations. Requires procedures which assure that adequate consideration is given to the relative needs of various sections of the country, based on factors including amount of unemployment or underemployment in construction and construction-related industries. Requires applicants to assure that, if funds are available, on-site labor work can begin within 90 days after project approval. Requires: (1) contracting out; (2) competitive bidding; (3) awards to the lowest responsive bid; (4) advertising specifications; (5) environmental law and regulation compliance; and (6) applicability of specified requirements involving Buy American provisions, minority participation, individuals with disabilities, and Davis-Bacon Act prevailing wage rates. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
