<bill session="103" type="s" number="1209" updated="2012-07-17T06:10:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Government Landfill Compliance Deadline Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a delay in the applicability of certain regulations to certain municipal solid waste landfills under the Solid Waste Disposal Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406256"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1993-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1993-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1993-07-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8496-8500)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1993--Introduced.
Local Government Landfill Compliance Deadline Act - Exempts municipal solid waste landfills existing as of October 8, 1993, which meet criteria under the Solid Waste Disposal Act as in effect on January 1, 1993, from meeting any revised criteria (established for facilities which may receive hazardous wastes) for a period of one year. Makes such exemption inapplicable to landfill owners or operators who did not make a good faith effort before October 9, 1993, to comply with criteria. Provides for a 180-day extension of the exemption subject to specified factors beyond the control of the owner or operator. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue regulations to revise specified financial assurance requirements under the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) to broaden the mechanisms available to municipal landfill owners or operators for demonstrating financial responsibility. Makes current requirements inapplicable until the effective date of such regulations. Requires the Administrator to issue regulations that exempt certain small landfills from CFR groundwater monitoring requirements.

	</summary>
</bill>
