<bill session="103" type="s" number="1224" updated="2012-07-17T06:23:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-06">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-10-06" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Multiethnic Placement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Multiethnic Placement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit an agency, or entity, that receives Federal assistance and is involved in adoption or foster care programs from delaying or denying the placement of a child based on the race, color, or national origin of the child or adoptive or foster parent or parents involved, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-10-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-10-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1994-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1993-10-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-10-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8712-8713)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol. Hearings held. On related provisions.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-14"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-10-06"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="377" datetime="1994-03-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 377.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Foster home care"/>
		<term name="Indian children"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Multiethnic Placement Act of 1993 - Prohibits an agency or entity that receives Federal assistance and is involved in adoptive or foster care placements from categorically denying to any person the opportunity to become an adoptive or a foster parent, or delaying or denying the placement of a child, solely on the basis of race, color, or national origin of the adoptive or foster parent or parents, or the child, involved. Permits consideration of the child's race, color, or national origin when such factors are: (1) considered in conjunction with other factors; and (2) relevant to the child's best interest. Withholds specified adoption assistance funds from such an agency or entity in cases of noncompliance. Grants any individual aggrieved by a noncomplying agency or entity the right to bring an action in the appropriate U.S. District Court. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the application of the Indian Child Welfare Act of 1978.

	</summary>
</bill>
