<bill session="103" type="s" number="1222" updated="2012-07-17T04:03:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revise the boundaries of the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor in Massachusetts and Rhode Island, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1993-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8710-8712)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="641" datetime="1994-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 641.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-11-30"><text>By Senator Johnston from Committee on Energy and Natural Resources filed written report. Report No. 103-415.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2633" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2633" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Landscape protection"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Regional planning"/>
		<term name="Rhode Island"/>
		<term name="Right of property"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Sports and recreation"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
		<term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 1994 - Modifies the boundaries of the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor. Requires the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Commission to revise the Cultural Heritage and Land Management Plan to address the boundary change and include a natural resource inventory of areas or features that should be protected, restored, managed, or acquired because of their contribution to the understanding of national cultural landscape values. Prohibits changes other than minor revisions in the approved plan as amended without the approval of the Secretary of the Interior. Extends the date of termination of the Commission until ten years after this Act's enactment, subject to specified conditions. Directs the Secretary to approve an additional extension if the Secretary finds that: (1) the Governors of Massachusetts and Rhode Island provide adequate assurances of continued tangible contribution and effective policy support toward achieving the purposes of the Corridor; and (2) the Commission is effectively assisting Federal, State, and local authorities to retain, enhance, and interpret the distinctive character and nationally significant resources of the Corridor. Authorizes the Secretary to undertake a limited program of financial assistance for the purpose of providing funds for the preservation and restoration of structures on or eligible for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places within the Corridor which exhibit national significance or provide a wide spectrum of historic, recreational, or environmental education opportunities to the general public. Specifies that nothing in the Act establishing the Corridor shall be construed to affect or authorize the Commission to interfere with: (1) the rights of any person with respect to private property; or (2) any local zoning ordinance or land use plan of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts or a political subdivision of such Commonwealth. Increases and extends the authorization of appropriations under the Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
