<bill session="103" type="s" number="1232" updated="2012-07-17T05:13:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Used Car Consumer Notification and Reporting Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act to require the establishment of Federal requirements regarding the disclosure and reporting of salvage vehicles and manufacturer buyback vehicles.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400559"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8821-8822)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-371.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Automobile industry"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Defective products"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle registration"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Salvage"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/15/1993--Introduced.
Used Car Consumer Notification and Reporting Act - Amends the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act to direct the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate regulations that establish uniform Federal requirements regarding the disclosure to consumers that a motor vehicle is a salvage or manufacturer buyback vehicle. Deems a violation of a regulation promulgated by the Secretary to be an unfair or deceptive practice for purposes of the Federal Trade Commission Act. Provides that this Act shall supersede any State law relating to disclosure of whether a vehicle is a salvage or manufacturer buyback vehicle to the extent that such law is inconsistent with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
