<bill session="103" type="s" number="124" updated="2012-07-17T04:33:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Compassionate Pain Relief Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a temporary program under which parenteral diacetylmorphine will be made available through qualified pharmacies for the relief of intractable pain due to cancer, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S562-564)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Cancer"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Drugstores"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Narcotics"/>
		<term name="Opium"/>
		<term name="Pain"/>
		<term name="Terminal care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Compassionate Pain Relief Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a 60-month program under which parenteral diacetylmorphine may be dispensed from pharmacies for the relief of pain from terminal cancer (as defined by this Act). States that for purposes of such program the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and titles II and III of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 shall not apply with respect to: (1) the importing of opium; and (2) the manufacture, distribution, and dispensing of parenteral diacetylmorphine. Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees concerning: (1) program-related activities; and (2) activities related to the management of pain. Permits the Secretary at any time six months after implementation of the program to modify or terminate the program if: (1) the program is no longer needed; or (2) modifications or termination are needed to prevent substantial diversion of the diacetylmorphine.

	</summary>
</bill>
