<bill session="103" type="s" number="1254" updated="2012-07-17T06:04:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Authorization bill FY94, Military Construction</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Military Construction FY94 Authorization bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize certain construction at military installations for fiscal year 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408252"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-07-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8900-8901, S8907-8909)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20"><committee name="Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Subcommittee on Military Readiness. Approved for full committee consideration without amendment favorably.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Readiness and Defense Infrastructure" activity="Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Air bases"/>
		<term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
		<term name="Army posts"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense contracts"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Easements"/>
		<term name="Electricity"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Gas companies"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military construction operations"/>
		<term name="Military dependents"/>
		<term name="Military housing"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="NATO military forces"/>
		<term name="National Guard"/>
		<term name="Natural gas"/>
		<term name="Naval bases"/>
		<term name="New York State"/>
		<term name="Public utilities"/>
		<term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
		<term name="Rent"/>
		<term name="Rental housing"/>
		<term name="Reservoirs"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Virginia"/>
		<term name="War"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title XXI (sic): Army Title XXII: Navy Title XXIII: Air Force Title XXIV: Defense Agencies Title XXV: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Infrastructure Title XXVI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities Title XXVII: Expiration and Extension of Authorizations Title XXVIII: General Provisions Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994 - Part A: Fiscal Year 1994 - Title XXI (sic): Army - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to construct or acquire family housing units, to carry out architectural planning and design activities, and to improve existing military family housing in specified amounts. Authorizes appropriations to the Army for FY 1994 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of the Army. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Title XXII: Navy - Provides, with respect to the Navy, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army under the previous title. Title XXIII: Air Force - Provides, with respect to the Air Force, authorizations paralleling those provided for the Army. Title XXIV: Defense Agencies - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out certain energy conservation projects. Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY 1994 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of DOD. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Title XXV: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Infrastructure - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to make contributions for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Infrastructure Program and authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 1993 for such contributions. Title XXVI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities - Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after 1993 for the Guard and Reserve forces for acquisition, architectural planning and design activities, and construction of facilities. Title XXVII: Expiration and Extension of Authorizations - Terminates all authorizations contained in the preceding titles of this Act on October 1, 1996, or the date of enactment of an Act authorizing funds for military construction for FY 1997, whichever is later. Extends certain FY 1991 military construction projects. Title XXVIII: General Provisions - Authorizes the Secretary to undertake military construction projects not otherwise authorized by law in connection with military contingency operations. Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act and the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act to: (1) provide for the use of proceeds received from the disposal or closure of military installation property; and (2) authorize the Secretary to contract with local governments for the provision of community services at military installations to be closed. Makes miscellaneous changes with respect to the military family housing programs, military construction programs, and activities related to the closure or realignment of military installations. Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to convey to: (1) Washington Gas Company, Virginia, the natural gas distribution system at Fort Belvoir, Virginia; (2) American Water Company, Virginia, the water distribution system at Fort Lee, Virginia; and (3) Blackstone, Virginia, the waste water treatment facility at Fort Pickett, Virginia.

	</summary>
</bill>
