<bill session="103" type="s" number="1255" updated="2012-07-17T04:04:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Energy National Security Programs Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the Department of Energy for national security programs for fiscal year 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408252"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-07-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8909, S8911-8912)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20"><committee name="Committee on Armed Services"/><text>Subcommittee on Nuclear Deterrence. Approved for full committee consideration without amendment favorably.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="Nuclear Deterrence, Arms Control, and Defense Intelligence" activity="Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
		<term name="Nuclear research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Radiation safety"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/1993--Introduced.
Department of Energy National Security Programs Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994 - Subtitle A: National Security Programs Authorizations - Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY 1994 for operating expenses, plant projects, and capital equipment necessary in carrying out the following under national security programs: (1) weapons activities; (2) environmental restoration and waste management; (3) nuclear materials support and other defense programs; and (4) defense nuclear waste disposal. Subtitle B: Recurring General Provisions - Prohibits the use of funds appropriated pursuant to this title for: (1) the cost of a program exceeding the lesser of 105 percent of the program authorization or $10 million more than the amount authorized; or (2) programs which have not been presented to, or requested of, the Congress, unless the Secretary of Energy transmits to specified congressional committees a full statement of the action proposed and 30 days have expired since such notification. Places certain funding limits for general plant and contruction projects of DOE and requires congressional reports for amounts in excess of such limits. Limits fund transfer authority. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out advance planning and construction design services in connection with proposed construction projects not exceeding $2 million and requires certain congressional notification. Authorizes the use of DOE funds for emergency planning, design, and construction activities in order to meet the needs of national defense or to protect property and public health and safety. Makes funds appropriated for management and support activities and for general plant projects under this subtitle available for all national security programs of DOE. Subtitle C: Fiscal Year 1995 Authorization - Authorizes appropriations to DOE for FY 1995 to carry out national security programs and environmental restoration and waste management programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
