<bill session="103" type="s" number="1263" updated="2012-07-17T05:06:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide disaster assistance to agricultural producers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1993-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="1993-07-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9069-9070)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-20"><committee name="Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Agricultural Production.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="Agricultural Production and Stabilization of Prices" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Agricultural credit"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
		<term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
		<term name="Cotton"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Droughts"/>
		<term name="Earthquakes"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Feed grain program"/>
		<term name="Indian economic development"/>
		<term name="Oilseeds"/>
		<term name="Peanuts"/>
		<term name="Rice"/>
		<term name="Rural conditions"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Soybeans"/>
		<term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
		<term name="Tobacco"/>
		<term name="Trees"/>
		<term name="Weather"/>
		<term name="Wheat"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/20/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Emergency Crop Loss Assistance Subtitle A: Annual Crops Subtitle B: Orchards Subtitle C: Forest Crops Subtitle D: Administrative Provisions Title II: Rural Businesses Title III: Disaster Credit and Forbearance Disaster Assistance Act of 1993 - Title I: Emergency Crop Loss Assistance - Subtitle A: Annual Crops - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make 1993 disaster payments to producers of wheat, feed grains, upland cotton, extra long staple cotton, rice, peanuts, sugar, tobacco, oilseeds, and other nonprogram crops. (Sec. 105) Extends crop quality reduction disaster assistance through the 1993 crop year. (Sec. 106) Reduces disaster assistance payments in relation to Federal crop insurance payments. (Sec. 107) Requires producers to obtain Federal crop insurance for 1994 and 1995 in order to be eligible for disaster payments and other specified assistance for 1992-1993 crop losses. (Sec. 108) Requires the Secretary to announce within a specified time the conditions for establishing a 1993 farm yield for forage-use-crops. (Sec. 109) Limits assistance under this subtitle to $100,000. (Sec. 110) Prohibits double payments on replanted acreage. Authorizes: (1) the substitution of crop insurance program yields for 1993 disaster assistance eligibility purposes; and (2) the Secretary to determine a de minimis yield for each crop eligible for reduced yield disaster payments. (Sec. 112) Permits the planting of oilseeds on certain prevented planting acreage. Subtitle B: Orchards - Directs the Secretary to provide assistance (up to $25,000 per person) to eligible orchardists who lost more than 35 percent of their trees in 1993 to freeze, earthquake, or related condition. Subtitle C: Forest Crops - Directs the Secretary to provide assistance (up to $25,000 per person) to eligible tree farmers who lost more than 35 percent of their 1992-1993 tree seedlings to drought, earthquake, or related condition in 1993. Subtitle D: Administrative Provisions - Makes a person with qualifying annual gross income (as defined by this Act) in excess of $2,000,000 ineligible for assistance under this title. Title II: Rural Businesses - Directs the Secretary to make loan guarantees to rural businesses (including Indian tribes and entities) affected by damaging weather in 1992 or 1993. Limits: (1) individual payments to $500,000; and (2) program guarantees to $200 million. Title III: Disaster Credit and Forbearance - Directs the Secretary to provide 1994 direct credit operating loans and loan guarantees to assist farmers who suffered major weather-caused crop losses in 1992 or 1993.

	</summary>
</bill>
