<bill session="103" type="s" number="1270" updated="2012-07-17T06:24:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cache La Poudre River Basin Heritage Study Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Cache La Poudre River National Water Heritage Area in the State of Colorado.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401874"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-22"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-23"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-610.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Flood control"/>
		<term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Hydrology"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="River regulation"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/21/1993--Introduced.
Cache La Poudre River Basin Heritage Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to prepare a study of alternatives for the Cache La Poudre River Basin in Colorado, including: (1) an inventory and assessment of significant cultural, natural, recreational, and scenic resources throughout the Basin; (2) an evaluation of properties to determine potential eligibility for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places; (3) the suitability and feasibility of designating the Basin as a National Heritage Area; and (4) the identification of preservation strategies for resources located within the Basin, and management alternatives and funding options for the implementation of such strategies. Authorizes the Secretary to undertake a demonstration project to evaluate the potential of using voluntary land exchanges within the Cache La Poudre River flood plain as a means to provide for the long-term preservation and management of the lands within the floodplain. Establishes the Cock La Poudre River Basin Heritage Advisory Commission to advise the Secretary on the preparation of the study. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
