<bill session="103" type="s" number="1282" updated="2012-07-17T05:59:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Graduate Reform Opportunities and Work Force Training in Health Act (GROWTH)</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the number of primary health care providers, help assure access to health care in rural and other underserved areas, and increase retention rates among primary health care providers in rural and underserved areas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9367-9368)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-23" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Accreditation (Education)"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Continuing education"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical residents"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
		<term name="Nurses"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
		<term name="Public health personnel"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/1993--Introduced.
Graduate Reform Opportunities and Work Force Training in Health Act (GROWTH) - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Health Work Force Interagency Task Force to: (1) review and coordinate all Federal health work force development and training efforts; (2) make recommendations for coordinating Federal vocational education policy with national health work force needs and goals; (3) develop standards for programs on vocational education in the health care professions and procedures for program accountability; and (4) carry out other appropriate activities. Requires a report to the appropriate congressional committees. Authorizes the use of grant or contract funds for training programs for primary health care in rural areas. Requires the Secretary to develop training programs for nurse practitioners, clinical nurse specialists and physician assistants designed to prepare trainees to staff tertiary care centers. Authorizes appropriations for the establishment of demonstration projects concerning the retraining of physicians in oversubscribed specialties. Requires a study on health work force needs, the results of which are to be reported to appropriate congressional committees. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise provisions concerning payments for direct graduate medical education costs, including: (1) establishing a national average direct medical education payment; (2) limiting the total number of medical residents eligible for such payments; and (3) providing a higher weighting factor for residents placed in a rural area. Establishes the National Health Care Work Force Board to: (1) recommend to the Secretary the residency training programs that should receive direct graduate medical education funding; (2) report to the Congress on a study of current and projected health care work force needs; and (3) present legislative proposals every three years on adjusting federally-funded residency positions and specialty residency positions.

	</summary>
</bill>
