<bill session="103" type="s" number="1296" updated="2012-07-17T05:05:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Act For Reform In Emerging New Democracies and Support and Help for Improved Partnership with Russia, Ukraine and Other New Independent States</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FRIENDSHIP with Russia, Ukraine, and other new independent States Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill for reform in emerging new democracies and support and help for improved partnership with Russia, Ukraine and other new independent states.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9554, S9556-9559)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12239)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Afghanistan"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Angola"/>
		<term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="Christianity"/>
		<term name="Civil defense"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Climate"/>
		<term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Communism"/>
		<term name="Communist countries"/>
		<term name="Communist parties"/>
		<term name="Communist propaganda"/>
		<term name="Communists"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cuba"/>
		<term name="Cultural relations"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="East Germany"/>
		<term name="Eastern Europe"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational exchanges"/>
		<term name="Embassies"/>
		<term name="Emigration"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Estonia"/>
		<term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign service"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Freedom of association"/>
		<term name="Fur trade"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Guided missiles"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Insurgency"/>
		<term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International propaganda"/>
		<term name="Jews"/>
		<term name="Latvia"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Lithuania"/>
		<term name="Military command and control"/>
		<term name="Military intervention"/>
		<term name="Military occupation"/>
		<term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="Nuclear warfare"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Officer personnel"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Postal service"/>
		<term name="Press"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Right to travel"/>
		<term name="Russian Republic"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
		<term name="Sealing"/>
		<term name="Sovereignty"/>
		<term name="Special days"/>
		<term name="Strategic materials"/>
		<term name="Subversive activities"/>
		<term name="Tariff preferences"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Totalitarianism"/>
		<term name="U.S.S.R."/>
		<term name="Ukraine"/>
		<term name="Warsaw Pact countries"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/27/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Policy of Friendship and Cooperation Between the United States and Russia, Ukraine, and the Other Independent States of the Former Soviet Union Title II: Trading and Business Relations Title III: Cultural, Educational and Exchange Programs Title IV: Arms Control Title V: Provisions Related to Diplomatic Relations Title VI: Provisions Related to Oceans and Environment Title VII: Regional and General Diplomatic Issues Title VIII: Internal Security Provisions; Soviet Conspiracy to Establish Worldwide Communist Dictatorship Title IX: Miscellaneous Act for reform in emerging new democracies and support and help for improved partnership with Russia, Ukraine, and other new independent States or FRIENDSHIP with Russia, Ukraine, and Other New Independent States Act - Title I: Policy of Friendship and Cooperation Between the United States and Russia, Ukraine, and the Other Independent States of the Former Soviet Union - (Sec. 102) Affirms that certain existing statutory provisions that impose limitations on the Soviet Union or utilize language that reflect the tension that existed between the Soviet Union and the United States should not be construed as being directed against the independent states of the former Soviet Union, connoting an adversarial relationship between the United States and these states, or implying unfriendliness toward such states. Title II: Trading and Business Relations - (Sec. 201) Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to remove the Soviet Union from the list of countries ineligible for the generalized system of preferences. (Sec. 204) Amends the Federal criminal code to consider persons engaged in legal commercial transactions as agents of Cuba or any other country determined by the President to pose a threat to national security interests to be foreign agents subject to notification requirements. (Current law considers agents of the Soviet Union, the German Democratic Republic, Hungary, Czechoslovakia, Poland, Bulgaria, and Romania as foreign agents for such purposes.) (Sec. 205) Amends the Department of Defense Appropriations Authorization Act, 1975 to remove the Soviet Union and the aforementioned Eastern European countries from the definition of a &quot;controlled country&quot; under provisions restricting exports of Department of Defense-funded items to controlled countries. (Sec. 206) Authorizes the President, with respect to the former Soviet Union, to waive a requirement that nondiscriminatory trade treatment be limited to periods during which a country is not in arrears on lend-lease obligations. Title III: Cultural, Educational, and Exchange Programs - (Secs. 301 through 306) Changes references in specified laws concerning exchanges from the Soviet Union to the independent states. Title IV: Arms Control - (Secs. 401 through 404) Changes certain references to the Soviet Union and the Warsaw Pact in the Arms Control and Disarmament Act and the Arms Export Control Act to the independent states, Russia, and Eastern Europe. Title V: Provisions Related to Diplomatic Relations - (Secs. 501 through 503) Repeals specified provisions concerning: (1) personnel restrictions on Soviet national employees of foreign missions or international organizations; and (2) Soviet embassies and consulates (particularly with regard to security measures) and U.S. embassies in the former Soviet Union. (Sec. 504) Repeals a provision of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 which authorizes appropriations to carry out such Act in the Soviet Union. Title VI: Provisions Related to Oceans and Environment - (Secs. 602 and 603) Replaces references to the Soviet Union in specified provisions of the Fur Seal Act of 1966 and the Global Climate Protection Act of 1987 with Russia and the independent states. Title VII: Regional and General Diplomatic Issues - (Secs. 702 and 705) Repeals specified provisions concerning U.S. policy toward Afghanistan and Angola and removes references to Communist countries under policy provisions of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. Title VIII: Internal Security Provisions; Soviet Conspiracy to Establish Worldwide Communist Dictatorship - (Secs. 802 and 803) Repeals provisions of law concerning: (1) reports on Soviet press manipulation in the United States; and (2) findings on Communism and prohibitions on communications with members of Communist parties and on attempting to establish a totalitarian dictatorship. Title IX: Miscellaneous - (Sec. 901) Repeals provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 concerning: (1) Soviet missile tests near Hawaii; (2) emigration from the Soviet Union; (3) delivery of international mail within the Soviet Union; and (4) persecution of Christians in the Soviet Union. (Sec. 902) Repeals provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 concerning: (1) the murder of a certain U.S. army officer; and (2) Soviet policy toward pentecostal Christians.

	</summary>
</bill>
