<bill session="103" type="s" number="1301" updated="2012-07-17T05:02:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-16">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-07-16" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1994 for intelligence activities of the United States Government and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar datetime="1993-07-16"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Intelligence ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Committee on Intelligence. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator DeConcini. With written report No. 103-115. Additional and minority views filed.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services pursuant to the order of Senate Resolution 400, 94th Congress, for the thirty day period provided in section 3(b) of the Resolution.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-10-05" ><text>Committee on Armed Services. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-10-05"><text>Committee on Armed Services. Reported to Senate by Senator Nunn with an amendment. With written report No. 103-155.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="224" datetime="1993-10-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 224.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14485-14486)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S15505-15506, S15539-15570"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 2330 as an amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 2330 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup" />
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="superseded" session="103" type="h" number="2330" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2330" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2330" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Civil service retirement"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Counterintelligence"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Divorcees"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Military intelligence"/>
		<term name="Military pay"/>
		<term name="New York City"/>
		<term name="Official secrets"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s1154"/>
		<amendment number="s1155"/>
		<amendment number="s1156"/>
		<amendment number="s1157"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Indefinitely postponed in Senate. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Intelligence Activities Title II: Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Title III: General Provisions Title IV: Central Intelligence Agency Title V: Department of Defense Title VI: Federal Bureau of Investigation Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994 - Title I: Intelligence Activities - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1994 for Federal intelligence activities. Authorizes the Director of Central Intelligence (DCI) to employ civilian personnel in excess of the personnel ceiling when necessary for the performance of important intelligence functions. Authorizes appropriations for the Community Management Account of the DCI for FY 1994. Establishes an end strength ceiling of 237 full-time Community Management Account employees. Title II: Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1994 for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund. Amends the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act to exclude interest earned from voluntary contributions to the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System from the definition of &quot;lump-sum credit.&quot; Prohibits a former spouse of a participant from being entitled to an annuity from the Fund unless such spouse elects to receive it instead of any survivor annuity (currently, any other annuity) to which such spouse may be entitled under any Government retirement system on the basis of a marriage to someone other than the participant. Prohibits the payment of retirement annuities to former spouses unless an application was submitted by June 2, 1990 (currently, 1991). Makes amendments under this title effective as of February 1, 1993. Title III: General Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1994 for increases in employee compensation and benefits authorized by law. Requires the DCI and the Secretary of Defense to jointly prepare and submit by February 15, 1994, to specified congressional committees a report: (1) identifying and assessing the critical gaps between the information needs of the Government and intelligence collection capabilities and gaps in the ability of the intelligence community to provide intelligence support needed by the armed forces and, in particular, by commanders of combatant commands; and (2) containing joint recommendations of the DCI and the Secretary on appropriate means, to include specific budgetary adjustments, for reducing or eliminating such gaps. Revises provisions of the Federal Employees Pay Comparability Act of 1990 to provide that: (1) employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) New York Field Division who were receiving certain retention payments as part of a previously authorized demonstration project shall not suffer a loss in pay as a result of the termination of that project on September 29, 1993; and (2) the basic pay of such employees shall not rise in the future until the level of payments being made under such project has been surpassed as a result of incremental increases in the compensation of the employees concerned. Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to make clear that the general authorization for any funds necessary and appropriate to carry out the provisions and purposes of the Act does not satisfy the requirement that there be a specific authorization by the Congress in order for intelligence agencies to obligate or expend funds available to them. Deems funds obligated or expended for the Accelerated Architecture Acquisition Initiative of the Plan to Improve the Imagery Ground Architecture based upon the notification to the appropriate congressional committees by the DCI, dated August 16, 1993, to have been specifically authorized by the Congress. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the aggregate amount requested and authorized for, and spent on, intelligence and intelligence-related activities each year should be disclosed to the public. Title IV: Central Intelligence Agency - Amends the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to establish a General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency. Title V: Department of Defense - Revises the formula for determining foreign language proficiency pay for reserve members of the armed forces. Title VI: Federal Bureau of Investigation - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require consumer reporting agencies to furnish reports to the FBI at the FBI's request if the records are necessary to conduct a foreign counterintelligence investigation and there is reason to believe that the consumer whose report is sought is a foreign power or agent of a foreign power as defined under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978. Makes Federal agencies who obtain or disclose credit information in violation of this Act liable for damages to the consumer.

	</summary>
</bill>
