<bill session="103" type="s" number="1304" updated="2012-07-17T04:58:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wetlands Conservation and Regulatory Improvements Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to improve the conservation of wetlands and thereby restore and maintain the physical, chemical and biological integrity of the Nation's waters, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9721-9722)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Clean Water, Fisheries. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Clean Water, Fisheries and Wildlife" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Dredging"/>
		<term name="Ecological research"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Farm lands"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Navigation"/>
		<term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Storm drains"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetlands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1993--Introduced.
Wetlands Conservation and Regulatory Improvements Act - Prohibits the issuance of revisions to or clarifications of the guidelines for identifying and delineating wetlands under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act until the National Academy of Sciences has completed a specified wetlands study. Provides for the continued use of the 1987 Corps of Engineers wetlands delineation manual until such guidelines are issued. Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue guidelines to identify and delineate wetlands. Earmarks funding for: (1) wetlands delineation training and certification programs; and (2) assistance to private landowners who lack financial capacity to identify or delineate wetlands in order to apply for dredge or fill permits or avoid impacts to wetlands. Provides for a public information program on Federal regulations, permitting requirements, and wetlands delineation. Expands the definition of &quot;discharge of dredged or fill material&quot; to include draining, mechanized landclearing, ditching, and excavations (thus, making such activities subject to permit requirements). Sets forth permit decision deadlines and administrative appeal procedures. Authorizes the issuance of general permits on a State, regional, or nationwide basis for any category of activities involving discharges of dredged or fill materials if the activities are similar in nature and will cause only minimal adverse environmental effects when performed separately and cumulatively. Requires specified Federal officials to enter into agreements to make technical determinations concerning wetlands on agricultural lands. Exempts prior converted croplands and certain waters and activities from regulation under dredged and fill permit provisions. Provides for the establishment of mitigation banks (wetlands restoration projects that provide compensation credits to offset foreseeable wetlands losses from future discharges of dredged or fill material into navigable waters where compensatory mitigation is not practicable). Authorizes funding to States for wetlands conservation and watershed management planning. Requires the Administrator to initiate a wetlands and watershed management research program. Establishes a committee to coordinate Federal, State, and local government wetlands policies. Provides for the development of a National Cooperative Wetlands Restoration Strategy.

	</summary>
</bill>
