<bill session="103" type="s" number="1310" updated="2012-07-17T05:25:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Breast and Cervical Cancer Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the program of grants relating to preventive health measures with respect to breast and cervical cancer, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300073"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-07-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9872-9873)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Blood pressure"/>
		<term name="Breast cancer"/>
		<term name="Cervical cancer"/>
		<term name="Cholesterol"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Indian medical care"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Mammography"/>
		<term name="Medical screening"/>
		<term name="Medical tests"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/1993--Introduced.
Breast and Cervical Cancer Amendments of 1993 - Amends Public Health Service Act provisions authorizing grants for breast and cervical cancer preventive health measures to allow States to make contracts with private entities, provided the amount paid does not exceed the amount that would be paid under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act. Requires special consideration to be given to projects that have been peer reviewed and approved and that involve areas that have high cervical or breast cancer mortality rates or a high incidence of such cancers. Revises breast and cervical cancer screening quality assurance requirements. Allows the grants to be made to tribes and tribal organizations. Includes these changes in evaluation and reporting requirements. Authorizes demonstration project grants to up to three States receiving the cancer grants to provide: (1) additional preventive services, including health education and screening regarding blood pressure and cholesterol; (2) referrals and follow up for women receiving the cancer services; and (3) related evaluations. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the breast and cervical cancer preventive health measures provisions.

	</summary>
</bill>
