<bill session="103" type="s" number="1319" updated="2012-07-17T06:21:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sexually Transmitted Diseases Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to extend the program of grants regarding the prevention and control of sexually transmitted diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-07-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9881-9882)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Colleges"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Human fertility"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Public health administration"/>
		<term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/1993--Introduced.
Sexually Transmitted Diseases Amendments of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations through FY 1998 for programs for: (1) the prevention and control of sexually transmitted diseases; and (2) the prevention of infertility arising as a result of such diseases. Authorizes the award of grants to States and political subdivisions for the development, implementation, and evaluation of interdisciplinary approaches to the prevention and control of sexually transmitted diseases and their sequelae by: (1) expanding access to sexually transmitted disease services through collaborations with public health programs and nongovernmental partners; (2) implementing community-based behavioral interventions to prevent disease transmission; and (3) establishing collaborations between health departments and university-based experts to strengthen sexually transmitted disease prevention programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
