<bill session="103" type="s" number="1320" updated="2012-07-17T05:20:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Injury Control and Violence Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title III of the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend certain injury control programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-07-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9881-9882)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Accidents"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Family violence"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Health surveys"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/1993--Introduced.
Injury Control and Violence Prevention Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to: (1) conduct research and provide technical assistance to public and nonprofit private entities and to academic institutions to assist such entities in performing research in, and conducting training and public health programs for, the prevention of injuries and deaths associated with family and interpersonal violence; and (2) award grants to States, political subdivisions, and public and nonprofit private entities for specified activities regarding the prevention of such violence. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to: (1) support the establishment of national systematic surveillance of injuries; and (2) establish an advisory committee to advise the Secretary and the Director on the prevention and control of injuries. Extends the authorization of appropriations for injury control and violence prevention activities through FY 1998.

	</summary>
</bill>
