<bill session="103" type="s" number="132" updated="2012-07-17T06:00:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 1086 of title 10, United States Code, to provide for payment under CHAMPUS of certain health care expenses incurred by certain members and former members of the uniformed services and their dependents to the extent that such expenses are not payable under medicare, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S570-571)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Dental care"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Military dependents"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="Retired military personnel"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Authorizes payment through the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS) for items and services for which payment is also made through Medicare, with a reduction for the amount already covered by Medicare. Continues CHAMPUS eligibility for veterans eligible for care or treatment for a service-connected disability in facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs. Requires a person receiving medical or dental care for which payment may be made under both Medicare and CHAMPUS to certify the amounts charged and paid for such items and services.

	</summary>
</bill>
