<bill session="103" type="s" number="1333" updated="2012-07-17T04:13:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-11">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-08-11" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-07-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Expedited Exclusion and Alien Smuggling Enhanced Penalties Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the admissions process at airports and other ports of entry and to strengthen criminal sanctions for alien smuggling investigatory authority of the Immigration and Naturalization Service.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-10-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1994-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-07-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-07-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9992-9994, S9997-9998)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-08-11"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee on Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration and Refugee Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2836" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Ferries"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Money laundering"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Passenger ships"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political refugees"/>
		<term name="Prostitution"/>
		<term name="Repatriation"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Sabotage"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="Wiretapping"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/1993--Introduced.
Expedited Exclusion and Alien Smuggling Enhanced Penalties Act of 1993 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to create grounds for exclusion of an alien who: (1) uses or attempts to use a fraudulent document to enter the United States, or to board a common carrier for such purpose; or (2) uses a document to board a common carrier and then fails to present such document to an immigration official upon arrival at a U.S. port of entry. Prohibits the granting of asylum to an alien who is found to be using fraudulent entry documents or who fails to present entry-related documents, unless a specially trained immigration officer determines such actions were pursuant to departure from a country in which the alien had a credible fear of persecution or of return to persecution. Provides for port of entry exclusion and deportation without administrative or judicial appeal (except by a limited petition of habeas corpus) for such admission document fraud. Increases immigration inspection fees, with exceptions for Great Lakes and connecting waterways entry ports. Increases penalties for certain alien smuggling offenses. Creates a separate offense and penalty for an alien smuggler who seriously injures or jeopardizes the life of an alien. Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to make appropriate sentencing guideline increases. Expands Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) forfeiture authority to include any real or personal property used or intended to be used to smuggle aliens, or that constitutes, is derived from, or traceable to such activities. Exempts property used without the owner's consent or knowledge, or not to his or her benefit. Amends Federal law to authorize, with judicial approval, INS wiretaps for alien smuggling investigations. Brings alien smuggling operations under the purview of the Racketeering Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) provisions. Permits payment of awards for information related to terrorist acts to be used in connection with terrorist acts committed in the United States.

	</summary>
</bill>
