<bill session="103" type="s" number="1341" updated="2012-07-17T04:55:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-23">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-03-23" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wheeling National Heritage Area Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wheeling National Heritage Area Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Wheeling National Heritage Area in the State of West Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300016"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10232-10233)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-04"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-09"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-516.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-03-23"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-249.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="411" datetime="1994-04-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 411.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2843" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2843" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Charities"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Corporations"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="West Virginia"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/14/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Wheeling National Heritage Area Act of 1994 - Establishes: (1) the Wheeling National Heritage Area in West Virginia; and (2) the Wheeling National Heritage Area Corporation to be structured as a private, nonprofit tax-exempt entity. Requires the Corporation to: (1) implement the August 1992 plan for the Wheeling National Heritage Area; (2) ensure integrated operation of the Area and to conserve and interpret its historic and cultural resources; (3) become a financially self-sustaining entity; (4) work with the State of West Virginia and local governments to ensure that the plan is formally adopted by the city of Wheeling and recognized by the State; and (5) report annually to the Secretary of the Interior on its accomplishments, expenses and income, the entities to which any loans and grants were made during the previous year, and a plan of operations for the upcoming year. Authorizes the Secretary: (1) upon the request of the Corporation, to provide appropriate interpretive, planning, educational, staffing, exhibits, and other materials for the Area consistent with the plan and as appropriate to the resources and associated values of the Area; (2) provide funds for capital improvements to the projects within the Area and, for a maximum five-year period, initial operating funding for the Corporation consistent with the plan; and (3) make loans and grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the Corporation, the State of West Virginia (or a political subdivision thereof), nonprofit organizations, or any person in order to assist in plan implementation. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance for planning efforts at the request of the Corporation. Requires any amendment to the plan to be approved by the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations. Prohibits the Secretary from expending more than 50 percent of the aggregate cost for implementing the plan with respect to cooperative agreements, loans, and grants awarded.

	</summary>
</bill>
