<bill session="103" type="s" number="1345" updated="2012-07-17T05:20:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-11-19" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide land-grant status for tribally controlled community colleges, tribally controlled postsecondary vocational institutions, the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development, Southwest Indian Polytechnic Institute, and Haskell Indian Junior College, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1994-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="403962" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10236-10237)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18"><committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-470.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Approved for reporting with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 103-194.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-19"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 321.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
		<term name="Agricultural education"/>
		<term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
		<term name="Agricultural research"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Community colleges"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Junior colleges"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Reported to Senate amended. Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1993 - Provides land-grant status for specified tribally controlled community colleges and postsecondary vocational institutions, Bureau of Indian Affairs postsecondary institutions, and the Institute of American Indian Arts (Institutions). Authorizes appropriations, in lieu of public land or land scrip donations, for such Institutions. Amends the Act of August 30, 1890, to include such Institutions in the annual appropriation for food and agricultural sciences instruction. Amends the Act of May 8, 1914, to authorize annual appropriations for agricultural extension services at such Institutions. States that no matching funds shall be required. Amends the Research Facilities Act to authorize FY 1995 through 1999 appropriations for research facility construction at such Institutions.

	</summary>
</bill>
