<bill session="103" type="s" number="1348" updated="2012-07-17T05:08:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Asylum Reform and Alien Smuggling Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform the asylum law, to increase penalties for alien smuggling, and to authorize appropriations for the Immigration and Naturalization Service, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400557"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10240-10241)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration and Refugee Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political refugees"/>
		<term name="Repatriation"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Fraudulent Asylum Applications and Alien Smuggling and Fraud Title II: Asylum Title III: Border Patrol and Asylum Officer Positions Asylum Reform and Alien Smuggling Control Act of 1993 - Title I: Fraudulent Asylum Applications and Alien Smuggling and Fraud - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide expedited exclusion procedures for aliens who arrive without proper documentation or who are determined by a special asylum officer not to have a proper claim of asylum (based upon a credible fear of persecution). Increases penalties for certain alien smuggling offenses. Extends penalties to persons who contract to bring in illegal labor. Treats smuggling as an aggravated felony. Creates a separate offense and penalty for an alien smuggler who seriously injures or jeopardizes the life of an alien. Title II: Asylum - Revises asylum procedures. Sets forth mandatory and discretionary conditions for granting asylum. Establishes new application deadlines. States that asylum applications shall be determined by specially trained asylum officers. Terminates an alien's claim for failure to appear at the application hearing. Title III: Border Patrol and Asylum Officer Positions - Increases the number of Border Patrol and asylum officer positions. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
