<bill session="103" type="s" number="1367" updated="2012-07-17T04:46:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit taxpayer financed mass mailings.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411818"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10576)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Senate"/>
		<term name="Congressional Record"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional newsletters and questionnaires"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Franking privilege"/>
		<term name="Mailing lists"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/5/1993--Introduced.
Prohibits the use of franked mass mailings by Senators, Senators-elect, and Senate offices beginning in FY 1994. Requires the chairman of the Committee on Rules and Administration to have printed in the Congressional Record: (1) the dollar amount of the allocation of official mail costs made to each Senator, Senator-elect, and Senate office for the fiscal year; (2) the quarterly costs that were incurred by them; and (3) the balance of such allocations that remain available to each individual and office. Requires the Secretary of the Senate, the Sergeant at Arms, and the Doorkeeper of the Senate, in connection with their FY 1995 budget presentations, to submit a report to the Senate Committee on Appropriations describing: (1) the best available and most recent information relating to the amount of expenditures made from each Senate office account for official mail activities during FY 1994 and 1993; and (2) the amount of any difference between the two fiscal years for such expenditures attributed to franked mass mailings. Prohibits a member, officer, or employee of the Senate from using any appropriated funds, equipment, or other resources paid for with appropriated funds for procuring, gaining access to, or using a mailing list of any kind (including a voter registration list) that is produced by any public or private entity except a mailing list of: (1) postal patrons; (2) members of the communications media; (3) Federal, State, or local government officials; or (4) fewer than 500 persons identified as having an interest in a legislative topic that is different from a topic in any list previously used for a mass mailing.

	</summary>
</bill>
