<bill session="103" type="s" number="1363" updated="2012-07-17T04:48:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Good Neighbor Environmental Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to transfer funds to the Secretary of State, and award grants, to provide assistance to promote public health, the environment, and water quality in the United States-Mexico border area, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10574-10575)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/5/1993--Introduced.
Good Neighbor Environmental Assistance Act of 1993 - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, for purposes of carrying out construction of treatment works in the U.S.-Mexican border region, to: (1) transfer funds to the Secretary of State or the heads of other Federal agencies; and (2) make grants to appropriate entities or border States designated by the President. Permits the Administrator to make grants for construction projects in Mexico if an existing treatment works is not sufficient to protect residents of border States from water pollution originating in Mexico. Requires such projects to be constructed in accordance with plans and specifications approved by the Administrator. Provides for full funding of projects by the Federal Government unless a cost-sharing agreement with the Mexican Government is executed. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
