<bill session="103" type="s" number="1380" updated="2012-07-17T04:37:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate portions of the Maurice River and its tributaries in the State of New Jersey as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401709"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-08-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10579)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-556.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="New Jersey"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/5/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Maurice River, the Menantico Creek, the Manumuskin River, and the Muskee Creek in New Jersey as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to manage such segments through cooperative agreements with appropriate political jurisdictions except that publicly-owned lands within the boundaries of the segments shall be managed by the agency having jurisdiction over them. Requires cooperative agreements for the management of the segments to provide for the long-term protection, preservation, and enhancement of the segments and to be consistent with the comprehensive management plan prepared by the Secretary and with the local river management plans prepared by appropriate local political jurisdictions in conjunction with the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to review compliance with the local river management plans biennially and to report to specified congressional committees on any deviation which may diminish the values for which the river segment was designated. Encourages the Secretary to work with municipalities to negotiate agreement for designating additional eligible segments of the Maurice River and its tributaries. Designates the eligible segments for study as potential additions to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers system. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
