<bill session="103" type="s" number="1383" updated="2010-04-19T18:06:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-05">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Protection from Violent Programming Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the distribution to the public of violent video programming during hours when children are reasonably likely to comprise a substantial portion of the audience.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300053"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-11-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10581-10582)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-852.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Cable television"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Television and children"/>
		<term name="Television broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Television programs"/>
		<term name="Television stations"/>
		<term name="Violence in television"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/5/1993--Introduced.
Children's Protection from Violent Programming Act of 1993 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to make it unlawful for any person to: (1) distribute to the public any violent video programming during hours when children are reasonably likely to comprise a substantial portion of the audience; or (2) knowingly produce or provide material for such distribution. Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to promulgate regulations to implement this Act. Authorizes the FCC, as part of its rulemaking proceeding, to exempt programming (including news programs, documentaries, educational programs, and sporting events) whose distribution does not conflict with the objective of protecting children from the negative influences of violent video programming. Exempts premium and pay-per-view cable programming. Requires the FCC to immediately repeal the license of any person who repeatedly violates this Act and to consider, in its review of an application for renewal of a license, whether the licensee has complied with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
