<bill session="103" type="s" number="1400" updated="2012-07-17T06:09:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Arming Felons (SAFE) Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to permanently prohibit the possession of firearms by persons who have been convicted of a violent felony, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-08-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10847-10850)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-16"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Pardons"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Stop Arming Felons (SAFE) Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to: (1) prohibit the possession of, or transactions in, firearms by any natural person convicted of a serious drug offense or violent felony, regardless of any expungement or setting aside of the conviction, pardon, or restoration of other civil rights; (2) deny convicted natural persons the opportunity to seek administrative relief from prohibitions against possessing, shipping, transporting, or receiving firearms or ammunition; (3) eliminate provisions permitting persons to appeal for judicial review of denials of relief; (4) eliminate the authority of Federal courts to admit additional evidence in reviewing denials of such relief; and (5) require publication of additional information about administrative relief granted to any person. Increases penalties for unlawful possession of a firearm by a convicted felon or other prohibited person.

	</summary>
</bill>
