<bill session="103" type="s" number="1417" updated="2012-07-17T05:00:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wastewater Treatment Operator Training and Certification Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide for training and certification of individuals in the operation of wastewater treatment works, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411818"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-08-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10893)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Community colleges"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Teaching materials"/>
		<term name="Technical education"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Women's education"/>
		<term name="Women's employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Wastewater Treatment Operator Training and Certification Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to revise provisions concerning training grants and contracts to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) implement a national program to train persons in the operation of municipal and industrial wastewater treatment works and other water pollution control facilities; (2) make grants to, or contracts with, institutions of higher education to support such programs; and (3) publish guidance on the minimum elements of such programs. Requires chief operators and other designated personnel of publicly owned treatment works to be certified as proficient by the Administrator. Directs the Administrator to publish: (1) guidelines on minimum standards for certification; and (2) a treatment works operator's manual. Authorizes the delegation of authority for a certification program to a State, subject to certain conditions. Makes certifications valid for a five-year period. Permits recertification for an additional five years provided that the individual complies with in-service training and related education. Requires institutions of higher education, in addition to other requirements for receiving scholarships for individuals planning to enter occupations involving treatment works, to: (1) have participated in the treatment works training program; and (2) ensure representation of minorities and women in the scholarship program. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
