<bill session="103" type="s" number="1411" updated="2012-07-17T04:25:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Yakima Basin Water Enhancement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize certain elements of the Yakima River Basin Water Enhancement Project, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400559"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10882-10883)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-09"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14756)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-3" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
		<term name="Canals"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Indian water rights"/>
		<term name="Irrigation"/>
		<term name="Lakes"/>
		<term name="River basin commissions"/>
		<term name="Stream conservation"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Water rights"/>
		<term name="Water storage"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetlands"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Yakima Basin Water Enhancement Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and administer a Yakima River Basin Water Conservation Program for the purpose of evaluating and implementing measures to improve the availability of water supplies for irrigation and the protection and enhancement of fish and wildlife resources, including wetlands, while improving the quality of water in the Yakima River basin. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of carrying out this Act. Directs the Secretary to establish the Yakima River Basin Conservation Advisory Group. Authorizes appropriations. Provides for the implementation by the Yakima Indian Nation of: (1) an irrigation demonstration project on the Yakima Indian Reservation that shall provide for the construction of distribution and on-farm irrigation facilities to use water savings resulting from system improvements to the Wapato Irrigation Project; and (2) a Toppenish Creek corridor enhancement project to demonstrate integration of management of agricultural, fish, wildlife, and cultural resources to meet tribal objectives. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary for initiation, operation, and maintenance of such projects and for implementation of system improvements to the Wapato Irrigation Project. Details the instream flows the Secretary is required to provide through the Yakima Project Superintendent, requiring flow increases (obtained through voluntary sale and leasing of water or water rights) to facilitate anadromous fish mitigation. Dedicates water savings resulting from improvements to the Wapato Irrigation Project to fish, wildlife, and on-reservation irrigation. Authorizes appropriations for Chandler Power Canal operations for the delivery of water to the Kennewick Division. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) modifying the radial gates at Cle Elum Dam to provide additional storage capacity in Lake Cle Elum; (2) providing for shoreline protection of the Lake; (3) constructing juvenile fish passage facilities at the Dam; (4) operation and maintenance responsibilities of the Federal Government for the Dam; and (5) environmental mitigation. Provides for the enhancement of water supplies for Yakima River Basin tributaries for fish and wildlife and irrigation purposes. Requires a study to determine the measures to be implemented to enhance water supplies for such purposes on Taneum Creek. Authorizes appropriations for such enhancement and for the Taneum Creek study. Makes implementation of this Act contingent upon compliance by the Secretary with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Authorizes appropriations for environmental compliance activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
