<bill session="103" type="s" number="1424" updated="2012-07-17T04:32:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Police Pursuit Policy Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 4 of title 23, United States Code, to establish a national program concerning motor vehicle pursuits by law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10905)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11949-11950)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Police training"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
National Police Pursuit Policy Act of 1993 - Prohibits the Secretary of Transportation from approving any State highway safety program which does not have in effect throughout the State: (1) a law that makes it unlawful for the driver of a motor vehicle to increase speed or take other evasive action if a law enforcement officer signals the driver to stop the vehicle, and that provides a minimum penalty of three months imprisonment and seizure of the driver's vehicle for any driver who commits such an unlawful act; and (2) a requirement that each public agency in the State which employs law enforcement officers (officers) who in the course of employment may conduct a motor vehicle pursuit shall have in effect a policy (meeting requirements set by the Secretary) concerning the manner and circumstances in which such a pursuit should be conducted, shall train all such officers in accordance with such policy, and shall transmit to the State in such fiscal year a report containing information on each such pursuit. Directs the Attorney General, the Secretaries of Agriculture, the Interior, and the Treasury, the Chief of the Capitol Police, and the Administrator of General Services to report to the Congress concerning: (1) the policy of the respective department or agency on motor vehicle pursuits by officers of the department or agency; and (2) a description of procedures being used to train their officers in implementing such policy.

	</summary>
</bill>
