<bill session="103" type="s" number="1429" updated="2012-07-17T04:49:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women and AIDS Research Initiative Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish programs of research with respect to women and cases of information with the human immunodeficiency virus, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-08-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-08-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10915-10916)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
		<term name="Clinical trials"/>
		<term name="Contraceptives"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugs and women"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Family violence"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Gynecology"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Human behavior"/>
		<term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical tests"/>
		<term name="Mental health services"/>
		<term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Women and AIDS Research Initiative Amendments of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish a program to conduct or support biomedical and behavioral research on cases of infection with the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) in women. Regulates clinical trials with women subjects. Mandates the conduct or support of: (1) clinical trials regarding the effectiveness of standard gynecological treatments in treating conditions arising from HIV infection; (2) clinical trials regarding whether the treatment protocols approved for men with HIV infection are effective for women with HIV infection; (3) research on barrier methods for the prevention of sexually transmitted diseases that women can use without their sexual partner's cooperation or knowledge; and (4) epidemiological research to determine HIV risk factors particular to women. Mandates support services for women in clinical trials. Regulates the Women's Interagency HIV Study. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
