<bill session="103" type="s" number="1423" updated="2012-07-17T05:56:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-08-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-08-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Eligibility Simplification Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to improve access to Medicaid benefits and to reduce State administrative burdens under the Medicaid program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402412"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-08-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10901-10904)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Contraceptives"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical screening"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Ovarian cancer"/>
		<term name="Poverty"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="State officials and employees"/>
		<term name="Sterilization (Birth control)"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/6/1993--Introduced.
Medicaid Eligibility Simplification Act - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) permit States to extend Medicaid coverage of prenatal care services to alien pregnant women who are neither officially nor under color of law permanent residents of the United States, but who are otherwise eligible for medical assistance under Medicaid; and (2) provide for simplification of the application process for enrollment in Medicaid. Amends SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) to preserve the Medicaid and SSI eligibility of individuals who would otherwise become ineligible for Medicaid benefits and SSI payments due to their receipt of weekly or biweekly income. Amends the Medicaid program: (1) to make optional currently mandatory reporting requirements under program provisions extending Medicaid coverage to eligible families making the transition from welfare to work; (2) with respect to program provisions concerning presumptive eligibility for pregnant women to include as a qualified provider any individual employed by the State and capable of making determinations of the type described under such provisions; (3) to revise the definition of qualified Medicare beneficiary and income requirements relating to pregnant women and coverage of reproductive health services; and (4) with respect to the income methodology used in determining the eligibility of certain individuals for Medicaid benefits.

	</summary>
</bill>
