<bill session="103" type="s" number="1445" updated="2012-07-17T04:32:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Appeals Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve and clarify certain adjudication and appeal procedures relating to claims for benefits under laws administered by the Department of Veterans' Affairs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-09" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11314-11317)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-09" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Video telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/9/1993--Introduced.
Veterans' Appeals Improvement Act of 1993 - Provides for the appointment by the Chairman of the Board of Veterans Appeals of any necessary number of Deputy Vice Chairmen. Rescinds the Chairman's authority to appoint temporary Board members from employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs. Removes current limitations on the authorized period of service for acting Board members. Requires the Chairman to include in an annual report information as to the number of acting Board members who served during the previous year and the number of appeal cases each such member participated in. Authorizes the Chairman to decide alone, or to assign to another Board member, any matter or motion before the Board. (Current law requires a minimum three-member Board determination of such matters.) Prohibits judicial review of any such assignments. Authorizes the Board to: (1) dismiss appeals which allege no specific error of fact or law or in which the determination being appealed has become moot; (2) remand cases for which additional developments require appropriate disposition; and (3) render a written final Board decision on issues not dismissed or remanded. Revises provisions concerning situations under which the Chairman shall exclude himself from the reconsideration of an appeal. Provides for the reconsideration of a case based on a difference of opinion as to how the evidence should be evaluated rather than on a specific error in the prior decision. Authorizes Board members to collect medical opinions from Board employees, Department employees, or employees of other Federal departments and agencies, as long as such employees are licensed to practice medicine in any State. Requires such opinions to be in writing and to be made part of the record, with an opportunity for the appellant to respond. Revises provisions concerning appellant hearing procedures.

	</summary>
</bill>
