<bill session="103" type="s" number="1448" updated="2012-07-17T05:34:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Police Corps and Law Enforcement Scholarship and Employment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bil to establish a Police Corps Program and a Law Enforcement Scholarship and Employment Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409580"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407786" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-09-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400564" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1993-09-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11445-11446)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Leave of absence"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Part-time employment"/>
		<term name="Police"/>
		<term name="Police training"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Student employment"/>
		<term name="Summer employment"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/10/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Police Corps Program Title II: Enforcement Scholarship and Employment Program Police Corps and Law Enforcement Scholarship and Employment Act - Requires a State that desires to participate in the Police Corps program or the Law Enforcement Scholarship program (established pursuant to this Act) to designate a lead agency and submit a State plan containing assurances with respect to: (1) lead agency cooperation with other State and local agencies; (2) the State advertising of the assistance available; (3) State screening and selection of law enforcement personnel for participation in the program; and (4) compliance with other specified requirements. Title I: Police Corps Program - Establishes within the Department of Justice (DOJ) an Office of the Police Corps to be headed by a Director. (Sec. 103) Authorizes the Director to award scholarships (including direct payments to institutions and reimbursement of educational costs) to participants who agree to work for four years in a State or local police force after completion of a baccalaureate program and police corps training, subject to specified conditions. Sets forth provisions with respect to: (1) scholarship assistance for dependent children of law enforcement officers; (2) the selection of participants; (3) minority recruitment; and (4) leaves of absence. (Sec. 105) Requires the Director to establish up to three training centers to provide basic law enforcement training to State Police Corps program participants. Requires participants to attend two eight-week training sessions at such training centers and to meet certain performance standards in order to remain in the Police Corps program. Requires the Director to pay participants a weekly stipend during training. (Sec. 107) Requires a State, in order to participate in the Police Corps program, to submit a plan for implementing such program to the Director for approval. Requires such plan to: (1) include assurances that participants will receive additional State or local training after completing Federal training which shall count toward the four-year service obligation; and (2) provide that program participants shall be assigned to community and preventive patrol in geographic areas with the greatest need for additional law enforcement personnel. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the swearing in of participants as members of the police force which they are assigned after completing Federal training and meeting the requirements of that police force; (2) layoffs; and (3) assistance to States and localities employing Police Corps officers. (Sec. 110) Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Law Enforcement Scholarship and Employment Program - Directs each State to pay from funds under this Act the Federal share (not more than 60 percent) of the costs of: (1) awarding scholarships to in-service law enforcement personnel for further education; and (2) providing full-time employment in the summer or part-time (up to 20 hours per week) employment for a period not to exceed one year. (Sec. 206) Sets forth application requirements. Grants priority in awarding scholarships to persons who are members of underrepresented groups, are pursuing an undergraduate degree, and are not receiving financial assistance under the Higher Education Act of 1965. (Sec. 208) Requires each scholarship recipient to work in a law enforcement position in the State for a period of one month for each credit hour for which funds are received under the scholarship (with a six-month minimum and two-year maximum). (Sec. 210) Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
