<bill session="103" type="s" number="1454" updated="2012-07-17T05:23:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Breast Cancer Strategy Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to research on breast cancer.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11683-11684)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7054)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="615" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Breast cancer"/>
		<term name="Cancer research"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Lung cancer"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Prostate cancer"/>
		<term name="Psychiatric research"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/14/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Establishment of Office of Breast Cancer and National Breast Cancer Commission Title II: Duties of Director of the National Cancer Institute Relating to Breast Cancer National Breast Cancer Strategy Act of 1993 - Title I: Establishment of Office of Breast Cancer and National Breast Cancer Commission - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish: (1) the Office of Breast Cancer in the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health; and (2) the National Breast Cancer Commission to study public and private breast cancer prevention, early detection, treatment, education, and research. Title II: Duties of Director of the National Cancer Institute Relating to Breast Cancer - Authorizes appropriations for conducting and supporting breast cancer research. Adds biomedical and behavioral research, training, and dissemination of information regarding breast cancer to the duties of the National Cancer Institute Director. Establishes the Rose Kushner Scholarship Program of scholarships in exchange for completing post-graduate clinical oncology training and serving as National Institutes of Health (NIH) employees carrying out breast cancer programs. Establishes a program of educational loan repayments in exchange for breast cancer activities as NIH employees. Authorizes appropriations for at least ten programs for research on breast, lung, and prostate cancer under designated Specialized Programs of Research Excellence.

	</summary>
</bill>
