<bill session="103" type="s" number="1459" updated="2012-07-17T04:10:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal Waters Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make improvements in the protection of coastal waters, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11916-11918)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Bacteria"/>
		<term name="Bacterial diseases"/>
		<term name="Beaches"/>
		<term name="Biodegradation"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Coast guard"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
		<term name="Estuarine ecology"/>
		<term name="Estuarine pollution"/>
		<term name="Eutrophication"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Industrial pollution"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marine insurance"/>
		<term name="Marine pollution"/>
		<term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
		<term name="Marine terminals"/>
		<term name="Nitrogen"/>
		<term name="Nonpoint source pollution"/>
		<term name="Passenger ships"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Plastics"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Sewage disposal"/>
		<term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
		<term name="Ships"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Storm drains"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Virus diseases"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Whistle blowing"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/15/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Beach Testing and Monitoring Title II: Coastal Protection Title III: Pollution from Ships Coastal Waters Improvement Act of 1993 - Title I: Beach Testing and Monitoring - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue water quality criteria for pathogens in coastal recreation waters. Requires States to adopt consistent water quality standards. (Sec. 103) Requires the Administrator to publish regulations specifying methods to be used by States to monitor coastal recreation waters, during periods of use by the public, for compliance with standards. Requires notification of local governments and the public of water quality standards violations. Requires the Administrator to: (1) issue guidance on uniform assessment and monitoring procedures for floatable materials in coastal recreation waters; and (2) specify the conditions under which the presence of floatable materials constitutes a threat to public health and safety. (Sec. 104) Requires an ongoing study and report to the Congress on developing better indicators for detecting harmful bacteria and viruses in coastal recreation waters. (Sec. 105) Authorizes the Administrator to make grants to States to fulfill requirements under this Act. (Sec. 107) Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Coastal Protection - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to direct the EPA Administrator to: (1) submit a coastal environment toxics release strategy to the Congress; and (2) prepare an annual assessment of the extent and environmental effect of certain industrial discharges into marine waters. (Sec. 204) Extends the authorization of appropriations for the National Estuary Program. (Sec. 205) Directs the Administrator to list each marine water that does not support the protection and propagation of a balanced, indigenous population of fish and wildlife and allow for recreational activities in and on the water. Requires the Administrator, with respect to such waters, to: (1) implement certain ocean discharge criteria requirements when issuing a permit for point source discharges; (2) consider prohibiting the use of such waters as disposal sites or restricting their use; (3) prohibit the discharge of sewage from vessels; (4) implement a management program for the watershed areas; and (5) enforce programs for the pretreatment of industrial waste discharges. Requires States to adopt standards for any pollutant for which the Administrator has established criteria if the pollutant is likely to be present in such waters. (Sec. 206) Directs the Administrator to establish a national program to provide information and technical assistance to owners of marine land. (Sec. 207) Makes it unlawful to discharge sewage: (1) into waters designated under this Act; and (2) that has not been treated by a marine sanitation device. Requires the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to provide for a public use pumpout station for marine sanitation devices at each Coast Guard installation. Waives such requirement under certain circumstances. (Sec. 208) Directs the Administrator to submit a five-year plan for the development, review, and revision of criteria for pollutants found in marine waters to the Congress. Requires each State that borders on marine waters to establish marine and numerical water quality standards. (Sec. 209) Conditions the issuance of permits for discharges into the territorial sea, the waters of the contiguous zone, the oceans, or waters designated under this Act on the protection of fish and wildlife and recreational activity and the attainment of marine water quality standards. (Sec. 210) Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to provide financial assistance to local governments for the construction of facilities for the control of overflows from combined storm and sanitary sewers to marine waters. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 212) Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress on Federal activities that may result in degradation of marine waters. Directs Federal agencies to minimize degradation and to consider alternative actions to avoid adverse effects on marine waters. Title III: Pollution From Ships - Amends the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships to authorize the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to issue a certificate attesting to the adequancy of garbage reception facilities at a port or terminal only if an onsite inspection has been conducted prior to the issuance of a certificate. Makes such certificates valid for a period of five years unless there is a change of operator. (Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations that require the operators of ports or terminals subject to MARPOL Protocol (the Protocol of 1978 relating to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution From Ships, 1973) requirements relating to reception facilities to post placards stating that users should report facility inadequacies to the Secretary. Requires all vessels to display placards and conduct briefings that notify the crew and passengers of requirements of Annex V of the Convention. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to refuse or revoke certain clearances or permits to proceed or depart of foreign vessels in violation of MARPOL requirements. Provides for a toll-free telephone number for reporting MARPOL violations. (Sec. 303) Amends the Marine Plastic Pollution Research and Control Act of 1987 to prohibit ports or terminals from charging a vessel a separate fee for the disposal of waste that is not regulated by the Secretary of Agriculture in carrying out the functions of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service. Expresses the sense of the Congress that certain shipper insurance policies should not provide for the payment of penalties under the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships. Requires persons in charge of vessels to include information on the disposal of onboard waste in the notice of arrival to the port. Directs the EPA Administrator to establish a Marine Debris Coordinating Committee.

	</summary>
</bill>
