<bill session="103" type="s" number="1462" updated="2012-07-17T05:59:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nonviolent Futures for Children Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce and prevent the incidence of violence involving children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11928-11929)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Community and school"/>
		<term name="Continuing education"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Dropouts"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="School personnel"/>
		<term name="School violence"/>
		<term name="School-to-work transition"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/15/1993--Introduced.
Nonviolent Futures for Children Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to eligible local educational agencies for preventive services and interventions to reduce the incidence of violence. Gives priority to areas with high concentrations of disadvantaged students and high rates of violence affecting children and youth. Allows such grants to be used for: (1) school-based activities, including peer education or mediation, conflict resolution training, social skills training, youth designed and developed programs, parenting education, postsecondary educational opportunity projects, or remodeling and security personnel; or (2) school-community partnership activities, including after-school programs, mentoring programs, parenting skills courses, professional training for school personnel, or job training and placement. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to eligible entities for establishing community-based programs to: (1) assist out-of-school youth and rehabilitate youth offenders; and (2) provide opportunities for such youth to continue their education or obtain job training. Gives priority to areas with high concentrations of out-of-school youth or youth offenders and high rates of violence affecting children and youth. Allows such grants to be used for community-based programs, including peer and adult support and redirection, incentives for continuing education, assessments of needs and referrals to appropriate services, community service, job training and placement opportunities, mentoring services, and other rehabilitative opportunities. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
