<bill session="103" type="s" number="1463" updated="2012-07-17T05:27:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Education for Girls and Boys Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to address gender equity in mathematics and science education and to assist schools and educational institutions in the elimination of sexual harassment and abuse.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300073"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1993-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1994-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-11-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1994-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11931-11932)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Assault"/>
		<term name="Computers in education"/>
		<term name="Eating disorders"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational counseling"/>
		<term name="Educational statistics"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Mathematics"/>
		<term name="Mental depression"/>
		<term name="School health programs"/>
		<term name="School violence"/>
		<term name="Scientific education"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination in education"/>
		<term name="Sexual harassment of women"/>
		<term name="Suicide"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Vocational guidance"/>
		<term name="Women's education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/15/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Gender Equity in Mathematics and Science Education Title II: Elimination of Sexual Harassment and Abuse Fairness in Education for Girls and Boys Act of 1993 - Title I: Gender Equity in Mathematics and Science Education - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to revise the Eisenhower Mathematics and Science Education program with respect to: (1) grants to higher education institutions for elementary and secondary mathematics and science programs of school teacher training in gender-equitable instruction, targeted intervention and followup to encourage historically underserved students, and community-based informal education for historically underserved and underrepresented students; (2) State application statistics on sex and race (or ethnicity) of students and teachers involved; (3) Federal model standards for reporting data by sex within race (or ethnicity) and socioeconomic status; and (4) model program grant priority for gender equity in computer use and teaching practices; and (5) national clearinghouse information dissemination; (6) regional consortia use of funds; and (7) programs for computer-based instruction. Title II: Elimination of Sexual Harassment and Abuse - Amends ESEA to make an environment free from sexual harassment and abuse a distinguishing feature of effective schools. Adds to certain targeted uses of funds certain programs of training, technical assistance, and education designed to eliminate sexual harassment and abuse in schools. Adds programs to address sexual harassment and violence as part of efforts to ensure that educational institutions are free from threats to student and employee safety (among programs which may receive Women's Educational Equity assistance). Includes the areas of sexual harassment and assault, depression and suicide, and eating disorders among those for which grants for comprehensive school health education may be used.

	</summary>
</bill>
