<bill session="103" type="s" number="1478" updated="2012-07-17T04:52:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food Quality Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to ensure that pesticide tolerances adequately safeguard the health of infants and children, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408939"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406084" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="408252" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-10-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1994-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-10-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="403962" joined="1994-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1993-09-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12130-12131)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-29"><committee name="Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Committee on Agriculture. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><committee name="Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Subcommittee on Agricultural Research. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="Agricultural Research, Conservation, Forestry and General Legislation" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agricultural research"/>
		<term name="Agricultural statistics"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Child nutrition"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Farm produce"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Food additives"/>
		<term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
		<term name="Food industry"/>
		<term name="Food safety"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Integrated pest management"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Packaging"/>
		<term name="Pest control"/>
		<term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
		<term name="Pesticide residues in food"/>
		<term name="Pesticides"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Veterinary medicine"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/21/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Data Collection and Procedures to Ensure that Tolerances Safeguard the Health of Infants and Children Title II: Cancellation and Suspension Title III: Amendments to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act Food Quality Protection Act of 1993 - Title I: Data Collection and Procedures to Ensure that Tolerances Safeguard the Health of Infants and Children - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretaries of Agriculture and Health and Human Services to establish procedures to ensure that pesticide tolerances adequately safeguard the health of infants and children based on the recommendations of a specified report prepared by the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences. (Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to collect pesticide use data of statewide or regional significance for all the major crops and crops of dietary significance. (Sec. 103) Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) to mandate research, development, and dissemination of integrated pest management techniques and other pest control methods that enable producers to reduce or eliminate application of pesticides which pose a greater than negligible dietary risk to humans. Title II: Cancellation and Suspension - Amends FIFRA provisions relating to cancellations, changes in classifications, or other terms of registration with respect to the authority of the Administrator. Requires that a rulemaking under such provisions be based on a validated test or other significant evidence raising prudent concerns of unreasonable adverse effects to the environment. Denies registration applications that are not in compliance with this Act. Title III: Amendments to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FDCA) to define, subject to exception, &quot;pesticide chemical&quot; as it is defined in FIFRA. (Sec. 304) Deems a food adulterated if it bears or contains: (1) a pesticide chemical residue that is unsafe; or (2) a new animal drug or conversion product that is unsafe. (Sec. 305) Sets forth requirements relating to tolerances and exemptions from tolerances for pesticide chemical residues in food, including residues of degradation products. Prohibits establishment of a tolerance higher than a level the Administrator determines is adequate to protect the public health. Allows a greater than negligible dietary risk if: (1) use protects from greater adverse health effects to humans or the environment; (2) use avoids greater risks from another pesticide; or (3) the unavailability of the pesticide would reduce the availability of an adequate, wholesome, and economical domestic supply of the food, and the adverse effects from the reduction would outweigh the risk posed by the residue. Allows the Administrator to issue an exemption from the requirement for a tolerance only if a tolerance is not needed to protect the public health, in view of the levels of dietary exposure that could reasonably be expected to occur. Prohibits a final rule that revokes, modifies, or suspends a tolerance or exemption until the Administrator has taken any necessary action under FIFRA with respect to the registration of the pesticide involved. Requires the Administrator, if the Administrator takes certain actions with respect to the registration of a pesticide, to revoke any tolerance or exemption that allows the presence of the chemical or chemical residue. Requires the suspension of any tolerance or exemption upon the suspension of the use of an associated registered pesticide. Provides for: (1) tolerances for unavoidable residues in the case of a residue of a canceled or suspended pesticide chemical that will unavoidably persist in the environment and be present in or on a food; and (2) residues resulting from an application which was lawful at the time of application. Prohibits, subject to exception, a State from enforcing any limit on a qualifying pesticide chemical residue in or on any food which is not identical to Federal requirements. Prohibits a State from enforcing a residue limit which was lawful at the time of application. (Sec. 306) Authorizes appropriations for increased monitoring of pesticide residues in imported and domestic food.

	</summary>
</bill>
