<bill session="103" type="s" number="1496" updated="2012-07-17T04:24:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">High Technology Indexation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 to provide for updated indexing standards for emerging technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-09-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12732-12733)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Computers"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Supercomputers"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/1993--Introduced.
High Technology Indexation Act of 1993 - Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979 to change from discretionary to mandatory the Secretary of Commerce's authority to establish indexing standards which provide for automatic increases (instead of currently authorized annual increases) in the performance levels of certain goods or technology subject to export licensing controls. Requires removal from the commodity control list of goods or technology which no longer require licensing under the increased performance level standards, unless the Secretary reports to specified congressional committees that removal of controls will permit exports detrimental to U.S. national security or U.S. policies. Directs the Secretary to require technical advisory committees to recommend indexing standards for certain goods or technology. Requires the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register a performance-based indexing system to ensure that the definition of &quot;supercomputer&quot; and all controls and security safeguard procedures on supercomputer exports or reexports are commensurate with technological advances. Sets forth circumstances under which such safeguards are not required.

	</summary>
</bill>
