<bill session="103" type="s" number="1493" updated="2010-04-19T18:23:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-24">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-09-24" where="s" result="pass" how="by Voice Vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">South African Democratic Transition Support Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the transition to nonracial democracy in South Africa.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406188"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="407786" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1993-09-24" withdrawn="1993-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400558" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400564" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1993-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-09-24" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S12491-12495"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-09-27T13:03:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-27"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-27T16:49:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Banking, Finance + Urban Affrs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Public Works + Transportation.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Referred jointly to the House Committee on Government Operations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-12-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-12-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSWM-04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral" />
		<committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSGO-06" name="House Government Operations" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3225" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3225" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Apartheid"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="EEC countries"/>
		<term name="Economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Economic growth"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational exchanges"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Export credit"/>
		<term name="Export finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Free enterprise"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="Japan"/>
		<term name="Local government"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="South Africa"/>
		<term name="State politics and government"/>
		<term name="Tax treaties"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/1993--Introduced.
South African Democratic Transition Support Act of 1993 - Expresses the sense of the Congress with respect to U.S. policy towards South Africa. Repeals specified provisions of the Comprehensive Anti-Apartheid Act of 1986, providing for a total repeal of such Act when the President certifies to the Congress that an interim government that was elected on a nonracial basis through free and fair elections has taken office in South Africa. Urges all State or local governments and private entities in the United States to rescind any restrictions on economic interactions with South Africa. Authorizes the President to provide development and economic support fund assistance to support the transition to nonracial democracy in South Africa. Prohibits such assistance to the Government of South Africa unless the President certifies to the Congress that an interim government elected on a nonracial basis through free and fair elections has taken office. Exempts from such prohibition assistance to the Transitional Executive Council, South African higher education institutions, and any other entity that would promote the transition to nonracial democracy. Declares that the President should: (1) negotiate a tax treaty with South Africa; (2) initiate negotiations with the South African Government to provide for Overseas Private Investment Corporation programs in such country; (3) conclude cooperative agreements with South Africa on various issues; and (4) encourage other donors to expand their activities in support of the transition to nonracial democracy. States that: (1) the Director of the Trade and Development Agency should provide additional funds for projects in South Africa; (2) the Export-Import Bank should expand its activities in connection with exports to South Africa; and (3) the Director of the U.S. Information Agency should use his authorities to promote the transition to nonracial democracy. Requires the heads of Federal Government agencies, in procuring goods or services, to make affirmative efforts to assist business enterprises having more than 50 percent ownership by nonwhite South Africans. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. executive directors of international financial institutions to urge financial assistance to South Africa to support the transition to democracy.

	</summary>
</bill>
