<bill session="103" type="s" number="1503" updated="2012-07-17T06:19:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans PTSD Treatment and Psychological Readjustment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand services provided by the Department of Veterans' Affairs for veterans suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD).</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400566"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1993-11-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12850-12851)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Halfway houses"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health counseling"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Mental health services"/>
		<term name="Military dependents"/>
		<term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
		<term name="Psychiatrists"/>
		<term name="Psychologists"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Veterans' employment"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/30/1993--Introduced.
Veterans PTSD Treatment and Psychological Readjustment Act of 1993 - States that it shall be the policy of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to implement the recommendations of the Special Committee on Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder to establish and operate specialized inpatient post-traumatic stress disorder units (SIPUs) at Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers. Requires such facilities and services to be available to all eligible veterans, including veterans of the Persian Gulf War. Requires the Secretary to gradually increase the number of SIPUs in order to meet a total increase of not less than 30 units by the end of 1997. Requires the Secretary to direct the Special Committee to identify areas of the country in which there are significant needs for expanding the Vet Center program. Requires a gradual increase in the number of Vet Centers in order to meet a total increase of not less than 40 by the end of 1997. Requires the Secretary to furnish counseling at the request of any veteran who served in a combat theater of operations while on active duty. Establishes in the Department the Advisory Committee on Veteran Readjustment Counseling and requires such Committee to report to the Secretary on recommendations to increase outreach efforts to Vietnam-era and post-Vietnam-era veterans who have readjustment counseling needs. Directs the Secretary to conduct a pilot program to contract for care and treatment and rehabilitative services in halfway houses, therapeutic communities, psychiatric residential treatment centers, and other community based treatment facilities for eligible veterans suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Directs the Special Committee to report to specified congressional committees on PTSD contract care. Requires the Secretary, in administering the Health Professionals Educational Assistance Program, to encourage the participation of individuals who desire to become psychologists, psychiatrists, and related personnel specializing in the treatment of PTSD. Requires the Department's Under Secretary for Health to conduct a research program into the most effective treatment modalities for PTSD, including family involvement. States that it shall be the policy of the Secretary to implement the recommendations of the Special Committee to establish and operate PTSD clinical teams at Department medical centers which provide mental health services. Directs the Secretary to increase the number of such clinical teams by 50 units by the end of 1997.

	</summary>
</bill>
