<bill session="103" type="s" number="1511" updated="2012-07-17T04:54:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-09-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-09-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violent Crime Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to eliminate the crediting of &quot;good time&quot; for violent and repeat offenders in Federal and State prisons, authorize funding for boot camps and the conversion of military facilities to regional prisons, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400564" joined="1993-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1993-10-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1993-10-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12862-12863)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13028-13030)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13115-13116)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal statistics"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health counseling"/>
		<term name="Judicial statistics"/>
		<term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Medical tests"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Military training camps"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="State courts"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/30/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Elimination of &quot;Good Time&quot; for Violent and Repeat Offenders Title II: Boot Camps and Prisons Title III: Sentencing Reports Title IV: Victim's Right of Allocution Violent Crime Prevention Act of 1993 - Title I: Elimination of &quot;Good Time&quot; for Violent and Repeat Offenders - Amends: (1) the Federal criminal code to exclude Federal prisoners convicted of a crime of violence or of more than one felony from provisions regarding credit toward service of sentence for satisfactory behavior (good time); and (2) the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (Omnibus Act) to require the elimination of certain formula grants to States failing to prohibit the crediting of the State equivalent of good time with respect to such prisoners and to reduce the amount allocated to States not requiring State officials to administer to a convicted defendant a test for acquired immune deficiency syndrome, disclose the results to the defendant and victim, and provide the victim with related counseling, testing, and referral. Title II: Boot Camps and Prisons - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish within the Bureau of Prisons ten military-style boot camp prisons, located on closed military installations, to provide a highly regimented schedule of strict discipline, physical training, work, drill, and ceremony characteristic of military basic training, and remedial education and treatment for substance abuse; and (2) acquire, convert, and operate as regional prisons at least ten former military facilities. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Sentencing Reports - Directs the Attorney General to prepare and make available to the public an annual report on the sentences that were imposed by each Federal judge during the preceding year on defendants convicted of Federal felonies. Amends the Omnibus Act to require the elimination of formula grants to States not requiring that annual reports be submitted on the sentences imposed by each State judge on defendants convicted of State felonies. Title IV: Victim's Right of Allocution - Amends: (1) Rule 32 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to require the Court, before sentencing a defendant for a crime of violence or sexual abuse, to address the victim personally and determine if the victim wishes to make a statement and present information in relation to the sentence; and (2) the Omnibus Act to require the elimination of formula grants to States not providing for a victim's right of allocution.

	</summary>
</bill>
