<bill session="103" type="s" number="1521" updated="2012-07-17T04:35:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Endangered Species Act Procedural Reform Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to improve and protect the integrity of the programs of such Act for the conservation of threatened and endangered species, to ensure balanced consideration of all impacts of decisions implementing such Act, to provide for equitable treatment of non-Federal persons and Federal agencies under such Act, to encourage non-Federal persons to contribute voluntarily to species conservation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300089"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1993-11-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1993-11-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="406256" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="411271" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1994-01-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1993-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13172-13173)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-29"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Clean Water, Fisheries. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Clean Water, Fisheries and Wildlife" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
		<term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Eminent domain"/>
		<term name="Endangered species"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Hunting"/>
		<term name="International environmental law"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Parties to actions"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Trapping"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Ensuring the Integrity of the Listing, Critical Habitat Designation, and Consultation Processes Title II: Providing Significance to the Recovery Planning Process Title III: Ensuring that the Compliance Procedures and Standards for Non-Federal Persons Are Not More Burdensome than the Procedures and Standards Applicable to Federal Agencies Title IV: Providing for Habitat Conservation Incentive Programs Title V: Reauthorization and Other Amendments Endangered Species Act Procedural Reform Amendments of 1993 - Title I: Ensuring the Integrity of the Listing, Critical Habitat Designation, and Consultation Processes - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to establish a peer review (upon request) requirement with respect to a determination of endangered or threatened species status. (Sec. 103) Establishes discretionary priorities for determining and conserving endangered or threatened species. (Sec. 105) Requires that the economic impact be considered in making a critical habitat determination. (Sec. 107) Revises consultation and related provisions, including establishing procedures with respect to private actions. Title II: Providing Significance to the Recovery Planning Process - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to develop and implement a recovery plan for each endangered or threatened species, unless the Secretary determines such plan to be unnecessary. Gives priority to multispecies plans. Title III: Ensuring that the Compliance Procedures and Standards for Non-Federal Persons Are Not More Burdensome than the Procedures and and Standards Applicable to Federal Agencies - Establishes consultation and permit conditions for non-Federal activities concerning endangered or threatened species. (Sec. 306) Exempts non-Federal persons under specified circumstances from prohibitions against the taking of an endangered species. (Sec. 307) Provides for compensation of property owners adversely affected by specified determinations pursuant to such Act. Title IV: Providing for Habitat Conservation Incentive Programs - Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into an agreement (Cooperative Management Agreement) with any affected non-Federal person (currently, only with a State) for the management of a species' habitat; and (2) provide grants to any non-Federal person for habitat preservation of endangered or threatened species. Title V: Reauthorization and Other Amendments - Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) experimental population release; (2) captive propagation, including grants; and (3) citizen suits. (Sec. 505) Authorizes appropriations for activities under such Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
