<bill session="103" type="s" number="1525" updated="2012-07-17T05:16:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Language Assistance Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the quantity and quality of foreign language instruction offered in our Nation's elementary and secondary schools.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404598"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-01-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13265-13266)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Private schools"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Teachers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1993--Introduced.
Foreign Language Assistance Act of 1993 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a foreign language assistance program. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants: (1) as allocations to States in any fiscal year in which appropriations equal or exceed a specified amount; or (2) when appropriations are below such amount, to State educational agencies, local educational agencies (LEAs), consortia of LEAs, or consortia of LEAs and institutions of higher education. Requires that half of such funds be used for foreign language instructional programs at elementary and secondary schools and half for foreign language teacher development and recruitment. Authorizes as Federal activities: (1) grants for model demonstration programs of foreign language instruction for elementary or secondary school students; (2) evaluation and research; and (3) bonus grants to States for having specified levels of foreign language requirements or enrollments. Provides for Federal share and for participation of children and teachers from private schools. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
