<bill session="103" type="s" number="1535" updated="2012-07-17T04:09:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-09">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-11-09" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Early Out bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Workforce Restructuring Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Workforce Restructuring Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to eliminate narrow restrictions on employee training, to provide a temporary voluntary separation incentive, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404598"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1993-10-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1993-10-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13279-13280)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19"><committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/><text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-683.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-09"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/><text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-02-04"><text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Glenn with amendments. With written report No. 103-223.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="362" datetime="1994-02-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 362.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-04-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4087"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-11"><text>See also H.R. 3345.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3345" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3345" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Civil service retirement"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
		<term name="Dismissal wage"/>
		<term name="Early retirement"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
		<term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="Judicial compensation"/>
		<term name="Judicial officers"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Magistrates"/>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Federal Workforce Restructuring Act of 1993 - Amends Federal civil service law to eliminate various restrictions on employee training. Authorizes temporary &quot;buy-out&quot; programs for encouraging selected groups of employees in the executive and judicial branches (except employees of the Department of Defense, Central Intelligence Agency, or the General Accounting Office) to separate from Government service, generally by September 30, 1994, by offering them lump-sum payments in order to assist in the restructuring of the Federal workforce while minimizing reductions in force (RIFs). Requires: (1) such payments (the lesser of $25,000 or the amount of the employee's severance pay) to be paid from amounts available for the employee's pay, and, generally, to be fully repaid if the employee rejoins the Federal Government within five years of separation; (2) employment in the executive branch to be reduced by at least one full-time equivalent position for each one vacated by reason of a lump-sum payment; (3) that there be no increase in service contract procurement by reason of this Act except where it is financially advantageous to the Federal Government; and (4) participating Federal agencies to make a specified contribution to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund based on the final rate of basic pay of each employee who retires early. Authorizes the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts to establish a program for judicial employees consistent with this Act. Sets annual limitations on the total number of full-time equivalent executive agency positions each year through FY 1999, subject to waiver under certain conditions, such as war or national emergency. Prevents further agency hiring in cases of noncompliance with such limitations. Amends Federal civil service law and the Central Intelligence Agency Voluntary Separation Pay Act regarding the forgiveness of the lump-sum repayment obligations of bought-out employees reemployed in positions for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting qualified employees. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to make conforming reductions in the discretionary spending limits under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 over such five year period. Revises the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP), with changes providing all separating TSP participants with the same options for withdrawal. Amends the Alaska Railroad Transfer Act of 1982 to allow application to employees of a State-owned railroad under such Act of the buyout provisions of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
