<bill session="103" type="s" number="154" updated="2012-07-17T05:29:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ronald Reagan Peace Dividend Investment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to insure that any peace dividend is invested in America's families and deficit reduction.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300159"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1993-11-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Budget; Governmental Affairs pursuant to the order of august 4, 1977, with instructions that if one Committee reports, the other Committee have thirty days to report or be discharged.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exemption"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Ronald Reagan Peace Dividend Investment Act - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide for a reduction in the deficit and an increase in the personal income tax exemption when outlays in the defense category for FY 1993 or 1994 are estimated to be below the discretionary spending limit for such outlays. Requires an adjustment in such spending limits under such circumstances. Prohibits Senate consideration of legislation that would reduce defense spending below the spending limit for the defense category if such legislation does not allocate the total amount of reduced new budget authority or outlays between deficit reduction and increases in the personal income tax exemption.

	</summary>
</bill>
