<bill session="103" type="s" number="1544" updated="2012-07-17T05:42:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">World Summit for Children Implementation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assist in implementing the Plan of Action adopted by the World Summit for Children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-10-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-10-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13492-13493)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14769)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
		<term name="Adult education"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Child nutrition"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Debt relief"/>
		<term name="Deficiency diseases"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Food relief"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
		<term name="Illiteracy"/>
		<term name="Infant mortality"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International cooperation"/>
		<term name="International economic relations"/>
		<term name="Literacy programs"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Philippines"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Poverty"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Refugee policy"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Vaccination"/>
		<term name="Vitamins"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="World health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/14/1993--Introduced.
World Summit for Children Implementation Act of 1993 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that specified amounts should be appropriated for FY 1994 and 1995 to achieve full participation in the special supplemental food program for women, infants, and children under the Child Nutrition Act (WIC program) and the Head Start program. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize appropriations for FY 1994 and 1995 for contributions to the United Nation's Children's Fund and for the Child Survival Fund. Expresses the sense of the Congress that authority should be granted to the President to exercise specified debt forgiveness for least developed countries that are pursuing economic policy reforms to promote long-term development. Earmarks development assistance funds for FY 1994 and 1995 for the Vitamin A Deficiency Program. Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 1994 and 1995 for: (1) iodine and iron fortification programs; and (2) prevention, care, and control programs related to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) and acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) in developing countries. Earmarks development and economic assistance funds for FY 1994 and 1995 for programs in support of basic education. Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 1994 and 1995 for population assistance activities. Expresses the sense of the Congress that specified amounts should be appropriated for FY 1994 and 1995 for migration and refugee assistance. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the World Bank to: (1) ensure that poverty reduction and support of basic human needs become a higher priority within the Bank; (2) ensure that the majority of water and sanitation projects fall within targeted interventions against poverty; and (3) increase the proportion of total Bank lending which supports primary health care and basic education, with a minimum of five percent of total lending devoted to each area. Requires the President to call upon other governments to provide their share of resources required to achieve the World Summit for Children goals by the year 2000.

	</summary>
</bill>
