<bill session="103" type="s" number="1547" updated="2012-07-17T06:20:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Drinking Water Act Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and amend title XIV of the Public Health Service Act (commonly known as the &quot;Safe Drinking Water Act&quot;), and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-11-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13495-13496, S13510-13512)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-438.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Carcinogens"/>
		<term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
		<term name="Interstate commerce"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Lead"/>
		<term name="Lead poisoning"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Negligence"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
		<term name="Radioactive pollution of water"/>
		<term name="Radon"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/14/1993--Introduced.
Safe Drinking Water Act Amendments of 1993 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to make capitalization grants to States to establish State drinking water treatment revolving loan funds. Requires the Administrator to reserve one percent of funds for such grants for financial assistance to Indian tribes for the improvement of public water systems and to respond to public health emergencies, respectively. Authorizes the Administrator to make grants for the improvement of public water systems to the District of Columbia and specified U.S. terrorities. Directs States to prepare intended use plans prior to receiving grants. Requires priority for the use of funds to be given to public water systems that are in violation of a national primary drinking water regulation and in which residential water system rates are the highest percentage of median household income. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes (currently, requires) the Administrator to publish a maximum contaminant level goal (MCLG) and promulgate a national primary drinking water regulation for any contaminant that may have adverse health effects and is anticipated to occur in public water systems in a concentration that indicates a public health concern. Requires the Administrator to publish a list and assessment of at least 15 unregulated contaminants that present the greatest public health concern, with additional lists and assessments of at least seven contaminants every three years. Directs the Administrator to publish health assessments for listed contaminants. Requires the Administrator to establish a publicly-available data base on the occurrence of unregulated contaminants in public water systems. Authorizes a minimum of seven State Governors to petition the Administrator to publish an MCLG and a national primary drinking water regulation for a contaminant. Requires drinking water regulations to be reviewed at least once every six (currently, three) years. Authorizes the Administrator to modify a drinking water regulation to remove monitoring requirements for public water systems that have not detected the contaminant that is the subject of the regulation if the systems have conducted at least two rounds of monitoring and the contaminant has only been detected at specified minimum levels. Permits the Administrator to modify monitoring requirements with respect to cancer-causing contaminants to waive such requirement for public water systems serving populations of fewer than 10,000 individuals if monitoring for any one quarter after this Act's enactment fails to detect the presence of the contaminant. Revises provisions concerning variances to drinking water regulations to require States with primary enforcement responsibility to submit triennially to the Administrator a State drinking water supply plan for the management of public water systems that serve fewer than 3,300 individuals. Provides for one of the following management approaches for systems that are in violation of a maximum contaminant level (MCL): (1) compliance with an MCL if the system has the financial and management capacity to comply; or (2) an individualized compliance program that implements consolidation, alternative water supply, alternative small system technology, or other system restructuring. Requires the Administrator, at the same time a drinking water regulation for a contaminant is published, to publish guidance describing treatment technologies associated with the contaminant that is appropriate for systems serving fewer than 3,300 individuals. Sets forth enforcement authorities. Requires the Administrator to issue regulations to establish a health-effects based performance standard that establishes minimal leaching levels of lead from new plumbing pipes, fittings, and fixtures that convey drinking water. Imposes restrictions on the importation, manufacturing, processing, or distribution in commerce of fixtures that contain more than a specified percentage of lead by dry weight if such regulations are not established. Directs the Administrator to promulgate national primary drinking water regulations and an MCL for radon. Permits alternative contaminant levels if a system is: (1) implementing an approved alternative compliance program; or (2) located in a State that is implementing a program to reduce radon in indoor air and is receiving specified grant assistance for the program. Lists requirements for alternative compliance programs. Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit Federal agencies from providing financial assistance relating to the financing of a residence located in a high-risk radon area unless the sale of the residence is conducted in compliance with regulations requiring testing for radon in indoor air at the time of such sale. Requires potential purchasers to be provided with results of any radon test and background information on radon health threats prior to the date of purchase of a residence in such an area. Requires the Administrator to establish a program to: (1) determine the effectiveness of water treatment devices designed to remove contaminants installed at a residence at the point of water use; and (2) ensure that consumers are provided with appropriate information about the devices at the time of sale. Replaces provisions concerning the sole source aquifer demonstration program and State programs to establish wellhead protection areas with programs to protect water supply areas. Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to make funds under such Act available for water supply protection programs. Authorizes appropriations for drinking water research, investigations, and demonstrations. Requires the Chief Operator of a public water system and additional personnel, as designated by the Administrator, to be certified for proficiency. Extends the authorization of appropriations for technical assistance to small water systems. Authorizes appropriations for public water system supervision programs and grants to States for groundwater protection. Replaces provisions concerning special project grants to require the Administrator to establish a program for the collection of fees from public water systems to support the costs of administration of public water system supervision programs in States without primary enforcement responsibility for the programs. Establishes the Public Drinking Water System Supervision Fund. Extends the authorization of appropriations for recordkeeping and inspection requirements. Waives the sovereign immunity of the United States with respect to any requirement, administrative authority, process, or sanction imposed concerning the provision of safe drinking water. Directs the Administrator to study and report to the Congress on the seriousness of contamination of private sources of drinking water that are not regulated by this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
