<bill session="103" type="s" number="1556" updated="2012-07-17T04:45:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require commercial television stations to maintain, and provide copies of, commercials and program promotions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300066"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1993-10-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13833-13834)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Cable television"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Television advertising"/>
		<term name="Television stations"/>
		<term name="Video tape recording"/>
		<term name="Violence in television"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/18/1993--Introduced.
Requires the Federal Communications Commission to prescribe a regulation requiring each commercial television broadcast station licensee and cable operator to: (1) maintain a copy of any commercial or program promotion for 30 days following its broadcast or transmission; (2) provide to any person, upon timely request, a video copy of any commercial or program promotion, subject to the payment of a reasonable charge for the cost of duplication; (3) maintain a copy of each complaint it receives regarding violent commercials or program promotions for a 12-month period, including any video which contains the subject of such complaint; (4) compile and maintain a record of each such complaint and the number of them received during the preceding 12 months; and (5) make a copy of such compiled material available, upon a written request, to the public.

	</summary>
</bill>
