<bill session="103" type="s" number="1569" updated="2012-07-17T06:13:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00">PASSED:BILL</state>
	<status><vote2 datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="without objection" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preventive Health Services and Health Professions Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Minority Health Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Disadvantaged Minority Health Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Disadvantaged Minority Health Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Multiethnic Placement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish, reauthorize and revise provisions to improve the health of individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by senate">An act to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend programs relating to the health of individuals who are members of minority groups, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1994-03-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13916)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-10-20"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-200.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="327" datetime="1993-11-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 327.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-03-26"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4037-4047"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-26"><text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-03-26" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-04-13"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill as reported.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14T10:02:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14T11:43:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Waxman asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3828-3835"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00"><text>The House struck all after the enacting clause and inserted in lieu thereof the provisions of a similar measure H.R. 3869. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended to that of similar measure H.R. 3869. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:11:00-04:00"><text>A similar measure H.R. 3869 was laid on the table without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:12:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Waxman asked unanimous consent that the House insist upon its amendments, and request a conference.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:12:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House insist upon its amendments, and request a conference Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3835"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:12:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Dingell, Waxman, Richardson, Towns, Washington, Moorhead, Bliley, and Bilirakis.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:12:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23T13:12:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Ways and Means for consideration of titles VI and VII of the Senate bill, and modifications committed to conference: Gibbons, Ford (TN), and Archer.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25"><text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate bill and House requests a conference.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><text>Senate disagreed to the House amendments by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><text>Senate agreed to request for conference. Appointed conferees. Kennedy; Metzenbaum; Simon; Kassebaum; Hatch.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S6855"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-26T19:14:00-04:00"><text>APPOINTMENT OF ADDITIONAL CONFEREES ON S. 1569. - The Speaker appointed the following Members as additional conferees from the Committee on Ways and Means for consideration of titles VI and VII of the Senate bill, and modifications committed to conference: Gibbons, Ford (TN), and Archer.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement held at the desk in Senate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06T23:20:00-04:00"><text>Conference report H. Rept. 103-843 filed.</text><reference label="text of conference report" ref="CR H11037-11053"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T02:42:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 574 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to S. 1569. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T16:49:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 574 passed House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T17:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Waxman brought up conference report H. Rept. 103-843 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 574.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T17:02:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 574, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T17:28:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T17:49:00-04:00"><text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="504" datetime="1994-10-07T17:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 394 - 5 (Roll no. 504).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11291"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="rule" session="103" type="hr" number="574" />
		<bill relation="supersedes" session="103" type="h" number="3869" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Adopted children"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="American Samoa"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Asian American ethnic groups"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Birth defects"/>
		<term name="Blacks"/>
		<term name="Blacks in medicine"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="Brain"/>
		<term name="Brain diseases"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Career education"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Clinics"/>
		<term name="College teachers"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Compensatory education"/>
		<term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer cooperatives"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Dental care"/>
		<term name="Dentists"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Diabetes"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse in pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Drug industry"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational counseling"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="English language"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Equal pay for equal work"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Eye diseases"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Family medicine"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Female circumcision"/>
		<term name="Fetal alcohol syndrome"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Foster home care"/>
		<term name="Geriatrics"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Hawaiians"/>
		<term name="Head injuries"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Homeless"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Indian medical care"/>
		<term name="Infant mortality"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Marshall Islands"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical laboratories"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Medical students"/>
		<term name="Mental health services"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Micronesia"/>
		<term name="Migrant labor"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Minority students"/>
		<term name="Minority teachers"/>
		<term name="Minority women"/>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="New York City"/>
		<term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
		<term name="Nursing education"/>
		<term name="Osteopathy and osteopaths"/>
		<term name="Pacific Islanders"/>
		<term name="Palau Islands"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Parental leave"/>
		<term name="Pay equity"/>
		<term name="Pharmacists"/>
		<term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Prescription pricing"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Primates"/>
		<term name="Psychologists"/>
		<term name="Public health"/>
		<term name="Public health personnel"/>
		<term name="Public housing"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Scientists in government"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Siblings"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
		<term name="Trauma care"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Urban areas"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women scientists"/>
		<term name="Women's employment"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s1605"/>
		<amendment number="s1606"/>
		<amendment number="s1607"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Conference report filed in House. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Office of Minority Health; Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights Title II: Primary Health Services Title III: Health Professions Programs Title IV: Research Title V: Native Hawaiian Health Care Title VI: Women's Health Title VII: Traumatic Brain Injury Title VIII: Miscellaneous Provisions Title IX: General Provisions Minority Health Improvement Act of 1994 - Title I: Office of Minority Health; Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise the duties of the Office of Minority Health. Provides for the establishment of the Advisory Committee on Minority Health to advise the Secretary of Health and Human Services concerning minority health. Authorizes appropriations through FY 1997. (Sec. 102) Requires each of the following agencies to establish its own Office of Minority Health: (1) Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; (2) Agency for Health Care Policy and Research; (3) Health Resources and Services Administration; (4) Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration; and (5) National Institutes of Health (NIH). Reserves 0.5 percent of an agency's appropriation for such Office. (Sec. 103) Establishes in the Department of Health and Human Services an Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Title II: Primary Health Services - Provides for the treatment of pregnant women for substance abuse by migrant health centers and community health centers. Authorizes the development and operation of more than one migrant or community health center in a catchment area if specified circumstances exist. Permits such centers to offer offsite services. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 202) Extends, through FY 1998, authorizations of appropriations for health services for: (1) the homeless; and (2) residents of public housing. (Sec. 204) Sets forth provisions concerning grants for: (1) loan repayment programs regarding obligated service of health professionals; (2) the operation of State offices of rural health; and (3) demonstrations for community scholarship programs regarding obligated services of health professionals. (Sec. 207) Revises provisions concerning programs regarding birth defects. (Sec. 208) Authorizes grants for up to 22 demonstration projects for the purpose of reducing the incidence of: (1) infant mortality; (2) low-birthweight births; and (3) maternal mortality. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 209) Provides for demonstration projects regarding diabetic-retinopathy. Directs the Secretary to make grants for such projects. (Sec. 210) Requires the Secretary to issue regulations to reduce the extent to which having limited English proficiency constitutes a significant impediment to individuals for eligibility in health programs under the Public Health Service Act. Title III: Health Professions Programs - Renames provisions concerning scholarships for students of exceptional financial need the Cesar Chavez Program for Primary Care Scholarships. Requires students receiving such a scholarship to be from a disadvantaged background and have a financial need for scholarship. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 302) Revises and renames the scholarship program for students from disadvantaged backgrounds the Thurgood Marshall Program for Health Services Scholarships. Makes designated schools of allied health eligible for such program. (Sec. 303) Revises and authorizes appropriations for the program on loan repayments and fellowships regarding faculty positions. (Sec. 304) Revises provisions concerning Centers of Excellence. Requires grants to be made only to designated health professions schools. Requires such Centers to carry out community-based training programs to prepare students in secondary schools and institutions of higher education for attendance at such schools. Requires such schools to train their students at community-based health facilities that provide services to a significant number of minority individuals and that are located at a site remote from the main facilities of the school. Allows such schools to establish consortia. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 305) Revises provisions concerning educational assistance regarding undergraduates. Authorizes grants to assist disadvantaged students who are interested in a career in the health professions who are students of either elementary, secondary, or higher level schools. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 306) Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) repayment of student loans for nursing students; (2) authorizations of appropriations for certain federally supported student loan funds with respect to certain medical schools and with respect to individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds; and (3) requirements for and funding of area health education centers. Title IV: Research - Directs the Director of the Office of Research on Minority Health to establish the Advisory Committee on Research on Minority Health. (Sec. 402) Revises activities of the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research. (Sec. 403) Authorizes appropriations for the National Center for Health Statistics for health statistical and epidemiological activities. Title V: Native Hawaiian Health Care - Revises the Native Hawaiian Health Care Improvement Act completely, including: (1) the findings, declaration of policy, and intent of the Congress; (2) the comprehensive health care master plan for Native Hawaiians; (3) functions of Papa Ola Lokahi; (4) provisions concerning Native Hawaiian health care systems; (5) administration of grants and contracts; (6) scholarship provisions; (7) assignment of personnel; and (8) definitions. Authorizes appropriations through FY 2000 to carry out the Act. Title VI: Women's Health - Establishes an Office of Women's Health within the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 602) Requires the Director of NIH to establish policies regarding the employment by NIH of women scientists and to study and report to specified congressional committees on pay differences between men and women scientists. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to such committees on the termination of NIH scientists. (Sec. 603) Provides for data collection and education outreach on female genital mutilation. (Sec. 604) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to study and report to specified congressional committees on whether medical and osteopathic school curricula provide adequate education on women's health conditions. Title VII: Traumatic Brain Injury - Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to carry out projects to reduce the incidence of traumatic brain injury. (Sec. 702) Authorizes grants or contracts for research regarding traumatic brain injury. (Sec. 703) Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to make grants for carrying out demonstration projects to improve the availability of health services regarding traumatic brain injury to States that establish advisory boards. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 704) Directs the Secretary to study and report to specified congressional committees on traumatic brain injury. Title VIII: Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes appropriations through FY 1997 for health services for Pacific Islanders under the Disadvantaged Minority Health Improvement Act of 1990. (Sec. 804) Provides for the establishment of such technical and scientific peer review groups and scientific program advisory committees as are necessary to carry out the functions of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. (Sec. 805) Authorizes the Secretary to make a grant to establish a laboratory on the U.S.-Mexican border to protect the public health through analyzing human, wildlife, air, water, and soil samples. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 807) Treats diagnostic and treatment centers owned and operated by the New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation as covered entities for purposes of limitations on prices of drugs. Limits a certain exclusion based on participation in group purchasing organizations for purposes of considering the Health Services Purchasing Group under the control of Los Angeles County, California, as a covered entity. Prohibits the Secretary from finding that the hospital system for the Dallas County Hospital District of Texas fails to meet requirements for a covered entity solely because the hospital used a group purchasing arrangement to obtain a covered outpatient drug before the effective date of specified entity guidelines if, at the time the hospital purchased the drug, the drug manufacturer did not offer to furnish the drug at the required price. (Sec. 808) Extends the demonstration project for grants to States for Alzheimer's disease through FY 1998. Requires improved access for individuals with Alzheimer's disease, particularly racial and ethnic minorities and individuals living in isolated rural areas, to services that are home-based or community-based. (Sec. 811) Reduces the funding provisions of the National Center for Research Resources with respect to the construction of Regional Centers for Research on Primates. Title IX: General Provisions - Makes this Act effective upon enactment.

	</summary>
</bill>
