<bill session="103" type="s" number="1560" updated="2012-07-17T04:39:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-02">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-03-02" where="s" result="pass" how="by Voice Vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Administration Independence Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Social Security Administration Independence Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Social Security Disability and Rehabilitation Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Social Security Administration as an independent agency, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400563"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="407786" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-11-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="1993-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-10-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13836-13837)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-19"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Finance"/><text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16535-16537)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Committee on Finance. Reported to Senate by Senator Moynihan without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="317" datetime="1993-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 317.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-01-25"><text>By Senator Moynihan from Committee on Finance filed written report. Report No. 103-221.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S2193-2217"/></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-03-02" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03T11:29:00-05:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03T17:41:00-05:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 4277 as an amendment.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S6186"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23"><text>See also H.R. 4277.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4277" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4277" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4277" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Alcoholism"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Ombudsman"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Social work"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Welfare fraud"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s1474"/>
		<amendment number="s1475"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/2/1994--Passed Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Establishment of New Independent Agency Title II: Conforming Amendments Title III: Social Security Disability and Rehabilitation Social Security Administration Independence Act of 1994 - Title I: Establishment of New Independent Agency - Amends title VII (Administration) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish an independent Social Security Administration, headed by a Commissioner, to administer the Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance (OASDI) program and the Supplemental Security Income program under SSA titles II and XVI. Establishes a Social Security Advisory Board to advise the Commissioner on policies related to such programs. Transfers to the Administration all functions carried out by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) pertaining to such programs. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Conforming Amendments - Makes conforming amendments to SSA and other Federal laws. (Sec. 202) Replaces the Advisory Council on Social Security with an Advisory Council on Hospital and Supplemental Medical Insurance. Sets forth rules of construction. Title III: Social Security Disabiity and Rehabilitation - Social Security Disability and Rehabilitation Act of 1994 - Amends titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income (SSI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require individuals on drugs or alcohol to: (1) undergo, or be scheduled for, appropriate treatment for substance abuse if it is reasonably available; (2) comply with the terms of such treatment; and (3) have a qualified governmental respresentative payee in order to receive disability benefits under the social security disability insurance (SSDI) and SSI programs. (Sec. 302) Sets up a monitoring and testing program under each such title for ensuring such compliance, with benefits terminated or suspended in cases of noncompliance, and with all disability benefits related to substance abuse terminated after three years. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 303) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) assure that every individuals on drugs or alcohol who is receiving SSDI or SSI disability benefits be given high priority for treatment through entities supported by State substance abuse blocks grants; and (2) provide for the establishment of referral and monitoring agencies for each State for carrying out treatment requirements under this Act. (Sec. 305) Requires the proceeds derived from crimimal activities to support substances abuse to be considered substantial gainful activity. (Sec. 306) Revises penalty provisions, with changes providing for the exclusion of SSDI and SSI program defrauders from such programs and other Federal health and social services programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
