<bill session="103" type="s" number="1571" updated="2012-07-17T04:27:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Law Enforcement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal Alien Deportation and Enhanced Transfer Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Executive Order Enhanced Consideration Revocation Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Improved Border Control and Narcotics Abatement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve immigration law enforcement.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-10-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14012-14015)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-03"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration and Refugee Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Abortion"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Citizenship"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Executive orders"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
		<term name="Police training"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/20/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Border Personnel, Training and Infrastructure Enhancement Title II: Asylum Reform Title III: Criminal Alien Deportation and Enhanced Prisoner Transfer Immigration Law Enforcement Act of 1993 - Title I: Border Personnel, Training and Infrastructure Enhancement - Improved Border Control and Narcotics Abatement Act - Authorizes appropriations and increases personnel levels for: (1) the Border Patrol; and (2) land border inspectors. Provides for: (1) primary deployment of such personnel on the Southwest border of the United States; (2) hiring preference for bilingual Border Patrol agents; and (3) improved training and improvement of border crossing infrastructure. Authorizes appropriations for Immigration and Naturalization Service technology and equipment acquisition. Establishes in the Treasury the Immigration Law Enforcement Fund. Creates a border crossing user fee. Title II: Asylum Reform - Executive Order Enhanced Consideration Revocation Act - Amends a specified Executive Order to partially revoke a provision with respect to asylum claims based upon birth control policies. Title III: Criminal Alien Deportation and Enhanced Prisoner Transfer - Criminal Alien Deportation and Enhanced Transfer Act of 1993 - Amends Federal criminal law to provide for a judicial order of deportation in the sentencing of an alien convicted of certain aggravated felonies. Authorizes the Secretary of State with the Attorney General to negotiate agreements with foreign countries for home-country incarceration of aliens subject to U.S. deportation. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) make an alien convicted of an aggravated felony ineligible for suspension of deportation and status of adjustment; and (2) prohibit the waiver of exclusion for an alien convicted of an aggravated felony.

	</summary>
</bill>
