<bill session="103" type="s" number="1586" updated="2012-07-17T05:25:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-12">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-04-12" where="s" result="pass" how="by Voice Vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">New Orleans Jazz National Historical Park Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">New Orleans Jazz National Historical Park Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">New Orleans Jazz National Historical Park Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the New Orleans Jazz National Historical Park in the State of Louisiana; and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1993-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-11-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-02-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14381-14382)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-12-10"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-503 New Orleans, LA.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-15"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-594.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-03-23"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-242.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="396" datetime="1994-03-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 396.</text></calendar>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-04-12" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4177-4180"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-04-13T14:25:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-13"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands"/><text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Prior to Referral.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-11"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>See S.21.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="3408" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3408" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="21" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Louisiana"/>
		<term name="Music"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/12/1994--Passed Senate amended. New Orleans Jazz National Historical Park Act of 1994 - Establishes the New Orleans Jazz National Historical Park, Louisiana, to be administered in conjunction with the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to complete a national historic landmark evaluation of sites associated with jazz in and around New Orleans. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) designate and acquire appropriate sites as part of the Park; (2) enter into cooperative agreements with property owners for the preservation and interpretation of such property; (3) construct and operate an interpretive center in the Park; (4) provide technical assistance to the city of New Orleans for the designation of certain areas as jazz heritage districts; and (5) provide, in consultation with the New Orleans Jazz Commission, grants or technical assistance to public and private organizations. Directs the Secretary: (1) in administering the Park, to promote a broad range of educational activities relating to jazz and its history; and (2) to prepare a general management plan, meeting specified criteria, for the Park. Establishes the New Orleans Jazz Commission to: (1) advise the Secretary in the preparation of the general management plan, assist in public discussions of planning proposals, and assist the National Park Service in working with individuals, groups, and organizations in determining programs in which the Secretary should participate through cooperative agreements; (2) develop partnerships with educational groups, schools, universities, and other groups, including city-wide organizations, in furtherance of this Act; (3) raise and disperse funds for programs that assist mutual aid and benevolent societies, social and pleasure clubs, and other traditional groups in encouraging the continuation of and enhancement of jazz cultural traditions; (4) acquire or lease property for jazz education, advise on hiring brass bands and musical groups to participate in education programs, and help train young musicians; (5) assist in providing recommendations for the location of the Park's visitor center and other interpretive sites and funds to support research on the origins and early history of jazz in New Orleans; and (6) seek and accept donations to use for providing services, programs, and facilities for jazz education or assisting in the rehabilitation and restoration of structures identified in the national historic landmark study as having outstanding significance to the history of jazz in New Orleans. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
