<bill session="103" type="s" number="1592" updated="2012-07-17T04:04:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fiscal Accountability and Intergovernmental Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Federal decision making by requiring a thorough evaluation of the economic impact of Federal legislative and regulatory requirements on State and local governments and the economic resources located in such State and local governments.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1994-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1994-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1994-06-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14530-14531)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Economic growth"/>
		<term name="Economic impact statements"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Regulatory reform"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/27/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Legislative Reform Title II: Federal Intergovernmental Relations Fiscal Accountability and Intergovernmental Reform Act (FAIR Act) - Title I: Legislative Reform - Provides that, with certain exceptions, whenever a committee of either House reports a bill or resolution of a public character (excluding resolutions of ratification of a treaty) to its House mandating unfunded requirements upon State or local governments or the private sector, the report accompanying that bill or resolution shall analyze the effect of the new requirements on: (1) State and local government expenditures necessary to comply with Federal mandates; (2) private businesses; and (3) economic growth and competitiveness. Requires the Congressional Budget Office to prepare such economic analyses. Title II: Federal Intergovernmental Relations - Provides that, whenever an agency publishes a general notice of proposed rulemaking or promulgates a final rule, the agency shall prepare and make available for public comment an Intergovernmental and Economic Impact Assessment. Specifies the contents of such an assessment.

	</summary>
</bill>
