<bill session="103" type="s" number="1597" updated="2012-07-17T05:01:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-02">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-02-02" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Organ Transplant Program Reauthorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Organ Transplant Program Reauthorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise certain organ procurement and transplantation programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14537-14538)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-02-02"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-03-07"><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-233.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="378" datetime="1994-03-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 378.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2659" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/7/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Organ Transplant Program Reauthorization Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the grant program for organ procurement organizations (OPOs) and other public or nonprofit institutions to increase organ donation through public education programs, training individuals to request organ donations, and providing technical assistance to organ-procuring organizations and hospitals. Requires priority to be given to grant requests designed to alleviate organ shortages for minority and other populations where there is a greater degree of organ shortages relative to the general population. Requires OPOs to make systematic efforts to increase the number of potential donors. Revises requirements regarding allocations of donated organs. Requires OPOs to be a member of and abide by the requirements of the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network. (Currently, requires participation in the Organ Procurement Transplantation Network.) Revises evaluation requirements. Requires the Office of Technology Assessment to report to specified congressional committees on a study of OPOs. Requires the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network to make recommendations concerning the approval of alternative local units. Modifies requirements regarding the activities and organization of the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network. Directs the Comptroller General to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the composition of the boards of OPOs and the Network; (2) various transplant matters involving foreign nationals, nonresident aliens, foreign countries, or territories; and (3) the allocation of organs. Extends the authorization of appropriations for the OPO grant program.

	</summary>
</bill>
