<bill session="103" type="s" number="1633" updated="2012-07-17T05:23:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Consolidation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to consolidate under a new Federal Banking Commission the supervision of all depository institutions insured under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-11-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15321-15324)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank holding companies"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Community development banking"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Deposit insurance"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
		<term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="International banking"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
		<term name="Savings banks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/8/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Federal Banking Commission Title II: Abolition of Federal Banking Agencies Regulatory Consolidation Act of 1993 - Title I: Federal Banking Commission - Establishes the Federal Banking Commission (the Commission) as an independent agency in the executive branch. Transfers to the Commission all functions vested in: (1) the Comptroller of the Currency for the regulation of national banks; (2) the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision for the regulation of savings associations and savings and loan holding companies; (3) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System for certain banking activities; (4) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation for the regulation of State nonmember banks (excluding insurance-related functions); and (5) the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council for the conduct of schools for bank examiners. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury (the Secretary) to designate a single calendar date by which to complete the transfer of functions. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the initial Commission appointments by the President be completed within a specified deadline. Grants the Federal Reserve Board access to the Commission's records. Title II: Abolition of Federal Banking Agencies - Abolishes the office and the position of: (1) Comptroller of the Currency; (2) Office of Thrift Supervision; and (3) the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council. Amends the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 to redesignate the Appraisal Subcommittee as the Appraisal Committee.

	</summary>
</bill>
