<bill session="103" type="s" number="1634" updated="2012-07-17T06:16:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Municipal Solid Waste Flow Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize each State and certain political subdivisions of States to control the movement of municipal solid waste generated within, or imported into, the State or political subdivisions of the State, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405310"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-06-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15325)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Superfund, Recycling. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Superfund, Recycling, and Solid Waste Management" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/8/1993--Introduced.
Municipal Solid Waste Flow Control Act of 1993 - Authorizes a State or a political subdivision to which a State has delegated authority, if conditions under this Act are met, to: (1) direct, limit, regulate, or prohibit the movement of municipal solid waste generated or imported within its boundaries; and (2) designate waste management facilities to which such waste shall be transported. Permits States or political subdivisions to exercise such authorities only if: (1) recyclable materials will be removed from the waste through separation at the source or at facilities unless the political subdivision in which the waste is generated is exempt from recycling requirements; and (2) the designated waste management facilities are not in violation of Federal and State environmental laws and regulations. Bars States or political subdivisions from prohibiting persons from selling, conveying, or arranging for the transportation of recyclable materials that have been separated from municipal solid waste.

	</summary>
</bill>
