<bill session="103" type="s" number="1640" updated="2012-07-17T05:23:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-09">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-11-09" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hazardous Materials Transportation Authorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Hazardous Materials Transportation Authorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to authorize appropriations to carry out that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403962"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15334-15335)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-09"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-12-09"><text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings under the authority of the order of Nov 17, 93 with amendments. With written report No. 103-217.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="347" datetime="1993-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 347.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S11320-11325"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 2178 as an amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 2178 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="superseded" session="103" type="h" number="2178" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2178" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2178" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3460" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Agricultural accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Agricultural machinery"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Common carriers"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Contracts"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugs and employment"/>
		<term name="Drugs and transportation workers"/>
		<term name="Drunk driving"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Farmers"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Foreign corporations"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Highway research"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Household moving"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
		<term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Motor bus lines"/>
		<term name="Motor carrier rates"/>
		<term name="Motor transportation"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Packaging"/>
		<term name="Personnel records"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
		<term name="Railroad safety"/>
		<term name="Reciprocity"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Traffic engineering"/>
		<term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Transportation planning"/>
		<term name="Transportation safety"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Truck drivers"/>
		<term name="Trucking"/>
		<term name="Trucks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s2552"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/9/1993--Reported to Senate amended. Hazardous Materials Transportation Authorization Act of 1993 - Amends the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1994 through 1996 for the regulation of the transportation of hazardous materials. Exempts from the requirement to file a registration statement persons domiciled outside the United States who offer, solely from a location outside the United States, hazardous materials for transportation in commerce. Directs the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to make grants to Indian tribes for the development of emergency response plans with respect to the transportation of hazardous materials through Indian lands. Requires States or Indian tribes receiving such grants to ensure that such emergency planning is coordinated with emergency plans conducted by adjacent States and Indian tribes. Requires States, local governments, or Indian tribes that levy fees in connection with the transportation of hazardous materials to comply with certain disclosure requirements. Changes from annual to biennial the Secretary's periodic comprehensive report to the President (for transmittal to the Congress) on the transportation of hazardous materials. Directs the Secretary to ensure that the National Intelligent Vehicle-Highway Systems Program addresses the use of intelligent vehicle-highway system technologies to promote hazardous materials transportation safety. Requires the Secretary to issue final regulations under specified dockets concerning: (1) crashworthiness protection requirements for tank cars; and (2) detection and repair of cracks, pits, corrosion, lining flaws, thermal protection flaws and other defects of tank car tanks. Directs the Secretary to study the existing practices regarding the placement of cars on trains, with particular attention to the placement of cars carrying hazardous materials. Requires the Secretary to amend regulations under the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act and the Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1984 to prohibit the driver of a motor vehicle transporting hazardous materials in commerce or of any commercial vehicle from driving it onto a highway-rail grade crossing without sufficient space to drive completely through the crossing without stopping. Requires the Secretary to issue regulations to require that any document bearing on the record of duty status of a driver who operates a commercial motor vehicle: (1) be retained by the employing motor carrier for at least six months after receipt; and (2) include information identifying the driver and vehicle. Directs the Secretary to amend the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) with respect to the acquisition of safety performance histories of new drivers employed by a motor carrier. Requires the retention of shipping papers by persons who provided them and the motor carrier required to maintain it after the hazardous material involved is no longer in transportation. Requires the Secretary to establish a toll-free &quot;800&quot; telephone number for transporters of hazardous materials and other individuals to report possible violations of the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act or any regulation issued under this Act. Requires the Secretary to exempt farmers and retail farm suppliers from CFR hours of service requirements when they transport supplies for agricultural purposes within a 50-mile radius of their distribution point during the crop-planting season.

	</summary>
</bill>
