<bill session="103" type="s" number="1649" updated="2012-07-17T04:14:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Adjudication Procedures Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to make improvements in the procedures used by the Department of Veterans Affairs in adjudicating claims for veterans benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400566"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15603-15604)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Rating of employees"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Introduced.
Veterans Adjudication Procedures Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide that under the work rate standards that apply to Department of Veterans Affairs employees who adjudicate claims for benefits that have been submitted to the Secretary, such employees shall not receive credit for work on a claim until the claim decision becomes final. Requires the Secretary to report annually to the Congress the status of claims for benefits before the Department during the preceding fiscal year, including the average length of time required for such adjudications. Requires a rating official to make the initial determination of the Secretary on all original and reopened claims filed with the Secretary. Allows a single member (currently three) of the Board of Veterans' Appeals to be assigned to and make a determination on a proceeding before such Board. Makes such decision final unless the Chairman of such Board orders reconsideration, in which case three other Board members must hear the proceeding. Subjects decisions made by the Secretary or the Board to revision or reversal on the grounds of clear and unmistakable error.

	</summary>
</bill>
