<bill session="103" type="s" number="1657" updated="2010-04-19T18:48:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-10">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-11-10" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bill to enforce the fourteenth amendment and to reform habeas corpus</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform habeas corpus procedures.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300092"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1993-11-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-10"  state="REPORTED"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 281.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-16"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S15731-15745"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-17"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S15807, S15809-15815"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-17"><text>Motion to table S. 1657 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 65-34. Record Vote No: 374.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4519)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5662-5664)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4018" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Appellate procedure"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Constitution"/>
		<term name="Constitutional law"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Lawyers"/>
		<term name="Legal assistance to prisoners"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Public defenders"/>
		<term name="Right to counsel"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State courts"/>
		<term name="Supreme Court decisions"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Introduced.
Bill to enforce the fourteenth amendment and to reform habeas corpus - Amends the Federal judicial code to impose a 180-day limitations period for the filing of Federal habeas corpus petitions, applicable in both capital and non-capital cases in which the State has offered the petitioner counsel for State post-conviction review, which begins from the time the petitioner's conviction becomes final on State direct review. Tolls such period while the petitioner pursues State post-conviction remedies, unless the petitioner fails to initiate post-conviction review within specified time frames. Provides for a one-time 60-day extension of the period upon a showing of good cause. (Sec. 303) Provides an automatic stay of execution in capital cases through the consideration of the first Federal habeas corpus petition. Permits a stay of execution to be granted thereafter only if the petition on its face satisfies the requirements for successive petitions. (Sec. 304) Requires that in Federal habeas corpus proceedings: (1) all claims be governed by the law as it was when the petitioner's conviction became final; and (2) a court consider intervening decisions by the U.S. Supreme Court which establish fundamental constitutional rights. Codifies case law providing for an independent Federal habeas corpus review of claims under Federal law, except for fourth amendment exclusionary rule claims. Specifies that the State bears the burden of proving harmless error in Federal habeas corpus review of State criminal convictions. (Sec. 305) Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) limits on successive petitions (allows a prisoner to bring a second or subsequent petition only upon a showing of cause for not having brought the claim before and prejudice if the claim is not heard, subject to specified restrictions); and (2) new evidence (allows prisoners in capital cases to present claims of actual innocence based on newly discovered evidence that the petitioner did not previously know about). (Sec. 308) Sets forth: (1) time requirements for consideration by district courts, and by courts of appeals of district court determinations, of habeas corpus petitions in capital cases; (2) provisions regarding the exhaustion of collateral remedies requirement in capital cases; and (3) standards and procedures for the provision of counsel for indigent defendants at all stages of State capital litigation. Requires each State in which a sentence of death may be imposed to establish a State counsel certification authority, comprised of members of the State's criminal defense bar, to create a roster of qualified lawyers eligible for court appointment and monitor the performance of attorneys so certified. (Sec. 312) Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to States to help fund the provision of defense counsel. Authorizes: (1) Federal grants of up to 75 percent of the additional costs imposed by the new counsel requirements during the first three years following enactment of this Act and 50 percent thereafter; and (2) grants for the prosecution of Federal habeas corpus cases in an amount equal to that allocated to capital resource centers. (Sec. 313) Abrogates State sovereign immunity from suit in Federal court for a violation of specified provisions regarding the establishment of a State certification authority and attorney compensation.

	</summary>
</bill>
