<bill session="103" type="s" number="1658" updated="2012-07-17T05:07:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Antitrust Improvements Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish safe harbors from the application of the antitrust laws for certain activities of providers of health care services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1994-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1994-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1994-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-11-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15614-15615)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-03"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Antitrust, Monopolies and Business.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11791-11792)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Antitrust, Monopolies and Business Rights" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Antitrust actions"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Competition"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health facilities"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Joint ventures"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Medical associations"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medical technology"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/10/1993--Introduced.
Health Care Antitrust Improvements Act of 1993 - Exempts from the antitrust laws specified &quot;safe harbor&quot; activities listed in, or designated by the Attorney General pursuant to, this Act. Sets forth provisions regarding the award of attorney's fees and costs of suit to the prevailing party in an action based on a claim involving activity found to be exempt. Lists as safe harbors specified: (1) activities relating to health care services of combinations of health care providers with market share below a specified threshold; (2) activities of medical self-regulatory entities relating to standard setting or enforcement activities not conducted for purposes of financial gain; (3) participation of a health care provider in a written survey of the prices of services, reimbursement levels, or the compensation and benefits of employees and personnel; (4) activities relating to health care joint ventures for high technology and costly equipment and services; (5) activities relating to hospital mergers; (6) joint purchasing arrangements; and (7) negotiations. Directs the Attorney General to publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting proposals for additional safe harbors. Sets forth criteria in establishing safe harbors, including: (1) the extent to which a competitive or collaborative activity will accomplish an increase in health care access and quality, the establishment of cost efficiencies, and increased ability of health care facilities to provide services in medically underserved areas or to underserved populations; and (2) whether designation as a safe harbor will result in specified desirable outcomes. Directs the Attorney General to issue certificates of review for providers of health care services and to assist persons in applying for such certificates. Sets forth procedures regarding applications for, revocation of, and review of determinations regarding, such certificates. Limits the disclosure of information. Sets forth provisions regarding notifications providing for a reduction in certain penalties under the antitrust laws for health care cooperative ventures. Directs the Attorney General to periodically review the safe harbors and certificates of review. Establishes within the Department of Health and Human Services an Office of Health Care Competition Policy.

	</summary>
</bill>
