<bill session="103" type="s" number="1663" updated="2012-07-17T06:24:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Chemical Diversion Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 to control the diversion of certain chemicals used in illicit production of controlled substances such as methcathinone and methamphetamine, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300066"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="1993-11-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-11-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-11-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15900-15901)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Drugs"/>
		<term name="Amphetamines"/>
		<term name="Chemical industries"/>
		<term name="Chemicals"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug industry"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/17/1993--Introduced.
Domestic Chemical Diversion Control Act of 1993 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to remove ephedrine products from the legal drug exemption of the Chemical Diversion and Trafficking Act (which currently precludes the application of any of the regulatory control measures of such Act to a listed chemical which is contained in a drug product approved under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act). Directs the Attorney General to remove from exemption any other drug products which are being diverted to use in the illicit production of controlled substances. Establishes a registration system for distributors, importers, and exporters of listed chemicals which are diverted within the United States. Directs the Attorney General to register an applicant to distribute, and to import or export, a list I (currently, listed precursor) chemical unless the Attorney General determines that registration of the applicant is inconsistent with the public interest, based on specified criteria. Amends the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to set penalties for knowingly or intentionally importing or exporting a listed chemical in violation of such registration requirements. Makes provisions of the Controlled Substances Act regarding administrative inspections and authority, forfeiture, and threshold amounts of substances applicable to listed chemicals, as well as to controlled substances. (Currently only the latter are covered by such provisions.)

	</summary>
</bill>
