<bill session="103" type="s" number="1665" updated="2012-07-17T04:28:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Library of Congress Retention of Proceeds Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Librarian of Congress to retain the proceeds of certain sales, payments or restitution.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15903-15904)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Books"/>
		<term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
		<term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional Research Service"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Libraries"/>
		<term name="Library of Congress"/>
		<term name="Newspapers"/>
		<term name="Periodicals"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/17/1993--Introduced.
Library of Congress Retention of Proceeds Act - Authorizes the Librarian of Congress to sell personal property, including books, periodicals, and other materials, determined to be excess to the collections or the exchange and donation programs of the Library, except for: (1) copies of unpublished works that became the property of the United States pursuant to copyright registration; (2) copies of materials received by the Library under written deeds of gift or other contractual agreements which expressly preclude the transfer of ownership or possession by the Library; (3) materials distributed by the National Library Service for the Blind and Physically Handicapped; or (4) products of the Congressional Research Service. Authorizes the Librarian to accept payment or restitution for lost, stolen, damaged, or destroyed books, periodicals, newspapers, or other materials from the Library's collection if such sums are: (1) ordered by any judicial or administrative authority to be paid to the Library; or (2) received from a borrower. Establishes in the Treasury an account consisting of the proceeds of any sale of excess materials or any payment or restitution described under this Act. Provides that account funds shall be available to the Librarian, to the extent provided in appropriations Acts, until expended, for the acquisition of books, periodicals, and other materials, including the costs of administering the national and international acquisition programs of the Library.

	</summary>
</bill>
