<bill session="103" type="s" number="1677" updated="2012-07-17T04:38:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Code of Conduct on Arms Transfers Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit United States military assistance and arms transfers to foreign governments that are undemocratic, do not adequately protect human rights, are engaged in acts of armed aggression, or are not fully participating in the United Nations Register of Conventional Arms.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1994-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1994-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1994-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1994-08-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16219-16220)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14139-14140)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="3538" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Aggression"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Congressional hearings"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Conventional weapons"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Equality before the law"/>
		<term name="Food relief"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Freedom of association"/>
		<term name="Freedom of speech"/>
		<term name="Freedom of the press"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International relief"/>
		<term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
		<term name="Political prisoners"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/18/1993--Introduced.
Code of Conduct on Arms Transfers Act of 1993 - Prohibits U.S. military assistance and arms transfers to a foreign government unless the President certifies to the Congress that the government: (1) meets specified conditions regarding democracy, including that it was chosen in free and fair elections and promotes civilian control of the military, the rule of law, and respect for individual rights; (2) does not engage in human rights violations, investigates and prosecutes those responsible for human rights violations, permits access to political prisoners by international organizations, and provides access to such organizations in situations of conflict or famine; (3) is not engaged in acts of armed aggression in violation of international law; and (4) is participating in the United Nations Register of Conventional Arms by annually reporting to the Register the number and type of conventional weapons possessed by, and transferred to and from, the country during the preceding year. Authorizes an exemption from such prohibition for a fiscal year if: (1) the President requests an exemption from the Congress stating that it is in the national security interest to provide military assistance and arms transfers to a government; and (2) the Congress enacts a law approving such request. Requires the President to submit initial certifications and requests for exemptions in conjunction with the submission of the annual request for enactment of authorizations and appropriations for foreign assistance. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the House Foreign Affairs Committee and the Senate Foreign Relations Committee should hold hearings on controversial certifications and all requests for exemptions.

	</summary>
</bill>
