<bill session="103" type="s" number="1672" updated="2010-04-19T18:51:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-18">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-11-18" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Act for Reform In Emerging New Democracies and Support and Help for Improved Partnership with Russia, Ukraine, and Other New Independent States</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FRIENDSHIP Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to revise obsolete laws related to the Cold War.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-18"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Pell. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="299" datetime="1993-11-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 299.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Measure laid before Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S16996"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 3000 as an amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 3000 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="superseded" session="103" type="h" number="3000" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3000" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Afghanistan"/>
		<term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Angola"/>
		<term name="Antimissile missiles"/>
		<term name="Arctic regions"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Aviation safety"/>
		<term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="Christianity"/>
		<term name="Civil defense"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Climate"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
		<term name="Communications"/>
		<term name="Communism"/>
		<term name="Communist countries"/>
		<term name="Communist parties"/>
		<term name="Communist propaganda"/>
		<term name="Communists"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cuba"/>
		<term name="Cultural relations"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="East Germany"/>
		<term name="Eastern Europe"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational exchanges"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Embassies"/>
		<term name="Emigration"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Estonia"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Foreign service"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Freedom of association"/>
		<term name="Fur trade"/>
		<term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
		<term name="Greenhouse effect"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
		<term name="Insurgency"/>
		<term name="Intelligence activities"/>
		<term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International broadcasting"/>
		<term name="International propaganda"/>
		<term name="Jews"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Latvia"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Lithuania"/>
		<term name="Military command and control"/>
		<term name="Military intervention"/>
		<term name="Military occupation"/>
		<term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="Nuclear warfare"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Officer personnel"/>
		<term name="Postal crimes"/>
		<term name="Postal service"/>
		<term name="Press"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Russia"/>
		<term name="Russian Republic"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
		<term name="Sealing"/>
		<term name="South Asia"/>
		<term name="South Korea"/>
		<term name="Sovereignty"/>
		<term name="Special weeks"/>
		<term name="Subversive activities"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Totalitarianism"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="U.S.S.R."/>
		<term name="Ukraine"/>
		<term name="United Nations delegations"/>
		<term name="United Nations finances"/>
		<term name="Victims"/>
		<term name="Warsaw Pact countries"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/18/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Policy of Frienship and Cooperation Title II: Trade and Business Relations Title III: Cultural, Educational, and Other Exchange Programs Title IV: Arms Control Title V: Diplomatic Relations Title VI: Oceans and the Environment Title VII: Regional and General Diplomatic Issues Title VIII: Internal Security; Worldwide Communist Conspiracy Title IX: Miscellaneous Act for Reform in Emerging New Democracies and Support and Help for Improved Partnership with Russia, Ukraine, and Other New Independent States or the FRIENDSHIP Act - Title I: Policy of Friendship and Cooperation - Declares that it is the purpose of this Act to amend or repeal numerous statutory provisions that restrict or impede normal relations between the United States and the Russian Federation, Ukraine, and the other independent states of the former Soviet Union. Affirms that certain existing statutory provisions that impose limitations on the Soviet Union or utilize language that reflect the tension that existed between the Soviet Union and the United States should not be construed as being directed against the independent states, connoting an adversarial relationship between the United States and these states, or implying unfriendliness toward such states. Title II: Trade and Business Relations - Sets forth U.S. policy concerning the shooting down of Korean Airlines Flight 7. (Sec. 202) Amends the Federal criminal code to consider persons engaged in legal commercial transactions as agents of Cuba or any other country determined by the President to pose a threat to national security interests to be foreign agents subject to notification requirements. (Current law considers agents of the Soviet Union, the German Democratic Republic, Hungary, Czechoslovakia, Poland, Bulgaria, and Romania as foreign agents for such purposes.) (Sec. 203) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 to prohibit military technology developed with funds for the Ballistic Missile Defense Program from being transferred to any independent state unless the President certifies to the Congress that such transfer is in the national interest and is for purposes of maintaining peace. (Sec. 204) Amends the Department of Defense Appropriations Authorization Act, 1975 to repeal provisions that restrict exports of Department of Defense-funded items to controlled countries. Title III: Cultural, Educational, and Other Exchange Programs - Changes references in specified laws concerning exchanges from the Soviet Union to the independent states. Title IV: Arms Control - Changes certain references to the Soviet Union and the Warsaw Pact in the Arms Control and Disarmament Act and the Arms Export Control Act to the independent states, Russia, and Eastern Europe. Title V: Diplomatic Relations - Repeals specified provisions concerning: (1) personnel restrictions on Soviet national employees of foreign missions or international organizations; and (2) Soviet embassies and consulates (particularly with regard to security measures) and U.S. embassies in the former Soviet Union. (Sec. 503) Repeals a provision of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 which authorizes appropriations to carry out such Act in the Soviet Union. Title VI: Oceans and Environment - Replaces references to the Soviet Union in specified provisions of the Fur Seal Act of 1966 and the Global Climate Protection Act of 1987 with Russia and the independent states. Title VII: Regional and General Diplomatic Issues - Repeals specified provisions concerning U.S. policy toward Soviet intervention in Afghanistan and Angola and removes references to Communist countries under policy provisions of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. Title VIII: Internal Security; Worldwide Communist Conspiracy - Repeals provisions of law concerning: (1) reports on Soviet press manipulation in the United States; and (2) findings on Communism and prohibitions on communications with members of Communist parties and on attempting to establish a totalitarian dictatorship. Title IX: Miscellaneous - Repeals provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 concerning: (1) Soviet missile tests near Hawaii; (2) emigration from the Soviet Union; and (3) delivery of international mail within the Soviet Union. Removes references to the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe in provisions concerning persecution of Christians. (Sec. 903) Repeals provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 concerning: (1) the murder of a specified U.S. army officer; and (2) Soviet policy toward pentecostal Christians. (Sec. 905) Authorizes the National Captive Nations Committee, Inc., to construct an international memorial in the District of Columbia to honor victims of communism.

	</summary>
</bill>
