<bill session="103" type="s" number="1687" updated="2012-07-17T05:26:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Flexible Funding Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the effective and efficient use of Federal grant assistance provided to State governments to carry out certain environmental programs and activities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1994-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1994-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1994-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1994-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1994-02-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16433-16434)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-22"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5411-5412)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
Environmental Flexible Funding Act of 1993 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish an environmental medium grant program to authorize consolidated grants to States (in lieu of individual grants under Federal environmental laws) to fund programs relating to pollution prevention, control, and abatement and related environmental activities. Authorizes a State, in carrying out a consolidated grant program, to exercise the authorities it would otherwise exercise under an individual grant program. Requires grants to be awarded to address the pollution prevention, control, and abatement problems and related environmental problems of one area of environmental concern on a statewide basis in accordance with a priority work plan developed by the State. Limits a consolidated grant to the amount that would otherwise be awarded under individual grant program authorities. Requires States to pay 50 percent of program costs. Authorizes the Administrator to reduce or disapprove a grant based on a State's failure to make satisfactory progress in achieving performance measures. Directs the Administrator to establish a multi-media environmental grant program to assist States in designing and carrying out pollution prevention, control, and abatement programs and related environmental programs that affect two or more areas of environmental concern. Applies the same cost-sharing and progress conditions to such grants as are applicable to medium grants. Authorizes the Administrator, on the request of a State Governor, to transfer up to 20 percent of the amount that would otherwise be awarded to the State pursuant to individual grant authorities or grant authorities under this Act and award the funds as a supplemental amount subject to the same requirements of such grants.

	</summary>
</bill>
