<bill session="103" type="s" number="1690" updated="2012-07-17T04:43:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">S Corporation Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform the rules regarding subchapter S corporations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408939"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409580" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1994-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="406084" joined="1994-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1994-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1994-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="406256" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400564" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1994-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1994-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1994-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1994-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1994-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="404219" joined="1994-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1994-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1994-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="411271" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="403171" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1994-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1994-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1993-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1994-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1994-07-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16436-16437, S16441-16442)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Accounting"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Business losses"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Charitable contributions"/>
		<term name="Charities"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Corporate liquidations"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Debt"/>
		<term name="Dividends"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Employee ownership"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Foreign corporations"/>
		<term name="Foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Fringe benefits"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Inventories"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Partnerships"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Profit"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Stockholders"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
		<term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
		<term name="Tax administration"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Unrelated business income tax"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
		<term name="S CORPORATIONS"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Eligible Shareholders of S Corporation Subtitle A: Number of Shareholders Subtitle B: Persons Allowed as Shareholders Subtitle C: Other Provisions Title II: Qualification and Eligibility Requirements for S Corporations Subtitle A: One Class of Stock Subtitle B: Elections and Terminations Subtitle C: Other Provisions Title III: Taxation of S Corporation Shareholders Title IV: Effective Date S Corporation Reform Act of 1993 - Title I: Eligible Shareholders of S Corporation - Subtitle A: Number of Shareholders - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase from 35 to 50 the maximum number of shareholders of an S corporation (small business corporation). Allows members of a family to be treated as one shareholder. Subtitle B: Persons Allowed as Shareholders - Allows the following entities to be shareholders of S corporations: (1) certain tax-exempt organizations; (2) financial institutions that do not use the reserve method of accounting for bad debts; (3) nonresident aliens; and (4) certain small business trusts. Subtitle C: Other Provisions - Extends the post-death qualification for certain trusts to be permitted as shareholders from 60 days to two years. Title II: Qualification and Eligibility Requirements for S Corporation - Subtitle A: Once Class of Stock- Allows an S corporation to issue qualified preferred stock. Permits financial institutions to hold safe harbor debt. Subtitle B: Elections and Terminations - Revises the rules on inadvertent terminations by certain trusts of the election to be an S corporation. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to treat certain late elections as timely and to provide an automatic waiver procedure for certain inadvertent terminations. Expands the post-termination transition period until 120 days after a determination is made that the election had terminated in a prior year. Repeals excessive passive investment income as a termination event. Increases the tax imposed on such excessive income. Subtitle C: Other Provisions - Permits an S corporation to own more than 80 percent of another corporation's stock. Repeals the requirement that partnership rules apply for fringe benefit purposes (making C corporation rules applicable). Provides for the treatment of distributions during loss years. Provides a consent dividend for S corporation elections to by-pass amounts in the accumulated adjustments account when making distributions. Eliminates the need to keep records of certain generally small amounts of earnings arising before 1983. Allows S corporations to make charitable contributions of inventory and scientific property. Title III: Taxation of S Corporation Shareholders - Treats losses on liquidations of S corporations as ordinary to the extent the loss created by ordinary income pass-through triggered the liquidation. Title IV: Effective Date - Makes this Act effective after December 31, 1993.

	</summary>
</bill>
