<bill session="103" type="s" number="1700" updated="2012-07-17T04:22:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to limit the interest deduction allowed corporations and to allow a deduction for dividends paid by corporations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16450-16451)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="5124" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Corporate mergers"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Dividends"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Foreign corporations"/>
		<term name="Foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Life insurance"/>
		<term name="Real estate investment"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Stockholders"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Unrelated business income tax"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reduce the deduction for corporate interest payments by 20 percent. Excepts small corporations and farming businesses from such reduction. Allows corporations a deduction of 50 percent of the dividends paid during a taxable year. Limits such deduction to the amount in the qualified dividend account established by the corporation for the payment of such dividends. Prohibits the following corporations from using such deduction: (1) regulated investment companies; (2) real estate investment trusts; (3) an S corporation (certain small business corporations); (4) cooperative organizations; and (5) foreign sales corporations and domestic international sales corporations. Provides for an increase in the withholding tax on dividends paid to nonresident aliens or foreign corporations to reflect the dividend paid deduction. Requires, in the case of the acquisition of assets of a corporation by another corporation, that the acquiring corporation carryover the qualified dividend account.

	</summary>
</bill>
