<bill session="103" type="s" number="1714" updated="2012-07-17T06:25:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">State Transportation Financing Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for the establishment of State transportation investment loan funds, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16461, S16463)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Highway engineering"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Toll roads"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
State Transportation Financing Improvement Act of 1993 - Amends Federal transportation law to authorize a State to establish a transportation revolving investment loan fund to make loans and provide other assistance to public or private entities constructing projects eligible to receive assistance under the surface transportation program. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to establish each fiscal year a schedule for deposits and payments made by or on behalf of a State with respect to the fund. Authorizes a State to use the fund as security for bonds or notes issued to provide capital for the fund. Authorizes a State to loan an amount equal to all or part of the Federal share of a project to a public or private entity constructing: (1) a nontoll facility if loan repayment will be made from a dedicated revenue source, including any excise tax, sales tax, motor vehicle use fees, tax on real property, tax increment financing, or other dedicated revenue sources; or (2) a toll project. Requires the public or private entity, as a condition of receiving loans or other assistance, to comply with the requirements of this Act, the Federal Transit Act, and any Federal environmental laws.

	</summary>
</bill>
