<bill session="103" type="s" number="1713" updated="2012-07-17T04:27:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Work Force Diversity Partnership Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to award grants to public-private partnerships to encourage work force diversity in order to improve the working conditions of all Americans and to help organizations compete more effectively both domestically and internationally, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16459-16460)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Industry-university relations"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="Labor policy"/>
		<term name="Labor supply"/>
		<term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
		<term name="Teaching materials"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
Work Force Diversity Partnership Act of 1993 - Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to award grants for public-private partnerships to encourage work force diversity through study of relevant issues and development of education and training materials and programs. Makes eligible for such grants institutions of higher education in partnership with for-profit or nonprofit corporations, businesses, or partnerships, labor organizations, or organizations with demonstrated interest or expertise in such issues. Gives priority to grant proposals demonstrating availability of sufficient amounts of non-Federal contributions, or resources from non-governmental entities. Requires peer review panels, recipient reports, and annual reports by the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
