<bill session="103" type="s" number="1727" updated="2012-07-17T04:38:11-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Maritime Heritage Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Maritime Heritage Program to make grants available for educational programs and the restoration of America's cultural resources for the purpose of preserving America's endangered maritime heritage.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402727"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1994-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="406256" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1994-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1994-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1994-09-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1994-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1994-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1994-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1994-09-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="1994-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1994-03-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16480-16481, S16484-16485)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15032)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Marine transportation"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="Merchant ships"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Salvage"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/1993--Introduced.
National Maritime Heritage Act of 1993 - Declares that it shall be the policy of the Federal Government, in partnership with State and local governments and private organizations and individuals, to support and encourage Federal, State, and local governmental and private conservation of historic maritime resources. Creates the National Maritime Trust to receive, preserve, and administer donations of real property and objects significant in American maritime history and culture and accept, hold, and administer gifts to carry out a maritime preservation and education program. Establishes the National Maritime Heritage Grants Program to foster a greater awareness and appreciation of the role of maritime endeavors in our nation's history and culture. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to make a cooperative agreement with the Trust for assistance in administration of the Program. Provides for a matching grants-in-aid program to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Secretary, to administer a program of direct grants for the preservation of maritime resources, including direct preservation, demonstration projects, training, and educational programs. Authorizes conveyance to the Trust, without consideration, of each vessel in the National Defense Reserve Fleet that has no usefulness to the Government and is scheduled to be scrapped. Requires the Trust to sell: (1) the vessels for scrap and use the proceeds for the purposes of this Act; and (2) sufficient vessels to derive a minimum annual dollar amount. Declares that amounts available to, or used by, the Trust under these provisions shall not be considered in any determination of amounts available to the Department of the Interior. Establishes the Maritime Heritage Grants Committee to perform certain duties, including overseeing the grants program and reviewing grant proposals. Requires the Committee to determine whether any projects exist that meet specified criteria regarding receiving a grant prior to issuance of implementing regulations. Provides for disbursal of scrapped vessel funds to approved projects. Mandates an annual audit of Trust accounts by independent accountants and authorizes annual audits by the General Accounting Office.

	</summary>
</bill>
