<bill session="103" type="s" number="1736" updated="2012-07-17T05:55:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy and Environment Tax Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance the Nation's energy security by promoting renewable energy resources and energy conservation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16719-16721)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
		<term name="Biomass energy"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
		<term name="Diesel motor"/>
		<term name="Electric utilities"/>
		<term name="Electric vehicles"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy tax credits"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Farms"/>
		<term name="Fuel"/>
		<term name="Gas companies"/>
		<term name="Investment tax credit"/>
		<term name="Minimum tax"/>
		<term name="Motor buses"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Reforestation"/>
		<term name="Soil conservation"/>
		<term name="Solar energy"/>
		<term name="Subsidies"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Trucks"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Wind power"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Incentives for Renewable Energy Resources Title II: Incentives to Promote Energy Conservation Energy and Environment Tax Act of 1993 - Title I: Incentives for Renewable Energy Resources - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a portion of the alcohol fuels credit to offset the tentative minimum tax. Allows the use of energy tax credits when computing the regular tax and the alternative minimum tax. Allows an alcohol fuels credit for the production of biodiesel fuel. Excludes from gross income the alcohol fuels credit attributable to biodiesels and certain ethanol-based ethers. Includes certain small wind turbine equipment as energy property for purposes of the energy credit. Title II: Incentives to Promote Energy Conservation - Allows electric or gas utilities a deduction for energy conservation expenditures. Makes certain trucks, vans, and buses ineligible for the credit for electric vehicle costs. Allows taxpayers primarily engaged in a farming-related business an investment tax credit for a percentage of: (1) the costs of agricultural environmental property; and (2) the amount allowed as a deduction for soil and water conservation expenditures. Extends the existing deduction for the cost of pollution abatement property to plants or property in operation before January 1, 1994. (Current provision only applies to plants or property in operation before January 1, 1976.)

	</summary>
</bill>
