<bill session="103" type="s" number="1735" updated="2012-07-17T04:25:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Privacy Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Privacy Protection Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1994-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16493-16498)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Senate Committee on Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs by unanimous consent.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Computers and government"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Electronic data processing"/>
		<term name="Executive orders"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidential commissions"/>
		<term name="Public records"/>
		<term name="Records management"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
Privacy Protection Act of 1993 - Establishes the Privacy Protection Commission to: (1) provide leadership and coordination for the efforts of all Federal agencies to enforce all Federal statutes, executive orders, regulations, and policies which involve privacy or data protection; (2) maximize effort and eliminate conflict, competition, duplication, and inconsistency among the operations, functions, and jurisdictions of Federal agencies responsible for privacy or data protection, data protection rights and standards, and fair information practices and principles; (3) develop model standards, policies, and routine uses for and by Federal, State, and local agencies in implementing the Privacy Act of 1974; (4) publish on a regular basis a guide to such Act and the Freedom of Information Act and other data protection laws; (5) publish a compilation of agency system of records notices, including an index and other finding aids; (6) make recommendations to the Congress to amend the Privacy Act; (7) provide active leadership, guidance, and assistance to private sector businesses, and organizations, institutions, and individuals regarding privacy, data protection rights and standards, and fair information practices and principles; (8) develop model practices, principles, standards, policies, and routine uses for use by the private sector; and (9) upon written request, provide assistance to the private sector in implementing them. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
