<bill session="103" type="s" number="1750" updated="2012-07-17T05:09:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food Safety Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to transfer certain food safety and inspection functions to the Consumer Product Safety Commission, to establish an Office of Public Liaison, and to require the development of certain plans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16763-16765)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fish inspection"/>
		<term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
		<term name="Food irradiation"/>
		<term name="Food safety"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
		<term name="Milk"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Poultry inspection"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Transfer of employees"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Transfer of Food Safety and Inspection Functions Title II: Specific Functions of the Commission After Transfer Title III: Establishment of a Liaison Office Title IV: General Provisions Food Safety Reform Act of 1993 - Title I: Transfer of Food Safety and Inspection Functions - Transfers to the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) all functions of any office relating to food safety and inspection carried out by the Secretaries of Agriculture, the Interior, Commerce, and Health and Human Services (HHS), the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. Authorizes the Chairman of the CPSC to: (1) delegate any of the functions transferred by this title, with exceptions; and (2) allocate or reallocate any function so transferred among CPSC officers and to establish, consolidate, alter, or discontinue such organizational entities necessary or appropriate. Title II: Specific Functions of the Commission after Transfer - Establishes the position of Executive Director of Food and Safety in CPSC, to be appointed by the Chairman. Requires the Chairman to enter into a separate memorandum of understanding with the Secretaries of HHS, Commerce, and Defense, the Administrator of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, the executive officers of State health departments, and the head of any other necessary governmental entity to carry out specified objectives respecting food safety and inspection. Requires the Chairman to prepare and submit to appropriate congressional committees a plan for: (1) the development of a comprehensive nationwide food safety database and surveillance system; and (2) the innovation and implementation of food safety and inspection techniques, including techniques of hazard analysis of critical control points, rapid pathogen detection, trace-back technology, food irradiation, and other necessary techniques. Title III: Establishment of a Liaison Office - Establishes an Office of Public Liaison within CPSC to provide information and advice regarding food safety and inspection to U.S. Public Health Service agencies, the National Academy of Sciences, State and local public health agencies, and academia and to carry out other necessary food safety and inspection activities. Title IV: General Provisions - Requires the Chairman to report to the Congress on the estimated additional cost of implementing this Act. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
