<bill session="103" type="s" number="1760" updated="2012-07-17T05:10:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Buildings Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Buildings Act of 1959 to improve the process of constructing, altering, purchasing, and acquiring public buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-11-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16779-16780, S16782)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Water Resources, Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-592.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Water Resources, Transportation, Public Buildings, and Economic Development" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal office buildings"/>
		<term name="Furniture industry"/>
		<term name="General Services Administration"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Monopolies"/>
		<term name="Office equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Ombudsman"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
		<term name="Surveys"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
Public Buildings Reform Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Buildings Act of 1959 (the Act) to require the Administrator of General Services to: (1) submit biennially to the Congress a public buildings plan for the first two fiscal years that begin after the date of submission for such projects relating to the construction, alteration, purchase, or acquisition of public buildings, or the lease of office or storage space that is necessary to carry out the duties of the Administrator under any law; and (2) hold a public hearing and certify in the biennial plan that the hearing was held in the locality of each major project included in the plan. Includes in the biennial plan, with respect to each project: (1) any final report that is required to be prepared pursuant to any applicable Federal law including any environmental assessment or impact statement pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969; and (2) a report that indicates the consideration that was given to facts and issues concerning the project and the various alternatives that were raised during the hearing or that were otherwise considered. Authorizes the Administrator to include a project in the next biennial plan if such project is included in a biennial plan and the project is not approved in accordance with the Act or if funds are not made available to carry out the project. Prohibits the Administrator from obligating funds that are made available for any project for which approval is required unless the project was included in the biennial plan for the fiscal year and a prospectus for the project was submitted to the Congress. Reduces the ceiling on appropriations from $1.5 million to $1 million for the General Services Administration (GSA), without congressional approval, to construct, alter, purchase, or acquire any building to be used as a public building, or to lease any space at an average annual rental for public purpose use. Prohibits, without prior approval, the use of funds to: (1) alter a public building if the aggregate cost of such alteration exceeds the ceiling over a five-year period; or (2) lease space within a public building if the aggregate cost of the leased space annually exceeds the ceiling. Authorizes the Administrator to submit to specified congressional committees a written request for authority to carry out an emergency project if the Administrator determines that an overriding economic or safety interest requires such authority and it cannot be obtained in a timely manner through the biennial planning process. Requires a specific Act of the Congress before such emergency project can be carried out. Repeals provisions authorizing the Administrator to increase the estimated maximum cost of any project set forth in any prospectus that has been transmitted to the Congress. Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) include in a biennial public building plan a prospectus for the funding of an authorized uncompleted public building project; and (2) use the results of the continuing investigation and survey required by the Act to establish a central repository for Federal asset management information. Requires the Administrator to designate an official to act as ombudsman within the Public Building Service of the GSA. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to: (1) report to the Congress on ending GSA monopoly with respect to providing office and storage space for Federal agencies, including whether the ending of the monopoly is necessary and would be cost-effective; and (2) submit a plan for ending the monopoly, along with recommendations to implement the plan, if the report determines that it is feasible and desirable to do so. Requires: (1) each Federal agency to review and report to the Congress on the agency's long-term housing needs and to attempt to reduce such needs; and (2) the Administrator to designate two account managers for each agency to assist the agency in carrying out the review and to assist the Administrator in preparing uniform standards for housing needs for Federal executive agencies and establishments in the judicial branch. Directs each Federal agency, by the end of the third fiscal year that begins after the enactment of this Act, to reduce by at least five percent: (1) the aggregate office and storage space held on the enactment of this Act; or (2) the annual housing costs (including the costs of energy, supplies, furniture, and minor repairs) of the agency as compared to the housing costs of the agency for the fiscal year during which this Act was enacted.

	</summary>
</bill>
