<bill session="103" type="s" number="1768" updated="2012-07-17T04:42:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300150"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16828-16829)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Indian claims"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Korean War, 1950-1953"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Mining claims"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/1993--Introduced.
Treats certain lands (Kageet Point) as acreage allotted to the Chugach Alaska Corporation for the purpose of making selections under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act. Ratifies specified conveyances to the Caswell and Montana Creek Native Associations as full entitlements under such Act. Amends the Act with respect to requirements, administration, and revenues of mining claims patented to a Regional Corporation. Authorizes appropriations for technical assistance to Village Corporations to implement conveyances under the Act. Provides a one-year land allotment period for certain Native Alaskan veterans of the Korean conflict or the Vietnam era. Authorizes Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, to transfer Wrangell Institute in Wrangell, Alaska, to the General Services Administration in exchange for the restoration of specified bidding credits to the corporation's property account. Makes technical corrections to provisions concerning lapsed mining claims located with the boundaries of the Wrangell-St. Elias National Park and Preserve.

	</summary>
</bill>
