<bill session="103" type="s" number="1801" updated="2012-07-17T05:06:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mutual Depository Institution Conversion Protection Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to apply certain minimum standards to the conversion of savings associations and savings banks from the mutual form to the stock form, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1994-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S178-179)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-25"><committee name="Committee on Banking"/><text>Committee on Banking. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-510.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Bank deposits"/>
		<term name="Bank directors"/>
		<term name="Bank employees"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Executive compensation"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
		<term name="Insider trading in securities"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
		<term name="Savings banks"/>
		<term name="Stockholders"/>
		<term name="Stocks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1994--Introduced.
Mutual Depository Institution Conversion Protection Act of 1994 - Amends the Home Owners' Loan Act with respect to conversions from mutual to stock form of ownership by State and Federal savings banks and associations to: (1) subject State institutions to Federal regulations; (2) authorize State regulatory authorities to impose conversion rules more restrictive than the Federal rules; (3) restrict the beneficial interest available to insider transactions pursuant to such conversions to the same interest available to non-insiders; (4) prohibit for one year compensation to savings institution personnel which exceeds that received before the conversion date; and (5) require the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision to establish aggregate limits on the beneficial interests of insiders pursuant to such conversions. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and report to the Congress on the adequacy of Federal regulations and disclosure requirements regarding such conversions.

	</summary>
</bill>
