<bill session="103" type="s" number="1806" updated="2012-07-17T05:57:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to rescind the fee required for the use of public recreation areas at lakes and reservoirs under the jurisdiction of the Army Corps of Engineers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300079"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1994-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1994-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1994-03-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S286-287)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Boats and boating"/>
		<term name="Camping"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Lakes"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Reservoirs"/>
		<term name="Sports and recreation"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Flood Control Act of 1968 to allow user fees to be collected at lakes and reservoirs under the jurisdiction of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (Corps) only from users of highly developed facilities requiring continuous presence of maintenance and supervision personnel and to prohibit the collection of such fees for access to or use of water areas, shoreland, sites, drives, or boat launching ramps which are undeveloped or lightly developed or where no mechanical or hydraulic equipment is provided. Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to require, at each Corps lake or reservoir at which camping is permitted, the provision of at least one campground with minimal facilities where no charge shall be imposed.

	</summary>
</bill>
