<bill session="103" type="s" number="1800" updated="2012-07-17T06:20:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Predator Criminal Imprisonment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the personal security of Americans by ensuring the imprisonment of violent criminals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300159"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1994-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1994-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1994-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S177-178)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Child abuse"/>
		<term name="Child molesting"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Constitutional law"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drugs and youth"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Increased Use of Existing Prison Space Title II: Construction of Regional Prisons for Violent Criminals Title III: Effective Mandatory Minimum Prison Sentences Title IV: Violent Crime Reduction Trust Fund Predator Criminal Imprisonment Act - Title I: Increased Use of Existing Prison Space - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit a Federal court from: (1) holding prison or jail crowding unconstitutional under the eighth amendment except to the extent that an individual plaintiff inmate proves that the crowding causes the infliction of cruel and unusual punishment of that inmate; and (2) placing a ceiling on the inmate population of any Federal, State, or local detention facility as an equitable remedial measure for conditions that violate the eighth amendment unless crowding is inflicting cruel and unusual punishment on particular identified prisoners. Directs that each Federal court order or consent decree seeking to remedy an eighth amendment violation be reopened at the behest of a defendant for recommended modification at a minimum of two-year intervals. Title II: Construction of Regional Prisons for Violent Criminals - Directs the Attorney General: (1) to construct and operate a minimum of ten regional prisons, situated throughout the United States, each containing space for at least 2,500 inmates; and (2) in determining the location of such prisons, to consider the feasibility of converting Federal correctional complexes currently in the planning or construction phase. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) consideration of cost-effective alternatives and State and local re-use plans; and (2) acceptance of qualifying prisoners. Prohibits the Attorney General from certifying a State as a qualifying State unless the State is providing: (1) &quot;truth in sentencing&quot; with respect to specified felony crimes of violence which provides that defendants will serve at least 85 percent of the sentence ordered and which limits the sentencing judges' discretion; (2) pretrial detention similar to that provided in the Federal system; (3) sentences at least as long as those imposed under Federal law for murderers, firearm offenders where death or serious bodily injury results, sex offenders, and child abuse offenders; and (4) suitable recognition for victims' rights, including consideration of the victim's perspective at all appropriate stages of criminal proceedings. Title III: Effective Mandatory Minimum Prison Sentences - Amends the Federal criminal code to set mandatory prison terms for: (1) using or carrying a firearm during a crime of violence or a drug trafficking crime; and (2) distributing illegal drugs to minors or using minors in drug trafficking activities. Amends the Controlled Substances Act to provide for mandatory life imprisonment without release for drug felons and violent criminals convicted a third time. Title IV: Violent Crime Reduction Trust Fund - Directs: (1) the President, through the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), to ensure that the number of full-time equivalent positions in all executive agencies (excluding the General Accounting Office) does not exceed specified levels for FY 1994-1998; and (2) OMB to continuously monitor all agencies for compliance and to notify the President and the Congress of any failure to comply. Establishes as a separate account in the Treasury the Violent Crime Reduction Trust Fund, which: (1) may be appropriated exclusively for the purposes authorized in this Act and the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1993; and (2) shall be excluded from, and not taken into account for purposes of, any budget enforcement procedures under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. Requires: (1) the President to report annually on the status of the Fund; and (2) the Director of OMB to reduce discretionary spending limits for FY 1994-1998 as specified.

	</summary>
</bill>
