<bill session="103" type="s" number="1808" updated="2012-07-17T05:07:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to allow States to regulate the disposal of municipal solid waste generated outside of the State, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300026"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S374)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Industrial pollution"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Methane"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/28/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize States to enact and enforce laws that regulate the treatment, incineration, and disposal of municipal solid waste generated in another State. Prohibits owners or operators of landfills, incinerators, or other waste disposal facilities from accepting municipal solid waste generated outside the State unless they have a written authorization from: (1) the affected local government; and (2) any affected local solid waste planning unit. Exempts from such prohibition owners or operators that: (1) otherwise comply with all State laws relating to the treatment, incineration, or disposal of municipal solid waste; and (2) during 1992, accepted municipal solid waste generated outside the State for such purposes. Continues the validity of authorizations to conduct such activities that were issued prior to this Act's enactment. Requires owners or operators who expand landfills, incinerators, or other waste disposal facilities to obtain such authorizations prior to accepting waste generated outside the State. Provides for disclosure to interested persons of information regarding the site, environmental controls, required permits, personnel requirements, violations of regulations, and capital and insurance requirements prior to issuance of an authorization by the affected local government and local solid waste planning unit. Requires each State Governor to designate the type of political subdivision that shall serve as the affected local government with respect to authorizing facilities to accept out-of-State municipal solid waste under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
