<bill session="103" type="s" number="1815" updated="2012-07-17T04:14:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Firearm Buy-Back Initiative Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize matching funds for State and local firearm buy-back programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403515"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1994-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1994-02-01" withdrawn="1994-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1994-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1994-02-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S528-529)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/1/1994--Introduced.
Federal Firearm Buy-Back Initiative Act - Directs the Attorney General to establish a program under which the Attorney General will contribute up to 50 percent of the funds needed to provide merchandise, certificates for merchandise or services, or other non-cash incentives to individuals who turn in firearms under State, local, or private firearm buy-back programs. Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) agree to contribute an amount that is no greater than the State, local, and private funds committed to the particular program; and (2) set such other terms to ensure that each program is operated in an efficient and bona fide manner consistent with the interests of law enforcement. Prohibits the Attorney General from prescribing the terms under which such programs will accept firearms in exchange for any offered incentive. Directs the Attorney General to require that: (1) all firearms that are turned in be destroyed; and (2) a program agree to provide only non-cash incentives. Terminates the Attorney General's program on September 30, 1995. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Attorney General to report on the effect of the firearm buy-back programs in reducing the incidence of crime.

	</summary>
</bill>
