<bill session="103" type="s" number="1818" updated="2012-07-17T04:16:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-05">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-10-05" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor in the State of Ohio as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1994-02-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S660-661)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-10-05"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 718.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Canals"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Ohio"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/2/1994--Introduced.
Ohio &amp; Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 - Establishes the Ohio and Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor in Ohio. Establishes the Ohio and Erie Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission to assist Federal, State, and local authorities and the private sector in developing and implementing an integrated management plan for the Corridor. Requires the Commission to submit a management plan for the Corridor to the Secretary of the Interior and the Governor of Ohio for review and approval. Authorizes the Secretary, upon request of the Commission, to provide technical assistance to the Commission for the Corridor and requires the Secretary, upon request, to provide assistance through the Cuyahoga Valley National Recreation Area. Authorizes the Secretary to accept transfers of real property from the Commission within the boundaries of the Corridor as established in the Corridor Management Plan. Requires property outside the legislated boundaries of the Cuyahoga Valley National Recreation Area which is transferred to the National Park Service by the Commission to be added to and administered as part of the Area. Limits the Federal share of the funding provided to the Commission to not more than 50 percent of the total cost of the Commission's annual administrative expenditures, development expenditures to implement the Corridor Management Plan, and land acquisition expenditures. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
