<bill session="103" type="s" number="1813" updated="2012-07-17T04:59:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">River Bottom Lands Revitalization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make additional funds available to repair damage from the Midwest floods of 1993 through the wetlands reserve program, to make certain non-Federal levees are eligible for assistance under the Federal levee rehabilitation program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300010"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1994-02-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S527-528)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3583" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
		<term name="Floods"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wetlands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/1/1994--Introduced.
River Bottom Lands Revitalization Act - Appropriates an additional $50 million to repair damage from the 1993 Midwestern floods via the wetlands reserve program established under the Food Security Act of 1985. States that the eligibility to receive assistance under the levee rehabilitation assistance program of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers within an area that was affected by such flooding shall not be affected by the status of participation (or lack of participation) of the public sponsor in the program. Provides application requirements of a public sponsor for such assistance, subject to specified conditions, including a 25 percent non-Federal share of program costs. Limits to $50 million the amount of the FY 1994 funding for the levee rehabilitation program that may be used to provide assistance to public sponsors who become eligible to receive assistance under such program as a result of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
