<bill session="103" type="s" number="1811" updated="2012-07-17T05:27:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-01-31">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Television Violence Reduction Through Parental Empowerment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require new television sets to have built-in circuitry to allow viewers to block the display of programs rated violent.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-01-31" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S431)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-31" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S657-658)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2888" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Interstate commerce"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Television"/>
		<term name="Television and children"/>
		<term name="Television programs"/>
		<term name="Violence in television"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/1994--Introduced.
Television Violence Reduction Through Parental Empowerment Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require that any television with a screen of at least 13 inches which is manufactured, or imported for use, in the United States be equipped with circuitry designed to enable viewers to block the display of channels, programs, time slots, and all programs with a common rating. Prohibits shipping in interstate commerce, manufacturing, assembling, or importing any such television except pursuant to rules prescribed by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC). Requires such rules to provide performance and display standards for such blocking technology. Directs the FCC, as new video technology is developed, to ensure that blocking service continues to be available to consumers.

	</summary>
</bill>
