<bill session="103" type="s" number="1838" updated="2012-07-17T05:10:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-09">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-09"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to liberalize controls on the export of telecommunications equipment and technology in order to promote democracy and free communication and enhance economic competitiveness.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300089"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1994-03-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1284-1285)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-09" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Albania"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="China"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Czech Republic"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="Estonia"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Latvia"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Lithuania"/>
		<term name="Poland"/>
		<term name="Romania"/>
		<term name="Russia"/>
		<term name="Russian Republic"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Slovakia"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/9/1994--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Commerce to propose to the Coordinating Committee for Multilateral Export Controls (COCOM) (or to its successor export control regime), and to any other export control regime which maintains controls on telecommunications equipment and technology, that exports of telecommunications technology for civil end uses shall not require a validated license or reexport authorization for export or reexport to any of the republics of the former Soviet Union, China, Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Bulgaria, Romania, Albania, Estonia, Lithuania, or Latvia. Requires the President to submit to specified congressional committees a report that certifies that such proposal was made and that outlines plans to gain the concurrence of other members of COCOM or the appropriate regime in the proposal.

	</summary>
</bill>
