<bill session="103" type="s" number="1830" updated="2012-07-17T04:38:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-14">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-06-14" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Defense Conversion Guaranteed Loan Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Small Business Defense Conversion Assistance Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize funding for the small business defense conversion program of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1994-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1994-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1994-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1994-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1994-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1994-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1994-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1994-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1994-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1994-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1994-06-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S959)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-14"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Small Business"/><text>Committee on Small Business. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><text>Committee on Small Business. Reported to Senate by Senator Bumpers with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="462" datetime="1994-06-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 462.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Conversion of industries"/>
		<term name="Defense contracts"/>
		<term name="Defense industries"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Job creation"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Location of industries"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/14/1994--Reported to Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Small Business Defense Conversion Loan Guarantee Program Title II: Miscellaneous Small Business Administration Authorities Small Business Defense Conversion Assistance Act of 1994 -Title I: Small Business Defense Conversion Loan Guarantee Program - Amends the Small Business Act (the Act) to authorize the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make up to $4 billion in guaranteed loans for the small business defense conversion program (a program aiding small businesses adversely affected by military base closures or defense program terminations). Adds to small businesses eligible for such loans those experiencing substantial revenue reduction because of an overall reduction in economic activity in a community due to such closures or terminations. Requires such defense conversion loans to be funded through appropriations that are separate and distinct from funds appropriated for general business loans under the Act. Title II: Miscellaneous Small Business Administration Authorities - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 through 1997 under the Small Business Development Center Program for the defense conversion assistance program. Requires 50 percent of such grant amounts to be provided by non-Federal sources. Prohibits any such amounts from being included in the calculation of the amount of SBA assistance to the Development Center Program. Directs the SBA to develop procedures to ensure that assistance is provided for projects that have the greatest potential for creating new jobs in areas experiencing terminations or reductions due to reductions in defense spending or for preventing job loss by small business employees, and that have substantial potential for stimulating new economic activity in communities most impacted by reductions in defense spending. Increases the amount authorized for the Small Business Development Company loan program. Authorizes the SBA Administrator to pay transportation expenses and per diem for up to 12 months (currently six) for SBA employees rendering temporary services in connection with disaster assistance.

	</summary>
</bill>
