<bill session="103" type="s" number="1855" updated="2012-07-17T04:46:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-11">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-11"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the coverage of certain Federal labor laws to foreign documented vessels, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411818"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1994-05-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-11" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1517" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Collective bargaining"/>
		<term name="Flags of convenience"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Industrial relations"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="Merchant seamen"/>
		<term name="Merchant ships"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Passenger ships"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/11/1994--Introduced.
Extends coverage under the National Labor Relations Act and the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to certain foreign vessels which: (1) regularly engage in transporting passengers from and to a place in the United States, with or without intervening stops at foreign ports, including a vessel regularly engaged in transporting passengers only from or to a place in the United States if such transport is so arranged for the purposes of avoiding certain consequences that would otherwise result; (2) (if nonliners) regularly engage in transporting cargo in the foreign trade of the United States; and (3) produce or process goods or services for sale or distribution in the United States, and a vessel that engages in transporting cargo between vessels in international waters and a vessel, port, or place in the United States regardless of the vessel's ownership or control. Excludes any such vessel that can demonstrate that citizens of the country of registry: (1) compose at least one-half of the crew; and (2) hold legal title and beneficial ownership and control.

	</summary>
</bill>
