<bill session="103" type="s" number="1869" updated="2012-07-17T05:14:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Counterintelligence Improvements Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Security Act of 1947 to improve counterintelligence measures through enhanced security for classified information, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402727"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="406256" joined="1994-03-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1994-03-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1870)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1964)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-08"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><committee name="Committee on Intelligence"/><text>Committee on Intelligence. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Counterintelligence"/>
		<term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Cryptography"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Financial disclosure"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Polygraphs"/>
		<term name="Profit"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
		<term name="Security clearances"/>
		<term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Travel"/>
		<term name="Vice Presidents"/>
		<term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/24/1994--Introduced.
Counterintelligence Improvements Act of 1994 - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to establish requirements for access to &quot;top secret&quot; information (access). Entitles the President and Vice President, Members of Congress, Justices of the Supreme Court, and Article III judges to access needed for the performance of their governmental functions without regard to the other provisions of this Act. Restricts access among government employees to those who are U.S. citizens who require routine access for the performance of official governmental functions and who have been determined to be trustworthy based upon background investigations. Permits access by others only as permitted in accordance with specified regulations issued by the President which: (1) require of such individuals background investigations and consent to the examination of financial and foreign travel records, as well as the reporting of unauthorized contacts with foreign nationals; (2) provide follow-up investigations; (3) allow access by others for national security reasons; and (4) provide implementation and reporting requirements. Sets forth provisions authorizing waivers for national security reasons. Requires, as conditions of access to classified cryptographic information, that persons: (1) meet the requirements applicable to those having access to top secret information; and (2) be subject, during the period of such access, to periodic polygraph examinations limited in scope to questions of a counterintelligence nature. Amends the Right to Financial Privacy Act to permit a customer who is the subject of a personnel security investigation conducted by an authorized investigative Government agency as a condition of being granted or maintaining access to authorize nonrevocable disclosure of all financial records maintained by financial institutions to the appropriate governmental authorities for the period of the customer's access and for up to five years after such access has been terminated. (Under current law, a person may consent to access to his financial records for a period of three months.) Makes it a crime to possess espionage devices with intent to violate the espionage statutes and to sell top secret documents or materials to foreign governments, with exceptions and a defense that the information was public. Makes it a misdemeanor for a U.S. officer, employer, or contractor to knowingly remove top secret documents and retain them at an unauthorized location. Amends the Federal criminal code to: (1) grant specified U.S. courts jurisdiction to try cases involving espionage and related offenses begun or committed outside the United States; and (2) extend coverage of the special forfeiture provision (permitting the Attorney General to file suit to recover the profits of certain crimes) to additional crimes of espionage and to espionage convictions in foreign courts for misconduct that would constitute offenses under U.S. espionage laws. Permits the Government to deny retirement pay to U.S. retirees in the civil service, Foreign Service, and Central Intelligence Agency retirement and disability systems who are convicted of espionage in foreign courts which involve U.S. national defense information, subject to certification by the Attorney General as to the presence of certain procedural safeguards for such individuals. Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to require consumer reporting agencies, upon request, to furnish: (1) consumer reports to the FBI pursuant to a written certification by the Director of the FBI that the records are sought for an authorized foreign counterintelligence investigation and that the person to whom such reports relate is believed to be a foreign agent; and (2) identifying information respecting any consumer at the Director's request when necessary to the conduct of an authorized counterintelligence investigation. Prohibits such agencies from divulging to the consumer that the FBI has sought or obtained such information. Authorizes the Attorney General to pay rewards of up to $1 million for information leading to: (1) the arrest or conviction of any individual for committing, or conspiring or attempting to commit, espionage; or (2) the prevention or frustration of an act of espionage against the United States. Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to provide a court order process, similar to that required for electronic surveillance, for physical searches for foreign intelligence purposes. Sets forth: (1) reporting requirements; (2) penalties for intentional violations of search or nondisclosure requirements; and (3) provisions for civil actions, including punitive damages, for violations with respect to an unauthorized search or the disclosure of information arising out of an unauthorized search.

	</summary>
</bill>
