<bill session="103" type="s" number="1866" updated="2012-07-17T05:25:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Personnel Security Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Security Act of 1947 to improve personnel measures that enhance security for classified information, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1994-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1994-02-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1867-1868)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><committee name="Committee on Intelligence"/><text>Committee on Intelligence. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Financial disclosure"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Official secrets"/>
		<term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
		<term name="Security clearances"/>
		<term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
		<term name="Travel"/>
		<term name="Vice Presidents"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/24/1994--Introduced.
Personnel Security Act of 1994 - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to: (1) entitle the President and Vice President, Members of Congress, Justices of the Supreme Court, and judges of other U.S. courts established pursuant to Article III of the Constitution to access to top secret information needed for the performance of their governmental functions (category I); and (2) limit such access to only those Government employees who are U.S. citizens who require access for the performance of official governmental functions, who have been determined to be trustworthy based upon a background investigation and appropriate reinvestigations, and who have otherwise satisfied specified requirements (category II). Permits access by others only in accordance with regulations to be issued by the President providing that: (1) no Government employee shall be given access unless such employee has been subject to an appropriate background investigation, has consented to permit examination of financial records, consumer reports, and foreign travel records maintained by U.S. commercial entities pertaining to such employee and has agreed to report any foreign travel which has not been authorized as part of the subject's official duties and any unauthorized contracts with persons known to be foreign nationals or persons representing foreign nations where an effort to acquire classified information is made or where such contacts appear intended for such purpose; (2) all employees granted access shall be subject to additional background investigations at least every five years and to investigation at any time during the period of access; (3) access by persons other than those in categories I and II may be permitted only where the President determines that such access is essential to protect or further national security interests; and (4) a single office within the executive branch shall be designated to monitor and report regarding the implementation and operation of this title. Provides for waivers in extraordinary cases.

	</summary>
</bill>
