<bill session="103" type="s" number="1876" updated="2012-07-17T05:25:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to grant State status to Indian tribes for purposes of the enforcement of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1994-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1946-1947)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution control"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
		<term name="Underground storage"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) treat Indian tribes as States under such Act; (2) delegate primary enforcement authority for programs under such Act to Indian tribes; and (3) provide grant and contract assistance to tribes to carry out such Act. Sets forth conditions under which Indian tribes may be treated as States. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress on: (1) recommendations for addressing hazardous and solid wastes and underground storage tanks (USTs) within Indian country; (2) methods to maximize Indian participation in, and administration of, programs under such Act; and (3) an estimate of the amount of assistance required and a discussion of proposals by the Administrator concerning the provision of assistance to Indian tribes for the administration of such programs. Requires the Administrator to establish an inventory of sites within Indian country at which hazardous waste has been stored or disposed. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reserve at least three percent of the amounts made available to States from the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund for Indian tribes to carry out response actions for petroleum USTs.

	</summary>
</bill>
