<bill session="103" type="s" number="1885" updated="2012-07-17T04:51:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Security Classification Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Security Act of 1947 to provide a uniform framework for the classification and declassification of information in the interests of national security.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1994-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1994-03-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2295-2296)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Archives"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Defense contracts"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="Executive orders"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Information leaking"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Military personnel"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Rating of employees"/>
		<term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
		<term name="Security clearances"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/2/1994--Introduced.
Security Classification Act of 1994 - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to set forth provisions concerning the classification of information in the interests of national security. Allows information to be classified only if: (1) it is owned or under the control of the U.S. Government; and (2) it can be specifically demonstrated that the public release of such information could be expected to impair the ability of the Government to defend the United States or engage in armed conflict, increase the vulnerability of personnel, damage or impair foreign relations, reveal intelligence sources and methods, damage critical research or technology, or impair the ability of the Secret Service to provide required protection. Prohibits the classification of information to: (1) conceal violations of law, inefficiency, or error; (2) prevent embarassment; (3) restrain competition; (4) prevent the release of information not needed for national security purposes; (5) control access to basic research information; (6) control information after its release to the public; or (7) prevent the public release of a group of items of information which individually are not classified. Requires all classified information to be identified as either &quot;Top Secret&quot; or &quot;Secret&quot; and to be so classified only by originating agencies within the executive branch. Requires such originating agency, at the time of classification, to establish a specific date for declassification based upon the expected duration of the national security sensitivity of the information. Provides a duration of 15 years for Top Secret information, and ten years for Secret information, if no duration period can be determined by an agency. Limits access to classified information to persons who have received a security clearance permitting such access and only to the extent needed for the performance of official government functions. Directs the President to issue regulations which provide a uniform system for the protection of classified information applicable to all of the executive branch. Provides access to classified information for the President, Vice President, Members of Congress, and judicial appointees. Authorizes the President to allow access to persons, foreign governments, and international organizations if deemed appropriate. Allows the President to authorize the establishment of special access programs by the Secretaries of State, Defense, and Energy and the Director of Central Intelligence when there is a need for a formal mechanism for access and for more stringent security measures than those generally applicable to classified information. Provides program requirements, including its applicability to Top Secret information. Provides for the declassification of information generally (when the duration period has expired or when determined by any agency head as no longer classified) or pursuant to a request by a member of the public requiring a declassification review. Provides for the declassification for historical reasons of permanently valuable government records. Provides special declassification reviews for topics of historical interest. Requires a senior oversight official, appointed by the President, to monitor the implementation of this title and report annually to the President and appropriate congressional committees. Provides sanctions for unlawful classification activity or disclosure. Requires implementing regulations. Provides transition provisions for currently classified information.

	</summary>
</bill>
