<bill session="103" type="s" number="1884" updated="2012-07-17T06:10:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Immigration and Asylum Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform asylum procedures, to strengthen criminal penalties for the smuggling of aliens, and to reform other procedures to control illegal immigration to the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409923"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1994-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="1994-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1994-03-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2288-2293)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration and Refugee Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Agricultural labor"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Automobile theft"/>
		<term name="Bombings"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="Bribery"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="Burglary"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Child pornography"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Civil service retirement"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal negligence"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Extortion"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid programs"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Food stamps"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Forgery"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Gambling"/>
		<term name="Gangs"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Housing subsidies"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigrants"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Information leaking"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Money laundering"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Officer personnel"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Perjury"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political refugees"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Prostitution"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Repatriation"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Retired military personnel"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Sabotage"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Slavery"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Tax evasion"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Territorial waters"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Treason"/>
		<term name="Undercover operations"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="Wiretapping"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/2/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Alien Smuggling Control Title II: Port of Entry Inspections Title III: Penalties for Document Fraud and Misrepresentation Title IV: Asylum Reform Title V: Illegal Immigration and Border Security Title VI: Border Crossing User Fee Title VII: Detention of Illegal Aliens Title VIII: Public Benefits Abuse Title IX: Work Authorization Verification Title X: Numerical Limitations on Admission of Aliens into the United States Title XI: Miscellaneous Provisions Comprehensive Immigration and Asylum Reform Act of 1994 - Title I: Alien Smuggling Control - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) increase the penalty for alien smuggling; (2) provide an additional penalty for a smuggler who subjects an alien to a substantial risk of death or bodily harm; and (3) subject any smuggler to the death penalty for causing the death of an alien. (Sec. 103) Makes it a crime to smuggle aliens for the purpose of committing crimes in the United States. (Sec. 104) Adds smuggling to RICO. (Sec. 105) Expands Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) seizure authority to permit the seizure of any property used for smuggling or harboring aliens. (Sec. 106) Grants the INS wiretap authority for alien smuggling investigations. (Sec. 111) Expands the definition of aggravated felony for purposes of the immigration laws to include firearms violations, child pornography, RICO violations, and specified other crimes. (Sec. 112) Presumes deportable any alien convicted of an aggravated felony. Provides for the elimination of an administrative hearing for an alien convicted of an aggravated felony who is not lawfully admitted for permanent resident or is a conditional permanent residence. Eliminates other specified deportation procedures for such aliens. (Sec. 113) Permits a U.S. district court to enter a judicial order of deportation at the time of sentencing an alien. (Sec. 114) Restricts certain defenses to deportation available for certain criminal aliens. (Sec. 115) Increases criminal and civil penalties for failing to depart. Title II: Port of Entry Inspections - Makes excludable any alien who presents forged, stolen, altered, or counterfeit documents. Excepts those with a credible fear of persecution or of return to persecution who used such documents. Defines credible fear of persecution or of return to persecution. (Sec. 203) Restricts judicial review to limited habeas corpus proceedings. Title III: Penalties for Document Fraud and Misrepresentation - Increases penalties for fraud and misuse of immigration documents and government issued identification documents. (Sec. 302) Establishes civil and criminal penalties for the preparers of false documents. (Sec. 303) Makes it unlawful to present fraudulent documents before boarding a common carrier or upon arrival. Title IV: Asylum and Reform - Places limits on an asylum applicant's authority to work. (Sec. 403) Grants the Attorney General authority for two years for a program to address the asylum backlog. (Sec. 405) Precludes counting any time in deportation proceedings towards the seven consecutive years defense. Title V: Illegal Immigration and Border Security - Provides for the hiring of 125 additional INS investigators and support staff. Provides additional funding for deportation costs. Title VI: Border Crossing User Fee - Providers for the imposition of fees at ports of entry sufficient to cover the INS's costs of maintaining and operating port of entry facilities. Requires fees to be deposited in the Land Border User Fee Account. Provides for the funding of 100 additional Border Patrol agents and support personnel from the Account. Title VII: Detention of Illegal Aliens - Provides for a two year pilot program of using closed military bases for the detention of illegal aliens. Title VIII: Public Benefits Abuse - Prohibits any unlawful alien from receiving any financial benefits under any Federal program except for specified emergency health care or child nutrition programs. (Sec. 802) Attributes sponsor income to family preference aliens. Title IX: Work Authorization Verification - Provides for the development and implementation of a counterfeit-resistant system to verify work eligibility and Federally-funded public assistance benefits eligibility for all individuals within the United States. Prohibits any document which may be issued under such program from being used as a national identification card. Title X: Numerical Limitations on Admission of Aliens into the United States - Reduces worldwide immigration during FY 1995 through 1999. Limits numerically the number of refugees that may be admitted in any year, unless the Congress enacts an exception. Title XI: Miscellaneous Provisions - Provides for the availability of information for use in criminal prosecutions. Provides for communications between Federal agencies and the INS.

	</summary>
</bill>
