<bill session="103" type="s" number="1890" updated="2012-07-17T06:13:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain disclosures of financial information to expose espionage activities by foreign agents in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405310"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2416-2417)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><committee name="Committee on Intelligence"/><text>Committee on Intelligence. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Counterintelligence"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Financial disclosure"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Security clearances"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/7/1994--Introduced.
Directs the head of each component of the U.S. intelligence community to submit to the President and the congressional intelligence committees a list of all positions that are classified at or below the GS-15 level and that require the individuals to have access to information critical to U.S. national security interests. Requires individuals occupying such positions in excess of 90 days in a calendar year to submit with the head of their agency or component disclosure statements as required under the Ethics in Government Act of 1978. Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require a consumer reporting agency (CRA) to file with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) when requested a consumer report concerning an individual when the FBI Director has certified that: (1) such records are necessary for the conduct of an authorized foreign counterintelligence investigation; and (2) there is sufficient reason to believe that the subject of the report is a foreign power or agent. Outlines information with respect to: (1) identifying information required to be included by a CRA in the report: (2) CRA protection of confidentiality requirements; (3) FBI fee payments for such reports; (4) FBI information dissemination limits; (5) required congressional reports by the Attorney General with respect to all such requests; (6) authorized damages to the consumer for unauthorized receipt or disclosure of such information; (7) disciplinary actions against violators; (8) good faith exceptions for CRA reliance on an FBI certification; and (9) injunctive relief.

	</summary>
</bill>
