<bill session="103" type="s" number="189" updated="2010-04-19T15:00:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-03-03" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the entry into the United States of items produced, grown, or manufactured in the People's Republic of China with the use of forced labor.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300154"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S672)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-03-03"  state="REPORTED"><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 17.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5993-5994)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="194" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="China"/>
		<term name="Diplomacy"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1993--Introduced.
Prohibits the importation of Chinese products unless: (1) the Secretary of the Treasury determines that they are not manufactured with the use of forced labor; (2) such determination is based on certain consultations with international organizations conducting inspections; and (3) a certification is made to the Secretary that a product was not manufactured with the use of forced labor. Requires the United States to use all diplomatic efforts to persuade China to permit representatives of certain international organizations to inspect all facilities holding detainees to assure that products for export are not being produced with the use of forced labor. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of such prohibition and the making of a false certification.

	</summary>
</bill>
