<bill session="103" type="s" number="1928" updated="2012-07-17T04:57:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Second Generation Nuclear Waste Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the availability of adequate waste emplacement capacity for the future licensing of construction and operation of nuclear utilization facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400566"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1994-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1994-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1994-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-03-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2963-2965)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Nuclear energy"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/1994--Introduced.
Second Generation Nuclear Waste Act - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit the issuance of a construction permit or combined construction and operating license for a utilization facility used to generate electricity for commercial sale unless: (1) a federally licensed facility exists for the permanent emplacement of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste generated by the utilization facility; and (2) the emplacement facility has adequate capacity to accept all such generated waste during the reasonably foreseeable operational lifetime of the utilization facility. Prohibits such utilization facilities from generating nuclear wastes in volumes exceeding the capacity of those permanent emplacement facilities.

	</summary>
</bill>
