<bill session="103" type="s" number="1932" updated="2012-07-17T04:30:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Welfare Reform Through State Innovation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish demonstration projects to expand innovations in State administration of the aid to families with dependent children program under title IV of the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2966-2970, S2974)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6810-6811)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Business and social problems"/>
		<term name="Child development"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Child support"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Compulsory education"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
		<term name="Dropout prevention"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Family enterprises"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Marriage"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Savings accounts"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Single-parent families"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Socially handicapped"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Unmarried mothers"/>
		<term name="Vaccination"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Youth employment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Initiatives to Move Welfare Recipients into the Work Force Title II: Initiatives to Strengthen Families and Break the Cycle of Welfare Dependency Title III: Initiatives to Diversify and Improve the Performance of Welfare Services Title IV: Offsetting Expenditure Reductions Welfare Reform Through State Innovation Act - States that the purpose of this Act is to implement the demonstration projects established below as part of a comprehensive national program to: (1) terminate part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) after two years; and (2) make employment available to such families where necessary. (Sec. 4) Provides for demonstration project approval, evaluation, duration, and implementation when effective in breaking the cycle of welfare dependency, unemployment, and poverty. (Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations. Title I: Initiatives to Move Welfare Recipients into the Work Force - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (NHS) to provide for demonstration projects in States with approved applications which: (1) condition AFDC benefits on school attendance or job training for single parents under age 20 with at least one dependent child but no children under six months; (2) limit the time period for the receipt of such benefits; and (3) generally require the parent to live in an adult-supervised home and receive such benefits through a parent or legal guardian. (Sec. 101) Requires participating States to make child care available and pay all education and job training costs in order to conduct such a demonstration project. (Sec. 102) Amends the Job Training Partnership Act to authorize the Secretary to establish a pilot JOB CORPS program targeting young, disadvantaged mothers on AFDC with below school-age children. Requires such program to include a parents as teachers program designed to educate parents in child development. (Sec. 103) Directs the Secretary to provide for State demonstration projects which generally require a parent or other relative of a dependent child to undergo as part of the application process, 30 days of assisted job search or substance abuse treatment before the family may receive AFDC. (Sec. 104) Amends SSA title IV part A to permit States to allow families on AFDC to save up to $10,000 in a qualified education and employment account and still be eligible for AFDC. (Sec. 105) Amends SSA title IV part A and the Internal Revenue Code to allow various offsets against income for self-employment program participants owning small businesses with regard to purchasing capital equipment, repaying business loans, and retaining cash from the business for future business uses for purposes of determining earned income under the AFDC program. Directs the Secretary to provide for demonstration projects in States which: (1) establish public-private partnerships for technical assistance to self-employed AFDC recipients; (2) train AFDC recipients as self-employed providers of child care services; and (3) promote ownership of extended family-owned businesses by AFDC recipients. (Sec. 106) Amends SSA title IV part F (Job Opportunities and Basic Skills Training Program) (JOBS) to emphasize moving people into the work force, then providing post-employment education and training. (Sec. 107) Directs the Secretary to provide for additional demonstration projects in States which move AFDC recipients into the work force. Title II: Initiatives to Strengthen Families and Break the Cycle of Welfare Dependency - Directs the Secretary to provide for State demonstration projects which: (1) establish child centered programs through conversion of certain AFDC and JOBS payments into block grants; (2) provide no additional benefits with respect to children born while a family is on AFDC and allow increases in the earned income disregard; (3) provide incentives to marry; (4) reduce AFDC benefits if school attendance is irregular or preventive health care for dependent children is not obtained; (5) increase child support collection; (6) develop community-based programs for teenage pregnancy prevention and family planning; and (7) strengthen families and break the cycle of welfare dependency. Title III: Initiatives to Diversify and Improve the Performance of Welfare Services - Directs the Secretary to provide for State demonstration projects which: (1) provide placement of AFDC recipients in private sector jobs; and (2) establish performance-based incentives for State public welfare providers. Title IV: Offsetting Expenditure Reductions - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to make certain changes, including elimination of the &quot;three-entity rule,&quot; to provide offsetting expenditure reductions.

	</summary>
</bill>
