<bill session="103" type="s" number="1934" updated="2012-07-17T04:31:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal Alien Control Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to facilitate the apprehension, detention, and deportation of criminal aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400565"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3068, S3071-3072)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration and Refugee Affairs" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political refugees"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/16/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Deportation of Criminal Aliens Title II: Local Cooperation with Federal Officials and Procedures Title III: Miscellaneous Criminal Alien Control Act of 1994 - Title I: Deportation of Criminal Aliens - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that an alien who is convicted of any felony, not just specified felonies as under current law, may be deported. (Sec. 102) Presumes conclusively that an alien convicted of a felony is deportable. Eliminates the administrative hearing process for criminal aliens not lawfully admitted for permanent residence or those with conditional permanent resident status. (Sec. 103) Permits a U.S. district court or a State court to enter a judicial order of deportation at the time of sentencing an alien. (Sec. 105) Restricts certain defenses to deportation available for certain criminal aliens. (Sec. 106) Requires the deportation of a criminal alien after the issuance of the deportation order, even if an appeal is made. Permits review of the order by such alien while outside the United States. (Sec. 107) Increases penalties for deported criminal aliens who return to the United States. (Sec. 108) Places restrictions on asylum claims for criminal aliens. (Sec. 109) Requires the Federal incarceration of an undocumented criminal alien under specified circumstances. Title II: Local Cooperation with Federal Officials and Procedures - Denies funding under the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1993 to a State or local government that will not provide requested information to Federal immigration officials. Title III: Miscellaneous - Provides for the detention of undocumented criminal aliens on closed military installations.

	</summary>
</bill>
