<bill session="103" type="s" number="1948" updated="2012-07-17T04:09:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Counterintelligence and Security Enhancements Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Security Act of 1947 to improve the counterintelligence and security posture of the United States intelligence community and to enhance the investigative authority of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in counterintelligence matters, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1994-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1994-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="406084" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1994-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-05-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3224)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03"><committee name="Committee on Intelligence"/><text>Committee on Intelligence. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8326-8327)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
		<term name="Bank accounts"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer credit"/>
		<term name="Counterintelligence"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of Defense"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Informers"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Investments"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Military intelligence"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
		<term name="Security clearances"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Subversive activities"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transfer of employees"/>
		<term name="Travel"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/17/1994--Introduced.
Counterintelligence and Security Enhancements Act of 1994 - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to prohibit a person from becoming an employee of an agency within the U.S. intelligence community unless the person: (1) authorizes the disclosure of tax returns; (2) agrees to allow an investigative agency to inspect financial accounts valued at over $10,000; and (3) agrees to the inspection of such person's foreign travel records. Sets forth additional requirements for critical intelligence positions, including requirements for information with respect to the nature, location, and material changes to accounts valued at over $10,000 and information with respect to foreign travel unrelated to official duties. Requires authorized investigative agencies to periodically review all information so obtained and notify the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) upon an indication of the loss or compromise of critical intelligence information. Provides for: (1) requests by authorized investigative agencies for appropriate information from governmental entities; (2) protection of the confidentiality of such information; and (3) investigative agency liability for unlawful disclosure of such information. Empowers the FBI Director with overall responsibility for conducting counterintelligence and law enforcement investigations involving persons in critical intelligence positions. Requires the Director of Central Intelligence to report to the congressional intelligence committees on the effectiveness of such investigative activities. Requires implementation of such provisions with respect to current employees in the intelligence community as well as congressional staff having access to critical intelligence information. Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide for the disclosure to the FBI of consumer credit reports (CRs) for counterintelligence purposes if the FBI Director certifies that such records are necessary for an investigation and there is reason to believe that the person for whom the CR is sought is a foreign power or agent. Sets forth provisions governing, with respect to such disclosures by a credit reporting agency: (1) the disclosure of identifying information to the FBI; (2) confidentiality requirements concerning such disclosure; (3) the payment of fees by the FBI for such disclosures; (4) limits on the dissemination of information contained in the CRs; (5) disciplinary actions for disclosure violations (with an exception for a good faith disclosure); and (6) remedies (including injunctive relief). Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide FBI access to tax returns for counterintelligence purposes. Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize the Attorney General to award individuals who provide information which leads to an arrest or conviction with respect to an act of espionage. Provides U.S. court jurisdiction to try cases involving acts of espionage by a U.S. citizen outside the United States. Makes the unauthorized removal and retention of classified documents or material a misdemeanor criminal offense. Allows for the forfeiture of property for violation of certain espionage laws.

	</summary>
</bill>
