<bill session="103" type="s" number="1955" updated="2012-07-17T04:21:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-22">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Budget Process Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to reform the budget process, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300069"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300159" joined="1994-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1994-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400558" joined="1994-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1994-03-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3446-3448)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-22"><text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Budget; Governmental Affairs pursuant to the order of August 4, 1977, with instructions that if one Committee reports, the other Committee have thirty days to report or be discharged.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional voting"/>
		<term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Entitlements"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Federal budget process"/>
		<term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Item veto"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Presidential messages"/>
		<term name="Presidential powers"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/22/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Statement of Congressional Purpose Title II: Binding Budget Law Title III: Enforcement Mechanics Title IV: Sustaining Mechanism Title V: Protection of Social Security Title VI: Timetable Title VII: Conforming Amendments Title VIII: Definitions and Rules of Interpretation Title IX: Effective Date Budget Process Reform Act - Title I: Statement of Congressional Purpose - Declares that the purpose of this Act is to facilitate rational, informed, and timely decisions by the Congress in the course of the Federal budget process. (Sec. 102) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Federal budget process should focus the attention of policymakers and the public on the aggregate impact of Federal spending on the economy, and on the tradeoffs that must be made among priorities in order to control overall levels of spending. (Sec. 103) Declares that the budget process should contain safeguards against delay and inaction, so that temporary shut-downs of the Government may be avoided. Title II: Binding Budget Law - Requires the Congress to enact a binding budget law, in the form of a joint resolution, by April 15 of the calendar year before that in which the fiscal period commences. (Sec. 202) Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives of the Senate to consider any spending bill affecting spending in a major functional category unless and until a joint resolution on the budget is enacted. (Sec. 203) Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to prohibit baseline budgeting. (Sec. 204) Requires the President to submit to the Congress on or before the 15th day after a joint resolution on the budget is enacted a detailed budget for the fiscal period beginning on October 1 of the current calendar year. Title III: Enforcement Mechanics - Subtitle A: Supermajority Required to Break Budget Law - Requires a three-fifths majority vote in the House and the Senate to consider any spending bill prior to the enactment of the budget law. (Sec. 302) Requires the Congressional Budget Office to provide to the Congress an estimate of the costs in each major functional category of certain spending bills as soon as practicable after its introduction. Requires a three-fifths affirmative vote in the House and the Senate to consider over-budget spending bills. Requires a three-fifths affirmative vote in the House and the Senate to waive any provision of this Act. Subtitle B: Limited Enhanced Rescission Authority - Amends the Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to limit the President's rescission authority to spending that is above the limits of the budget law. Subtitle C: &quot;Blank Check&quot; Appropriations Prohibited - Declares the intent of the Congress to end open-ended, &quot;blank check&quot; appropriations which typically authorize spending &quot;such sums as may be necessary.&quot; Requires fixed-dollar appropriations for every account except social security and interest on the debt. Prohibits open-ended appropriations. Requires Executive agencies to adjust benefit levels to ensure that appropriations for entitlement programs are not exceeded. (Sec. 309) Restricts budget authority and entitlement authority to one fiscal period. Subtitle D: &quot;Pay As You Go&quot; Requirement for New Spending - Prohibits the Congress from considering any legislation which exceeds the budget ceiling unless it offsets such increased spending with an equal amount of reductions. Requires a three-fifths affirmative vote in the House and the Senate to waive such prohibition. Title IV: Sustaining Mechanism - Makes appropriations to provide for an automatic continuing resolution if for any account an appropriation for a fiscal period does not become law before the beginning of such period. (Sec. 403) Restricts legislation providing funding to the Committees on Appropriations. Title V: Protection of Social Security - Provides that no reduction in benefits under title II of the Social Security Act (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) shall be made as a consequence of this Act. Title VI: Timetable - Revises the timetable for the congressional budget process. Title VII: Conforming Amendments - Makes various technical and conforming amendments, including changing references to a concurrent resolution on the budget to references to a joint resolution on the budget. Title VIII: Definitions and Rules of Interpretation - Sets forth definitions for specified terms. Title IX: Effective Date - Declares the effective date of this Act to be January 1, 1995, applicable to fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1995.

	</summary>
</bill>
