<bill session="103" type="s" number="1979" updated="2012-07-17T05:17:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sexual Harassment Prevention Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require employers to post, and to provide to employees individually, information relating to sexual harassment that violates title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300076"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1994-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1994-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1994-04-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3723-3724)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Library of Congress"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Sexual harassment of women"/>
		<term name="Supervisors"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/24/1994--Introduced.
Sexual Harassment Prevention Act of 1994 - Directs employers (including Federal and congressional agencies) to keep posted in conspicuous places a notice prepared or approved by the appropriate primary enforcement agency (the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Office of Fair Employment Practices of the House of Representatives, and the Office of Senate Fair Employment Practices) that sets forth: (1) the definition of sexual harassment found in the Code of Federal Regulations or any corresponding similar regulation; (2) the fact that sexual harassment is a violation of Federal law; (3) information describing how to file a complaint with the agency alleging such harassment; (4) an address and toll-free number to be used to contact the agency; and (5) other information required by the agency. Provides for annual notices by employers to individual employees which provide such information and a description of the procedures used by the employers to resolve allegations of sexual harassment. Requires employers to provide to each supervisory employee information specifying the responsibility of, and the methods to be used by, such employee to ensure that immediate and corrective action is taken to address allegations of sexual harassment. Prescribes civil penalties for willful violations of this Act. Directs each primary enforcement agency to make model notices and voluntary guidelines for procedures dealing with allegations of sexual harassment available to employers at no cost as well as a toll-free number for information regarding this Act. Sets forth provisions governing actions by the primary enforcement agencies to enforce sexual harassment statutes and rules.

	</summary>
</bill>
