<bill session="103" type="s" number="1991" updated="2012-07-17T05:19:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-23">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-23" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Professional Boxing Safety Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Professional Boxing Safety Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the safety of journeyman boxers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300071"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1994-05-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3961-3962)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-23"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28"><text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="666" datetime="1994-09-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 666.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-29"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill as reported.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4753" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Sports and recreation"/>
		<term name="Athletes"/>
		<term name="Boxing"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug testing"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Professional associations"/>
		<term name="Professional sports"/>
		<term name="Sports and state"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/28/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Professional Boxing Safety Act - Allows a professional boxing match to be held in the United States only if: (1) the State where the match is to be held has a State boxing commission or the promoter who seeks to put on a boxing event in a State that does not have such a commission has entered into an agreement with the chief administrative officer of a State that does to oversee the match; and (2) such commission has established procedures to carry out this Act. Directs each professional boxer to register with the commission of the State in which such boxer resides or, where a boxer is a resident of a foreign country or a State without such a commission, with any State commission. Requires a commission to issue an identification card to each registered professional boxer to be renewed by the boxer at least once every three years and to be presented to the commission by the time of the weigh-in for a professional boxing match. Directs each commission to establish procedures to: (1) evaluate the professional records of each boxer participating in a boxing match in the State; (2) ensure that no boxer is permitted to box while under suspension from any commission due to injury or other medical-related reason, including a recent knockout, failure of a drug test, inability to safely compete, and the use of false aliases; and (3) ensure that if such commission is considering permitting a boxer, promoter, manager, or other licensee to participate in a boxing event while the individual is under suspension for any other reasons, such commission shall notify and consult the chief administrative officer that ordered the suspension prior to the grant of approval. Requires the results of a professional boxing match and the suspension of a boxer, promoter, or manager to be reported to the professional boxing registries certified by the Association of Boxing Commissions (ABC) and the Florida State Athletic Commission within 48 business hours. Specifies that if the State of Florida ceases to publish and circulate a national suspension list at no cost to other States on a frequent basis, ABC shall select a different public or private entity to voluntarily undertake such task. Authorizes the U.S. Attorney to bring a civil action in U.S. district court requesting relief to restrain a person or entity from continuing to engage in, or to sanction, a professional boxing match in violation of this Act. Imposes criminal penalties on managers, promoters, matchmakers and licensees who knowingly and willfully violate this Act. Directs the Secretary of Labor to conduct a study on the feasibility and cost of a national pension system for professional boxers, including potential funding sources.

	</summary>
</bill>
