<bill session="103" type="s" number="2009" updated="2012-07-17T06:17:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-11">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-11"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Welfare to Self-Sufficiency Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title IV of the Social Security Act by reforming the Aid to Families with Dependent Children Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1994-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1994-04-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-11" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4077-4082)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-11" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Automobiles"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Child support"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Employment subsidies"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Food stamps"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Grievance procedures"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
		<term name="Interest"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="National service"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Savings bonds"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social problems"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tax administration"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/11/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Family Investment Program and Other Welfare Reform Title II: Improvements in the Collection of Child Support Welfare to Self-Sufficiency Act of 1994 - Title I: Family Investment Program and Other Welfare Reform - Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require State AFDC plans in States without a waiver from the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to provide for a program in which the State agency negotiates an agreement with each family on AFDC outlining the steps non-exempt family members must take. Includes among such steps participation in education or job training programs, or in substance abuse treatment or parenting programs, in order to obtain self-sufficiency within a certain period. Requires supplemental services, such as transportation and child care, when necessary for achieving such goal, as well as support and case management when adapting such agreement for changing family circumstances. Requires the State agency to offer such families enrollment in a limited benefit plan under which benefits are suspended after six months, and in which families failing to comply with the agreement are automatically enrolled. (Sec. 101) Requires the Secretaries of Health and Human Services, of Labor, and of Education to ensure appropriate coordination in the planning, development, and operation of the family investment program above and other specified programs, including the JOBS program under SSA title IV part F (Job Opportunities and Basic Skills Training Program) in order to improve departmental services and reduce program overlap and administrative costs. (Sec. 102) Makes numerous miscellaneous amendments to SSA title IV part A. Provides States with various specified options for moving AFDC recipients towards self-sufficiency, including options for: (1) increasing asset limits and disregards for work expenses, earned income, and automobiles; (2) disregarding interest income and certain earned income of new employees and dependent children as well as certain income and resources related to microenterprise and other employment and self-sufficiency initiatives; and (3) requiring certain unemployed parents to participate in job search and training activities. Eliminates the earned income disregard time limitation and various work-related requirements with regard to unemployed parent households. Provides for the inclusion of microenterprise training and activities in the JOBS program, and makes various specified changes with regard to program job searches, work assignments, and grievance procedures. (Sec. 106) Requires pregnant AFDC recipients to participate in the JOBS program. Changes payment formulae for the JOBS program and child care. Increases the JOBS program's authorization. (Sec. 109) Extends transitional child care benefits and the disregards for earned income and child care to non-recipient stepparents. Provides for timely preventive health care for children of AFDC recipients. (Sec. 110) Directs the Secretary to establish wage supplementation demonstration projects for certain AFDC-eligible individuals to provide an incentive to work. (Sec. 111) Amends the Public Health Service Act to increase the authorization for family planning services. Title II: Improvements in the Collection of Child Support - Amends SSA title IV part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) and the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the establishment of a system under which the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) would collect child support via wage withholding and estimated tax payments and disperse it as appropriate. Requires the entire amount of child support owed to be paid to the IRS by the end of the applicable tax year along with the individual's tax return. Subjects delinquent individuals to generally the same penalties applicable to back taxes. (Sec. 203) Gives States the option of periodically making available for publication the identity of individuals at least three months behind in child support payments.

	</summary>
</bill>
