<bill session="103" type="s" number="2018" updated="2012-07-17T04:13:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize Public Law 81-815 (School Construction), and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408898"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4339-4340, S4344)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Building laws"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Construction workers"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Impacted area programs"/>
		<term name="Indian children"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Low-income housing"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/14/1994--Introduced.
Reauthorizes and revises specified Federal law relating to construction of school facilities in areas affected by Federal activities (school construction portion of impact aid program). Provides for financial assistance to federally impacted school districts urgently in need of: (1) school facilities in districts having substantial increases in school membership resulting from new or increased Federal activities and whose membership includes children in need of minimum school facilities; and (2) facility improvements or structural modifications to meet life safety codes, average daily attendance requirements, Federal laws or regulations, or curriculum improvements. Extends the authorization of appropriations. Divides equally between payments to school districts for militarily-connected children (or other children residing on or with a parent working on Federal property) and payments to districts for Indian children (or children with inadequate school facilities due to the revenue impact of Federal property) the remaining funds after the Secretary of Education has determined the portion of funds for temporary school facilities and for children whom local educational agencies (LEAs) are unable to provide education. Prohibits approval of applications for payments based upon increases in the number of students residing on, or residing with a parent employed on, property which is part of a low-rent housing project assisted under the United States Housing Act of 1937 until all other applications for payments relating to militarily connected children and Indian children have been approved for that fiscal year. Revises formulas used in determining: (1) the Federal share for any project; and (2) limitation on total payments to LEAs. Revises application provisions to require: (1) assurance of compliance with Davis-Bacon Act prevailing wage requirements, except for emergency relief impact aid; and (2) resubmission of applications after a three-year period. Provides that provisions for certain additional payments shall take effect only when funds are specifically appropriated for such purpose. Requires that, prior to transfer, facilities meet all State and Federal building health and safety requirements. Authorizes the Secretary, in carrying out school construction impact aid, to use and pay for the services and facilities of other Federal agencies and public or nonprofit agencies or institutions. Sets forth criteria for certain determinations.

	</summary>
</bill>
