<bill session="103" type="s" number="2022" updated="2012-07-17T04:22:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">North Pacific Fishery Waste Reduction Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce waste of fishery resources off Alaska by eliminating the catch of prohibited species, requiring full retention of economic discards and full utilization of processing waste, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300094"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4349)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fish kills"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Fishing boats"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Seafood"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/14/1994--Introduced.
North Pacific Fishery Waste Reduction Act of 1994 - Amends the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act to mandate that the North Pacific Fishery Management Council (the Council) include in each fishery management plan conservation and management measures to reduce economic discards, processing waste, prohibited species catch, and bycatch in each fishery. Authorizes the imposition of a fee incentive system to reduce such discards and waste. (Sec. 4) Sets a deadline for the Council to submit to the Secretary of Commerce (the Secretary) a plan to phase-in fishery management plan amendments which require full retention by fishing vessels and full utilization by U.S. fish processors of all fishery resources caught under its jurisdiction (except prohibited species). Outlines conservation and management measures to reduce the incidental harvest of prohibited species for each groundfish fishery. Directs the Council to include in each fishery management plan a rebuilding plan of each fishery stock identified as being either overfished or at risk. Requires the Council to establish a mandatory observer program on all fishing vessels and fish processors. Grants the Secretary emergency closure authority to prevent overfishing, reduce bycatch, protect prohibited species, or minimize economic discards. Requires the Council to submit a list for publication in the Federal Register of all fishing technologies employed in fisheries under its jurisdiction. Prohibits any person from employing a fishing technology or engaging in any fishery not included on such published list without giving the Council advance notice. Requires the Secretary, at the Council's request, to grant an emergency rule prohibiting any persons or vessels from employing an unlisted technology or engaging in an unlisted fishery in specified circumstances. Instructs the Secretary to submit to certain congressional committees: (1) a plan to develop jointly with industry accurate methods of weighing or determining the volume of harvested fish; and (2) a plan to develop markets and harvesting and processing techniques for arrowtooth flounder. Permits consortia of owners and operators of fishing vessels or fish processing facilities to apply for loan guarantees under the Fishing Vessel Obligation Guarantee program to finance the construction of processing waste reduction facilities onshore, processing waste reduction technology on vessels, or the conversion of vessels for the carriage of fish waste and discards to processing waste reduction facilities. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
