<bill session="103" type="s" number="2024" updated="2010-10-13T13:49:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-26">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1994-05-26" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">AIP bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Airport Improvement Program Temporary Extension Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Airport Improvement Program Temporary Extension Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Airport Improvement Program Temporary Extension Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide temporary obligational authority for the airport improvement program and to provide for certain airport fees to be maintained at existing levels for up to 60 days, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404219"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4397-4399)</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-04-19" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4394, S4397-4403"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21T11:05:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21T14:40:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03T12:25:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Oberstar moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03T12:25:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2946-2951"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03T12:25:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="1994-05-03T12:51:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE"><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03T12:51:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04"><text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-12"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="pingpong" datetime="1994-05-12" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_BACK:SENATE"><text>Senate concurred in the House amendment with an amendment (SP 1705) by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5704-5707"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-05-16"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17T19:46:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Wise moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17T19:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17T19:54:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3496"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17T19:54:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1994-05-17" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident datetime="1994-05-20" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1994-05-26" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-260" type="public" datetime="1994-05-26"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-260.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Commercial aviation"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Air cargo"/>
		<term name="Air traffic"/>
		<term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
		<term name="Airlines"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Personnel management"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Regulatory reform"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Transportation planning"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s1705"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1994--Senate agreed to House amendment with amendment. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Airport Improvement Program Title II: Airport-Air Carrier Disputes Regarding Airport Fees Title III: Reform of Air Traffic Control System Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions Airport Improvement Program Temporary Extension Act of 1994 - Title I: Airport Improvement Program - Amends the Airport and Airway Improvement Act of 1982 to authorize appropriations for FY 1994 for airport development and planning projects. (Sec. 101) Extends the obligational authority of the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to make grants for airport development and planning projects through June 30, 1994. (Sec. 102) Limits to a specified percentage the apportionment for primary and cargo service airports if the Congress enacts a law limiting the apportionment for airport development and planning to less than $1.9 billion for any fiscal year. (Sec. 103) Increases the minimum funding for primary airports. (Sec. 104) Sets forth a formula for the reduction of funds not apportioned in any fiscal year for primary airports, cargo service airports, and Alaskan airports. Requires such reduced amounts to be credited to a discretionary fund. (Sec. 105) Sets forth mandates that not less than: (1) five percent (currently, ten) of the funds for airport development and planning be distributed for reliever airports; or (2) 1.5 percent (currently, 2.5 percent) of such funds be distributed for nonprimary commercial service airports and certain noncommercial service public airports. (Sec. 106) Provides as an allowable project cost reimbursable by the Government any airport development and planning costs: (1) incurred during FY 1994, before execution of a grant agreement that is in accordance with an approved airport layout plan and applicable requirements, for project work for which the agreement was previously executed during FY 1994; and (2) where the Federal share of such costs is only paid from sums apportioned for primary an cargo service airports. (Sec. 107) Limits to no more than $200,000 the amount of discretionary funds that may be used by a sponsor of a reliever airport for project costs related to terminal development, including allowable project costs for commercial service airports enplaning up to .05 percent of total U.S. enplanement. Allows the unlimited use of such funds for terminal development at primary airports enplaning up to .05 percent of total U.S. enplanements (small airports). (Sec. 109) Declares that nothing shall preclude the Secretary, after September 30, 1993, from obligating by grant agreement funds which have been recovered by the United States from grants made for airport development and planning projects if they are obligated only for increases in such grants. Title II: Airport-Air Carrier Disputes Regarding Airport Fees - Authorizes air carriers to file with the Secretary complaints alleging the unreasonableness of increased fees imposed upon them by airport operators. Permits airport operators and affected air carriers to submit comments and any related materials to the Secretary with respect to such complaints. Title III: Reform of Air Traffic Control System - Directs the Secretary to undertake a study of management, regulatory, and legislative reforms which would enable the Federal Aviation Administration's (FAA) air traffic control system to provide better services to users and reduce the costs of providing such services without reducing the safety or availability or structure of the system. Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Requires the FAA to continue to pay quarterly retention allowance payments to certain terminated employees of a FAA demonstration project. Authorizes the Administrator of the FAA to make payment for costs incurred under such project for a specified period. (Sec. 401) Requires the Administrator of the FAA to study, and submit the results to specified congressional committees, of any impediments that may exist in achieving appropriate air traffic controller staffing levels at hard-to-staff facilities.

	</summary>
</bill>
