<bill session="103" type="s" number="2033" updated="2012-07-17T04:30:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lost Creek Land Exchange Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the exchange of certain lands within the State of Montana.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-04-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4557-4565)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-21"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-22"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Agriculture, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Parks, Preservation and Recreation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-942.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Easements"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Forest roads"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Lumber trade"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/1994--Introduced.
Lost Creek Land Exchange Act of 1994 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire certain lands owned by the Brand S Corporation and located in the Lost Creek area of the Deerlodge National Forest and within the Gallatin National Forest (to be added to and administered as part of such National Forests) in exchange for certain lands within such National Forests and specified timber rights on Deerlodge National Forest lands. Directs the Secretary to secure legal public road access to Gallatin National Forest System lands in the Eightmile Creek area and the Miller Gulch-Fridley Creek-Dry Creek area. Releases the United States from any liability under Federal, State, or local law solely as a result of acquiring an interest in the Lost Creek Tract or due to circumstances or events occurring before acquisition, including any release or threat of release of hazardous substances.

	</summary>
</bill>
