<bill session="103" type="s" number="2051" updated="2012-07-17T04:23:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-04-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Volunteer Firefighter and Rescue Squad Worker Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude from the definition of employee firefighters and rescue squad workers who perform volunteer services and to prevent employers from requiring employees who are firefighters or rescue squad workers to perform volunteer services, and to allow an employer not to pay overtime compensation to a firefighter or rescue squad worker who performs volunteer services for the employer, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300099"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409580" joined="1994-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1994-05-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-09-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4890-4891)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Fire fighters"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Rescue work"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/1994--Introduced.
Volunteer Firefighter and Rescue Squad Worker Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude from coverage any employee fire fighters or rescue squad members during the period in which they volunteer their services at a location where they are not employed. Waives overtime compensation requirements when fire fighters or rescue squad members volunteer their services to their employer and sign a legally binding waiver. Prohibits employer coercion of such volunteering.

	</summary>
</bill>
