<bill session="103" type="s" number="2066" updated="2012-07-17T06:28:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mni Wiconi Act Amendments of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Mni Wiconi Act Amendments of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the Mni Wiconi Rural Water Supply Project, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1994-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5076)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-844.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. With written report No. 103-378.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="632" datetime="1994-09-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 632.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-3" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3954" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Ecosystem management"/>
		<term name="Electric power distribution"/>
		<term name="Electric utility rates"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Indian water rights"/>
		<term name="Irrigation"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Missouri River development"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="South Dakota"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/26/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Mni Wiconi Act Amendments of 1994 - Amends the Mni Wiconi Project Act of 1988 to include within its purposes the provision of a sufficient water supply to the Rosebud and Lower Brule Indian Reservations in South Dakota. (Sec. 4) Requires the connection of the Rosebud and Lower Brule Indian Reservations to the Oglala Sioux Rural Water System. (Sec. 5) Increases the Federal share to up to 80 percent (currently 65 percent) of the West River and the Lyman-Jones Rural Water Systems. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with non-Federal entities to plan, operate, and replace municipal, rural, and industrial water systems, to be known respectively as the Rosebud Sioux Rural Water System and the Lower Brule Sioux Rural Water System (Systems). Includes in such Systems appropriate pumping, treatment, and electrical power facilities, pipelines, and related equipment. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary to interconnect the Lyman-Jones and the West River rural water systems with the other systems under such Act and to provide water from the Missouri River through common facilities of the Oglala, Rosebud, and Lower Brule systems. (Sec. 8) Subjects such Systems to specified: (1) water and fish and wildlife conservation requirements; and (2) irrigation use prohibitions. (Sec. 12) Authorizes appropriations for the planning, design, and construction of all systems cited under this Act, to be used through the end of FY 2003. Authorizes appropriations for the: (1) Oglala, Rosebud, and Lower Brule Sioux rural water supply systems; and (2) waste water disposal system feasibility studies required under such Act. States that water delivery expenses to the West River and Lyman-Jones rural water systems are a non-Federal responsibility and shall be paid for annually by the systems. (Sec. 13) Applies certain water rights provisions under such Act to the Systems. (Sec. 14) Requires the Secretary to conduct waste water feasibility studies with regard to the Pine Ridge, Rosebud, and Lower Brule Indian Reservations.

	</summary>
</bill>
