<bill session="103" type="s" number="2065" updated="2012-07-17T05:52:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to differentiate between fats, oils, and greases of animal, marine, or vegetable origin, and other oils and greases, in issuing regulations under the Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="411271" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1994-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1994-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5074-5075)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-12-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15423)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Oils and fats"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require the President, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the heads of other Federal agencies, in issuing or enforcing any regulation or interpretation or guideline relating to a fat, oil, or grease under any Federal law, to differentiate between: (1) animal fats and oils and greases and fish and marine mammal oils or oils of vegetable origin; and (2) other oils and greases, including petroleum. Requires the President, the Administrator, and the heads of Federal agencies, in differentiating between such classes, to consider differences in the physical, chemical, biological, and other properties and in the environmental effects of the classes.

	</summary>
</bill>
