<bill session="103" type="s" number="206" updated="2012-07-17T06:30:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401874"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S713-714)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-10"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Agriculture, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-19.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Department of the Interior.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Camping"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Geothermal resources"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Irrigation"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Lumber trade"/>
		<term name="Mining leases"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Water rights"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1993--Introduced.
Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 - Designates certain lands in Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Transfers administrative jurisdiction over designated lands from the Bureau of Land Management to the Forest Service. Amends the Endangered American Wilderness Act of 1978 with respect to the study of certain potential wilderness areas. Redesignates the Big Blue Wilderness as the Uncompahgre Wilderness. Establishes the Fossil Ridge Recreation Management Area, in Colorado. Withdraws such lands from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; from location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and from disposition under the mineral and geothermal leasing laws. Establishes the Bowen Gulch Protection Area in the Arapaho National Forest in Colorado. Applies the same restrictions concerning land withdrawal for the Fossil Ridge Recreation Management Area to the Protection Area. Prohibits the President and any other employee of the United States from issuing a license or permit for the development or enlargement of any water resource facility within specified areas described in this Act. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to allow reasonable access to water resource facilities within specified areas. Sets forth various restrictions on water rights. Withdraws certain lands in the Piedra, Roubideau, and Tabeguache areas of specified national forests from all forms of location, leasing, patent, disposition, or disposal under the public land, mining, and mineral and geothermal leasing laws of the United States. Permits livestock grazing in such areas. Bars mechanized or motorized travel in such areas, with exceptions. Requires the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to compile data concerning the water resources of such areas and water resources facilities affecting such values. Directs the Secretary: (1) to report to specified congressional committees on the status of private property interests located within the Spanish Peaks Further Planning Area of the Pike-San Isabel National Forest in Colorado; and (2) to manage the Area as provided by the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1980.

	</summary>
</bill>
