<bill session="103" type="s" number="2068" updated="2012-07-17T05:22:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lewis and Clark Rural Water System Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the construction of the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System and to authorize assistance to the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System, Inc., a nonprofit corporation, for the planning and construction of the water supply system, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408898"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1994-08-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1994-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1994-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5076-5077)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-14"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-28"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-844.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-3" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4363" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Drainage"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Electric power distribution"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Iowa"/>
		<term name="Irrigation"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Minnesota"/>
		<term name="Missouri River development"/>
		<term name="South Dakota"/>
		<term name="Water conservation"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/1994--Introduced.
Lewis and Clark Rural Water System Act of 1994 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to make grants to the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System, Inc., a nonprofit corporation, for the planning and construction of a water supply system to provide service to specified counties in South Dakota, Minnesota, and Iowa. Requires the Secretary to make grants and other funds available to the System and other private, State, and Federal entities for the initial development of the environmental enhancement component. Directs that the water conservation program: (1) be designed to ensure that users of water from the water supply system use the best practicable technology and management techniques to conserve water use; and (2) include provisions for periodic review and revision. Specifies that mitigation for fish and wildlife losses incurred as a result of the construction and operation of the water supply system be on an acre-for-acre basis, based on ecological equivalency, concurrent with project construction. Requires the Western Area Power Administration to make available the capacity and energy required to meet the pumping and incidental operational requirements of the water supply system during the period beginning May 1, and ending October 31, of each year from power designated for future irrigation and drainage pumping for the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin program. Provides that this Act shall not: (1) limit the authorization for water projects in South Dakota, Iowa, and Minnesota; or (2) preempt State water rights. Specifies the Federal and non-Federal share of the cost. Authorizes the Secretary to allow the Bureau of Reclamation to provide project construction oversight to the water supply system and environmental enhancement component. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
