<bill session="103" type="s" number="2077" updated="2012-07-17T05:07:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Improvement Volunteer Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for waivers of the requirements of the Davis-Bacon Act with respect to certain Federal programs as such requirements relate to volunteers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1994-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1994-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5193-5194)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Clinics"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Construction workers"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health facilities"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Libraries"/>
		<term name="Migrant labor"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
		<term name="Wages"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1994--Introduced.
Community Improvement Volunteer Act of 1994 - Provides for waivers of the prevailing-wage-setting requirements of the Davis-Bacon Act with respect to volunteers who perform services under the Library Services and Construction Act, the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, or migrant health centers or community health centers provisions of the Public Health Service Act. Prohibits approval of any expense, benefit, or fee being paid to such volunteers which has the effect of undermining labor standards by creating downward pressure on prevailing wages in the local construction industry. Directs the Secretary of Labor to report to the appropriate congressional committees on such waivers for volunteers on such projects and make recommendations with respect to other Davis-Bacon-related Acts that could be addressed to permit volunteer work.

	</summary>
</bill>
