<bill session="103" type="s" number="2091" updated="2012-07-17T04:09:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Firefighters Pay Fairness Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend certain provisions of title 5, United States Code, in order to ensure equality between Federal firefighters and other employees in the civil service and other public sector firefighters, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300086"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1994-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1994-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1994-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1994-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1994-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1994-07-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5450-5451)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4514" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Fire fighters"/>
		<term name="Fringe benefits"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Interoceanic canals"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Panama Canal"/>
		<term name="Panama Canal Commission"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Supervisors"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/1994--Introduced.
Firefighters Pay Fairness Act of 1994 - Amends Federal law to extend existing biweekly pay period and pay computation requirements to Federal fire fighters and employees of the judicial branch. Repeals the current exception from such requirements of employees on the Isthmus of Panama in the service of the Panama Canal Commission. States that, for fire fighters, the annual rate of basic pay shall be calculated on the basis of 26 administrative biweekly work periods of up to 106 hours each. Prescribes a formula for computing the basic biweekly pay of Federal employees who are not fire fighters but perform fire fighting duties. Requires compensation at time-and-a-half per hour for any hours worked in excess of 106 during a biweekly pay period by fire fighters subject to the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938. Specifies limits on the payment of other premium pay to such fire fighters. Prescribes basic rates of pay for fire fighters: (1) promoted to a supervisory position; and (2) selected and assigned for training. Authorizes a Federal agency to pay cash awards of up to five percent of basic pay to fire fighters or other employees performing fire fighting duties who possess and make substantial use of special skills or certifications, including handling hazardous materials or certification as an emergency medical technician.

	</summary>
</bill>
