<bill session="103" type="s" number="2118" updated="2012-07-17T06:08:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violent Crime Intervention Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the national crime database and create a Federal cause of action for early release of violent felons.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1994-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1994-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5828-5830)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Criminal Records Database Title II: Liability for Early Release of Violent Felons Violent Crime Intervention Act of 1994 - Title I: National Criminal Records Database - Directs the Attorney General to issue guidelines establishing specific requirements for a State to qualify as a fully participating member of the Interstate Identification Index of the Department of Justice. Specifies that such guidelines shall require that: (1) all arrest reports and final disposition orders be submitted to the State records repository within 21 days; (2) the State repository enter such records and orders into the State database within 14 days after receiving the information; (3) the State conduct and report to the Attorney General on annual audits to ensure that State criminal records contain correct and complete information about every felony arrest; and (4) the State certify to the Attorney General on January 1 of each year that the law enforcement agencies, courts, and records officials of the State are in compliance. Requires a State that does not qualify as a fully participating State pursuant to such guidelines to pay a user fee for each identification request made to the Index. Authorizes appropriations to the Attorney General for grants to States to establish or improve their criminal record databases to qualify as a fully participating member. Title II: Liability for Early Release of Violent Felons - Grants the victim (or in the case of a homicide, the family of the victim) of a violent crime a Federal cause of action in any district court against a State if the individual committing the crime previously had been convicted by the State of a violent offense, was released from incarceration prior to serving his or her full sentence, and committed the violent crime before the original sentence would have expired. Immunizes a State from such liability if the State requires a violent criminal to be incarcerated for the entire term of imprisonment to which the criminal is sentenced. Makes a State liable to the victim in an action brought under this title for the actual damages resulting from the violent crime, but not for punitive damages.

	</summary>
</bill>
