<bill session="103" type="s" number="2126" updated="2012-07-17T05:47:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Government Interstate Waste Control Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize local governments and Governors to restrict receipt of out-of-State municipal solid waste, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400564"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6452-6453)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Industrial pollution"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Maps"/>
		<term name="Methane"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/18/1994--Introduced.
Local Government Interstate Waste Control Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit owners or operators of landfills or incinerators from receiving out-of-State municipal solid waste unless they obtain authorization from the affected local government. Exempts from such prohibition: (1) landfills or incinerators that, during the one-year period preceding this Act's enactment date, received documented shipments of out-of-State municipal solid waste or, before this Act's enactment date, obtained authorization to accept such waste; (2) landfills in compliance with all Federal and State laws and regulations concerning design and location, leachate collection, groundwater monitoring, and financial assurance for closure and post-closure care and corrective action; or (3) incinerators in compliance with specified requirements of the Clean Air Act and State laws and regulations relating to facility design. Permits a Governor, if requested by an affected local government and local solid waste planning unit, to limit the amount of out-of-State waste, during a one-year period, received by landfills exempted from authorization requirements as a result of receiving documented shipments of such waste during the one-year period preceding this Act's enactment date. Requires owners or operators of landfills or incinerators exempt from this Act's requirements to make contracts entered into for the disposal of out-of-State waste available to the public for inspection. Permits States to exercise the option to become exempt from this Act's requirements if they notify the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and make specific reference to this Act in taking any appropriate action to reject this Act's applicability.

	</summary>
</bill>
