<bill session="103" type="s" number="212" updated="2012-07-17T05:44:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Reserve Reform Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the Federal Reserve System and to provide for prompt disclosure of certain decisions of the Federal Open Market Committee.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-07-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S730)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1350-1351)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Money"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Bank reserves"/>
		<term name="Credit"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Federal reserve system"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Monetary policy"/>
		<term name="Open market operations"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Price policy"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/1993--Introduced.
Federal Reserve Reform Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Reserve Act to require the Federal Open Market Committee (the Committee) to consult with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers before the Federal Reserve Board submits to the Congress certain mandated reports. Changes from August to January the calendar year expiration date of the term of the Chairman of the Federal Reserve. Mandates immediate public disclosure by the Committee of each change in intermediate monetary policy targets (monetary and credit aggregates, prices, interest rates, or bank reserves) which it adopts. Permits the Comptroller General to audit monetary policy deliberations, decisions, or actions, including transactions made under the Committee's direction. Requires the Board to submit annually to the President its estimated receipts and proposed expenditures for the current year, and the next two succeeding years (including those of the Federal Reserve Banks).

	</summary>
</bill>
