<bill session="103" type="s" number="2128" updated="2012-07-17T04:33:48-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize an entrance fee surcharge at the Grand Canyon National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300071"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5943-5946)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/18/1994--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to authorize the Superintendent of the Grand Canyon National Park to: (1) charge and collect, in addition to the entrance fee, a surcharge in an amount not to exceed $2 for each individual charged such fee; and (2) remit the surcharge to the special account for the Grand Canyon National Park infrastructure improvement established by this Act. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to use funds in the special account to pay the Federal share of the cost of eligible projects such as the design, construction, operation, maintenance, repair, or replacement of a facility within the Park that meets specified guidelines. Requires the Director to enter into a cost-sharing agreement with a non-Federal Government entity for each eligible project. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress on the Park infrastructure improvement.

	</summary>
</bill>
