<bill session="103" type="s" number="2121" updated="2012-07-17T04:21:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Park Service Entrepreneurial Management Reform Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Park Service Entrepreneurial Management Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote entrepreneurial management of the National Park Service, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5832-5834)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Energy Production and Regulation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-930.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="649" datetime="1994-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 649.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-11-30"><text>By Senator Johnston from Committee on Energy and Natural Resources filed written report. Report No. 103-422.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Mineral Resources Development and Production" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4533" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4533" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Blind"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fund raising"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Sports and recreation"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/1994--Reported to Senate amended. National Park Service Entrepreneurial Management Reform Act of 1994 - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to increase fees for admission to units of the National Park System (NPS) and other specified areas. Makes receipts from admission available, subject to appropriation, for authorized resource protection, rehabilitation, and conservation projects. Revises provisions regarding the issuance of lifetime admission permits, including a limitation that such a permit entitles only the permittee to free admission. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to report to the Congress identifying areas where the Secretary recommends that the establishment of admission fees would be appropriate but where such fees are prohibited by law, and areas where such fees are authorized but not being collected. Increases the penalty for violations of rules and regulations regarding admission and special recreation use fees. Modifies provisions regarding the use of fees collected. Requires that specified receipts be covered into a special National Park Renewal Fund. Makes such funds available for infrastructure needs at parks. Directs the Secretary to develop procedures for the use of amounts in the Fund. Repeals a requirement that qualified public or private entities selling annual admission permits reimburse the United States for the full amount to be received from the sale of such permits when or before the agency delivers the permits to such entity for sale. Directs the Secretary to establish reasonable fees for uses of NPS units that require special arrangements. Prohibits charging an admission or recreation use fee for entrance into, or use of, any federally owned area operated and maintained by a Federal agency which is used for outdoor recreation purposes, except as provided for by such Act. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) negotiate and enter into agreements with State or local governments, individuals, or other entities for the purpose of sharing costs or services in carrying out authorized functions and responsibilities of the Secretary with respect to NPS units; and (2) provide, subject to appropriation, the Federal funding share from any funds available to the NPS in carrying out such agreements. Provides for cost recovery by the United States for damage to NPS resources.

	</summary>
</bill>
