<bill session="103" type="s" number="2127" updated="2012-07-17T05:46:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Railroad Grade Crossing Safety Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve railroad safety at grade crossings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403171"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1994-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1994-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1994-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1994-08-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5943)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Bridges"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Driver licenses"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Highway research"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for railroad accidents"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
		<term name="Railroad research"/>
		<term name="Railroad safety"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Signs and signboards"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Traffic engineering"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Truck drivers"/>
		<term name="Trucks"/>
		<term name="Vandalism"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/18/1994--Introduced.
Railroad Grade Crossing Safety Act of 1994 - Amends the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 to direct the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to establish uniform standards regarding the allocation of responsibility for selection and installation of signal devices at public railroad-highway grade crossings. (Sec. 3) Requires the Secretary to conduct a rulemaking proceeding to require that each State highway safety management system include: (1) public railroad-highway grade crossing closure plans that are aimed at eliminating high-risk or redundant crossings; and (2) railroad-highway grade crossings policies that limit the creation of new at-grade crossings for vehicle or pedestrian traffic, recreational use, or any other purpose. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to establish an emergency &quot;800&quot; telephone number notification system that the public can use to convey to railroads information about malfunctions or other safety problems at such crossings. Prohibits a court from holding the Secretary or other Federal agency, or State or local government agency liable for damages caused by any action or failure to perform a duty under this Act. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations for Operation Lifesaver, Inc. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to ensure that the National Intelligent Vehicle-Highway Systems Program addresses the use of intelligent vehicle-highway system technologies to promote safety at railroad-highway grade crossings. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations to prohibit the driver of a motor vehicle transporting hazardous materials in commerce, and of any commercial vehicle, from driving such vehicle onto a railroad-highway crossing without having sufficient space to drive through the crossing without stopping. Sets forth civil penalties for persons who deface signs or devices or who trespass on such crossings. (Sec. 8) Amends the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1986 to require the Secretary to issue regulations establishing sanctions and penalties for persons who operate a commercial motor vehicle and violate laws pertaining to railroad-highway grade crossings. (Sec. 9) Requires the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, and the Office of Motor Carrier Safety within the Federal Highway Administration, to cooperate with the National Association of Governors' Highway Safety Representatives, the Commercial Vehicle Safety Alliance, and Operation Lifesaver, Inc., to improve enforcement of laws pertaining to railroad-highway grade crossings.

	</summary>
</bill>
