<bill session="103" type="s" number="2137" updated="2010-04-19T20:03:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-07">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-06-07" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Montana National Forest Management Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain National Forest lands in the State of Montana as wilderness, to release other National Forest lands in the State of Montana for multiple use management, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6133)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-07"  state="REPORTED"><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 455.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2473" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Flood control"/>
		<term name="Geothermal resources"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Hunting"/>
		<term name="Hydrology"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Lakes"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National recreation areas"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
		<term name="Reservoirs"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Water rights"/>
		<term name="Weather forecasting"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/19/1994--Introduced.
Montana National Forest Management Act of 1994 - Designates certain national forest lands in Montana as wilderness areas. Retains existing water rights in such areas. Directs that, prior to the revision of Land and Resource Management Plans for national forest lands in Montana that were completed prior to this Act's enactment, decisions to allocate roadless areas to wilderness or nonwilderness categories and environmental analyses related to such allocations shall not be subject to judicial review. Provides that, except for decisions allocating lands to wilderness and nonwilderness categories, nothing in this Act shall preclude judicial review of: (1) Department of Agriculture decisions implementing such Plans or decisions made concerning the management of national forest lands subsequent to allocations to wilderness and nonwilderness categories; and (2) Forest Service regional guides and other departmental policies of general applicability. Deems certain reviews by the Department of Agriculture of national forest lands in Montana to be an adequate consideration of the suitability of such lands for inclusion in the national wilderness preservation system. Requires certain lands which were not designated as wilderness, special management, national recreation, or wilderness study areas by this Act to be managed for multiple use. Prohibits the Department of Agriculture from conducting any further statewide roadless area review and evaluation of national forest system lands in Montana for purposes of determining suitability for inclusion in the national wilderness preservation system. Designates specified national forest system lands in Montana as national education, recreation, scenic, wildlife, and wilderness study areas. Withdraws the Badger-Two Medicine Area from all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under mining and public land laws and from disposition under geothermal and mineral leasing laws. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to manage such area as to protect its wilderness qualities. Provides that nothing shall preclude the gathering of timber by the Blackfeet Tribe in exercise of valid treaty rights. Requires the Secretary to review such area in accordance with the Wilderness Act of 1964. Provides that the Bitter Creek and Axolotl Lakes Wilderness Study Areas have been sufficiently studied for wilderness designations. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
