<bill session="103" type="s" number="2135" updated="2012-07-17T06:14:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">VA State Health-Care Reform Pilot Programs Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Department of Veterans Affairs to conduct pilot programs for delivering health care services in States which have statutorily reformed their health care systems.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6125, S6127)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/19/1994--Introduced.
VA State Health-Care Reform Pilot Programs Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct pilot programs in up to five States that have reformed health-care systems (a statutorily established system to assure residents access to health-care services) under which the Department of Veterans Affairs may provide, directly or by contract, health-care services on the same or a similar basis as the State plan mandates for residents. Makes eligible for such services veterans, survivors and dependents of disabled veterans or veterans who died in active service, and members of the family of any veteran participating in the pilot program. Outlines pilot program conditions, including a 30-day waiting period after notifying specified congressional committees of the intention to establish the program. Requires the payment of all applicable premiums, copayments, deductibles, and coinsurance payments by program participants. Terminates the authority to conduct the pilot programs as of December 31, 1990. Establishes a revolving fund and authorizes appropriations to the fund for FY 1995 through 1997 for pilot program purposes. Provides for the collection of funds from program participants. Allows any required administrative reorganization necessary to carry out a pilot program without the required congressional notification and waiting period. Provides for: (1) marketing activities to promote the pilot programs; and (2) required reports.

	</summary>
</bill>
