<bill session="103" type="s" number="2144" updated="2012-07-17T05:55:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Support for Families with Children with Disabilities Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Families of Children with Disabilities Support Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to provide family support for families of children with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6198-6199)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10281-10283)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/23/1994--Introduced.
Support for Families with Children with Disabilities Act of 1994 - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to add a new part I, Family Support, which may be cited as the Families of Children with Disabilities Support Act of 1994. Directs the Secretary of Education to make three-year grants to States for systems change and advocacy activities for statewide systems of support for families with children with disabilities. Sets forth priorities and application requirements. Requires States desiring such assistance to designate lead entities and establish State Family Support Policy Councils. Includes among authorized activities training and technical assistance, interagency coordination, local or regional councils, outreach, advocacy services, policy studies, hearings and forums, public awareness and education, needs assessment, program data, and pilot demonstration projects. Requires State strategic plans, progress criteria, and reports. Requires panels of experts to evaluate grant applications. Directs the Secretary to make grants to or contracts with appropriate public or private agencies and organizations, including institutions of higher education, for: (1) providing technical assistance and information on statewide systems of family support; and (2) conducting a national evaluation of the program of grants to States. Directs the Secretary to: (1) review Federal programs with respect to their impact on such family support, consistent with specified policies; and (2) make grants or contracts for projects of national significance for developing national and State policies and practices for family-centered and family-directed systems of support for families of children with disabilities. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
