<bill session="103" type="s" number="2143" updated="2012-07-17T04:13:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Deficit and Debt Reduction and Health Care Financing Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a value added tax and to use the receipts from the tax to reduce the Federal budget deficit and Federal debt and to finance health care reform.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300053"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6197-6198)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-23" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-27"><text>Star Print ordered on on the bill.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Value-added tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/23/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Value Added Tax Title II: Surplus Revenues Deficit and Debt Reduction and Health Care Financing Act of 1994 - Title I: Value Added Tax - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a five percent tax on taxable transactions (such tax to be known as a value added tax). Describes taxable transactions as the sale, import, or export of certain property or services. Sets forth rules for the administration of such tax. Title II: Surplus Revenues - Establishes the Deficit Reduction and Health Care Reform Trust Fund. Appropriates to such Fund 80 percent of the revenues from the value added tax to reduce the public debt and 20 percent to carry out Federal health care reform programs.

	</summary>
</bill>
