<bill session="103" type="s" number="2152" updated="2012-07-17T05:09:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the transfer of lands contiguous to the Holloman Air Force Base, New Mexico, by the Secretary of the Interior to the Department of the Air Force for the construction of evaporation ponds to support a wastewater treatment facility, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300036"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1994-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6396)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-26"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Air bases"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Geothermal resources"/>
		<term name="Grazing"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
		<term name="Mining leases"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1994--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer to the Department of the Air Force jurisdiction and control of specified public lands located in Otero County, New Mexico, contiguous to Holloman Air Force Base to be used by the Secretary of the Air Force (Secretary) for the construction of new evaporation ponds to support a wastewater treatment facility at the Base. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) existing grazing rights on the transferred lands and the adjustment of grazing allotments; (2) compliance with environmental laws with respect to the use and management of such lands; (3) responsibility and liability for the cleanup of hazardous substances on such transferred lands; (4) mining; (5) rights-of-way; and (6) public access and uses. Prohibits the Secretary from requiring a permit for public access to such lands. Directs the Secretary to ensure that the entry gate to the transferred lands located along U.S. Highway 70 is open to the public.

	</summary>
</bill>
