<bill session="103" type="s" number="2151" updated="2012-07-17T05:15:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ward Valley Land Transfer Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain lands to the State of California and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-687.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1994--Introduced.
Ward Valley Land Transfer Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the California Department of Health Services all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified lands in San Bernardino County, California, and improvements thereon if: (1) the conveyance is in consideration of the fair market value of the conveyed lands; (2) such sums received are made available to the Secretary without further appropriation for land acquisition purposes; (3) the State of California releases the United States from any liability for claims relating to the property; and (4) the conveyance is of fee simple title to the property subject to reversion to the United States if the property is not licensed and used as a low-level radioactive waste disposal facility or if payment is not made in accordance with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
