<bill session="103" type="s" number="2157" updated="2012-07-17T04:25:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-05-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Counterproliferation Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the Department of Defense for fiscal year 1995 for counterproliferation of weapons of mass destruction.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300036"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-05-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Biological weapons"/>
		<term name="Chemical weapons"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Mass destruction weapons"/>
		<term name="Military intelligence"/>
		<term name="Military strategy"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/1994--Introduced.
Defense Counterproliferation Act of 1994 - Directs the United States to establish an integrated program in the Department of Defense (DOD) to counter potential threats to U.S. interests that arise from the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction (chemical, biological, and nuclear weapons, as well as their associated components, facilities, and delivery systems). Directs the Secretary of Defense to designate the Deputy Secretary of Defense as program manager. Authorizes funds from DOD's FY 1995 appropriations for the program. Establishes a Counterproliferation Program Review Committee to: (1) optimize funding for, and ensure the development and deployment of, highly effective technologies and capabilities for the counterproliferation of such weapons; and (2) identify and eliminate undesirable redundancies or uncoordinated efforts in the development and deployment of such technologies and capabilities. Provides for Committee access to all appropriate information.

	</summary>
</bill>
