<bill session="103" type="s" number="2165" updated="2012-07-17T05:43:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Adopting Families Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction for qualified adoption expenses, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-06-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6602)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/8/1994--Introduced.
Fairness for Adopting Families Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit an individual income tax deduction for qualified adoption expenses. Makes deductible reasonable and necessary expenses that are directly related to a legal adoption of any child if the adoption has been arranged by a State, local, or other nonprofit agency or through a private placement. Excludes from an employee's gross income any amounts paid on behalf of the employee by an employer pursuant to a qualified adoption assistance program. Limits both the deduction and the exclusion to $5,000 ($7,000 in the case of an international adoption). Reduces the amount when the taxpayer's income exceeds $60,000. Permits an employer to treat an adoption assistance program as a statutory employee benefit plan, thus making the employer's contributions to such a program tax deductible as business expenses.

	</summary>
</bill>
