<bill session="103" type="s" number="2167" updated="2012-07-17T04:21:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Benefits Cost-of-Living Adjustment Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase, effective as of December 1, 1994, the rates of disability compensation for veterans with service-connected disabilities and the rates of dependency and indemnity compensation for the survivors of such veterans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6604)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/8/1994--Introduced.
Veterans' Benefits Cost-of-Living Adjustment Act of 1994 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to increase, effective December 1, 1994, the rates of and limitations on veterans' disability compensation, additional compensation for dependents of certain disabled veterans, the clothing allowance for certain service-disabled veterans, dependency and indemnity compensation, and supplemental dependency and indemnity compensation for children. Increases each such rate by the same percentage as the increase in benefit amounts under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act. Authorizes the Secretary to adjust administratively the rates of disability compensation payable to persons who are not in receipt of compensation for service-connected disability or death. Requires the Secretary to publish such increases in the Federal Register at the same time that percentage increases under title II of the Social Security Act are required to be published.

	</summary>
</bill>
