<bill session="103" type="s" number="2164" updated="2012-07-17T05:32:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Junior Duck Stamp Conservation and Design Program Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a program to be known as the Junior Duck Stamp Conservation and Design Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409580"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Art"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Elementary school students"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marketing"/>
		<term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
		<term name="Philately"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Wetland conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/7/1994--Introduced.
Junior Duck Stamp Conservation and Design Program Act of 1994 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to carry out the Junior Duck Stamp Conservation and Design Program. Permits the Secretary, as part of the Program, to conduct an annual competition to: (1) solicit the submission by elementary and secondary school students of designs relating to migratory bird conservation; and (2) select winning designs for use for licensing and marketing. Authorizes the Secretary to license and market winning designs and stamps bearing such designs, to be known as Junior Duck Stamps. Makes licensing and marketing proceeds available solely for awards and scholarships to individuals who submit designs, awards to further education activities related to the conservation education goals of the Program, and expenses for licensing and marketing. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
