<bill session="103" type="s" number="2161" updated="2012-07-17T04:44:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Disability Amendments Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVI of the Social Security Act to improve work incentives for people with disabilities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1994-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1994-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1994-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6531-6532)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Earnings"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Students"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/7/1994--Introduced.
Social Security Disability Amendments Act of 1994 - Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act to: (1) disregard the deemed income and resources of an ineligible spouse when determining the continued eligibility of the disabled spouse for Medicaid; (2) provide that individual Plans for Achieving Self Support (PASS) shall be deemed approved unless disallowed within 60 days by the Social Security Administration; (3) disregard the income and/or resources received by a PASS recipient for the purpose of achieving housing or career goals; (4) require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate regulations that consider both individual career and housing goals, and the difficulty of achieving self-support; (5) treat certain grant, scholarship, or fellowship income as earned income according to a certain formula; and (6) retain SSI eligibility for students temporarily outside the United States who demonstrate that their absence is to conduct studies as part of an educational program sponsored by an educational institution in the United States and designed to prepare the individual for gainful employment.

	</summary>
</bill>
