<bill session="103" type="s" number="2160" updated="2012-07-17T04:25:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Tax Restructuring and Simplification Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to replace the corporate income tax with a broad-based business activities tax, to provide relief from such tax for individuals with moderate incomes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403171"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1994-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6523-6524)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6552-6561)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Accounting"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Corporation taxes"/>
		<term name="Dividends"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Exports"/>
		<term name="Foreign corporations"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Postal service"/>
		<term name="Public utilities"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Stockholders"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Withholding tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/7/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Repeal of Corporate Income Tax Title II: Individual Income Tax Relief Title III: Business Activities Tax Comprehensive Tax Restructuring and Simplification Act of 1994 - Title I: Repeal of Corporate Income Tax - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to terminate corporate income tax. Provides for taxing corporations based on business activities. Treats distributions to shareholders as ordinary income of the shareholder. Allows certain businesses to elect to be taxed as domestic corporations. Title II: Individual Income Tax Relief - Reduces the payroll tax (old-age, survivors and disability insurance) for employers and employees by 50 percent. Increases the standard deduction for low-income taxpayers. Establishes an individual tax credit for low-income taxpayers and provides for advance payment of such credit. Title III: Business Activities - Imposes a business activities tax of 14.5 percent on the amount by which gross business receipts exceed business purchases. Treats the following as business activities of a governmental entity: (1) public utility services; (2) mass transit services; (3) postal services; and (4) any activity not involving the exercise of any essential governmental function. Excepts certain tax-exempt organizations from the tax unless the activity constitutes an unrelated trade or business. Provides the treatment for post-sale price adjustments, refunds, and bad debts. Sets forth special rules for the administration of the business activity tax. Allows a tax credit for taxable periods of excess business purchases. Exempts certain small businesses from the business activity tax.

	</summary>
</bill>
