<bill session="103" type="s" number="2197" updated="2012-07-17T05:19:42-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Illegal Immigration Control and Enforcement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to control illegal immigration to the United States, reduce incentives for illegal immigration, reform asylum procedures, strengthen criminal penalties for the smuggling of aliens, and reform other procedures.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6949-6950)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Agricultural labor"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Alien labor"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Automobile theft"/>
		<term name="Bombings"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="Bribery"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="Burglary"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Child pornography"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Civil service retirement"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Customs administration"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Extortion"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid programs"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Food stamps"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Forgery"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Gambling"/>
		<term name="Gangs"/>
		<term name="Government attorneys"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Housing subsidies"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigrants"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Information leaking"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Money laundering"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="Officer personnel"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Perjury"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political refugees"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Prostitution"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Repatriation"/>
		<term name="Retired military personnel"/>
		<term name="Right of asylum"/>
		<term name="Sabotage"/>
		<term name="Searches and seizures"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Slavery"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Tax evasion"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Territorial waters"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Treason"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
		<term name="Wiretapping"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Illegal Immigration Control and Enforcement Title II: Illegal Immigration Incentive Reduction Title III: Enhanced Smuggling Control and Penalties Title IV: Admissions and Document Fraud Control Title V: Asylum Reform Title VI: Border Crossing User Fee Illegal Immigration Control and Enforcement Act of 1994 - Title I: Illegal Immigration Control and Enforcement - Part A: Expanded Border Patrol, Support, Training, and Resources - Provides for: (1) increased Border Patrol personnel levels; (2) deployment in areas of high-illegal entry; (3) bilingual hiring preference; (4) improved training; and (5) technology and equipment transfer to the Department of Justice. Part B: Expanded Border Inspection Personnel, Support, and Facilities - Provides for: (1) increased border inspection personnel levels; (2) deployment in areas of high-illegal entry; and (3) improved border crossing infrastructure. Part C: Detention and Deportation - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (Act) to revise penalties for failure to depart, or reentry, after a final deportation order. (Sec. 134) Establishes a San Diego sector pilot program to test the effectiveness of interior repatriation in deterring multiple illegal entries by aliens into the United States. Part D: Enhanced Criminal Alien Deportation and Transfer - Amends the Act to expand the definition of &quot;aggravated felony.&quot; (Sec. 142) Expedites deportation proceedings for non-immigrant aliens convicted of an aggravated felony. (Sec. 143) Provides for judicial deportation of an alien convicted of an aggravated felony. (Sec. 144) Restricts certain deportation defenses. (Sec. 146) Authorizes the Secretary of State with the Attorney General to negotiate agreements with foreign countries for home-country incarceration of aliens subject to U.S. deportation. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Illegal Immigration Incentive Reduction - Part A: Public Benefits Control - Prohibits direct Federal assistance or benefits (with specified exceptions) and unemployment benefits to unlawful aliens (as defined by this Act). (Sec. 214) Authorizes States and localities to limit general public assistance to aliens or classes of aliens. Part B: Employer Sanctions Support - Authorizes the hiring of additional INS investigators and staff to enforce employer sanctions. Part C: Enhanced Wage and Hour Laws - Authorizes additional Department of Labor hiring to enforce employer wage and hour law sanctions. (Sec. 232) Authorizes the hiring of additional Assistant United States Attorneys to help preclude illegal immigration. Part D: Authorization Verification - Requires the Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and implement a counterfeit-resistant system to verify work and public assistance eligibility. Title III: Enhanced Smuggling Control and Penalties - Amends the Act to increase alien smuggling penalties, including death penalty provisions for an alien-smuggling related death. (Sec. 302) Amends Federal criminal law to establish death penalty procedures related to alien smuggling. (Sec. 304) Brings alien smuggling operations under the purview of the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) provisions. (Sec. 305) Amends the Act to expand INS forfeiture authority for smuggling or harboring illegal aliens. (Sec. 306) Amends Federal criminal law to authorize INS wiretaps for alien smuggling investigations. Title IV: Admissions and Document Fraud Control - Part A: Port of Entry Inspections - Amends the Act to create grounds for exclusion of an alien who uses: (1) a fraudulent document to enter the United States, or to board a common carrier for such purpose; or (2) a document to board a common carrier and then fails to present such document to an immigration official upon arrival at a U.S. port of entry. Prohibits the granting of asylum to an alien who is found to be using fraudulent entry documents or who fails to present entry-related documents, unless a specially trained immigration officer determines such actions were pursuant to departure from a country in which the alien had a credible fear of persecution. (Sec. 412) Provides for port of entry exclusion and deportation without administrative or judicial appeal (except by a limited petition of habeas corpus) for such admission document fraud. Part B: Enhanced Penalties - Increases document fraud penalties. (Sec. 422) Establishes criminal penalties for failure to disclose one's role as the preparer of fraudulent documents. Title V: Asylum Reform - Establishes civil and criminal penalties for frivolous asylum applications. (Sec. 502) Authorizes the Attorney General to limit an asylee's U.S. work authorization. (Sec. 503) Provides temporary personnel and acquisition resources to help reduce the asylum backlog. Title VI: Border Crossing User Fee - Amends the Act to impose a $1 land border and port of entry user fee. Requires such fees' deposit in the Land Border and Port of Entry User Fee Account. Authorizes appropriations for activities under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
