<bill session="103" type="s" number="2196" updated="2012-07-17T04:41:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Protection Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assure fairness and choice to patients and providers under managed care health benefit plans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400566"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6945-6946)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Due process of law"/>
		<term name="Employee health benefits"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Managed care"/>
		<term name="Patients' rights"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Protection of Consumer Choice Title II: Certification of Managed Care Plans and Utilization Review Programs Title III: Choice of Health Plans for Enrollment Patient Protection Act of 1994 - Title I: Protection of Consumer Choice - Declares that this Act shall not be construed as prohibiting either: (1) an individual from purchasing health care services with his own funds, whether such services are covered within any benefits package otherwise available; or (2) an employer from providing benefit coverage in addition to any benefits package otherwise available. Title II: Certification of Managed Care Plans and Utilization Review Programs - Sets forth a certification scheme for managed care plans and for qualified utilization review programs. Title III: Choice of Health Plans for Enrollment - Requires each health benefit plan sponsor, including a self-insured sponsor, to provide a choice among the health plans offered. Sets forth choice and payment disclosure requirements for point of service plans.

	</summary>
</bill>
