<bill session="103" type="s" number="2202" updated="2012-07-17T05:53:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-16">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for increased economic growth, job creation and opportunity by reducing the Federal deficit.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300159"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Budget; Governmental Affairs pursuant to the order of August 4, 1977, with instructions that if one Committee reports, the other Committee have thirty days to report or be discharged.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/1994--Introduced.
Declares that the discretionary spending limits (new budget authority and outlays) for each of FY 1994 through 1998 set forth in the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, as adjusted in strict conformance with the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act), shall be reduced, as calculated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in amounts equal to the aggregate amount of rescissions in any Act enacted on or after the enactment of this Act for such fiscal years. Waives such reductions with respect to any rescissions enacted in any Act designated by the President and the Congress as emergency appropriations to the extent that the aggregate amount of rescissions in such Act reduces the aggregate amount of budget authority and outlays designated as emergency appropriation by the President.

	</summary>
</bill>
