<bill session="103" type="s" number="2210" updated="2010-04-19T20:14:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-01">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-07-01" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 1995</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 1995</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1995 for defense activities of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408252"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-09"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Armed Services ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-06-20"><text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Nunn. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="480" datetime="1994-06-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 480.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01"><text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 2182 amended. (Sections 1-3, Titles XXXI and XXXII only).</text></action>
		<vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="1994-07-01" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S8321"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14T10:02:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14T18:28:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="2182" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Accounting"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Career education"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Colorado"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Conventional weapons"/>
		<term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense contracts"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Demography"/>
		<term name="Department of Energy"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Engineers"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Finance"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fissionable materials"/>
		<term name="Government employees"/>
		<term name="Government information"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Hazardous substances"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
		<term name="Job training"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Military research"/>
		<term name="Missile warheads"/>
		<term name="National security"/>
		<term name="Nevada"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
		<term name="Nuclear fusion"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
		<term name="Nuclear research"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Ohio"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Radiation safety"/>
		<term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Rockets (Ordnance)"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Scientists in government"/>
		<term name="Solar energy"/>
		<term name="Solid wastes"/>
		<term name="Technology"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
		<term name="Tritium"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Water pollution"/>
		<term name="Water resources"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Weapons systems"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1994--Passed Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title XXXI: Department of Energy National Security Programs Subtitle A: National Security Programs Authorizations Subtitle B: Recurring General Provisions Subtitle C: Program Authorizations, Restrictions, and Limitations Subtitle D: Other Matters Title XXXII: Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board Authorization Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 1995 - Title XXXI (sic): Department of Energy National Security Programs - Subtitle A: National Security Programs Authorizations - Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY 1995 for operating expenses, plant projects, and capital equipment necessary in carrying out the following activities for national security programs: (1) weapons activities; (2) environmental restoration and waste management; (3) nuclear materials support and other defense programs; and (4) defense nuclear waste disposal. Reduces the total amount authorized to be appropriated in this Subtitle by a specified amount for use of FY 1994 balances. Subtitle B: Recurring General Provisions - Prohibits the use of funds appropriated pursuant to this title for: (1) the cost of a program exceeding 105 percent of the program authorization or $10 million more than the amount authorized, whichever is the lesser; or (2) programs which have not been presented to, or requested of, the Congress, unless the Secretary of Energy transmits to specified congressional committees a full statement of the action proposed and 30 days have expired. (Sec. 3122) Places certain funding limits (requiring congressional reports when amounts exceed such limits) for general plant and construction projects of DOE. Provides fund transfer authority. (Sec. 3125) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out advance planning and construction design services in connection with proposed construction projects not exceeding $3 million, requiring certain congressional notification for projects exceeding $600,000. Requires planning and design funds to be specifically authorized by law when their estimated cost exceeds $3 million. (Sec. 3126) Directs the Secretary, with exceptions, to complete a conceptual design for a construction project in support of a DOE national security program before submitting to the Congress a funding request for such project. (Sec. 3127) Authorizes the use of DOE funds for planning, design, and construction activities for any DOE national security program that must proceed expeditiously in order to protect public health and safety, meet the needs of national defense, or protect property. Requires the Secretary to report to the defense committees when funds are so used. Makes funds for management and support activities and for general plant projects under this Subtitle available for all DOE national security programs. Subtitle C: Program Authorizations, Restrictions, and Limitations - Directs the Secretary, as part of the stockpile stewardship program, to conduct a stockpile stewardship recruitment and training program at the Sandia, Lawrence Livermore, and Los Alamos national laboratories. Allows such program to support research for military or dual-use programs related to nuclear weapons stockpile stewardship. Earmarks funds from this title for such program. Directs the Secretary, as part of the program, to establish for such laboratories a retiree corps of retired scientists with expertise in R&amp;D of nuclear weapons. Requires a report to the defense committees. (Sec. 3132) Earmarks funds authorized under this title for the defense inertial confinement fusion program. (Sec. 3133) Authorizes the Secretary to pay to the Hazardous Substance Superfund specified stipulated civil penalties assessed against the Fernald Environmental Management Project, Ohio, and the Portsmouth Gaseous Diffusion Plant, Ohio. (Sec. 3134) Authorizes the Secretary to reimburse four Colorado cities a specified amount for the cost of implementing water management programs. (Sec. 3135) Allows obligation of no more than 20 percent of the DOE funds authorized for limited and special access programs until the Secretary submits to the defense committees certain reports concerning such programs required under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954. Allows obligation of no more than 90 percent of the DOE funds authorized for national security programs until the Secretary submits to such committees a five-year budget plan required under prior law. (Sec. 3136) Earmarks specified funds authorized under this title for: (1) worker protection programs at nuclear weapons facilities; (2) the Scholarship and Fellowship Program for Environmental Restoration and Waste Management; (3) a hazardous materials management and emergency response training program at the Hanford Nuclear Reservation, Washington; (4) certain programs for persons at such plant who may have been exposed to radiation released from such plant; and (5) solar energy development activities at the Nevada Test Site. Subtitle D: Other Matters - Directs the Secretary to prescribe accounting procedures concerning the use of DOE national security program funds. (Sec. 3152) Directs the Joint Nuclear Weapons Council to coordinate and approve DOE activities concerning the study, development, and production of nuclear warheads. (Sec. 3153) Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress on the feasibility of conducting specified disarmament and demilitarization activities, nuclear weapon simulator technology development programs, the stockpile stewardship program, and experiments related to the nonproliferation of nuclear weapons at the Nevada Test Site. (Sec. 3154) Adds to the membership of the Nuclear Weapons Council a second senior representative of DOE appointed by the Secretary. (Sec. 3155) Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to establish within DOE an Office of Fissile Materials Disposition. (Sec. 3156) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1989, to extend through FY 1997 the authority of the Secretary to loan personnel and facilities for the Idaho National Engineering Laboratory. (Sec. 3157) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1992 and 1993 to eliminate the requirement of a five-year plan for DOE defense nuclear facilities. (Sec. 3158) Authorizes the Secretary to appoint up to 200 persons in DOE for scientific, engineering, and technical personnel whose duties will relate to safety at DOE defense nuclear facilities. Requires the OPM Director to periodically evaluate the Secretary's appointment authority and take appropriate action, if necessary, to ensure such appointments. Terminates the Secretary's authority on September 30, 1997. (Sec. 3159) Earmarks specified funds authorized for DOE under this Act for the declassification productivity initiative. (Sec. 3160) Directs the Secretary to take specified action (and provide a report) with respect to safety oversight and enforcement activities at DOE defense nuclear facilities. (Sec. 3161) Imposes certain information disclosure and use conditions upon contracts between Federal departments and agencies and entities to which the Secretary leases a DOE facility or to which the Secretary transfers personal property of such a facility. Title XXXII: Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board Authorization - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.

	</summary>
</bill>
