<bill session="103" type="s" number="2227" updated="2012-07-17T05:02:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Flow Control Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to provide congressional authorization of State control over transportation of municipal solid waste, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1994-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="407786" joined="1994-06-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7371-7372, S7374-7376)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Superfund, Recycling. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-722.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Superfund, Recycling, and Solid Waste Management" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Industrial pollution"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Recycling industry"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/1994--Introduced.
Flow Control Act of 1994 - Authorizes each State and qualified political subdivision to direct, regulate, or prohibit the transportation of, and designate waste facilities for: (1) municipal solid waste generated from household sources within the boundaries of the State or subdivision; (2) municipal solid waste that is generated, or is commingled with municipal solid waste that is generated, from commercial, institutional, or industrial sources within such boundaries or that is incinerator ash or construction or demolition debris if, before May 15, 1994, the State or political subdivision adopted a law that regulated or prohibited the transportation of waste to a facility designated before such date; and (3) recyclable materials generated within such boundaries. Permits such authority with respect to recyclable materials only if: (1) the generator or owner of the materials voluntarily made the materials available to the State or subdivision and relinquished any rights to, or ownership of, such materials; and (2) the State or subdivision assumes such rights or ownership. Permits such authority only if the State or subdivision: (1) establishes a program to separate or divert specified materials for purposes of recycling, reclamation, or reuse before exercising such authority; (2) develops and implements a competitive designation process for facilities; and (3) finds on the basis of public hearings that it is necessary to exercise such authority to meet current and anticipated solid waste management needs. Retains the applicability of certain existing laws and contracts and provides that such laws and contracts shall not be considered to impair or discriminate against interstate commerce.

	</summary>
</bill>
