<bill session="103" type="s" number="2220" updated="2012-07-17T05:20:05-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a United States contribution to the Inter-American Development Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7248-7249)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Caribbean area"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Inter-American Development Bank Act to authorize the U.S. Governor of the Inter-American Development Bank to vote for resolutions that provide for increases in: (1) authorized capital stock of, and subscriptions to, the Bank; and (2) resources of the Fund for Special Operations and contributions to the Fund. Authorizes the U.S. Governor to subscribe to a specified amount of shares of the increase in the authorized capital stock and contribute a specified amount to the Fund. Authorizes appropriations. Permits the U.S. Governor to vote for a proposed resolution entitled &quot;Amendments to the Agreement Establishing the Inter-American Development Bank, the Regulations of the Board of Governors, the General Rules Governing Admission of Nonregional Countries to Membership in the Bank, and the Regulations for the Election of Executive Directors.&quot;

	</summary>
</bill>
