<bill session="103" type="s" number="2235" updated="2012-07-17T05:54:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the establishment of an Accredited Lenders Program for qualified State or local development companies under the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 and an Accredited Loan Packagers Pilot Program for loan packagers under the Small Business Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400566"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7579-7580)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/23/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish an Accredited Lenders Program which designates a State or local development company as an accredited lender if it demonstrates: (1) adequate knowledge of the SBA guaranteed loan program; and (2) proficiency in meeting the requirements of such program and any other applicable requirements. Authorizes the Administrator to expedite the processing of any loan application or servicing action submitted by a development company so designated. Suspends or revokes such designation upon certain determinations by the Administrator. Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator to establish an Accredited Loan Packagers Pilot Program under which loan packagers shall be designated as accredited loan packagers upon meeting certain requirements with respect to loan packaging under the SBA guaranteed loan program. Requires at least ten but no more than 15 loan packagers to be so designated. Authorizes the Administrator, during a three-year period, to expedite the processing of any loan application or servicing action prepared by a loan packager so designated. Suspends or revokes such designation upon certain determinations by the Administrator.

	</summary>
</bill>
