<bill session="103" type="s" number="2232" updated="2012-07-17T04:16:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize appropriations for each of fiscal years 1994 through 1998 for the construction of wastewater treatment works to serve United States colonias by providing water pollution control in the vicinity of the international boundary between the United States and Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1994-06-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7575-7576)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4478" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Potable water"/>
		<term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste water treatment"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Water supply"/>
		<term name="Water treatment plants"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/23/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide financial assistance to any U.S. State along the U.S.-Mexican border or to any entity designated by the President for construction of treatment works to serve U.S. colonias in Arizona, California, New Mexico, and Texas. Bases the determination of whether a community is a colonia on objective criteria, including lack of potable water supply or adequate sewage systems. Limits Federal funding to 50 percent of construction costs. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
