<bill session="103" type="s" number="225" updated="2012-07-17T04:35:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide that any concurrent resolution on the budget that contains reconciliation directives shall include a directive with respect to the statutory limit on the public debt, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403962"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-02-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S798)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27"><text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Budget; Governmental Affairs pursuant to the order of August 4, 1977, with instructions that if one Committee reports, the other Committee have thirty days to report or be discharged.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget process"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require any concurrent resolution on the budget that contains reconciliation directives relating to required changes in total budget authority amounts and revenue amounts to specify the amounts by which the statutory limit on the public debt is to be changed and to include this directive in the reconciliation legislation reported for the particular fiscal year. Declares it out of order in the Senate, with limited exception, to consider legislation that increases the public debt limit during a fiscal year above the level set forth in the concurrent resolution on the budget for that fiscal year.

	</summary>
</bill>
