<bill session="103" type="s" number="2267" updated="2012-07-17T06:03:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable all able-bodied Federal prisoners to work.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401874"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8389)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
		<term name="Floods"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Industrial standards"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Minimum wages"/>
		<term name="Prices"/>
		<term name="Prison labor"/>
		<term name="Recycling industry"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Sheltered workshops"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize Federal Prison Industries (FPI) to sell excess or obsolescent property on the open market at the best available price, with the proceeds of such sales to be deposited to the Prison Industries Fund. Requires FPI to determine the character of and necessity for its obligations and expenditures and the manner in which they shall be incurred, allowed, and paid, subject to laws applicable to Government corporations. (Current law requires FPI to deposit all of its monies into the Fund.) Requires commodities and services produced by FPI to be sold at current market prices and to conform to Federal and relevant private industry design, quality, and testing standards. Accords services of the workshops for the handicapped priority for Federal purchasing over those offered by FPI if both entities offer competitive services. Requires Federal agencies to provide to FPI the maximum opportunity to participate as a subcontractor in labor-intensive, light manufacturing segments of awarded contracts. Authorizes FPI to: (1) produce or provide for sale on the open market processes, products, and services that would otherwise be produced by foreign labor at offshore locations; and (2) enter into agreements with private industry for such purposes. Requires FPI to certify that such products, processes, or services: (1) are labor-intensive and limited to levels that replace goods and services produced by offshore labor; and (2) do not significantly increase competition with any remaining domestic labor or industry. Authorizes FPI to: (1) produce and provide recycled materials for sale on the open market; and (2) produce or provide goods and services for sale or donation on the open market to private, nonprofit organizations to assist in disaster relief. Exempts: (1) items sold on the open market pursuant to this Act from the prohibition against shipment in commerce of prison-made goods; and (2) inmates who work on the production of products or services from the minimum wage requirements of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938. Authorizes FPI funds to be used to enter into contracts related to the purchase of goods for industrial operations without regard to laws governing procurement by Federal agencies.

	</summary>
</bill>
