<bill session="103" type="s" number="2260" updated="2012-07-17T04:28:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-China Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide conditions for renewing nondiscriminatory (most-favored-nation) treatment for the People's Republic of China.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407786"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1994-07-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1994-07-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8382-8383)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Arms control agreements"/>
		<term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
		<term name="China"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Collective bargaining"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Communism"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional veto"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Due process of law"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="Emigration"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Export trading companies"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Free enterprise"/>
		<term name="Freedom of association"/>
		<term name="Freedom of speech"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Guided missiles"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Labor unions"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Missing persons"/>
		<term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Prison labor"/>
		<term name="Punishment"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Torture"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/1/1994--Introduced.
United States-China Act of 1994 - Declares that if nondiscriminatory treatment (most-favored-nation treatment) is not granted to China by reason of the enactment of a congressional disapproval resolution, such treatment shall continue to apply to goods that are produced by a person that is not a state-owned Chinese enterprise, but not apply to any goods that are produced by a state-owned Chinese enterprise. Provides that if nondiscriminatory treatment is granted to China for a 12-month period on July 3, 1994, such treatment shall not apply to: (1) any good that is produced by the People's Liberation Army or Chinese defense industrial trading company; or (2) any nonqualified good that is produced by a state-owned Chinese enterprise. Urges the Secretary of the Treasury to consult with American businesses that have significant trade with or investment in China, to encourage them to adopt a voluntary code of conduct that: (1) follows internationally recognized human rights principles; (2) ensures the employment of Chinese citizens is not discriminatory in terms of sex, ethnic origin, or political belief; (3) ensures that no convict, forced, or indentured labor is knowingly used; (4) recognizes the rights of workers to freely organize and bargain collectively; and (5) discourages mandatory political indoctrination on business premises. Requires the Secretary to determine, and publish in the Federal Register, which persons are state-owned Chinese enterprises and Chinese defense industrial trading companies. Authorizes the President to waive any condition or prohibition imposed under this Act if he determines and reports to the Congress that its continued imposition would have a serious adverse effect on the vital U.S. national security. Declares that if the President recommends in 1995 that the waiver of human rights and emigration requirements for nondiscriminatory treatment for China be continued, he shall state in a specified report to the Congress the extent to which China has made progress with respect to: (1) adhering to the provisions of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights; (2) ceasing the exportation to the United States of products made with convict, forced, or indentured labor; (3) ceasing unfair and discriminatory trade practices which restrict and unreasonably burden American businesses; and (4) adhering to the guidelines of the Missile Technology Control Regime and the controls adopted by the Nuclear Suppliers Group and the Australia Group.

	</summary>
</bill>
