<bill session="103" type="s" number="2266" updated="2012-07-17T04:20:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Recreation Management Act of 1992, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401709"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8388-8389)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-27"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-382.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="636" datetime="1994-09-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 636.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-3" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Boats and boating"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Police"/>
		<term name="Reclamation of land"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/26/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Amends the Recreation Management Act of 1992 to impose a fine or up to six months' imprisonment or both on persons who violate regulations issued by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation, regarding the management of reclamation lands. (Allows such persons to be adjudged to pay all costs of the proceedings.) Authorizes the Secretary to designate certain officers or employees of the Department of the Interior to maintain law and order and to protect persons and property within the areas subject to the Bureau's jurisdiction. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, to: (1) designate officers and employees of any other Federal agency or law enforcement personnel of any State or political subdivision thereof, when deemed economical and in the public interest and with the concurrence of such appropriate entity, to act as special police in the areas under the Bureau's jurisdiction when supplemental law enforcement personnel may be needed and to exercise the same powers as designated Bureau law enforcement officers; and (2) provide limited reimbursement to a State or its political subdivisions for expenditures incurred in connection with such activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
