<bill session="103" type="s" number="2269" updated="2012-07-17T06:09:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-10">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-08-10" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Cultural Protection and Free Exercise of Religion Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Native American Cultural Protection and Free Exercise of Religion Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect Native American cultures and to guarantee the free exercise of religion by Native Americans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8390-8391)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14"><committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-940.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-08-10"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Indian Affairs"/><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-411.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="722" datetime="1994-10-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 722.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Destruction of property"/>
		<term name="Diet"/>
		<term name="District courts"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Eagles"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Hawaiians"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Peyote"/>
		<term name="Plants"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
		<term name="Wildlife management"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/1994--Reported to Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Protection of Native American Sacred Sites Title II: Prisoners' Rights Title III: Religious Use of Eagles and Other Animals and Plants Title IV: Jurisdiction and Remedies Title V: Miscellaneous Native American Cultural Protection and Free Exercise of Religion Act of 1994 - Title I: Protection of Native American Sacred Sites - Grants access to cultural, ceremonial, or religious sites on Federal lands to Native American practitioners. Authorizes Federal agencies to take reasonable measures to ensure that such access and use of natural products does not significantly endanger national security, environmental interest, or personal safety. Authorizes the temporary closure of such areas to general public use in order to protect the privacy of religious or cultural activities. (Sec. 103) Requires Federal agencies to manage their lands in ways that are consistent with the provisions of this Act. Provides for Federal, Indian, and Native Hawaiian cooperation and consultation in the identification, planning, and land management of areas with religious or cultural sites, including provisions for site confidentiality where appropriate. (Provides a special rule for Indian pueblos of New Mexico.) (Sec. 106) States that Indian tribes may regulate and protect sacred sites located on Indian lands within their jurisdiction. (Sec. 109) Imposes criminal sanctions upon a person or an organization damaging sacred sites on tribal lands. Title II: Prisoners' Rights - Grants Native American prisoners access to traditional religious leaders, ceremonial materials, and religious facilities. Directs the Attorney General to investigate the conditions of Native American prisoners with respect to their ability to engage in traditional cultural and religious practices. Title III: Religious Use of Eagles and Other Animals and Plants - Requires the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, in consultation with tribal and traditional leaders, to develop a plan for the distrubition and use of eagles and their parts for use in traditional cultural and religious ceremonies. (Sec. 302) Directs the Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture, Commerce, and the Treasury and the Administrator of the General Services Administration to establish administrative procedures to govern the disposition of surplus wildlife and plants for such purposes. Title IV: Jurisdiction and Remedies - Grants jurisdiction to U.S district courts for actions to enforce the provisions of this Act. Title V: Miscellaneous - Sets forth miscellaneous provisions. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
