<bill session="103" type="s" number="2282" updated="2012-07-17T04:27:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sustainable Development Through Trade Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title V of the Trade Act of 1974 to provide incentives for developing countries to develop and implement strong environmental protection programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8909-8910)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-13" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="4734" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Ecosystem management"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Tariff preferences"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/13/1994--Introduced.
Sustainable Development Through Trade Act of 1994 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize the President to waive certain requirements for the withdrawal of beneficiary country status with respect to a country's product if he is advised by the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrators of the Environmental Protection Agency and of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that such country is taking action to protect environmental resources, including ecosystems, that have environmental, economic, or national security significance for the United States. Authorizes the President to designate a product of a least-developed beneficiary developing country as an eligible product for duty-free treatment unless it is determined that such product is import-sensitive.

	</summary>
</bill>
