<bill session="103" type="s" number="2283" updated="2012-07-17T04:31:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prostate Cancer Diagnosis and Treatment Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of prostate cancer screening and certain drug treatment services under part B of the Medicare Program, to amend chapter 17 of title 38, United States Code, to provide for coverage of such screening and services under the programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and to expand research and education programs of the National Institutes of Health and the Public Health Service relating to prostate cancer.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300089"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1994-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300053" joined="1994-08-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1994-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1994-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1994-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1994-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1994-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9034)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4809" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Cancer research"/>
		<term name="Chemotherapy"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Health counseling"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Medical screening"/>
		<term name="Medical tests"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Prostate cancer"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/1994--Introduced.
Prostate Cancer Diagnosis and Treatment Act of 1994 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of specified prostate cancer screening services and certain drug treatments for such cancer. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish fee schedules for such services. Amends Federal law to cover such screening and treatment services for veterans as a preventive health service. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for certain public health programs related to prostate cancer research and education. Directs the Administrator of the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research to: (1) conduct and support prostate cancer health services and screening and treatment procedures; and (2) provide for the development, periodic review, and updating of clinically relevant guidelines, standards of quality, performance measures, and medical review criteria.

	</summary>
</bill>
