<bill session="103" type="s" number="2285" updated="2012-07-17T06:21:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-14">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Headwaters Forest Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the sound management and protection of redwood forest areas in Humboldt County, California, by adding certain lands and waters to the Six Rivers National Forest and by including a portion of such lands in the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1994-09-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9038)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-14" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-15"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Forests and forestry"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Birds"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Endangered animals"/>
		<term name="Endangered species"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Forest management"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Lumber trade"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Old growth forests"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Owls"/>
		<term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Timber sales"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/1994--Introduced.
Headwaters Forest Act of 1994 - Extends the boundaries of the Six Rivers National Forest, California, to include certain lands to be referred to as the Six Rivers National Forest Addition. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire land within the extended boundaries by donation, purchase, or exchange for other excess or surplus Federal lands. Directs the Secretary to develop and implement a land acquisition plan giving priority to the acquisition of lands for the Headwaters Forest Wilderness. Designates the Headwaters Forest Wilderness lands, upon acquisition, as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Requires the Secretary to develop a comprehensive management plan prescribing measures for the preservation of the existing old growth redwood ecosystems in the Addition, including: (1) a prohibition on timber sales from lands within the old growth redwood groves; and (2) measures to restore lands affected by previous timber harvests to mitigate watershed degradation and impairment of habitat for the marbled murrelet, spotted owl, native salmon stocks, and other old-growth forest dependent species. Sets forth provisions regarding payments to local governments in lieu of taxes for lands acquired under this Act. Directs the Secretary to study specified lands in the Addition, analyzing the area's potential for addition to the Headwaters Forest and identifying the area's natural resources. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
