<bill session="103" type="s" number="2294" updated="2012-07-17T05:22:43-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-19">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-19"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Morris K. Udall Parkinson's Research, Education, and Assistance Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the expansion and coordination of research concerning Parkinson's disease and related disorders, and to improve care and assistance for its victims and their family caregivers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1994-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1994-08-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-08-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1994-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1994-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1994-09-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9242-9247)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-19" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="4789" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Continuing education"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical screening"/>
		<term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Tissue banks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/19/1994--Introduced.
Morris K. Udall Parkinson's Research, Education, and Assistance Act of 1994 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health to establish a council to coordinate Parkinson's research activities. Directs: (1) the council to convene a National Consensus Conference on Parkinson's Disease and Related Neuro-degenerative Disorders to aid in the development of a broad-based strategy for identifying the cause of and treating such disorders; and (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and annually submit to specified congressional committees a coordinated research agenda and to provide for the establishment of ten Parkinson's Research Centers. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) award feasibility study grants to support the development of preliminary data sufficient to provide the basis for the submission of applications for independent research support grants or establishment of a Center; and (2) award grants to appropriate institutions for the provision of training and continuing education concerning health and long-term care of individuals with Parkinson's. Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a grant program to support scientists who have distinguished themselves in the field of Parkinson's research; (2) a registry for screening and collecting patient and family data that may be useful in determining incidence and possible risk factors concerning Parkinson's; and (3) a national education program designed to foster a national focus on Parkinson's and the care of those with Parkinson's. Sets forth application requirements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
