<bill session="103" type="s" number="2309" updated="2010-04-19T20:30:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-14">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-07-14" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health Care Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for reform of the health care benefits furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs and the administration of health care benefits by the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar datetime="1994-07-14"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Veterans ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9464-9466, S9469)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21"><text>Committee on Veterans. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Rockefeller. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="530" datetime="1994-07-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 530.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Veterans"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Ex-prisoners of war"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health care reform"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Public contracts"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="State and local government"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="World War I"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/21/1994--Introduced.
Veterans Health Care Reform Act of 1994 - Allows each veteran who is an eligible individual under provisions of the Health Security Act (the Act), individuals currently enrolled in a health plan under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS), and their family members to be enrolled in a Department of Veterans Affairs health plan (VA plan). Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that each VA plan provides to enrolled individuals the items and services in the comprehensive benefit package under the Act. Allows such plans to offer supplemental health benefits and cost-sharing policies consistent with the Act. Provides a limitation with regard to veterans enrolled with health plans outside the VA. Prohibits the imposition of any plan enrollment charges upon service-connected disabled veterans, veterans receiving disability compensation from the VA, former prisoners of war veterans of the Mexican border period or World War I, and veterans unable to defray the costs of such care. Allows the Secretary to establish plan charges for other veterans. Deems a VA facility to be a Medicare provider, and a VA health plan to be a Medicare HMO, for purposes of any program administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under Medicare (title XVIII of the Social Security Act). Allows for the recovery of certain care and services provided under a VA plan in the case of an individual who has coverage under another plan. Establishes in the Treasury the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Plan Fund to be used for VA health plan payments and services. Preserves existing benefits for VA facilities not operating within a health plan certified under the Act. Directs the Secretary to organize health plans and operate VA facilities as, or within, health plans under the Act. Preempts conflicting State health plan standards or requirements. Directs the Secretary to designate a health plan director for each VA health plan organized and operated under this Act. Authorizes such directors to enter into contracts and agreements for the provision of care and services under the VA plan as well as related services (equipment, maintenance, and repair). Authorizes the Secretary to enter into resource-sharing agreements with other health care plans and providers, health industry organizations, individuals, and other Government departments and agencies. Provides certain administrative and personnel flexibility, as well as expenditure authority, for care and services under a VA plan. Establishes in the Treasury the Veterans Health Care Investment Fund. Provides specified credits to the Fund for FY 1995 through 1997 for operation of VA health plans. Requires a report from the Secretary to the Congress on the operation of such plans. Authorizes the Secretary to accept and use grants for health care services provided to special populations if used by the VA while operating under a VA health plan.

	</summary>
</bill>
