<bill session="103" type="s" number="2305" updated="2012-07-17T05:39:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Law Judge Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that members of the Board of Veterans' Appeals be referred to as veterans law judges, to provide for the pay of such members, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1994-08-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1994-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1994-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-08-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9457-9459)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-14"><committee name="Committee on Veterans"/><text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative law judges"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/21/1994--Introduced.
Veterans Law Judge Act of 1994 - Redesignates the Chairman and other members of the Board of Veterans Appeals (other than temporary members) as veterans law judges. Classifies the pay rate for veterans law judges as that of administrative law judges. Authorizes the Chairman of the Board or other Board members to continue to serve in such positions, upon approval of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, after the expiration of their terms. Requires the Secretary to notify Board members at least 120 days in advance of a decision not to recommend such member for appointment to an additional term. Allows the opportunity for a hearing on such decision. Allows the President to disapprove the appointment of a Board member to an additional term. Provides for reversion to the civil grades and series held by Board members prior to their appointment upon the expiration of their terms of appointment. Directs the Secretary to prescribe criteria for Board member reappointment. Allows current Board members in the Senior Executive Service to continue to be paid at that rate.

	</summary>
</bill>
