<bill session="103" type="s" number="2300" updated="2012-07-17T04:29:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit all United States military and economic assistance for Turkey until the Turkish Government takes certain actions to resolve the Cyprus problem and complies with its obligations under international law.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408898"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1994-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1994-09-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9325)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14743-14744)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Census"/>
		<term name="Christianity"/>
		<term name="Churches"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Cyprus"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Hostages"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Islam"/>
		<term name="Military intervention"/>
		<term name="Military occupation"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Turkey"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/20/1994--Introduced.
Prohibits U.S. military and economic assistance to Turkey until the President certifies to the Congress that: (1) the Turkish Government has released or accounted for the five Americans abducted by the Turkish invasion forces in 1974 and the 1,614 Greek Cypriots who have been missing since the Turkish invasion; (2) the churches in the occupied parts of Cyprus that were converted to mosques in violation of the Geneva Conventions have been restored to their original condition for Christian worship; (3) the Turkish Government has authorized a census of the colonists on Cyprus; (4) all Turkish military forces and illegal Turkish colonists have been withdrawn from Cyprus; (5) the Turkish Government has returned the area of Famagusta/Varosha to the Government of Cyprus; (6) negotiations have resulted in progress towards establishing a democracy in Cyprus; and (7) the Turkish Government is in compliance with the United Nations Charter, specified United Nations resolutions, the North Atlantic Treaty, and the Helsinki Final Act of the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe and is not engaged in human rights violations.

	</summary>
</bill>
