<bill session="103" type="s" number="2314" updated="2012-07-17T04:29:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Court of Federal Claims Administration Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make administrative and jurisdictional amendments pertaining to the United States Court of Federal Claims and the judges thereof in order to promote efficiency and fairness, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405310"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9642-9643)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Administration of justice"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Disability retirement"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Judicial compensation"/>
		<term name="Judicial tenure"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Residence requirements"/>
		<term name="Social security taxes"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/25/1994--Introduced.
Court of Federal Claims Administration Act of 1994 - Amends the Federal judicial code to allow a judge of the U.S. Court of Federal Claims (Court) who is not reappointed to continue in office until a successor is appointed and takes office. (Sec. 3) Grants judges of the Court authority to conduct proceedings in the district courts of territories to the same extent as duly appointed judges of those courts upon request by or on behalf of a territorial court and with the concurrence of the chief judge of the Court and the chief judge of the judicial circuit involved based upon a finding of need. (Sec. 4) Exempts retired judges of the Court from residence restrictions. Provides that the place where a retired judge maintains the actual abode in which such judge customarily lives shall be the judge's official duty station. (Sec. 5) Provides for Court membership on the Judicial Conference of the United States. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the chief judge of the Court to summon the Court judges to a judicial conference annually to consider the business of, and improvements in the administration of justice in, the Court. Directs the Court to provide by its rules or by general order for representation and active participation at such conference by members of the bar. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the chief judge of the Court to recall a formerly disabled judge who retires under the disability provisions of the Court's retirement system if, in the chief judge's view, such judge has recovered sufficiently to render judicial service. (Sec. 8) Grants the Court: (1) the power to grant injunctive and declaratory relief; (2) jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim by or against, or dispute with, a contractor arising under specified provisions of the Contract Disputes Act of 1978; and (3) ancillary jurisdiction under the Federal Tort Claims Act when a claim is directly related to one otherwise within the Court's jurisdiction. (Sec. 9) Provides that Court judges over age 65 who are on senior status will receive the same treatment as other Federal trial judges on senior status insofar as Social Security taxes and annuity payments are concerned. (Sec. 10) Deems a Court judge to be a judicial officer eligible for coverage under annuity, insurance, and other programs available to other Federal trial judges, including the program for continued Federal life insurance coverage after retirement.

	</summary>
</bill>
