<bill session="103" type="s" number="2315" updated="2012-07-17T05:02:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rape and Assault Victims Counseling Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Attorney General to develop model legislation for the States to assure confidentiality of communications between victims of sexual assault or domestic violence victims and their counselors, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9734)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Crimes against women"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Family violence"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Rape victim services"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/1994--Introduced.
Rape and Assault Victims Counseling Protection Act - Expresses the sense of the Senate regarding the confidentiality of communications between victims of sexual assault or domestic violence and their therapists or trained counselors. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) evaluate State measures to protect such confidentiality and disseminate the findings to State authorities; (2) develop model legislation that will adequately protect such confidentiality; and (3) report to the Congress. Directs the Judicial Conference of the United States to complete and submit to the Congress a study evaluating whether and how the Federal Rules of Evidence should be amended to guarantee that such confidentiality will be adequately protected in Federal court proceedings.

	</summary>
</bill>
