<bill session="103" type="s" number="2325" updated="2012-07-17T05:33:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-23">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-23" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Veterans Programs Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Board of Veterans' Appeals Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend certain laws under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to reauthorize programs relating to substance abuse and homeless assistance for veterans, to authorize a demonstration program to provide assistance to homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1994-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1994-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1994-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9741-9743)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-14"><committee name="Committee on Veterans"/><text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-23"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Veterans"/><text>Committee on Veterans. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Committee on Veterans. Reported to Senate by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 103-385. Minority views filed.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="663" datetime="1994-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 663.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Administrative law judges"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Birth defects"/>
		<term name="Black veterans"/>
		<term name="Building leases"/>
		<term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Childbirth"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Clinical trials"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Community organization"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="East Asia"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Employee rights"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Foreign exchange"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Halfway houses"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Homeless"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Ionizing radiation"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Mental health services"/>
		<term name="Mentally ill"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
		<term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
		<term name="Nurses"/>
		<term name="Occupational therapy"/>
		<term name="Oregon"/>
		<term name="Personnel management"/>
		<term name="Philippines"/>
		<term name="Pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Prisoners of war"/>
		<term name="Radiation victims"/>
		<term name="Radiobiology"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Whistle blowing"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women veterans"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/1994--Reported to Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Department of Veterans Affairs Homelessness and Substance Abuse Programs Title II: Minority Veterans Title III: Board of Veterans' Appeals Title IV: Miscellaneous Veterans Programs Improvement Act of 1994 - Title I: Department of Veterans Affairs Homelessness and Substance Abuse Programs - Extends through FY 1996 the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a compensated work therapy and therapeutic transitional housing demonstration program. (Sec. 102) Extends permanently a Department of Veterans Affairs program for the treatment and rehabilitation of veterans for alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disabilities. (Sec. 103) Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to reauthorize for FY 1995 through 1997 the homeless veterans' reintegration projects established under such Act. (Sec. 104) Authorizes the Secretary to provide care and treatment and rehabilitative services in halfway houses, therapeutic communities, psychiatric residential treatment centers, and other community-based treatment facilities to homeless veterans suffering from chronic mental illness disabilities who are eligible for veterans' medical care. Requires prior approval by the Secretary of the facility providing such care. (Sec. 105) Directs the Secretary to report annually to specified congressional committees on Department activities in assisting homeless veterans during the preceding year. (Sec. 106) Amends the Veterans' Medical Programs Amendments of 1992 to: (1) require the directors of regional Department medical centers or benefits offices to update for each of FY 1995 through 1997 an assessment of the needs of homeless veterans in their region; and (2) require the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees in each of such fiscal years describing such updates. (Sec. 107) Directs the Secretary to carry out a demonstration program at no more than five designated locations under which the Secretary enters into partnerships with community-based homeless service organizations in order to provide services and assistance to homeless veterans. Requires an agreement with a non-Federal entity to carry out a study of the program. Requires the Secretary to report the results of such study to specified congressional committees. (Sec. 108) Amends the Homeless Veterans Comprehensive Service Programs Act of 1992 to: (1) increase from four to 12 the authorized number of centers for the provision of comprehensive services to homeless veterans; and (2) remove a specified funding limitation. Title II: Minority Veterans - Directs the Secretary to establish the Advisory Committee on Minority Veterans to advise the Secretary with respect to the administration of benefits for veterans who are minority group members (Asian Americans, Blacks, Hispanics, Native Americans, and Pacific-Islander Americans). Requires biennial reports from the Committee to the Secretary on Department activities pertaining to minority veterans. Directs the Secretary to submit such reports to the Congress, together with comments. (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary to designate an appropriate official at each Department regional and medical facility to serve as the minority affairs officer at such facility. Title III: Board of Veterans' Appeals - Board of Veterans' Appeals Improvement Act of 1994 - Requires a member of the Board of Veterans' Appeals other than the Chairman and Vice Chairman to receive compensation and benefits equal to that received by administrative law judges. (Sec. 303) Allows the Chairman of the Board to serve after the expiration of his or her term until confirmation for an additional term or confirmation of a successor Chairman. Authorizes the Chairman to be removed from office for engaging in political activity. Directs the Chairman to provide for a panel of Board members to review the fitness of other Board members to serve on the Board. Outlines review procedures. (Sec. 304) Requires any Board members who are members of the Senior Executive Service (SES) to continue as SES members while serving on the Board and receive all benefits of the Service to which all other SES members are entitled. Title IV: Miscellaneous - Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement under which the Medical Follow-up Agency of the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences shall convene a panel to evaluate the feasibility of carrying out a study to determine the relationship between the exposure of veterans to ionizing radiation and: (1) genetic defects and illnesses in the children and grandchildren of such veterans; and (2) untoward pregnancy outcomes experienced by the spouses of such veterans, including stillbirths, miscarriages, and neonatal death. Requires reports in FY 1995 through 1997 from the Secretary to specified congressional committees on the study's results. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 402) Eliminates the requirement that veterans of the Philippine Commonwealth Army and their survivors and dependents be paid veterans' benefits (including disability compensation and survivors' and dependents' educational assistance) in Philippine pesos. (Sec. 403) Makes eligible for burial in national cemeteries spouses who predecease veterans. (Sec. 404) Authorizes the Secretary to provide for flat grave markers at the Willamette National Cemetery, Oregon. (Sec. 405) Makes permanent (currently terminates at the end of 1994) the authority of the Secretary to provide an exception from requirements for reductions in retirement pay for reemployed registered nurses during a severe shortage in such positions. (Sec. 406) Applies specified Federal provisions concerning protection of Federal employees from certain prohibited personnel practices (whistleblower provisions) to Department medical personnel. (Sec. 407) Changes from December 1 to April 1 the annual submission date for a report from the Secretary concerning Department medical facilities admission policies. (Sec. 408) Extends through December 31, 1996, the authority of the Secretary to enter into enhanced-use leases of real property.

	</summary>
</bill>
