<bill session="103" type="s" number="2323" updated="2012-07-17T06:22:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify the coverage and protection provided to medical quality assurance records by section 5705 of that title.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9738-9740)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-14"><committee name="Committee on Veterans"/><text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Quality of care"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Witnesses"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/1994--Introduced.
Prohibits Department of Veterans Affairs medical quality assurance records from being subject to discovery or admitted into evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding. Prohibits an individual who participates in the production of such records from being required to testify at such a proceeding. Allows testimony concerning such records (currently, only the records or documents themselves) to be disclosed to Federal agencies for certain limited purposes (licensing, accreditation). Specifies additional uses for which such information may be disclosed. Includes information and testimony related to such records within certain disclosure limitation provisions. Prohibits the disclosure of such records by the Department as public information to the extent that such disclosure would reveal the identities of the participants in the quality assurance process which generated the records or documents.

	</summary>
</bill>
