<bill session="103" type="s" number="2335" updated="2012-07-17T05:05:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-28">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to require that OMB and CBO estimates for paygo purposes to recognize the increased revenues generated by economic growth resulting from legislation implementing any trade agreement.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401874"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1994-08-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-08-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10057-10058)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28"><text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Budget; Governmental Affairs pursuant to the order of August 4, 1977, with instructions that if one Committee reports, the other Committee have thirty days to report or be discharged.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Cost accounting"/>
		<term name="Costs"/>
		<term name="Economic growth"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Tariff"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to require pay-as-you-go estimates with respect to legislation implementing a trade agreement to take into account increased revenues generated by growth in the gross domestic product resulting from such legislation to offset any loss in tariff revenues due to that legislation, subject to the condition that such increased revenues shall not be used as offsets beyond the total of lost revenues due to that legislation.

	</summary>
</bill>
