<bill session="103" type="s" number="2332" updated="2012-07-17T05:19:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bonneville Power Administration Refinancing Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Columbia River Transmission System Act to provide for the reconstitution of outstanding repayment obligations of the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration for the appropriated capital investments in the Federal Columbia River Power System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1994-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10051-10056)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-29"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-3" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Capital investments"/>
		<term name="Columbia River development"/>
		<term name="Dams"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Electric power distribution"/>
		<term name="Electric power transmission"/>
		<term name="Electric utility rates"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
		<term name="Indian claims"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/1994--Introduced.
Bonneville Power Administration Refinancing Act - Amends the Federal Columbia River Transmission System Act to prescribe guidelines under which the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration (BPA) is directed to refinance a certain appropriated debt by establishing: (1) a new principal amount for such debt; (2) new interest rates for such debt based on long-term Treasury rates in effect as of the date the principal is reset; and (3) a $100 million limit on prepayments of old capital investments before a certain date. States that certain claim settlement payments made by the Administrator to the Confederated Tribes of the Colville Reservation shall be credited against BPA payments made to the Treasury. Directs the Administrator to offer to include provisions in future electric power service contracts that preclude further increases in the principal amount or interest rate obligations to the Government.

	</summary>
</bill>
