<bill session="103" type="s" number="2336" updated="2012-07-17T04:37:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Communications Commission Authorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to extend the authorization of appropriations of the Federal Communications Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-08-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10141-10142)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-07-29"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Subcommittee on Communications. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="Communications" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Aircraft"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Delegation of powers"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Educational television"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Older workers"/>
		<term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Radio stations"/>
		<term name="Relocation of federal installations"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Ships"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
		<term name="Telephone rates"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/1994--Introduced.
Federal Communications Commission Authorization Act of 1994 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 (the Act) to authorize appropriations for the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) for FY 1994 and 1995. Derives a portion of such appropriations from application and regulatory fees. Repeals provisions regarding reimbursement of FCC travel expenses. Amends the Federal Communications Commission Authorization Act of 1988 to extend the FCC's: (1) authorization to make grants or enter into agreements to utilize the talents of older Americans in FCC programs through FY 1996; and (2) authorization for the relocation of the Hawaii monitoring station through FY 1997. Waives annual equipment inspections for vessels in compliance with the radio provisions of the Safety Convention that are operating solely in waters beyond U.S. jurisdiction, provided that an inspection is performed within 30 days after return to the United States. Revises application fee provisions to require the FCC, beginning in FY 1995, to modify such fees by proportionate increases or decreases so as to result in estimated total collections for the fiscal year equal to the sum of $40 million plus the amount specified in an appropriation Act to be collected, not to exceed necessary FCC expenses. Sets forth a schedule of application fees for personal communications services. Permits the FCC to reject a proposed tariff filing if the filing or any part is patently unlawful. Authorizes the FCC, subject to certain conditions, to require the refund of a portion of any charge by a carrier that results from violation of this Act. Permits the operation of the following radio services without individual licenses: (1) personal radio services; (2) specified aviation radio service on domestic flights; and (3) maritime radio service for ship stations navigated on domestic voyages when such ships are not otherwise required to carry a radio station. Adds a failure to comply with the Act's requirements or FCC rules that imperils the safety of life to the list of offenses for which the FCC may revoke a station license or construction permit. Imposes a forfeiture penalty for such violation. Bars forfeiture proceedings against common carriers to whom the notice of liability is issued five years after the date of the violation.

	</summary>
</bill>
