<bill session="103" type="s" number="2337" updated="2012-07-17T06:05:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-07-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend benefits for qualified service to certain merchant mariners who served during World War II, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300069"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403962" joined="1994-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1994-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1994-08-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-07-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Marine transportation"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Merchant marine"/>
		<term name="Merchant seamen"/>
		<term name="Military discharges"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/1994--Introduced.
Extends veterans' benefits to an individual who served as a member of the U.S. merchant marine between August 16, 1945 and December 31, 1946, who, during that period, was licensed or otherwise documented by an officer or employee of the United States authorized to license or document such individual, and who was a crewmember of a vessel that at the time of service was: (1) operated by the War Shipping Administration or the Office of Defense Transportation, or an agent thereof; (2) operated in waters other than inland waters, the Great Lakes, other lakes, bays, and harbors of the United States; (3) under contract, charter to, or property of, the U.S. Government; and (4) serving the armed forces. Establishes application procedures. Requires the issuance of an honorable discharge, subject to the same standards relating to the nature and duration of service that apply to the honorable discharges issued under the GI Bill Improvement Act of 1977, to an individual who performed qualified service. Deems qualified service of an individual who receives an honorable discharge under this Act and who is not eligible under any other provision of law for benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to be active duty in the armed forces during a period of war for purposes of eligibility for benefits. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) reimbursement of the Secretary for the value of benefits that the Department of Veterans Affairs provides to an individual by reason of eligibility under this Act; and (2) processing fees to correct records.

	</summary>
</bill>
