<bill session="103" type="s" number="234" updated="2012-07-17T04:20:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Government Officer Benefit Limitation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the use of United States Government aircraft for political or personal travel, limit certain benefits for senior Government officers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S816-819)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Concessions"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fringe benefits"/>
		<term name="General Services Administration"/>
		<term name="Government aircraft"/>
		<term name="Government employees' political activities"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Government vehicles"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health facilities"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Leave of absence"/>
		<term name="Medical fees"/>
		<term name="Physical fitness"/>
		<term name="Restaurants"/>
		<term name="Sports facilities"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="GOLF COURSE"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Senior Government Officer Benefit Limitation Act of 1993 - Prohibits the use of aircraft owned or leased by the Federal Government for: (1) any personal, political, or authorized special use travel; or (2) any official travel mixed with personal or political activities. Lists exceptions to such prohibition, which include the President, Vice President, and their families, if they reimburse the Federal Government for the travel. Requires the reimbursement for political travel on Government aircraft during a Presidential election campaign to be the commercial equivalent rate for applicable charter aircraft. Requires agency reports on the use of Government owned or leased aircraft. Prohibits the expenditure of Federal agency funds to equip, operate, or maintain any golf course owned or operated by an agency, except under certain circumstances. Requires any such golf course to be operated by concessionaire contract and be open to the general public. Limits use of golf course revenues. Prohibits the expenditure of Federal agency funds to: (1) subsidize dining rooms, kitchen facilities, or food preparation for the exclusive use of senior Government officers, except in certain circumstances; (2) acquire luxury vehicles to transport senior Government officers, except for cabinet officers and executive agency heads, among others; or (3) employ drivers for the exclusive use of transporting any senior Government officers except those specified. Requires the General Services Administration to prescribe regulations and uniform guidelines for all executive agencies for the purchase or lease of luxury vehicles that ensure the least cost of the Government. Sets forth additional limitations on other perquisites, namely: (1) physical fitness facilities; (2) medical services; and (3) souvenirs. Establishes a schedule for reductions in executive agency noncareer Senior Executive Service positions and Schedule C positions.

	</summary>
</bill>
