<bill session="103" type="s" number="2349" updated="2012-07-17T05:46:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elwha River Ecosystem and Fisheries Restoration Act with respect to the licensing of certain hydroelectric projects, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400559"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10358-10359)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-3" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Ecosystem management"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
		<term name="Fish culture"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/1994--Introduced.
Amends the Elwha River Ecosystem and Fisheries Restoration Act to authorize and direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to issue a license for the Elwha River and the Glines Canyon hydroelectric projects in the State of Washington, pursuant to the Federal Power Act, if by September 30, 1997, such projects are not acquired pursuant to the Act. Requires such license to include provisions for facility modifications and operational changes that will enhance Elwha River anadromous fish populations and that will be cost-effective and economically justifiable over the term of the license. Makes the authorization of appropriations under the Act to the Secretaries of the Interior and of Commerce (currently, through such Secretaries for expenditure through the Assistant Secretary for Fish, Wildlife, and Parks and through the National Marine Fisheries Service, respectively). Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) immediately prepare a program for the restoration of the Olympic Peninsula native anadromous fisheries, to commence not later than January 1, 1997, which shall provide for the recovery and enhancement of the native, anadromous fishes of that Peninsula, consistent with the rights of any Indian tribe secured by treaty or other Federal law and applicable State law; and (2) in developing such program, consider the use of experimental fisheries restoration techniques and ensure that native wild stock will not be adversely affected to a significant extent if hatchery-raised fish are used. Authorizes additional appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
