<bill session="103" type="s" number="2343" updated="2010-04-19T20:36:05-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-07-27">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-07-27" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to state the sense of the Senate on the TRICARE program of the Department of Defense and to facilitate the full implementation of the program by authorizing the reimbursement of the program for the cost of care provided under the program to certain medicare-eligible individuals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408252"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar datetime="1994-07-27"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Armed Services ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01"><text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Nunn. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="536" datetime="1994-08-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 536.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Defense policy"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Military hospitals"/>
		<term name="Military medicine"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/1994--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the health care program of the Department of Defense (DOD) known as TRICARE reflects a commitment to cooperation between the military departments and integrates the provision of health care by mlitary medical facilities; (2) full implementation of the TRICARE program will enhance DOD readiness to provide health care in support of military operations, as well as routine military health care, and will result in improved access to health care and enhancement of DOD medical facilities; and (3) Medicare (title XVIII of the Social Security Act) reimbursement is essential if the TRICARE program is to compete effectively among nationwide providers of health care services. Provides that, in the case of a person who is a Medicare-eligible individual who receives services in a certified military medical facility, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall be responsible for making reimbursement payments to the certified facility providing such care. Requires the Secretary of Defense to certify to the HHS Secretary a list of all military facilities that meet or exceed Medicare requirements that apply to a public facility, as well as all DOD health plans that meet or exceed Medicare HMO requirements.

	</summary>
</bill>
