<bill session="103" type="s" number="2344" updated="2012-07-17T04:27:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-03">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-08-03" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Science Foundation Strategic Research and Education Authorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Science Foundation Strategic Research and Education Authorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the National Science Foundation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1994-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="1994-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10219-10220)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-08-03"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-08-09"><text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy without amendment. With written report No. 103-328.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="549" datetime="1994-08-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 549.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-08-11"><text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce pursuant to the order of March 3, 1988, for not to exceed 30 session days.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-23" ><committee name="Committee on Commerce pursuant to the order of March 3, 1988, for not to exceed 30 session days"/><text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28"><text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings with amendments. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="670" datetime="1994-09-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 670.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3254" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3254" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity"/>
		<term name="Biotechnology"/>
		<term name="CIS countries"/>
		<term name="Chemicals"/>
		<term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
		<term name="College teachers"/>
		<term name="Colleges"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Computer industry"/>
		<term name="Computer literacy"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Computers"/>
		<term name="Computers in education"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost accounting"/>
		<term name="Curricula"/>
		<term name="Curriculum planning"/>
		<term name="Delegation of powers"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Educational facilities"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Engineering"/>
		<term name="Engineers"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Hawaiians"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Industry-university relations"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Information technology"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="International cooperation in science"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Materials"/>
		<term name="Materials research"/>
		<term name="Mathematics"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="National Science Foundation"/>
		<term name="Pacific Islanders"/>
		<term name="Patents"/>
		<term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research and development facilities"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Research grants"/>
		<term name="Russia"/>
		<term name="Russian Republic"/>
		<term name="Salaries"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Scientific education"/>
		<term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
		<term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
		<term name="Scientists"/>
		<term name="Strategic planning"/>
		<term name="Supercomputers"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Teachers' tenure"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/28/1994--Reported to Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Science Foundation Authorization Title II: Research and Education in Strategic Areas Title III: General Provisions National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 1994 - Title I: National Science Foundation Authorization - Authorizes appropriations to the National Science Foundation (NSF) and the Critical Technologies Institute for FY 1995 through 1999. (Sec. 103) Amends the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 to direct NSF to include in its annual report to the President a strategic plan defining its goals, criteria, and procedures. (Sec. 106) Requires the Director of NSF (Director) to develop an Arctic logistics support program and related budget to facilitate United States Arctic research. Authorizes FY 1996 through 1999 appropriations. Title II: Research and Education in Strategic Areas - National Science Foundation Strategic Research and Education Authorization Act of 1994 - Authorizes the Director to establish the following cross-directorate initiatives: (1) advanced manufacturing technology; (2) advanced materials and processing; (3) biotechnology; (4) civil infrastructure systems; (5) global change research; (6) environmental research; (7) high performance computing and communications; and (8) science, mathematics, engineering, and technology education. Authorizes FY 1995 through 1999 appropriations. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the Director, within the advanced manufacturing technology initiative, to: (1) make awards to universities for research and education to accelerate technologies of particular value to low population regions; (2) establish graduate student traineeships; (3) establish teaching fellowships for persons from industry; (4) develop curricula; and (5) establish the Small Manufacturers Renewal and Training (pilot) Program to sponsor engineering students to work as interns with small manufacturers. Requires the Director to expand the number of Engineering Research Centers and the Industry/University Cooperative Research Centers Program. (Sec. 208) Authorizes the Director, within the environmental reseach initiative, to establish a National Environmental Research Program (including a National Environmental Research Forum, research centers, and a fellowship program). Title III: General Provisions - Amends the Academic Research Facilities Modernization Act of 1988 to require the Director, when making awards for academic facilities maintenance, to include projects for the acquisition of research instrumentation. (Sec. 302) Amends the Science and Engineering Equal Opportunities Act to authorize the Director to make awards to institutions of higher education and local educational agencies to develop science, computer science, technology, and mathematics curricula in accord with traditional cultural values of Native Hawaiian students, Pacific Islander students, and Native American students. Includes individuals with disabilities as an underrepresented group for which the Committee on Equal Opportunities in Science and Engineering should encourage full participation in scientific, engineering, and professional fields. (Sec. 303) Authorizes appropriations for the Director to: (1) make grants to organizations, including colleges and universities, to promote cooperative research projects between scientists in the United States and scientists in Latin America; and (2) establish a cross-directorate program between the United States and the Newly Independent States to make awards to individuals, small groups, and research centers to support collaborative research efforts between scientists and engineers from both countries. (Sec. 304) Requires the Director to continue to carry out the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research in certain States that have: (1) historically received little research and development funding; and (2) demonstrated a research commitment. (Sec. 305) Authorizes appropriations for a National Undergraduate Teaching Fellows program to improve undergraduate education in science, mathematics, and engineering. (Sec. 306) Amends the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 and the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 1988 to modify certain administrative procedures.

	</summary>
</bill>
