<bill session="103" type="s" number="2363" updated="2012-07-17T04:44:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sexually Violent Predators Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish registration and tracking procedures and community notification with respect to released sexually violent predators.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400559"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1994-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1994-08-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10638)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Mentally ill"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="Sex offenders"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/4/1994--Introduced.
Sexually Violent Predators Act - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish guidelines for State programs to require a sexually violent predator (a person convicted of a sexually violent offense who suffers from a mental abnormality or personality disorder (condition) that makes the person likely to engage in predatory sexually violent offenses) to register a current address with a designated State law enforcement agency (agency) upon being released from prison, being placed on parole, or being placed on supervised release; and (2) approve each State program that complies with the guidelines. Makes a State that does not implement and maintain such a program ineligible to receive ten percent of the funds that would otherwise be allocated to it under the Drug Control and System Improvement Grant Program. Provides for reallocation of such funds to States in compliance. Requires: (1) the sentencing court to make the determination that a person is or is no longer a sexually violent predator after receiving a report by a board of experts on sexual offenses; and (2) each State to establish such a board. Directs a State prison officer, if a person required to register is anticipated to be released from prison, paroled, or placed on supervised release, to: (1) inform the person of the duty to register and to provide any change of address to a designated State agency in writing; (2) obtain the person's name, identifying factors, anticipated future residence, and offense history and documentation of any treatment received for the condition; and (3) require the person to read and sign a form stating that the duty to register has been explained. Requires the officer to forward the information to a designated State agency which which shall enter the information into the appropriate State law enforcement record system, notify the appropriate agency with jurisdiction over the area in which the person expects to reside, and transmit the information to the Identification Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) quarterly address verification; (2) notification of local agencies of address changes; (3) penalties for failing to register and keep registration current; (4) termination of the obligation to register; (5) community notification; and (6) immunity for good faith conduct under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
