<bill session="103" type="s" number="2370" updated="2012-07-17T05:16:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Peace Operations Support Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide procedures for the contribution of volunteer United States military personnel to international peace operations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1994-08-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-08-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10941-10942)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="Military pay"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Volunteer forces"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/8/1994--Introduced.
International Peace Operations Support Act of 1994 - Directs the President to submit a report to the Congress setting forth a plan and procedures for recruiting, training, and organizing into units of the armed forces a contingency force of up to 3,000 personnel, comprised of current active-duty military personnel, who volunteer additionally and specifically to serve in international peace operations and who receive added compensation for such service. Authorizes the President: (1) upon approval by the United Nations Security Council of an international peace operation and after appropriate congressional consultation, to make those units available for such operations; and (2) to terminate U.S. participation in international peace operations at any time and take actions necessary to protect U.S. forces. Requires termination of any use of the armed forces with respect to which a report was submitted or required to be submitted under the War Powers Resolution within 180 days, unless the Congress has extended by law such period. Authorizes the use of funds available to the Department of Defense to carry out this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
