<bill session="103" type="s" number="237" updated="2012-07-17T04:50:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Network Security Board Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create the National Network Security Board as an independent government agency, located within the Federal Communications Commission, to promote telecommunications network security and reliability by conducting independent network outage investigations and by formulating security improvement recommendations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408898"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S822-824)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Computer networks"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Information networks"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
National Network Security Board Act of 1993 - Establishes the National Network Security Board as an independent body within the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to: (1) investigate long distance or local telecommunications network outages in the United States; (2) report on the circumstances of each outage; (3) issue reports recommending responses to reduce the likelihood of outage recurrences; (4) conduct special investigations on telecommunications network security and reliability; and (5) assess methods of network outage investigation and publish recommended procedures. Authorizes the Chairman of the FCC, at the request of the Board, to carry out such outage investigations in lieu of or in addition to any Board investigation. Requires public access to information compiled by the Board. Requires the FCC Chairman to respond within 90 days to a Board recommendation regarding network outages. Requires the Chairman to report to the Congress on all the Board's recommendations regarding telecommunications network security and the Chairman's response. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
