<bill session="103" type="s" number="2399" updated="2012-07-17T04:40:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Railroad Grade Crossing Safety and Research Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote railroad safety and enhance interstate commerce.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403962"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11901-11902)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Railroad research"/>
		<term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
		<term name="Railroad safety"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Right-of-way"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Vandalism"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/16/1994--Introduced.
Railroad Grade Crossing Safety and Research Act of 1994 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation, in conjunction with a university or college having expertise in highway driver and railroad safety, to establish an Institute for Railroad and Grade Crossing Safety. Directs the Institute to: (1) research, develop, fund, or test measures for reducing the number of fatalities and injuries in rail operations; and (2) focus on improvements in railroad grade crossing safety, railroad trespass prevention, prevention of railroad vandalism, and the improved enforcement of laws in such areas. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to: (1) review current local, State, and Federal codes regarding trespass on railroad property and vandalism affecting railroad safety; and (2) develop model prevention and enforcement codes and strategies for the consideration of State and local legislatures and governmental entities. Requires the Secretary to: (3) develop a comprehensive outreach program to improve communications among Federal railroad safety inspectors, Federal Rail Administration-certified State inspectors, railroad police, and State and local law enforcement, in order to address trespass and vandalism dangers on railroad property; and (2) to strengthen law enforcement strategies. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to amend specified regulations under the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 to subject to a specified civil penalty: (1) any person who defaces, disables, damages, vandalizes, or commits any act that adversely affects the function of any railroad grade crossing related signal system, sign, gate, device, sensor, or equipment; and (2) any person who trespasses on a railroad owned or railroad leased right-of-way, road, or bridge. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to encourage railraods to warn the public about potential civil liability for violations of Federal regulations related to vandalism of railroad crossing related devices, signs and equipment, and trespass on railroad property. (Sec. 7) Prohibits any State or political subdivision from imposing a whistle ban with respect to a railroad grade crossing or series of railroad grade crossings unless one of enumerated actions has been taken. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to review Department of Transportation's (DOT) rules with respect to rail car visibility. Requires the Secretary to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to issue regulations requiring enhanced visibility standards for newly manufactured and remanufactured rail cars. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to issue regulations which impose a freeze on the total number of railroad grade crossings in each State. (Sec. 10) Requires the Secretary to incorporate the enhancement of railroad grade crossing safety, the prevention of trespassing on railroad property and vandalism to railroad grade crossing safety devices, signs, and equipment into the research, technology development, and testing priorities of DOT. (Sec. 11) Requires the Secretary to maintain an emergency notification system utilizing a toll free &quot;800&quot; telephone number that can be used by the public to convey to railroads information about malfunctions or other safety problems at railroad-highway grade crossings.

	</summary>
</bill>
