<bill session="103" type="s" number="2402" updated="2012-07-17T06:22:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homeowners Insurance Disclosure Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for public access to information regarding the availability of insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1994-08-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1994-08-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1994-08-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1994-08-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1994-08-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12099-12100)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Business insurance"/>
		<term name="Business losses"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Casualty insurance"/>
		<term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Computer software"/>
		<term name="Computers and government"/>
		<term name="Confidential communications"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fire insurance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Insurance"/>
		<term name="Insurance agents"/>
		<term name="Insurance companies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Property insurance"/>
		<term name="Racial discrimination"/>
		<term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Sex discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Statistics"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Urban areas"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women in business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/18/1994--Introduced.
Homeowners Insurance Disclosure Act of 1994 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish annual disclosure requirements for non-commercial insurers (providers of homeowners, dwelling fire, allied lines, and other personal lines of insurance), including: (1) the availability, affordability and type of insurance coverage by Metropolitan Statistical Area (MSA), and the region, race, and gender of policyholders; (2) the racial characteristics and location by MSA of the principal place of business of current and terminated insurance agents; and (3) for designated insurers, the total number of policies, exposures, nonrenewals, and racial characteristics of licensed agents, and the aggregate loss experience. Provides for disclosure requirements for certain non-designated insurers. Directs the Secretary to study and report to the Congress on the availability, affordability, and quality of types of commercial insurance for residential properties and small businesses in urban areas. Instructs the Secretary to establish requirements for insurers to report annually on the availability, affordability, and quality or type of insurance in designated rural areas. Authorizes the Secretary to waive certain disclosure requirements if the States collect equivalent information. Directs the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council to determine the extent to which private mortgage insurers disclose to the public and regulatory agencies information that is equivalent to that required under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975. Requires noncompliant insurers to submit the requisite information to the Secretary. Prescribes guidelines for information compilation and maintenance and for a public availability and access system. Prescribes guidelines for disclosures by insurers to applicants and policyholders, stating the reasons that an insurance application was declined. Authorizes the Secretary to provide immunity to insurers, agents, and brokers regarding their communication of a cancellation, denial, or nonrenewal of insurance. Sets forth enforcement guidelines, including civil penalties and injunctions. Directs the Secretary to establish a task force on insurance agency appointments to report to certain congressional committees on the appointment and retention of inner-city and minority agents representing property and casualty insurers. Instructs the Secretary to study and report to certain congressional committees on insurance industry practices regarding: (1) prescreening of insurance applicants; (2) meeting of the property and casualty insurance needs of the residential and small business community in low- and moderate-income and minority neighborhoods; (3) disparate claims treatment of policyholders based on race, gender, and income level; (4) basing of premium amounts on the territory in which the insured risk is located; and (5) the feasibility of establishing community reinvestment requirements for insurers comparable to those applicable to depository institutions.

	</summary>
</bill>
