<bill session="103" type="s" number="241" updated="2012-07-17T05:00:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Primary Care Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">State Health Service Corps Demonstration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide incentives to health care providers serving rural areas, to provide grants to county health departments providing preventative health services within rural areas, to establish State health service corps demonstration projects, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408939"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1993-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-01-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S827)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
		<term name="Physicians"/>
		<term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Public health personnel"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Urban areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Table of Contents: Title I: Tax Provisions Title II: Public Health Service Provisions Title III: State Health Service Corps Demonstration Projects Rural Primary Care Act of 1993 - Title I: Tax Provisions - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a nonrefundable personal income tax credit for any physician, physician assistant, or nurse practitioner who provides primary health services to residents of a rural health professional shortage area and who does not have certain connections with the National Health Service Corps loan repayment or scholarship programs. Excludes from gross income any payments made on behalf of a taxpayer by the National Health Service Corps loan repayment program. Amends provisions relating to election to expense certain depreciable business assets to specify a higher maximum aggregate cost to be taken into account for property used by a physician in providing primary health services in a rural health professional shortage area. Mandates a study to determine the present number of, and future need for, physician and nonphysician primary care providers in medically underserved urban areas. Requires that the determination form the basis for a study of the feasibility of extending the tax credit provided under this title. Title II: Public Health Service Provisions - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require a set-aside of a minimum amount of funds currently authorized for preventive health and health services block grants for the county health department grants mandated by this title. Requires grants to county health departments for preventive health services in areas within the county that are not urbanized. Title III: State Health Service Corps Demonstration Projects - State Health Service Corps Demonstration Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a State Health Service Corps Demonstration Project. Directs the Secretary to make grants under the Project to up to ten States for the Federal share of training and employment of physician and nonphysician providers serving health professional shortage areas. Authorizes appropriations. Requires each State carrying out a Project to establish a State Health Service Corps Scholarship Program involving a period of service in the service area or on the clinical staff of an area health education center or a medical school in return for a scholarship.

	</summary>
</bill>
