<bill session="103" type="s" number="2429" updated="2012-07-17T05:40:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs an Office for Women Veterans and an Office for Minority Veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12629-12630)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Clinical trials"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
		<term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Women"/>
		<term name="Women veterans"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/25/1994--Introduced.
Establishes in the Department of Veterans Affairs an Office for Minority Veterans, headed by a Director who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. Outlines Director duties with respect to advising, making recommendations, promoting, and disseminating information with respect to the implementation of policies and programs affecting veterans who are minority group members (Asian American, Black, Hispanic, Native American, or Pacific-Islander American). Requires the Secretary to include in budget documents submitted to the Congress each year information with respect to the Office's budget. Directs the Secretary to establish the Advisory Committee on Minority Veterans. Requires the Committee to report biennially to the Secretary, who shall report to the Congress, on Department programs and activities that pertain to minority veterans. Directs the Secretary to designate an appropriate official at each Department regional and medical facility to serve as minority affairs officer. Establishes in the Department an Office for Women Veterans, headed by a Director appointed by the Secretary. Outlines Director duties with respect to advising, making recommendations, promoting, and disseminating information with respect to the adoption of policies and programs affecting women veterans. Requires the Secretary to include in budget documents submitted to the Congress each year information with respect to the Office's budget. Requires the inclusion on the Advisory Committee on Women Veterans of members representing women veterans who do and who do not have experience in a military theater of operations.

	</summary>
</bill>
