<bill session="103" type="s" number="2423" updated="2012-07-17T06:19:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-08-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-08-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-08-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Arts Endowing the Arts Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the provisions of title 17, United States Code, to provide for the auction of certain copyrights to financially support the National Endowment for the Arts and the National Endowment for the Humanities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1994-08-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1994-08-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-08-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12620-12621)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-08-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Copyright"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Auctions"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Libraries"/>
		<term name="Library of Congress"/>
		<term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/25/1994--Introduced.
Arts Endowing the Arts Act of 1994 - Amends copyright law to provide for the auction of certain copyrights to financially support the National Endowment for the Arts and the National Endowment for the Humanities. Applies such provisions to copyrights in literary works, sound recordings, visual arts works, pictorial, graphic, and sculptural works, and motion pictures. Establishes the Arts and Humanities Copyright Board within the Library of Congress. Sets forth auction procedures, including selection of copyrights for auction, copyright for auction selected upon bidder's initiative, copyrights excluded from auction, notification, and auction copyright bids. Provides for registration and issuance of a certificate for auction copyright in a work for 20 years after the expiration of the term of copyright in the work last held under copyright law other than auction copyright provisions. Prohibits renewal or extension of such auction copyright. Limits U.S. liability. Provides that such auction shall have no effect on the original copyright. Establishes the National Endowments for the Arts and Humanities Copyright Trust Fund in the Treasury.

	</summary>
</bill>
