<bill session="103" type="s" number="2432" updated="2012-07-17T04:29:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for Fiscal Year 1995, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-09-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12814-12815)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="2811" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Air quality"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Atmospheric research"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Climate"/>
		<term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
		<term name="Coastal zone"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Geodesy"/>
		<term name="Geodetic research"/>
		<term name="Government aircraft"/>
		<term name="Government contractors"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Hydrology"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
		<term name="Maps"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
		<term name="Marine pollution"/>
		<term name="Marine safety"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="Meteorological research"/>
		<term name="Meteorological satellites"/>
		<term name="Meteorology"/>
		<term name="Oceanographic research"/>
		<term name="Oceanographic research ships"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Remote sensing"/>
		<term name="Space activities"/>
		<term name="Spacecraft"/>
		<term name="Tax exemption"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Weather"/>
		<term name="Weather forecasting"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/13/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: NOAA Atmospheric and Satellite Programs Title II: NOAA Ocean and Coastal Programs Title III: NOAA Marine Fishery Programs Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1994 - Title I: NOAA Atmospheric and Satellite Programs - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 to the Secretary of Commerce to enable the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to improve its public warning and forecast systems and to carry out: (1) the operations and research activities of the National Weather Service; (2) its climate and air quality research activities, including the study of climate and global change; (3) its atmospheric research activities; (4) its satellite observing systems activities; and (5) its data and information services activities. Title II: NOAA Ocean and Coastal Programs - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 to the Secretary to enable NOAA to carry out: (1) mapping, charting, and geodesy activities, including geodetic data collection and analysis; (2) observation and assessment activities; (3) a Coastal Ocean Program; (4) ocean and Great Lakes research activities; and (5) its undersea research activities. Title III: NOAA Marine Fishery Programs - Amends the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Marine Fisheries Program Authorization Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1995 to enable the National Marine Fisheries Service to carry out its duties relating to fisheries information collection and analysis, and fisheries conservation and management operations. Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1995 to the Secretary: (1) to enable NOAA to carry out executive direction and administrative activities and marine and aircraft services activities; and (2) for acquisition, construction, maintenance, and operation of NOAA facilities. (Sec. 402) Requires the Secretary to convey to the Commonwealth of Massachusetts all U.S. interests in the National Marine Fisheries Service laboratory in Gloucester, Massachusetts. (Sec. 403) Directs that all amounts received by the United States in settlement of, or judgment for, damage claims arising from the collision of the vessel Zachery into the NOAA research vessel Discoverer be retained as an offsetting collection in NOAA's Fleet Modernization, Shipbuilding, and Conversion account, be deposited in that account upon receipt by the Government, and be available only for obligation for NOAA vessel repairs. (Sec. 404) Requires the Secretary to contract with the National Research Council to examine and report to the Secretary and the Congress on NOAA Corps responsibilities and activities in supporting the missions of NOAA. (Sec. 405) Authorizes the Secretary to expend $340,000 to acquire, construct, and install weather reporting stations in Prince William Sound, Alaska, and $160,000 in each of FY 1995 and 1996 to maintain specified equipment. (Sec. 406) Exempts activities of the contractor on behalf of NOAA pursuant to the modernization of the National Weather Service from taxation. (Sec. 407) Amends the Fur Seal Act of 1966 to: (1) direct the Secretary to carry out his duties under the Act through contracts, compacts, or memoranda of agreement with the entities on the Pribilof Islands entitled to receive conveyance of lands by the Act; and (2) authorize the Secretary to clean up the dumps, debris, storage tanks, property, hazardous conditions, and contaminants which the Federal Government abandoned or conveyed to entities of the Islands.

	</summary>
</bill>
