<bill session="103" type="s" number="2431" updated="2012-07-17T05:12:39-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-13">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-13"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Crime Control Improvement Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to reduce the amount of social spending, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403515"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300159" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1994-09-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1994-09-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12809, S12813-12814)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-13" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Bombings"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Child pornography"/>
		<term name="Classified defense information"/>
		<term name="Community development corporations"/>
		<term name="Community schools"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Correctional institutions"/>
		<term name="Counterfeiting"/>
		<term name="Covert operations"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Drugs and youth"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Forgery"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Gangs"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Illegal aliens"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Intelligence officers"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
		<term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Organized crime"/>
		<term name="Passports"/>
		<term name="Perjury"/>
		<term name="Police"/>
		<term name="Prison alternatives"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Prostitution"/>
		<term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Sabotage"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
		<term name="Slavery"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Tax evasion"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Treason"/>
		<term name="Urban affairs"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Visas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/13/1994--Introduced.
Crime Control Improvement Act of 1994 - Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (the Act) to eliminate the Model Intensive Grant Program, the Local Partnership Grant Program, the Local Crime Prevention Block Grant Program, the Family and Community Endeavor Schools Program, the Community-Based Justice Grant Program, the Urban Recreation Program, the At-Risk Youth Program, the Police Recruitment Program, the National Community Economic Partnership Program, the Community Schools Program, the Ounce of Prevention Program, the Gang Resistance Education and Training Program, the Drug Courts Program, and the Family Unity Demonstration Project. Revises the Act to authorize the Attorney General to make grants to construct, expand, modify, operate, or improve conventional prisons (currently, correctional facilities). Repeals provisions regarding the transfer of unused funds. Increases Federal mandatory minimum sentences for using or carrying a firearm during and in relation to a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime, employing minors in drug trafficking, and selling illegal drugs to minors. Bars the court from placing on probation or suspending the sentence of any person convicted of such offenses. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to expand the definition of &quot;aggravated felony.&quot; Authorizes the Attorney General to issue a final order of deportation against any alien who was not lawfully admitted for permanent residence, or who had permanent resident status on a conditional basis, whom the Attorney General determines to be deportable under provisions relating to conviction of an aggravated felony. Limits judicial review of such determinations. Provides for deportation of permanent resident aliens under specified circumstances. Grants a U.S. district court jurisdiction to enter a judicial order of deportation at the time of sentencing against an alien whose criminal conviction causes such alien to be deportable if requested prior to sentencing by the U.S. Attorney. Restricts defenses to deportation. Enhances penalties for failing to depart or reentering after a final order of deportation. Limits collateral attacks on deportation orders. Directs the Attorney General to operate a criminal alien tracking center. Authorizes appropriations. Revises provisions of the Act pertaining to the non-application of mandatory minimum sentences in certain cases involving nonviolent drug offenses. Expresses the sense of the Congress that all grants authorized under the Act and not required to be distributed according to a formula prescribed by law shall be distributed in a fair and equitable manner that ensures that rural States receive a fair and proportional share of the funds.

	</summary>
</bill>
