<bill session="103" type="s" number="2443" updated="2012-07-17T05:23:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gun Victim Compensation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide compensation for victims from persons who unlawfully provide firearms to juveniles, felons, and other disqualified individuals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1994-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13032-13033)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="5284" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
		<term name="Criminal liability"/>
		<term name="Damages"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Punitive damages"/>
		<term name="Torts"/>
		<term name="Youth"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/1994--Introduced.
Gun Victim Compensation Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to make any person who sells, delivers, or otherwise transfers a firearm to a juvenile, felon, or other disqualified individual, or a handgun to a person who the transferor knows or has reasonable cause to believe is a juvenile liable for damages caused by a discharge of the transferred firearm by the transferee. Makes exceptions, including for certain temporary transfers to a juvenile who uses a handgun in the course of employment relating to ranching or farming with the prior written consent of a parent or guardian and for the issuance of a handgun to a juvenile who is a member of the armed forces or National Guard. Authorizes an action for damages to be brought in a U.S. district court by, or on behalf of, any person who suffers damages resulting from bodily injury or death caused by a discharge of the transferred firearm by the transferee. Specifies that there shall be no liability under this Act if it is established by a preponderance of the evidence that: (1) the damages were suffered by an individual who was engaged in a criminal act against the person or property of another at the time of the injury; or (2) the injury was self-inflicted unless the plaintiff establishes that, at the time of the transfer, the transferor knew or had reasonable cause to believe that the transferee had not attained age 18 or had been adjudicated as a mental defective or committed to a mental institution. Limits actions to those brought within five years after the date of the transfer of the firearm. Requires that a prevailing plaintiff be awarded attorney's fees. Permits the award of punitive damages.

	</summary>
</bill>
