<bill session="103" type="s" number="2442" updated="2012-07-17T05:49:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965 and to provide authorizations for the Appalachian highway and Appalachian area development programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="1994-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13031-13032)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Appalachia"/>
		<term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Electric power distribution"/>
		<term name="Electric power production"/>
		<term name="Electric power transmission"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Gas companies"/>
		<term name="Gas industry"/>
		<term name="Gas pipelines"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Natural gas"/>
		<term name="Regional economic development"/>
		<term name="Rural economic development"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/1994--Introduced.
Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 1994 - Amends the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965 to authorize: (1) appropriations for administrative expenses of the Appalachian Regional Commission and for the construction of an Appalachian development highway system and related purposes (increases the Federal share for such construction); and (2) the leasing of office space for any term expiring no later than September 30, 1999. Redefines &quot;Federal grant-in-aid programs&quot; to mean Federal grant-in-aid programs authorized on or before September 30, 1999. Repeals a provision prohibiting the authorization of financial assistance under the Act to be used to finance the cost of: (1) industrial plants, commercial facilities, machinery, working capital, or other industrial facilities or to enable plant subcontractors to undertake work theretofore performed in another area by other subcontractors or contractors; or (2) facilities for the generation, transmission, or distribution of electric energy or for the production, transmission, or distribution of gas (natural, manufactured, or mixed). Authorizes appropriations to carry out the Act. Terminates the Act on October 1, 1999, except with respect to the Appalachian development highway system.

	</summary>
</bill>
