<bill session="103" type="s" number="2451" updated="2012-07-17T06:16:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Farm, Ranch, and Homestead Protection Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to ensure that constitutionally protected private property rights are not infringed until adequate protection is afforded by reauthorization of such Act, to protect against and compensate for economic losses from critical habitat designation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300054"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300159" joined="1994-09-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13285)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="5073" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Eminent domain"/>
		<term name="Endangered species"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Habitat conservation"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/1994--Introduced.
Farm, Ranch, and Homestead Protection Act of 1994 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to prohibit, until its reauthorization, the Secretary of the Interior from: (1) determining a species as an endangered or threatened species; or (2) designating a species habitat as a critical habitat. Requires the Secretary to compensate, upon request, persons and entities for the loss in market value of land that has been designated a critical habitat. Limits the current requirement that Federal agencies insure that any action (regardless of its expense) they authorize, fund, or carry out is not likely to jeopardize the continued existence of an endangered or threatened species, or result in the destruction or adverse modification of habitat of such species determined to be critical, without an express exemption. Restricts such requirement to agency actions that result in expenditures of $500,000 or more.

	</summary>
</bill>
