<bill session="103" type="s" number="2472" updated="2012-07-17T05:14:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sound Science in Risk Assessment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue rules governing risk assessments, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300069"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13585-13586)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/28/1994--Introduced.
Sound Science in Risk Assessment Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop rules and review procedures that provide that: (1) risk assessments are consistent, of high technical quality, scientifically objective, and unbiased; and (2) significant uncertainties regarding facts, scientific knowledge, the validity of analytical techniques, or numerical risk estimates are clearly disclosed in terms readily understandable to the public. Requires the Administrator to issue proposed rules that: (1) set forth uniform general procedures governing risk assessments conducted by EPA and incorporate relevant guidelines existing prior to the issuance of such rules; and (2) govern use of a distinctive type of risk assessment approach, technique, or methodology. Directs the Administrator to issue procedures for the review and revision of a risk assessment completed prior to this Act's enactment or the issuance of final risk assessment rules. Permits petitions to the Administrator to perform reviews under certain conditions. Requires the Administrator to issue final rules for risk assessment approaches, techniques, or methodologies after taking into account comments by the public.

	</summary>
</bill>
