<bill session="103" type="s" number="248" updated="2012-07-17T04:44:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Death Penalty Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish constitutional procedures for the imposition of the death penalty for terrorist murders.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300092"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-03-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S848-849)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Age (Law)"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Appellate procedure"/>
		<term name="Assassination"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Correctional personnel"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Presidential protection"/>
		<term name="Protection of foreign officials"/>
		<term name="Protection of officials"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Right to counsel"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/27/1993--Introduced.
Terrorist Death Penalty Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize the imposition of the death penalty for any individual who kills a U.S. national while such national is outside the United States, if the killing is a first degree murder. Increases penalties for killings other than first degree murders. Sets forth procedures for the imposition of the death penalty, including provisions with respect to notice by the Government that it intends to seek the death penalty, the conduct of a special hearing to determine whether a sentence of death is justified, mitigating and aggravating factors to be considered, proof of such factors, the return of findings, and procedures for appeal and review of a sentence of death. Specifies that where a sentence of death is not imposed, the court may impose a sentence of life imprisonment without the possibility of release or furlough. Sets forth provisions with respect to the appointment of counsel for indigent defendants in Federal capital cases, including standards for the competence of counsel. Sets forth additional provisions regarding: (1) the appointment of counsel in State capital cases; (2) time limits for a collateral attack on a judgment imposing a sentence of death; and (3) stays of execution.

	</summary>
</bill>
