<bill session="103" type="s" number="2487" updated="2012-07-17T06:29:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-09-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-09-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Financial Services Organization Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the economic conditions and supply of housing in Native American communities by creating the Native American Financial Services Organization, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300017"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1994-09-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1994-09-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-09-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13857-13858)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-09-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Community development banking"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal incorporation"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Financial services"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Indian economic development"/>
		<term name="Indian housing"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/30/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Statement of Policy; Definitions Title II: Native American Financial Services Organization Title III: Capitalization of Organization Title IV: Regulation, Examination, and Reports Title V: Formation of New Corporation Title VI: Authorizations of Appropriations Native American Financial Services Organization Act of 1994 - Title I: Statement of Policy; Definitions - Sets forth a statement of policy and purposes and definitions with respect to this Act. Title II: Native American Financial Services Organization - Establishes the Native American Financial Services Organization (Organization) to assist in improving Native American housing and economic situations including the creation of Native American Financial Institutions. Authorizes a Native American lending services grant. Title III: Capitalization of the Organization - Sets forth Organization capitalization provisions. Title IV: Regulation, Examination, and Reports - Sets forth Organization regulation, examination, and reporting provisions. Title V: Formation of New Corporation - Provides for the formation of a new Organization under the laws of any tribe, State, or the District of Columbia. Title VI: Authorizations of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations for: (1) Native American Financial Institutions; and (2) the Organization.

	</summary>
</bill>
