<bill session="103" type="s" number="2509" updated="2012-07-17T06:07:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">American Heritage Areas Partnership Program Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an American Heritage Areas Partnership Program in the Department of the Interior.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400563"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14260-14261)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Capital investments"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Cultural property"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government publicity"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Recreation areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/5/1994--Introduced.
American Heritage Areas Partnership Program Act of 1994 - Establishes the American Heritage Areas Partnership Program within the Department of the Interior, consisting of such Areas designated by this Act. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) evaluate combinations of resources best preserved, interpreted, stabilized, and managed as American Heritage Areas under a partnership model; (2) evaluate nominated Areas; (3) advise State and local governments, nonprofit organizations, or other appropriate entities as to suitable methods of recognizing and preserving thematically and geographically linked natural, historic, and cultural resources and recreational opportunities; (4) provide technical assistance and grants for nominating areas for inclusion in the Program, for developing compacts for nominated Areas and management plans for designated Areas, and for undertaking capital projects and improvements; and (5) consider any designated Heritage Area for nomination to the World Heritage List if the Area meets the nomination qualification. Provides that an area may be designated as an American Heritage Area only by an Act of the Congress. Conditions such designation on the Secretary's approval of an Area feasibility study and compact. Provides that the designation of the Area shall not: (1) signify that it is included in, or eligible for, inclusion in the National Register of Historic Places; or (2) preclude nomination to, or inclusion in, the Register of any district, site, building, structure, or object located within the Area. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to make matching grants and provide technical assistance to: (1) assist in studies to identify the feasibility of establishing a heritage area; (2) prepare compacts outlining the objectives, boundaries, and management structure of the heritage area; (3) prepare management plans for designated Areas; and (4) provide support for early actions as part of the development of such Areas. Specifies contents of Area feasibility studies, compacts, and management plans. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the management entities named in the compacts for Areas to receive Federal funds in support of cooperative partnerships to prepare and implement the management plans and otherwise perform the functions contemplated in this Act. Sets forth eligibility requirements for such entities. Requires each such entity to submit to the Secretary a management plan within five years after the date of designation of an Area. Makes the entity eligible to receive funds appropriated through this Act for ten years after such date. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to: (1) report to the Congress on the Program annually; (2) monitor the welfare of the Areas whose eligibility for Federal funding has expired; and (3) provide the public with information on Program components. (Sec. 9) Permits adoption and implementation of land use plans for a designated Area by local governments or authorized management entities. (Sec. 10) Authorizes appropriations. Specifies fund limitations.

	</summary>
</bill>
