<bill session="103" type="s" number="2534" updated="2010-04-19T21:05:44-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-25">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
	<status><enacted datetime="1994-10-25" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Base Closure Community Redevelopment and Homeless Assistance Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Base Closure Community Redevelopment and Homeless Assistance Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revise and improve the process for disposing of buildings and property at military installations under the base closure laws.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407786"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400564" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1994-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-10-06" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14456-14461"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T00:49:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T01:31:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T02:26:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Gonzalez asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T02:26:00-04:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR 10/6/1993 H11163)</text></action>
		<vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="1994-10-07T02:32:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass"  state="PASSED:BILL"><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text></vote>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07T02:32:00-04:00"><text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<topresident datetime="1994-10-07" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident datetime="1994-10-17" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed datetime="1994-10-25" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="103-421" type="public" datetime="1994-10-25"  state="ENACTED:SIGNED"><text>Became Public Law No: 103-421.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Defense economics"/>
		<term name="Homeless"/>
		<term name="Housing"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Real estate development"/>
		<term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
		<term name="Surplus government property"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Base Closure Community Redevelopment and Homeless Assistance Act of 1994 - Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to direct the Secretary of Defense (Secretary), with respect to the use or transferability of any portion of a military installation closed or to be closed under such Act, to: (1) identify the buildings and property for which the Department of Defense (DOD) or another Federal department or agency has a use or will accept a transfer; (2) identify any property as surplus; (3) submit to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and to the redevelopment authority for such installation information on any property identified as surplus; and (4) publish in the Federal Register and the appropriate local newspaper information on the surplus property. Requires State and local governments, representatives of the homeless, and other parties interested in the surplus property to submit to the redevelopment authority (RA) a notice of interest in such property, with certain time limits. Requires the representative of the homeless to submit with such notice specific information with respect to the proposed homeless assistance program for such property, as well as certain assessments and descriptions. Directs the RA for each installation to prepare a redevelopment plan for such installation which includes legally binding agreements concerning the use of such property to assist the homeless. Requires redevelopment plan approval by the HUD Secretary. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the HUD Secretary, in completing a review of a plan, should take into consideration and be receptive to the predominant views on the plan of the communities in the vicinity of the installation covered by the plan. Requires an RA, upon completion of a redevelopment plan, to submit to the Secretary and the HUD Secretary an application containing such plan. Requires the Secretaries to complete a review of the plan within 60 days after receipt, including a determination as to whether such plan meets certain requirements with respect to the homeless population in the area, the availability of existing services to meet the needs of the homeless, and the suitability of the surplus property to meet such needs. Allows for the negotiation of plan deficiencies between the RA and the HUD Secretary during such review . Requires appropriate action by the parties concerned if the HUD Secretary determines a redevelopment plan to be inappropriate, including plan revision and resubmission by the RA. Provides for transfer to the representative of the homeless or the RA of surplus property for disposal, without consideration, under an approved redevelopment plan. Authorizes either Secretary to postpone any deadline related to plan consideration and approval in the interest of the communities affected. Provides transition provisions applicable to installations approved for closure before the enactment of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
