<bill session="103" type="s" number="2545" updated="2010-04-19T21:07:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-07">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Home and Community-Based Services for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for home community-based services for individuals with disabilities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14840-14842, S14851)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Ambulatory care"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Caregivers"/>
		<term name="Collective bargaining"/>
		<term name="Community health services"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Executive departments"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Health policy"/>
		<term name="Home care services"/>
		<term name="Hospital care"/>
		<term name="Hospital patients"/>
		<term name="Hospital personnel"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Labor"/>
		<term name="Long-term care"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Ombudsman"/>
		<term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Quality of care"/>
		<term name="Respite care"/>
		<term name="Social security"/>
		<term name="Surgery"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax returns"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transfer of employees"/>
		<term name="Welfare"/>
		<term name="X-rays"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1994--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Home and Community-Based Services for Individuals With Disabilities Title II: Provisions Relating to Medicare Long-Term Care Reform and Deficit Reduction Act of 1995 - Title I: Home and Community Based Services for Individuals with Disabilities - Entitles each State with an approved plan for home and community-based services for individuals with disabilities to specified payments. Prohibits such plans from requiring cost sharing for low-income individuals. Requires such plans to: (1) ensure the quality of services; (2) adhere to Federal quality standards; (3) provide for a client advocacy office; (4) provide safeguards on confidentiality and against abuse; and (5) protect individual rights. (Sec. 108) Establishes an advisory group to advise the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the States on all aspects of such State programs. (Sec. 110) Authorizes appropriations and provides for allotments to States. (Sec. 111) Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress on evaluations of services to individuals with low-incomes and disabilities. (Sec. 112) Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary to disseminate information and materials to assist specified entities in replicating successful programs aimed at offering care management to hospitalized individuals in need of long-term care so that services to meet individual needs and preferences can be arranged in home- and community-based settings as an alternative to long-term nursing home placement. Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to such entities. Directs the Secretary to establish a program under which incentive grants may be awarded to assist agencies and organizations in developing and expanding programs and projects that facilitate the discharge of individuals in hospitals or other acute care facilities who are in need of long-term care services and placement of such individuals into home- and community-based settings. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) eligibility to receive grants; (2) application requirements; (3) criteria for the award of grants; (4) use of, and limitations on, grants; and (5) evaluation and reports. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Provisions Relating to Medicare - Provides for the recapture of certain health care subsidies received by high-income individuals. Transfers such amounts to the Supplemental Medical Insurance Trust Fund. (Sec. 202) Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to impose a ten percent copayment on home health services. (Sec. 203) Reduces payments for capital-related costs for inpatient hospital services. (Sec. 204) Revises the payment formulae for ambulatory surgical center procedures and radiology services and diagnostic procedures. (Sec. 205) Reduces routine cost limits for home health services.

	</summary>
</bill>
