<bill session="103" type="s" number="2546" updated="2012-07-17T05:40:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Aviation Administration Independent Establishment Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the safety of air travel through a more effective Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404219"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14851-14852)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="5274" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Aeronautics"/>
		<term name="Air traffic"/>
		<term name="Airports"/>
		<term name="Aviation safety"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1994--Introduced.
Federal Aviation Administration Independent Establishment Act of 1994 - Establishes as an independent Federal agency the Federal Aviation Administration (Administration). Declares that the Administration shall be administered by an Administrator, who shall be appointed by the President to a five-year term, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Transfers to the new Administration all functions of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) of the Department of Transportation and of the Secretary of Transportation which are administered through the FAA. Directs the Administrator to prepare, and submit to specified congressional committees, a three-year development plan outlining goals and objectives for personnel, technology, and regulation in such areas as air traffic control, aviation standards, airport security, airport and airway development, and research and development. Establishes the Aviation Trust Fund Account (Account). Terminates the Airport and Airway Trust Fund on October 1, 1996, with all amounts to be transferred to the Account. Establishes the Federal Aviation Advisory Committee.

	</summary>
</bill>
