<bill session="103" type="s" number="255" updated="2012-07-17T04:36:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on Executive Organization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Commission on Executive Organization.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300017"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S895-896)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/><text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional Research Service"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/28/1993--Introduced.
Commission on Executive Organization Act - Establishes the Commission on Executive Organization to examine and make recommendations with respect to an effective and practicable organization of the executive branch. Requires the Commission to seek to reduce the total number of Federal employees by five percent within five years after the effective date of this Act. Requires the Commission to submit a report to the President describing its recommendations and legislative changes necessary to implement such recommendations. Requires the President to: (1) issue an Executive order implementing the recommendations made in the report; and (2) report to the Congress on the Commission's recommendations for legislation. Requires the Directors of the Congressional Research Service, the Congressional Budget Office, and the Office of Technology Assessment to submit to the Commission indices to, and synopses of, materials on executive organization useful to the Commission. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
