<bill session="103" type="s" number="2556" updated="2012-07-17T05:10:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the portability of validly executed advance directives, to provide patients with a better understanding of their health care choices, and to promote study of the quality of care for the gravely or terminally ill or injured, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403171"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Kidney diseases"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical ethics"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Right to die"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Terminal care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/1994--Introduced.
Provides for the portability among States of validly executed advance directives under Medicare and Medicaid provisions of the Social Security Act. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) and title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require written policies and procedures of service providers to provide for effective communication with individuals regarding relevant aspects of health care decisions affecting such individual, including obtaining informed consent, individual prognosis and treatment decisions, and the formulation of advance directives. Requires a report to the Congress on a study of issues relating to care at the end of life, including how to determine the application of medically necessary or appropriate care for gravely or terminally ill or injured persons. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
