<bill session="103" type="s" number="2555" updated="2012-07-17T04:12:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cooperative Units of Research in Infectious Disease (CURID) of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to establish Cooperative Units of Research in Infectious Diseases (CURID) to evaluate the potential etiology of chronic inflammatory diseases with emphasis upon arthritis and chronic lung disease.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14879)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Arthritis"/>
		<term name="Bacterial diseases"/>
		<term name="Communicable diseases"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Lung diseases"/>
		<term name="Medical laboratories"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Rheumatic fever"/>
		<term name="Rheumatism"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/1994--Introduced.
Cooperative Units of Research in Infectious Disease (CURID) Act of 1994 - Requires Infectious Disease Research and Clinical Units of Excellence to be established jointly by the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID) of the National Institutes of Health and the National Center for Infectious Diseases of the National Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Provides that the Units will be dedicated to finding the cause, prevention, and cure of chronic inflammatory diseases of suspected infectious etiology and committed to giving priority to diseases like arthritis and chronic lung disease which hold the most promise for beneficial research results. Requires the establishment of the Units to be based upon past research performance of researchers working on specific microorganisms. Makes the Units responsible for: (1) evaluation of patient specimens for the presence of infectious agents; (2) characterization of the immune response to these infectious agents; and (3) characterization of the genetic background of patients. Sets forth provisions regarding personnel, laboratory support, networking, and the initial period of grant funding. Makes NIAID the lead agency. Apportions responsibility for various aspects of the research program and development of a strategic research plan. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
