<bill session="103" type="s" number="2558" updated="2012-07-17T05:45:19-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">World War II Home Front Commemorative Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the World War II Home Front Council to reissue the World War II &quot;E&quot; award to the original recipients to commemorate the role of World War II Home Front veterans, including women, minorities, labor, and industry, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300094"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15037)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Anniversaries"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Defense industries"/>
		<term name="Flags"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Industrial production"/>
		<term name="Industrial productivity"/>
		<term name="Military history"/>
		<term name="Veterans in Congress"/>
		<term name="World War II"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/1994--Introduced.
World War II Home Front Commemorative Act - Authorizes the World War II Home Front Council to reissue the World War II &quot;E&quot; Award for Excellence in Industrial Production to individuals, firms, and businesses to which they were originally awarded in celebration of the 50th anniversary of the Allied victory in World War II. Directs the Council to: (1) establish the &quot;Excellence in Production Award Account&quot; to receive all proceeds derived from its activities to commemorate Home Front efforts; (2) implement Home Front education and commemoration programs; (3) establish a volunteer advisory committee; and (4) submit semi-annual status reports to the Congress. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
