<bill session="103" type="s" number="2569" updated="2012-07-17T04:07:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-12-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-12-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-12-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the United States from entering into any international agreement which would prevent full implementation of the United Nations moratorium on large-scale driftnet fishing on the high seas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300094"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1994-12-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-12-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15435-15436)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-12-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Driftnet fishing"/>
		<term name="Fishery agreements"/>
		<term name="Fishery products"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International fishery management"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/1/1994--Introduced.
High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act - Prohibits the United States from entering into any international agreement with respect to fisheries, marine resources, the use of the high seas, or trade in fish or fish products that would prevent full implementation of the global moratorium on large-scale driftnet fishing on the high seas, as such moratorium is expressed in a certain United Nations (U.N.) resolution. Directs the Secretary of State to seek to enhance the implementation and effectiveness of U.N. resolutions and decisions regarding the moratorium on large-scale driftnet fishing on the high seas through appropriate international agreements and organizations. Requires the President to utilize appropriate assets of the Federal government to detect, monitor, and prevent violations of such U.N. moratoriums.

	</summary>
</bill>
