<bill session="103" type="s" number="2562" updated="2012-07-17T04:27:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Succession Clarification Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify certain matters relating to Presidential succession.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15038)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Electoral college"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Presidential candidates"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Presidential succession"/>
		<term name="Vice Presidents"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/1994--Introduced.
Presidential Succession Clarification Act - Declares that for purposes of the 20th Amendment of the Constitution (with respect to presidential and vice presidential succession) a candidate for whom a majority of electors have cast their votes for President or Vice President shall be deemed to be &quot;President- elect&quot; or &quot;Vice President-elect&quot; from the time that the votes are cast, whether or not the candidate is living at the time the votes are counted in the Congress. Provides that if: (1) a major party candidate for the office of the President dies 14 or fewer days prior to the date specified for the appointment of electors of the President and Vice President, the electors shall be appointed in each State 14 days after the candidate's death; or (2) a leading candidate for the office of President dies 14 or fewer days prior to the date specified for the meeting of electors, the electors shall meet and give their votes 14 days after such candidate's death. Authorizes the House of Representatives, in the case of the death of any candidate from whom the House may choose a President after the right of choice has devolved upon them, to consider the designated running mate of the deceased candidate as the candidate's replacement for purposes of choosing a President. Permits the Senate, in the case of the death of any candidate from whom the Senate may choose the Vice President, to consider a candidate designated by the deceased candidate's political party as the candidate's replacement for purposes of choosing a Vice President.

	</summary>
</bill>
