<bill session="103" type="s" number="2561" updated="2012-07-17T04:32:45-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-08">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Programs Extension Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the extension of the Farmers Home Administration program under section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949 and other programs relating to housing and community development.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300010"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15038)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-08" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Apartment houses"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Boundaries"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
		<term name="Foreclosure"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing for the handicapped"/>
		<term name="Housing subsidies"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Low-income housing"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Public housing"/>
		<term name="Rent subsidies"/>
		<term name="Rental housing"/>
		<term name="Rural housing"/>
		<term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
		<term name="Texas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/1994--Introduced.
Housing Programs Extension Act of 1994 - Authorizes section 8 housing contract extensions and related displaced tenant assistance. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 to extend funding for the low-income housing preservation and ownership program. Amends the National Housing Act to extend authority to use rental assistance amounts for flexible subsidies. Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to extend authority for housing counseling programs. Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to extend set-asides for reconstruction of public housing for disabled families. Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to extend rural housing set asides for: (1) underserved areas; and (2) rental housing funds for nonprofit entities. Makes rural multifamily rental housing loan authority permanent. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to extend authority for the multifamily mortgage risk-sharing pilot program. Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to extend community development block grant set-asides for colonias.

	</summary>
</bill>
