<bill session="103" type="s" number="2564" updated="2012-07-17T04:48:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-11-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-11-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-11-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to delay the required implementation date for enhanced vehicle inspection and maintenance programs under the Clean Air Act and to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to reissue the regulations relating to the programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300049"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-11-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Automobile repair"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/30/1994--Introduced.
Provides that States will not be required to implement enhanced vehicle inspection and maintenance programs under the Clean Air Act prior to March 1, 1996. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to immediately rescind regulations relating to the operation of such programs on a centralized basis and issue new regulations to allow the operation of such programs on a centralized or decentralized basis at the option of each State. Prohibits, until the Administrator carries out such requirements, the imposition of sanctions for failures by States to implement such programs or specified adverse actions against States by the Administrator or the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration. Requires the Administrator to: (1) deem that emissions reductions calculated by States for inspection and maintenance under State implementation plans would be achieved as if the planned program had been implemented; or (2) consider the operation of the program on a decentralized basis as equivalent to operation on a centralized basis if the State demonstrates that such equivalency is reasonable.

	</summary>
</bill>
