<bill session="103" type="s" number="261" updated="2012-07-17T05:45:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Our Kids From Inhaling Deadly Smoke (PRO-KIDS) Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect children from exposure to environmental tobacco smoke in the provision of children's services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1993-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1993-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-02-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S917)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14742)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Passive smoking"/>
		<term name="Smoking"/>
		<term name="Smoking and youth"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/28/1993--Introduced.
Preventing Our Kids From Inhaling Deadly Smoke (PRO-KIDS) Act of 1993 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue guidelines for enforcing a nonsmoking policy at indoor facilities where children's services are provided. Requires such policy, at a minimum, to prohibit smoking in each portion of such a facility that is not ventilated separately. Directs the Administrator and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide technical assistance to persons who provide children's services and other persons who request it. Authorizes persons who make a good-faith effort to enforce a nonsmoking policy that meets requirements to petition their funding Federal agency for a waiver from the general requirements. Sets forth conditions for granting waivers, including that the person requesting the waiver will make a good-faith effort to enforce an alternative nonsmoking policy to protect children. Provides for special waivers for persons who provide children's services pursuant to certain collective bargaining agreements. Prescribes civil penalties for violations of this Act. Exempts from this Act's requirements registered persons providing children's services in a private residence to grandchildren, nieces, or nephews. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress on information concerning compliance with this Act and an assessment of the legal status of smoking in public places.

	</summary>
</bill>
