<bill session="103" type="s" number="262" updated="2012-07-17T06:05:03-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-28">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-28"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Smoking in Federal Buildings bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Our Federal Building Workers and Visitors From Exposure to Deadly Smoke (PRO-FEDS) Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate guidelines for instituting a nonsmoking policy in buildings owned or leased by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1993-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-02-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S917)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-28" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14742)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Air pollution control"/>
		<term name="Collective bargaining in government"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Courthouses"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Federal office buildings"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
		<term name="Passive smoking"/>
		<term name="Smoking"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/28/1993--Introduced.
Preventing Our Federal Building Workers and Visitors From Exposure to Deadly Smoke (PRO-FEDS) Act of 1993 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue guidelines for enforcing a nonsmoking policy at Federal agencies. Requires such policy, at a minimum, to prohibit smoking in each portion of a Federal building that is not ventilated separately. Directs the heads of Federal agencies, the Director of the Administrative Office of U.S. Courts, and specified entities of the legislative branch to adopt such a nonsmoking policy. Authorizes agencies to petition for a waiver from the general requirements if extenuating circumstances prevent enforcement and such agencies make a good-faith effort to enforce an alternative policy that will protect individuals from exposure to environmental tobacco smoke. Requires Federal agencies in which a labor organization has been accorded bargaining unit recognition to engage in collective bargaining to ensure implementation of requirements that affect work areas predominantly occupied by the organization's members. Exempts such work areas from the nonsmoking policy if the bargaining unit and the Federal agency have a collective bargaining agreement that includes provisions relating to smoking privileges that are in violation of this Act's requirements. Terminates such exemption on the earlier of the first expiration date of the agreement or one year after the date of issuance of the guidelines. Directs the Administrator and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide technical assistance to Federal agencies and other persons who request it. Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish an outreach program informing the public of the dangers of environmental tobacco smoke; (2) establish an Environmental Tobacco Smoke Advisory Office within the EPA Office of Radiation and Indoor Air; and (3) report to the Congress on compliance with this Act and an assessment of the legal status of smoking in public places.

	</summary>
</bill>
