<bill session="103" type="s" number="274" updated="2012-07-17T06:01:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Casa Malpais National Historical Park Establishment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Casa Malpais National Historic Park, in Springerville, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1036)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-15"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Archaeology"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/2/1993--Introduced.
Casa Malpais National Historical Park Establishment Act of 1993 - Establishes the Casa Malpais National Historical Park in Arizona as a unit of the National Park System, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior and the town of Springerville, Arizona. Directs the Secretary to submit a plan for the protection, preservation, interpretation, development, and maintenance of the site to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide technical assistance to Springerville for the site's management; (2) make grants to the town for annual costs of operation and maintenance; (3) enter into cooperative agreements for the management and interpretation of the Park; and (4) participate in, and provide technical assistance for, land use planning for lands adjacent to the Park. Directs the Secretary to submit a general management plan for the Park to the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs. Establishes the Casa Malpais National Historical Park Advisory Commission. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
