<bill session="103" type="s" number="278" updated="2012-07-17T04:09:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Chief Big Foot National Memorial Park and Wounded Knee National Memorial Establishment Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the establishment of the Chief Big Foot National Memorial Park and the Wounded Knee National Memorial in the State of South Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-02-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-02-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1041-1045)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-29"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-407.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="National monuments"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="South Dakota"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/2/1993--Introduced.
Chief Big Foot National Memorial Park and Wounded Knee National Memorial Establishment Act of 1993 - Establishes the Big Foot National Memorial Park in South Dakota to protect the historical significance of the 1890 Wounded Knee Massacre site and to protect and promote Sioux history and culture. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire lands for the Park by: (1) accepting leasehold interests in tribal trust lands located on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation and the Cheyenne River Indian Reservation offered by the Oglala Sioux Tribe and the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe, under specified conditions; and (2) purchase, donation, or condemnation of all surface and subsurface rights to any tract of fee patented land which the Director of the National Park Service deems necessary to include in the Park. Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to the Oglala Sioux Tribe in acquiring lands within the Wounded Knee Massacre site as defined in the 1990 boundaries studies authorized by the Service. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director, to manage such leasehold lands as a unit of the National Park System. Exempts all enrolled members of specified tribes from admission fees into the Park. Requires the Secretary to plan, design, and construct, within the boundaries of the Park, the Wounded Knee National Memorial dedicated to the Indian victims of the 1890 Wounded Knee Massacre. Establishes the Chief Big Foot National Memorial Park Advisory Commission. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with tribal organizations or nonprofit corporations to raise funds from private sources to supplement Federal funds authorized by this Act and or to raise private funds to plan, design, construct, operate, and maintain specified projects. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
