<bill session="103" type="s" number="288" updated="2012-07-17T04:48:55-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Capital Gains Tax Reduction bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Capital Gains Tax Fairness Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a reduction in the capital gains tax on individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1175-1176)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Capital gains tax"/>
		<term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
		<term name="Real property"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/3/1993--Introduced.
Capital Gains Tax Fairness Act of 1993 - Title I: Reduction in Capital Gains Tax for Individuals - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a reduction in the capital gains tax for individuals. Allows as a capital gains deduction an amount equal to the sum of: (1) the annual capital gains deduction, plus the lifetime capital gains deduction for nontradable property. Declares the annual capital gains deduction to be the lesser of the net capital gain or $1,000. Declares the lifetime capital gains deduction for nontradable property to be 50 percent of the qualified gain. Makes taxpayers whose incomes exceed $150,000 ineligible for such deduction. Bases the qualified gain on sales and exchanges on or after January 27, 1993. Title II: Depreciation Recapture - Revises provisions concerning the gain from dispositions of certain depreciabale realty to provide for the total amount of depreciation.

	</summary>
</bill>
