<bill session="103" type="s" number="294" updated="2012-07-17T05:55:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-07-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-07-21" where="s" result="pass" how="by Voice Vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Colonial New Mexico Commemorative Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Colonial New Mexico Commemorative Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Colonial New Mexico Commemorative Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to formulate a program for the research, interpretation, and preservation of various aspects of colonial New Mexico history, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1993-02-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1185, S1187)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-16"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-221.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-06-30"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. With written report No. 103-90.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="135" datetime="1993-07-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 135.</text></calendar>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-07-21" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASS_OVER:SENATE"><text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9178-9180"/></vote>
		<action datetime="1993-07-22T10:23:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-22"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-16"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-30"><committee name="House Committee on Natural Resources"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
		<committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="HSII-10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1561" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1561" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="Archaeology"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Colonial affairs"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Cultural centers"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="New Mexico"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Tourist trade"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/21/1993--Passed Senate amended. Colonial New Mexico Commemorative Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to prepare a comprehensive management plan to: (1) establish procedures for undertaking research relating to colonial New Mexico and a program for publication of research; (2) develop a survey to evaluate known resources and identify features that require additional study; (3) identify a core system of interpretive sites that would provide a comprehensive overview of the colonial New Mexico story; (4) prepare interpretive materials to address the colonial New Mexico story to be made available to the public; (5) recommend high priority sites that need protection and assistance; (6) prepare options for the management of priority New Mexico resources; (7) recommend highway routes that could be designated as colonial New Mexico tour routes; and (8) evaluate the feasibility of and need for developing commemorative centers in New Mexico. Requires the Secretary to: (1) award grants to tribal, governmental, and nongovernmental entities to conserve and protect structures, objects, and sites, and help support cultural events, that have significance in the commemoration of colonial New Mexico; and (2) prepare thematic nominations to the National Register of Historic Places of colonial sites and resources in New Mexico. Establishes the Colonial New Mexico Preservation Advisory Committee in the Department of the Interior. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) develop commemorative centers, operate educational programs, provide technical assistance, conduct cultural events, and prepare media materials; and (2) pay to the city of Espanola, New Mexico, the Federal share of planning and design of a cultural center as an element of Espanola Plaza. Directs the Secretary to undertake a special resource study of the major prehistoric and historic sites in the Galisteo Basin relating to colonial New Mexico. Authorizes appropriations. Redesignates the Masau Trail as the Pueblo Trail.

	</summary>
</bill>
