<bill session="103" type="s" number="299" updated="2012-07-17T05:34:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Abandoned Land Reuse Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to establish a program to demonstrate the benefits and feasibility of redeveloping or reusing abandoned or substantially underutilized land in economically and socially distressed communities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1993-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-02-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1191-1192)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05"><committee name="Committee on Banking"/><text>Committee on Banking. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-159.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2070" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Real property"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Depressed areas"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Factories"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Land use"/>
		<term name="Real estate development"/>
		<term name="Reclamation of land"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/3/1993--Introduced.
Abandoned Land Reuse Act of 1993 - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to add a new title designated as the Abandoned Land Reuse Act of 1993. Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to select appropriate States in which to carry out a program to provide grants to local community development organizations for programs to demonstrate: (1) the economic feasibility of the redevelopment or reuse of abandoned industrial or commercial property or facilities within the community; (2) the employment, economic, social, and other benefits to distressed local communities resulting from such redevelopment or reuse; (3) the beneficial impacts on community development and use of public resources of such redevelopment or reuse; and (4) the feasibility of timely and cooperative action between Federal, State, and local departments and agencies and private parties in the appropriate development or reuse of such land. Provides for: (1) the allocation of grant funds; (2) grant selection procedures; (3) site selections by State Governors; and (4) grant awards. Authorizes the Secretary to award a grant to a State in lieu of a local grantee in order to allow the State to conduct its own abandoned land redevelopment or reuse program. Provides for recovery of appropriate grant amounts if a State or local grantee fails to initiate and complete the redevelopment or reuse action within one year. Specifies criteria for selection of abandoned industrial or commercial sites for the program and for award allocation, including the degree of economic and social distress in the local community in which the site is located. Prohibits the awarding of a grant for a reuse action on a site that is federally controlled. Requires the Secretary to conduct and report to the Congress on an initial evaluation of the demonstration program using data collected from participants. Authorizes the Secretary to use up to five percent of the amounts appropriated to implement this title to fund technical assistance grants to local grantees to facilitate their participation in the demonstration program. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
