<bill session="103" type="s" number="301" updated="2012-07-17T05:30:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Trade Enforcement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revive and strenghten the &quot;Super 301&quot; authority of the United States Trade Representative to eliminate unfair trade barriers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="406084" joined="1993-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1993-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1993-05-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1503-1504,S1506-1507)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Balance of payments"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economic statistics"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Reciprocity"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/3/1993--Introduced.
Fair Trade Enforcement Act of 1993 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to make permanent the &quot;Super 301&quot; program which identifies certain trade priority practices. Requires the United States Trade Representative (USTR), not later than 60 days (currently 30 days) after the National Trade Estimates Report is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees, to identify as a priority practice: (1) any act, policy, or practice of a foreign country which constitutes a significant barrier to or distortion of U.S. exports of goods or services (including agricultural commodities and intellectual property) and U.S. foreign investment, and any other major barrier and trade distorting practice, the elimination of which is likely to have the most significant potential to increase U.S. exports; (2) any major barrier and trade distorting practice in the agricultural, manufacturing, and service sectors; and (3) the major barriers and trade distorting practices of each foreign country that accounted for at least 15 percent of any U.S. merchandise trade balance deficit for any calendar year (excluding trade petroleum imports), if such country also had a global current account surplus for such year in an amount equal to or greater than such deficit. Relieves the USTR of the duty to identify practices in either the agricultural, manufacturing, or services sector where the USTR certifies to the Congress for any calendar year that major barriers and trade distorting practices do not exist or have been eliminated. Requires the USTR, at the time such identification is made, to submit to specified congressional committees and publish in the Federal Register, a report which lists: (1) the identified priority practices; and (2) the estimated amount of U.S. exports lost as a result of such practices. Directs the USTR, upon identification of a priority practice or the adoption of a congressional resolution (according to specified procedures), to investigate whether U.S. rights under a trade agreement are being denied or a foreign country is conducting unfair trade practices. Requires the President, whenever a priority practice has been identified in cases where a trade dispute settlement cannot be resolved, to direct the USTR to take specified actions against such practices or submit to the Congress an alternative plan for their elimination. Provides for specified mandatory and discretionary authority for the USTR to take specified trade action against a foreign country whose acts, policies or practices threatens to burden or restrict U.S. commerce.

	</summary>
</bill>
