<bill session="103" type="s" number="320" updated="2012-07-17T04:24:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Unemployment Compensation, Reemployment, and Fairness Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for certain reforms with respect to unemployment programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411818"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1400-1401)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6759-6760)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Computers and government"/>
		<term name="Dislocated workers"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Employment agencies"/>
		<term name="Job hunting"/>
		<term name="Layoffs"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Unemployed"/>
		<term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
		<term name="Vocational guidance"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/1993--Introduced.
Unemployment Compensation, Reemployment, and Fairness Act of 1993 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow States to pay unemployment benefits to eligible individuals while they participate in qualified self-employment training programs. Amends the Social Security Act to require the State agency administering unemployment compensation to provide: (1) early reemployment review of unemployed workers; (2) technical and training program staff to assist with reemployment services; and (3) followup reevaluation and assistance to individuals participating in reemployment activities. Requires such agency to provide: (1) reemployment review information to other State employment and training program staff; and (2) job search and placement services, counseling, testing, occupational and labor market information, assessment, and referral to employers. Allows such agency to provide reemployment reviews and services for workers who have received notice of permanent layoff or impending layoff, or workers in occupations experiencing limited demand due to technological change, impact of imports, or plant closures. Amends the Social Security Act to require States to grant administrative hearings for employers with respect to their liability for paying unemployment taxes. Outlines the Secretary of Labor's administrative responsibilities under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
