<bill session="103" type="s" number="335" updated="2012-07-17T05:00:28-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-25">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-05-25" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emerging Telecommunications Technologies Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Emerging Telecommunications Technologies Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce to make additional frequencies available for commercial assignment in order to promote the development and use of new telecommunications technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1993-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300053" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="403171" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-03-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1437-1438,1441-1443)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Subcommittee on Communications. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-53.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-05-25"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-12-09"><text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings under the authority of the order of Nov 17, 93 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="344" datetime="1993-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 344.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2185)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="Communications" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="707" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Common carriers"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Cost control"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication policy"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/9/1993--Reported to Senate amended. Emerging Telecommunications Technologies Act of 1993 - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information and the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to conduct joint spectrum planning meetings with respect to: (1) future public and private use requirements and their allocations; and (2) promotion of efficient spectrum use. Requires the FCC to: (1) develop minority and small business opportunities; and (2) submit a study to the Congress on the spectrum needs of public safety agencies. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to identify bands of frequencies that are allocated on a primary basis for Federal use and those that may be reallocated to commercial users immediately or in the future. (Sec. 5) Directs the President to withdraw or limit the assignment of reallocable frequencies to the Federal Government, subject to substitution because of governmental, defense, or public health or safety needs. Authorizes Federal agency reimbursement for frequency displacement costs. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 6) Directs the FCC to issue frequency allocation and assignment rules. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the President to reclaim reassigned frequencies. (Sec. 8) Requires radio spectrum license competitive bidding through the earlier of FY 1998 or until license fees reach a specified level. Authorizes the FCC to use competitive bidding for such purposes. (Sec. 9) Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to treat a person engaged in the provision of commercial mobile services as a common carrier, with specified waivers. Continues to treat a person engaged in private land mobile service as not a common carrier. Sets forth related State regulatory authority and limits. (Sec. 10) Directs the FCC, within specified time periods, to: (1) issue final reports and orders with respect to two specified matters (ET Docket No. 92-9 and ET Docket No. 92-100); and (2) begin issuing personal communications service licenses and permits.

	</summary>
</bill>
