<bill session="103" type="s" number="338" updated="2012-07-17T05:53:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Petroleum Marketing Practices Act Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Petroleum Marketing Practices Act Amendments of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to clarify the Federal standards governing the termination and nonrenewal of franchises and franchise relationships for the sale of motor fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404219"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406487" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1993-05-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1445-1446)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-05"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Renewable Energy.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-36.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Energy, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Committee consideration held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-29"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. With written report No. 103-387. Additional and minority and supplemental views filed.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="693" datetime="1994-09-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 693.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Renewable Energy, Energy Efficiency, and Competitiveness" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1520" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Petroleum"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Contracts"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
		<term name="Gasoline"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Petroleum industry"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Service stations"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/1994--Reported to Senate amended. Petroleum Marketing Practices Act Amendments of 1993 - Amends the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to allow as grounds for nonrenewal of a franchise relationship the failure of the parties to agree to changes to the franchise provisions as long as such failure is not the result of the franchisor's insistence for the purpose of converting a franchisee operation into one operated by the franchisor's employees or agents (that is, turning the franchise into a company-owned station). Requires a franchisor that does not wish to exercise its underlying lease options to lease or purchase the marketing premises, to offer to assign them to the franchisee as a prerequisite to termination or nonrenewal of the franchise relationship. Bars a franchisor from requiring, as a condition of the franchise relationship, that the franchisee waive or release its rights under Federal or State law. Declares invalid and unenforceable any franchise provision which specifies that franchise interpretation or enforcement shall be governed by the law of any State other than the one in which the franchisee has its principal place of business. Prohibits a State or any political subdivision from implementing any law or regulation which requires payment for a franchisee's goodwill upon either termination or nonrenewal of a franchise. Permits State law to specify the terms and conditions under which a franchise or franchise relationship may be transferred to a franchisee's designated successor upon the franchisee's death. Amends the definition of &quot;failure&quot; to provide that it does not include any failure based on a provision of a franchise which is illegal or unenforceable under State law.

	</summary>
</bill>
