<bill session="103" type="s" number="345" updated="2012-07-17T06:11:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-05-20" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Library of Congress Fund Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Library of Congress Fund Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Library of Congress to provide certain information products and services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-02-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1459-1461)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-05-20"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Rules"/><text>Committee on Rules. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-05-26"><text>Committee on Rules. Reported to Senate by Senator Ford with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-50.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="75" datetime="1993-05-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 75.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Star Print ordered on on Senate Report 103-50.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Libraries"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Congressional Research Service"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional information resources"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional publications"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Library of Congress"/>
		<term name="Marketing"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
		<term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/26/1993--Reported to Senate amended. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Library Products and Services Title II: Library of Congress Revolving Fund for Specialized Products and Services Title III: General Standards and Limitations Library of Congress Fund Act of 1993 - Expresses the intent of the Congress that core Library of Congress services shall continue to be provided at no cost. Defines: (1) &quot;core library products and services&quot; as domestic interlibrary loan and information products and services customarily provided by libraries to users at no charge; and (2 ) &quot;specialized library products and services&quot; as specified customized information products and services that exceed core services, that are not national library products and services, and that are designed for individuals or discrete groups of persons or entities. Title I: Library Products and Services - Authorizes the Librarian of Congress to furnish national library products and services to institutions or individuals for a price that covers distribution costs. Requires the Librarian to report to the Joint Committee on the Library before establishing translation and foreign language services. Title II: Library of Congress Revolving Fund for Specialized Products and Services - Establishes the Library of Congress Revolving Fund to be available for specialized library information products and services. Authorizes the Librarian to furnish such products and services to institutions and individuals for purchase at a price covering production and distribution costs. Requires the Librarian to set fees to recover the costs of such products and services. Title III: General Standards and Limitations - Requires the Librarian to respect and preserve the security classification of any scientific or technical material in the possession or control of the Library. Requires the President to certify the classified status of items received as being essential in the interest of national defense. Declares that this Act shall not modify Federal copyright law. Prohibits: (1) the use of Congressional Research Service (CRS) resources to generate fee-based research and information services; or (2) the marketing or publication of CRS products without prior approval of either the Committee on House Administration or the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration. Requires the Library to follow rulemaking notification procedures of the Administrative Procedure Act when proposing new Fund service activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
