<bill session="103" type="s" number="371" updated="2012-07-17T04:26:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Interstate Banking and Branching Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for interstate banking and branching.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-02-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1612-1614)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Bank examination"/>
		<term name="Bank holding companies"/>
		<term name="Bank mergers"/>
		<term name="Branch banking"/>
		<term name="Community development"/>
		<term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
		<term name="Foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Interstate banking"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="Residence requirements"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/1993--Introduced.
Interstate Banking and Branching Act of 1993 - Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to authorize the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board (the Board) to approve applications by adequately managed and capitalized bank holding companies or subsidiaries to: (1) acquire banking interests across State lines; and (2) establish new banks across State lines. Permits a bank holding company to consolidate or merge its subsidiary banks (if the host State so permits). Amends Federal banking law to authorize the Comptroller of the Currency to approve interstate branching applications by national banks that are adequately managed and capitalized. Provides for State election to permit or prohibit interstate branching in express statutory language. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to permit interstate branching by insured State banks, subject to host State restrictions. Permits: (1) a host State's supervisory authority to examine such guest banks to determine compliance with its laws; (2) State compliance enforcement proceedings; (3) interstate cooperative agreements to facilitate State regulatory supervision; and (4) concurrent Federal regulatory authority over interstate banks. Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to set forth evaluation guidelines for branches of interstate banks. Amends the International Banking Act of 1978 to permit interstate banking operations by foreign banks. Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to set forth guidelines for the use of names by interstate banks.

	</summary>
</bill>
