<bill session="103" type="s" number="384" updated="2012-07-17T05:57:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-09-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-09-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Loan Securitization and Secondary Market Enhancement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the availability of credit to small businesses by eliminating impediments to securitization and facilitating the development of a secondary market in small business loans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403142"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300159" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="411271" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-02-24" withdrawn="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="403171" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-02-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1993-02-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1742-1744)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><committee name="Committee on Banking"/><text>Subcommittee on Securities. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-77.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06" state="REPORTED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5570-5571)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-09" state="REFERRED"><text>Committee on Banking. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-294.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-09-21"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Banking. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 1275 ordered to be reported.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSBK-4" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Securities" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1086" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="s" number="1275" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Bank capital"/>
		<term name="Bank loans"/>
		<term name="Brokers"/>
		<term name="Credit unions"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Loans"/>
		<term name="Margins (Security trading)"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Promissory notes"/>
		<term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
		<term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
		<term name="Securities regulation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/17/1993--Introduced.
Small Business Loan Securitization and Secondary Market Enhancement Act of 1993 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to define a &quot;small business related security&quot; (SBRS) as generally a high rated security that represents and is secured by promissory notes evidencing and that provides for payments of principal in relation to payments on the notes. Provides that SBRSs shall be exempt from: (1) certain restrictions in the margin and securities delivery rules; (2) certain restrictions on borrowing on securities by and lending among, brokers, dealers, and other members of national securities exchanges; and (3) certain prohibitions on the extension of credit by members of exchanges, brokers, and dealers against a security which was part of a new issue. Amends the Home Owners' Loan Act, the Federal Credit Union Act, and related statutes to allow banks, credit unions, and other depository institutions to invest in SBRSs. Amends the Secondary Mortgage Market Enhancement Act of 1984 to: (1) authorize any U.S. person or entity to invest in SBRS, to the same extent such person is authorized to invest in U.S. obligations issued; and (2) exempt SBRSs from any State law's security registration and qualification to the same extent that U.S. securities are so exempt. Provides for States to enact provisions prescribing specific requirement for SBRSs. Requires the accounting principles applicable to the transfer of a small business loan with recourse contained in reports or statements required by appropriate Federal banking agencies to be uniform and consistent with generally accepted accounting principles. Prohibits the amount of capital required to be maintained by a depository institution with respect to the sale of a small business loan with recourse from exceeding an amount sufficient to meet the institution's reasonable estimated liability under the recourse arrangement. Requires an SBRS to be treated as a mortgage-backed security under the risk-based capital requirements applicable to insured depository institutions. Directs the Secretary of Labor to exclude transactions involving SBRSs from certain restrictions and taxes imposed on &quot;prohibited transactions&quot; under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code (thereby allowing pension fund managers to participate in the pooling and packaging of small business loans for sale as securities). Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to promulgate regulations providing for the taxation of a small business loan investment conduit and the holder of an interest therein in a manner similar to the taxation of a real estate mortgage investment conduit and the holder of an interest therein under the Internal Revenue Code.

	</summary>
</bill>
