<bill session="103" type="s" number="387" updated="2012-07-17T06:15:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Life Patenting Moratorium Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 35, United States Code, to impose a 2-year moratorium on the patenting of certain human tissues and organs, on human gene cells and on animal organisms, in order to provide time for Congress to fully assess, consider and respond to the economic, environmental and ethical issues raised by the patenting of such entities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405212"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Patents, Copyrights and Trademarks.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Patents, Copyrights and Trademarks" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Patents"/>
		<term name="Animal genetics"/>
		<term name="Biotechnology"/>
		<term name="Genetic engineering"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Human genetics"/>
		<term name="International cooperation in science"/>
		<term name="Inventions"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Protection of animals"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/18/1993--Introduced.
Life Patenting Moratorium Act of 1993 - Amends Federal patent law to prohibit human beings, organs, or organ subparts or genetically engineered animals from being considered patentable subject matter. Imposes a two-year moratorium on the patentability of human tissues, fluids, cells, genes or gene sequences, or animals or animal organisms (genetically engineered or otherwise). Authorizes the continuation of such moratorium after such time pursuant to the Public Health Service Act. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) legislation addressing the implications of genetic research should be thoroughly studied and passed by the Congress as soon as possible; and (2) the Departments of Commerce and State and the National Institutes of Health should work with the international community to develop international standards relating to the patenting of, and access to, genetic information.

	</summary>
</bill>
