<bill session="103" type="s" number="389" updated="2012-07-17T04:11:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Aboveground Storage Tank Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to regulate above-ground storage tanks used to store regulated substances, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1889-1890)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Inventories"/>
		<term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
		<term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Petroleum storage"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Pollution liability insurance"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/18/1993--Introduced.
Aboveground Storage Tank Act of 1993 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to regulate aboveground storage tanks used to store regulated substances. Requires owners of such tanks to provide State or local authorities with all relevant particulars about such tanks, including age, size, type, location, and uses. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to issue notification and performance standards for such tanks. Requires the State to inventory all such tanks containing regulated substances, one inventory for petroleum, and another for all other regulated substances. Requires the Administrator to issue release detection, prevention, and correction regulations, including requirements for leak detection systems, reporting, release prevention, closure, upgrades, and evidence of financial responsibility. Permits corrective actions by the Administrator or State to protect human health and the environment, but makes owners or operators of tanks liable for costs. Authorizes States to conduct Administrator-approved programs to enforce this Act. Directs the Administrator to provide technical assistance to States, local governments, and owners and operators to assist in compliance with State programs. Sets forth authorized actions when a facility owner or operator has not complied with or cannot meet financial responsibility requirements. Requires owners or operators of tanks to furnish the relevant government employees with all necessary information, including submitting their facilities to inspection and monitoring. Provides for confidentiality of such information and criminal penalties for prohibited disclosure. Authorizes the use of compliance orders to enforce this Act, providing daily civil penalties for noncompliance. Includes tanks under Federal jurisdiction under this Act, permitting exemptions of up to one year upon the President's specific request. Requires that all exemptions be reported annually to the Congress. Directs the Administrator to study and report to the Congress on aboveground storage tanks used for both the storage of petroleum and of other regulated substances. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
