<bill session="103" type="s" number="407" updated="2012-07-17T04:28:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Commission on School Finance to Meet the National Education Goals Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a National Commission on School Finance To Meet the National Education Goals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-02-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1911-1912)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Educational equalization"/>
		<term name="Educational finance"/>
		<term name="Educational innovations"/>
		<term name="Educational planning"/>
		<term name="Educational policy"/>
		<term name="Educational research"/>
		<term name="Educational statistics"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="State aid to education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/18/1993--Introduced.
National Commission on School Finance to Meet the National Education Goals Act - Establishes the National Commission on School Finance to Meet the National Education Goals (the Commission), as an independent agency in the executive branch. Directs the Commission to: (1) study and report to the Congress on the research on innovations in practice to determine what will be necessary (including cost implications) to achieve the National Education Goals; (2) investigate the extent to which there is a Federal policy on educational equity of resources, Federal education laws promote such policy, there are alternatives to current school finance mechanisms, and schools and States can finance the reform demands implied in such goals; and (3) synthesize and evaluate existing information in specified areas relating to educational need-analysis, school finance, and educational program and cost data-gathering. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
