<bill session="103" type="s" number="410" updated="2012-07-17T04:44:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Agricultural Resources Management Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish within the Bureau of Indian Affairs a program to improve the management of rangelands and farmlands and the production of agricultural resources on Indian lands, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-02-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-02-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1915)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Native Americans"/>
		<term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural education"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Community colleges"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Continuing education"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Education of Indians"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental education"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Farm lands"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Government internships"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Indian economic development"/>
		<term name="Indian lands"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Minority employment"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Range management"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Student employment"/>
		<term name="Student loan funds"/>
		<term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/18/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Rangeland and Farmland Enhancement Title III: Education in Agriculture and Natural Resource Management Title IV: Authorization of Appropriations Title V: Miscellaneous Indian Agricultural Resources Management Act of 1993 - Title I: General Provisions - States that existing Federal laws do not sufficiently assure the adequate and necessary trust management of Indian rangelands and farmlands. Title II: Rangeland and Farmland Enhancement - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage Indian rangelands and farmlands, either directly or through cooperative agreements, self-determination contracts, and grants under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act. Requires a reservation-by-reservation resource management planning program. Requires the Secretary's recognition of tribal governments for purposes of their participation in such land management activities. Requires compliance with tribal laws pertaining to Indian agricultural lands. Directs the Secretary to assemble a task force to develop a comparative analysis of Federal investment and management efforts for Indian trust lands as compared to federally owned lands managed by other Federal agencies. Authorizes the Secretary to approve leasing of Indian rangelands or farmlands under specified conditions. Sets forth rights of individual land owners. Title III: Education in Agriculture and Natural Resource Management - Requires the establishment, in the Bureau of Indian Affairs or elsewhere, of at least 20 natural resources intern positions for Indians and Alaska Native students. Requires establishment of a cooperative education program for employment of Indian and Alaska Native students in Federal professional natural resource-related positions. Authorizes a scholarship program and requires outreach programs, postgraduate recruitment programs, education and training programs, and internships to attract and train Indians and Alaska Natives in careers in Indian natural resources management. Authorizes cooperative agreements between the Department of the Interior and Indian tribes for: (1) manpower and job training; (2) environmental education and natural resources planning materials development and publication; and (3) land and natural resource management and development activities. Title IV: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations. Title V: Miscellaneous - Provides for regulations and severability of this Act. Prohibits construing this Act as diminishing or expanding U.S. trust responsibility.

	</summary>
</bill>
