<bill session="103" type="s" number="415" updated="2012-07-17T05:02:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Boot Camp Prison Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Attorney General to establish 10 military-style boot camp prisons.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401604"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="403171" joined="1993-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-04-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2001-2002)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Corrections"/>
		<term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Military bases"/>
		<term name="Military training camps"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Prison overcrowding"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/24/1993--Introduced.
Boot Camp Prison Act of 1993 - Directs the Attorney General to establish within the Bureau of Prisons ten military-style boot camp prisons on closed military installations to provide: (1) a highly regimented schedule of strict discipline, physical training, work, drill, and ceremony characteristic of military basic training; (2) remedial education; (3) counseling as appropriate; and (4) treatment for substance abuse. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) capacity of such camps; (2) eligibility requirements for Federal and State prisoners; (3) post-release supervision (including aftercare, with provision for educational and vocational training and drug or other counseling and treatment where appropriate); and (4) termination of the program. Directs the Attorney General to evaluate the boot camp prisons and report to the Congress on their performance, including an assessment of the rate of recidivism of boot camp prisoners as compared with similar defendants in conventional prisons, the cost effectiveness of boot camp prisons as compared to conventional prisons, and the program's effect on the overcrowding of conventional prisons. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
