<bill session="103" type="s" number="436" updated="2012-07-17T05:56:18-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Efficiency Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a Special Assistant to the President to conduct a Federal performance audit and review, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406487"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2090-2091)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11"><committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/><text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Auditing"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="Management audit"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
Federal Efficiency Improvement Act of 1993 - Requires the President to appoint a Special Assistant (SA) for the Improvement of Federal Efficiency to serve within the Executive Office of the President. Requires the SA to conduct a Federal performance audit and review (FPAR) and report to the President and the Congress on: (1) ways to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of Federal programs or activities. Requires the SA to: (1) propose savings by restructuring incentives to motivate Federal employees; (2) propose actions to improve the efficiency and quality of services delivered and restructure Government organization to provide for long-term efficiency and savings; (3) establish a special team to study Government-wide issues such as procurement and personnel; (4) establish a telephone line for public comment and hold regional public meetings to increase public input; and (5) study ways to improve the effectiveness and to increase the independence of Inspectors General in executive agencies. Requires the President to submit any budget authority rescissions necessary to implement FPAR recommendations.

	</summary>
</bill>
