<bill session="103" type="s" number="439" updated="2012-07-17T06:00:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Interstate Transportation of Municipal Waste Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to permit Governors to limit the disposal of out-of-State solid waste in their States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402675"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="409580" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="1993-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="404219" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1993-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2093-2094)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Groundwater"/>
		<term name="Incineration"/>
		<term name="Interstate relations"/>
		<term name="Landfills"/>
		<term name="Municipal services"/>
		<term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="State-local relations"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
Interstate Transportation of Municipal Waste Act of 1993 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to authorize a State Governor, if requested by an affected local government and a local solid waste planning unit, to prohibit the disposal of out-of-State municipal waste in: (1) any landfill or incinerator subject to the jurisdiction of the Governor or the affected local government; and (2) landfill cells that do not meet the design and location standards and leachate collection and groundwater monitoring requirements of State law in effect on January 1, 1993, for new landfills. Permits such Governors, without the request of such entities, to limit the quantity of out-of-State municipal waste received for disposal, or disposal of such waste, at landfills covered by exceptions under this Act. Prohibits discrimination against any particular landfill and against shipments of out-of-State waste on the basis of State of origin with respect to limitations and responses to requests by local governments. Exempts from a Governor's authority to prohibit the disposal of out-of-State waste: (1) landfills that received documented shipments of such waste in 1991 and are in compliance with State laws relating to design and location standards, leachate collection, groundwater monitoring, and financial assurance for closure and post-closure and corrective action; (2) proposed landfills that, prior to January 1, 1993, received approval from the affected local government to receive municipal waste generated outside of the county or State and a State notice of decision to grant a construction permit; or (3) incinerators that received documented shipments of such waste during 1991 and are in compliance with performance standards under the Clean Air Act and State laws relating to facility design and operations.

	</summary>
</bill>
