<bill session="103" type="s" number="44" updated="2012-07-17T05:48:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit any person who is being compensated for lobbying the Federal Government from being paid on a contingency fee basis.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300157"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S449-450)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Collection of accounts"/>
		<term name="Federal aid programs"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Limitation of actions"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit any person from making any oral or written communication, with intent to influence, to any Federal agency, commission, House of Congress, or court on behalf of anyone other than the United States for compensation if such compensation has knowingly been made dependent upon: (1) any action of the Congress or the passage or defeat of legislation; or (2) the securing or the denial of a Federal grant or contract or other Federal financial assistance. Exempts lobbying to collect a debt or claim owed by the Government. Sets forth criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Authorizes the Attorney General to bring a civil action to enforce this Act and to recover twice the amount of proceeds obtained due to prohibited conduct. Establishes a six-year statute of limitations for such actions.

	</summary>
</bill>
