<bill session="103" type="s" number="441" updated="2012-07-17T04:14:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide a mandatory minimum sentence for the unlawful possession of a firearm by a convicted felon, a fugitive from justice, a person who is addicted to, or an unlawful user of, a controlled substance, or a transferor or receiver of a stolen firearm, to increase the general penalty for a violation of Federal firearms laws, and to increase the enhanced penalties provided for the possession of a firearm in connection with a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300017"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2105)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Ex-offenders"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
		<term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to require a minimum sentence of five years' imprisonment for the unlawful possession of a firearm by any person who: (1) has been convicted of a crime punishable by more than one year's imprisonment; (2) is a fugitive from justice; (3) is an unlawful user of or addicted to any controlled substance; (4) has transported in interstate commerce any stolen firearm; or (5) has received any stolen firearm. Increases from $5,000 to $10,000 and from five years to ten years the fine and term of imprisonment, respectively, for violation of Federal firearm laws. Increases the penalties for possession of a firearm in connection with a crime of violence or drug trafficking.

	</summary>
</bill>
