<bill session="103" type="s" number="443" updated="2012-07-17T05:31:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hazardous Waste Facilities Siting Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act and the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to make improvements in capacity planning processes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300092"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2107-2108)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Advertising"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Newspapers"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
		<term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
Hazardous Waste Facilities Siting Act of 1993 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require permit applications for the proposed construction of hazardous waste facilities to contain assurances that certain procedures concerning public notification and hearings, establishment of host community advisory committees, site analyses and findings of need, and requests for siting permission have been carried out. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, upon the request of an applicant, to establish a host community advisory committee. Requires the Administrator to establish a host community advisory committee assistance grant program. Authorizes appropriations. Prohibits the issuance of permits for new hazardous waste disposal facilities if the Administrator determines that a facility could cause the State to exceed its capacity needs, unless the State cannot fulfill capacity requirements under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (CERCLA). Prohibits a facility, as a permit condition, from managing hazardous waste generated outside of the State unless the the owner or operator enters into an agreement with the host community. Amends CERCLA to direct the Administrator to: (1) establish guidelines for the gathering of capacity assurance reporting data; and (2) require any State that documented a capacity shortfall in a quantity exceeding 50,000 tons per year or that is a net exporter of hazardous waste to submit specified information. Prescribes civil penalties for failures to submit such information. Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish guidelines for the inclusion of toxic chemical release information assurance data required under CERCLA; (2) develop a model capacity assurance plan to assist States; and (3) publish a statement concerning whether the United States has adequate capacity to treat and dispose of hazardous waste during the 20-year period following the statement's publication.

	</summary>
</bill>
