<bill session="103" type="s" number="447" updated="2012-07-17T06:23:14-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Insular Areas Policy Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the development of Federal policies with respect to those territories under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411271" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1993-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2115-2117)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-09-24"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
Insular Areas Policy Act - Establishes an Insular Areas Policy Council to coordinate the actions of the Federal Government with respect to the insular areas. Directs the Council to: (1) review the activities of Federal agencies with respect to the insular areas; (2) identify Federal funding priorities with respect to such areas; (3) review the &quot;State of the Islands&quot; report; and (4) determine the appropriate role of such areas in U.S. domestic and foreign policy and the effects of such policies on those areas. Requires the President to transmit a &quot;State of the Islands&quot; report to specified congressional committees that shall include data summarizing social, economic, and political conditions, a statement of current policy issues, foreseeable future developments, and recommended policy objectives for each of the insular areas. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) provide Federal agencies with assistance necessary to structure Federal programs or laws affecting insular areas to further the objectives of such programs or laws and prevent adverse impacts; (2) inform local governments of such areas of any Federal action which would affect such areas and solicit their comments and recommendations regarding such actions; and (3) assist in the development of priorities for, and levels of, Federal assistance for such areas. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
