<bill session="103" type="s" number="45" updated="2012-07-17T06:31:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protection Against Terrorism Act of 1991</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorism Death Penalty Act of 1991</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Alien Removal Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish constitutional procedures for the imposition of the death penalty for terrorist murders and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300157"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-03-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S450-451)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1238" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Aliens"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Capital punishment"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Correctional personnel"/>
		<term name="Counterintelligence"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure"/>
		<term name="Deportation"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
		<term name="Espionage"/>
		<term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
		<term name="Exclusionary rule (Evidence)"/>
		<term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Habeas corpus"/>
		<term name="Homicide"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Information leaking"/>
		<term name="Judicial review"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
		<term name="Wiretapping"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: &quot;Terrorism Death Penalty Act of 1991&quot; Title II: Terrorist Alien Removal Title III: Counterintelligence Access to Telephone Toll and Transactional Records Protection Against Terrorism Act of 1991 (sic) - Title I: Terrorism Death Penalty Act of 1991 - Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize the imposition of the death penalty upon any individual who kills a person while inside the United States, or kills a U.S. national while such national is outside the United States, if the killing is a first degree murder. Makes penalties with respect to homicide, attempt or conspiracy to commit homicide, and engaging in physical violence with the intent or result of causing serious bodily harm applicable to persons inside the United States or U.S. nationals while outside the United States. (Current law only applies where such person was a U.S. national.) Increases penalties for: (1) killings other than first degree murders; and (2) attempted murder and for engaging in physical violence with the intent or result of causing serious bodily harm. Title II: Terrorist Alien Removal - Terrorist Alien Removal Act of 1993 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make terrorist activity (as defined by this Act) grounds for deportation. Establishes removal procedures for alien terrorists, including a special removal hearing. Includes as excludable aliens those with respect to whom an appropriate consular officer or the Attorney General knows or has reasonable ground to believe are engaging in, have engaged in, or probably would, after entry, engage in terrorist activity. Grants exclusive jurisdiction to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit to review excludability orders. Provides for a ten-year prison sentence, to run concurrently with any other sentence, and a fine, for entering (or attempting to enter) the United States subsequent to exclusion or removal. Title III: Counterintelligence Access to Telephone Toll and Transactional Records - Authorizes the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to obtain (after submitting a written request) from a wire or electronic communications service provider subscriber information regarding a person or entity which is relevant to an authorized foreign counterintelligence investigation.

	</summary>
</bill>
