<bill session="103" type="s" number="451" updated="2012-07-17T06:09:41-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Triad Program Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish research, development, and dissemination programs to assist in collaborative efforts to prevent crime against senior citizens, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="404219" joined="1993-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1993-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2118-2120)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation in crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Criminal statistics"/>
		<term name="Elder abuse"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Public service advertising"/>
		<term name="Research"/>
		<term name="Social work"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
National Triad Program Act - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Justice to conduct a qualitative and quantitative national assessment of: (1) the nature and extent of crimes committed against senior citizens and the effect of such crimes on the victims; (2) the numbers, extent, and impact of violent and nonviolent crimes against senior citizens and the extent of unreported crime; (3) the collaborative needs of law enforcement, health, and social service organizations, focusing on prevention of crimes against senior citizens, to identify, investigate, and provide assistance to victims of such crimes; and (4) the development and growth of strategies to respond effectively] to such matters. Directs the Director to make grants to coalitions of local law enforcement agencies and senior citizens to assist in the development of programs and execute field tests of particularly promising strategies for crime prevention and related services, based on the concepts of the Triad model (which generally calls for the participation of the sheriff, at least one police chief, and a representative of at least one senior citizens' organization within a county) which can then be evaluated and serve as the basis for further demonstration and education programs. Requires the Director to make awards to: (1) organizations with demonstrated ability to provide training and technical assistance in establishing crime prevention programs based on the Triad model, for purposes of aiding in the establishment and expansion of pilot programs; (2) research organizations to evaluate the effectiveness of selected pilot programs, and to conduct research and development identified as being critical; and (3) public service advertising coalitions to increase public awareness of, and promote ideas or programs to prevent, crimes against senior citizens. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
