<bill session="103" type="s" number="459" updated="2012-07-17T06:24:51-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Forests Health Recovery Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to arrest the decline in, and promote the restoration of, the health of forest ecosystems on Federal lands, to reduce the escalating risk to human safety posed by potentially catastrophic wildfires on Federal lands, to require the Secretary of the Interior to establish a special fund for Bureau of Land Management activities in furtherance of forest health, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408420"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-04-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2140-2143)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-26"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Agriculture, Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Forests and forestry"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Forest conservation"/>
		<term name="Forest ecology"/>
		<term name="Forest management"/>
		<term name="Forest products"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Oregon"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Timber sales"/>
		<term name="Trees"/>
		<term name="Washington State"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
Federal Forests Health Recovery Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (or, with respect to specified lands, the Secretary of Agriculture) to prepare for and undertake or authorize forest health activities to: (1) arrest the deterioration in the health of forests and forest ecosystems on Federal lands; (2) restore and maintain the health of the forests and forest ecosystems that have suffered deteriorated health conditions; or (3) ensure the public safety that is threatened by the deteriorating health of the forests and forest ecosystems. Authorizes the Secretary to offer and award a timber sale as a forest health activity if the sale meets one or more of such objectives. Specifies that no sale shall be precluded because the anticipated total costs of the sale are greater than the anticipated revenues. Requires the Secretary to provide to the public a detailed statement of the determination that the activity meets one or more objective whenever the harvest of live trees is likely to occur in carrying out a forest health activity. Establishes in the Treasury a special fund to be used for forest health activities, activities to maintain healthy forests and forest ecosystems (including tree planting), and other specified activities. Provides for funding of specified Forest Service activities. Specifies that a forest health activity that is not inconsistent with the long-term management goals and objectives of a land management plan for the relevant unit of Federal lands shall not be deemed to be a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Establishes procedures for administrative and district court review of forest health activities. Sets forth provisions regarding budget disclosures, the establishment of advisory boards, and monitoring and reporting requirements.

	</summary>
</bill>
