<bill session="103" type="s" number="467" updated="2012-07-17T05:49:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-02-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Disaster Tax Relief Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax relief for certain disaster victims, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400562"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="406084" joined="1993-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2150)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Capital gains tax"/>
		<term name="Disaster insurance"/>
		<term name="Disaster relief"/>
		<term name="Disasters"/>
		<term name="Farmers"/>
		<term name="Florida"/>
		<term name="Guam"/>
		<term name="Hawaii"/>
		<term name="Home ownership"/>
		<term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Hurricanes"/>
		<term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
		<term name="Losses"/>
		<term name="Louisiana"/>
		<term name="Low-income housing"/>
		<term name="Mortgage loans"/>
		<term name="Property insurance"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Storms"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax penalties"/>
		<term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/1993--Introduced.
Natural Disaster Tax Relief Act of 1993 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow penalty-free distributions from individual retirement plans to pay acquisition costs to replace a principal residence that was destroyed or substantially damaged by the disasters Hurricane Andrew, Hurricane Iniki, or Typhoon Omar. Allows a farmer who has income derived from the sale or exchange of crops grown in such disaster areas, to elect to defer such income for the next taxable year. Provides a special rule for the self-employment tax. Requires the nonrecognition of gain of insurance proceeds for the contents of principal residences compulsorily or involuntarily converted as a result of a presidentially-declared disaster. Allows insurance proceeds from personal property and real property to be lumped together into one common fund. Extends the time to replace a principal residence so converted from two years to four years. Waives certain requirements with respect to low-income housing in areas damaged by the disasters Hurricane Andrew, Hurricane Iniki, or Typhoon Omar. Waives the dollar limitation for home improvement loans through mortgage revenue bonds for residences in such disaster areas.

	</summary>
</bill>
