<bill session="103" type="s" number="470" updated="2012-07-17T06:09:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-02">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 41 of title 18, United States Code, to punish stalking.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406487" joined="1993-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1993-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-03-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-09-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2211)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee on Judiciary. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Assault"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Ex-offenders"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Interstate commerce"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Prosecution"/>
		<term name="Recidivists"/>
		<term name="Stalking"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/2/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to establish penalties with respect to a person who: (1) in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, in the course of interstate travel, or by the use of an instrument of interstate or foreign commerce, harasses or makes a credible threat against another person; (2) under a protection order engages in such conduct; and (3) with a prior stalking conviction engages in such conduct. Prohibits an offense within the jurisdiction of a State from being prosecuted by the United States under such provisions unless the Attorney General (or the highest ranking subordinate of the Attorney General with responsibility for criminal prosecutions) makes a written determination that the offender will not be expeditiously or effectively prosecuted under State law. Requires as a condition of probation granted to an offender under such provisions that the offender participate in counseling, unless the court finds that counseling is not necessary. Requires a court to consider issuing an order enjoining an offender from any contact with the victim for a period of up to ten years.

	</summary>
</bill>
