<bill session="103" type="s" number="471" updated="2012-07-17T06:01:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-09-21">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-09-21" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">New Parks Study Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Park System Reform Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a new area study process for proposed additions to the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411271"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2211-2212)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-02" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-04-25"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-05-05"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-748.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-09-21"  state="REPORTED"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-09-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="640" datetime="1994-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 640.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="3709" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Parks"/>
		<term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Ecosystem management"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Historic sites"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Industrialization"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Sports and recreation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/1994--Reported to Senate amended. National Park System Reform Act of 1994 - Title I: National Park Systems Plan - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to prepare a National Park System (NPS) Plan to guide the direction of the NPS into the next century, including: (1) a statement of goals and objectives for use in defining the mission and role of the NPS; (2) detailed criteria to be used in determining which natural and cultural resources are appropriate for inclusion as NPS units; (3) identification of what constitutes adequate representation of a particular resource type and which aspects of the national heritage are adequately represented in the existing NPS or in other protected areas; (4) identification of appropriate aspects of the national heritage not currently represented; (5) priorities of the themes and types of resources which should be added to the NPS; and (6) a statement of the role of the NPS with respect to such topics as preservation of natural areas, ecosystems, industrial America, and cultural resources and provision of outdoor recreation non-physical opportunities; and (7) a statement of what areas constitute NPS units and the distinction between such units, affiliated areas, and other areas within the system. Establishes a National Park System Review Commission to review the existing NPS to determine whether there are more appropriate alternatives for managing specific units or portions of units within the NPS. Title II: New Area Establishment - Directs the Secretary: (1) to submit to specified congressional committees a list of areas recommended for study for potential inclusion in the NPS; (2) in developing such list, to give consideration to those areas that have the greatest potential to meet the established criteria of national significance, suitability, and feasibility and special consideration to themes, sites, and resources not already adequately represented in the NPS as identified in the NPS Plan; (3) to complete each such study provided for by law within three complete fiscal years after considering whether the area possesses nationally significant natural or cultural resources or outstanding recreational opportunities representing one of the most important examples of a particular resource type in the country and is a suitable and feasible addition to the NPS; and (4) to submit to specified congressional committees at the beginning of each calendar year a list of areas previously studied in numerical order of priority for addition to the NPS. Prohibits any study of the potential of an area for inclusion in the NPS from being initiated after the date of enactment of this title, except as provided by specific authorization of an Act of Congress.

	</summary>
</bill>
