<bill session="103" type="s" number="489" updated="2012-07-17T04:10:02-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the &quot;Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-03-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2321-2322)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-09"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Agriculture, Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-15"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Agriculture, Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-21"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered favorably reported H.R. 873 in lieu of this measure.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSEG-4" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="873" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Easements"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Mineral reserves"/>
		<term name="Montana"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
Gallatin Range Consolidation and Protection Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire, by exchange and cash equalization, specified lands and interests along the Gallatin Range north of Yellowstone National Park, including lands: (1) in and adjacent to the Hyalite-Porcupine-Buffalo Horn Wilderness Study Area, the Scapegoat Wilderness Area, and other land in the Gallatin National Forest from the Plum Creek Timber Company; and (2) in the Porcupine Area, the Taylor Fork Area, and other land within the Gallatin Range from Big Sky Lumber Company. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary, pursuant to an agreement with Burlington Resources, Incorporated, to acquire mineral interests owned by Burlington underlying surface lands owned by the United States and located within the Gallatin Area. Requires such acquisition to be made through exchange to Burlington of other federally owned mining interests that the parties may agree to. Requires consultation with the Secretary of the Interior prior to such exchange.

	</summary>
</bill>
