<bill session="103" type="s" number="490" updated="2012-07-17T05:12:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Flexibility Amendments Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to clarify procedures for judicial review of Federal agency compliance with regulatory flexibility analysis requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2323-2325)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="830" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
		<term name="Parties to actions"/>
		<term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
Regulatory Flexibility Amendments Act of 1993 - Amends Federal law to eliminate provisions respecting judicial review of Federal agency compliance with regulatory flexibility analysis requirements. Requires an agency to consider the direct and indirect effects of a rule in determining whether or not it is likely to have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities. Sets forth guidelines governing agency transmittal of proposed rules to the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration. Authorizes such official to transmit to the agency a statement of opposition to the proposed rule. Requires publication of such statement and the agency's response in the Federal Register. Expresses the sense of the Congress that such official should be permitted to appear as amicus curiae in any action or case brought in a U.S. court for the purpose of reviewing a rule.

	</summary>
</bill>
