<bill session="103" type="s" number="495" updated="2012-07-17T05:16:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Care Public-Private Partnership Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program to provide child care through public-private partnerships, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1993-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-03-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2355)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-13"><committee name="Committee on Labor and Human Resources"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Business and social problems"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
Child Care Public-Private Partnership Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a business-incentive grant program to provide child care through public-private partnerships. Provides program grants to cover not more than one-third of the costs for: (1) businesses or consortia (two or more businesses acting jointly, which may also include a nonprofit private organization) to start up, or provide additional, employee child care services; and (2) nonprofit business organizations to provide technical information and assistance to enable businesses to provide employee child care services. Requires: (1) provision of such services equitably and affordably to low- and moderate-income employees; and (2) compliance with State and local licensing requirements. Gives priority in grant selection to businesses with fewer than 100 full-time employees and to business and consortia applications. Requires equitable geographic distribution. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
