<bill session="103" type="s" number="496" updated="2012-07-17T04:44:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to strengthen Federal standards for licensing firearms dealers and heighten reporting requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1993-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-08-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-10-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2356-2357)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4441)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14770-14771)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Photography"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit: (1) a common or contract carrier from knowingly delivering in interstate or foreign commerce a firearm to a licensed importer, manufacturer, dealer, or collector unless the carrier identifies and maintains a record of the identity of the recipient; and (2) a person from selling or otherwise disposing of a firearm or ammunition if he or she has reasonable cause to believe that the recipient is acquiring the firearms or ammunition to commit a crime of violence. Increases license applicaton fees for firearms dealers. Repeals a provision requiring the Secretary of the Treasury to approve or deny an application for a license to deal in firearms or ammunition within 45 days and related requirements. Adds as a requirement for approval of such a license that the business to be conducted under the license not be prohibited by the applicable State or local law and that the applicant has complied with all requirements of applicable State and local law. Authorizes the Secretary to inspect the inventory and records of a licensed importer, manufacturer, dealer, or collector without reasonable cause or warrant to ensure compliance with firearms-related recordkeeping requirements (currently, limited to not more than once during any 12-month period). Requires each licensee to: (1) report the theft or loss of a firearm within 24 hours after it is discovered to the Secretary and appropriate local authorities; and (2) respond immediately to, and in no event later than 24 hours after receipt of, a request by the Secretary for information contained in required firearms records for determining the disposition of a firearm. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require that importers, manufacturers, and dealers in firearms include a photograph and fingerprints with their initial applications for registration.

	</summary>
</bill>
