<bill session="103" type="s" number="497" updated="2012-07-17T06:14:00-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">DNA Identification Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize funds received by States and units of local government to be expended to improve the quality and availability of DNA records, to authorize the establishment of a DNA identification index, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-09-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2358)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-03" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
		<term name="DNA fingerprints"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Justice"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Forensic medicine"/>
		<term name="Forensic scientists"/>
		<term name="Identification of criminals"/>
		<term name="Laboratories"/>
		<term name="Rating of employees"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/3/1993--Introduced.
DNA Identification Act of 1993 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the use of drug control and system improvement grants to develop or improve in a forensic laboratory a capability to analyze deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA) for identification purposes. Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Invesigation (FBI) to: (1) appoint an advisory board on DNA quality assurance methods; and (2) issue standards for quality assurance, including standards for testing the proficiency of forensic laboratories and forensic analysts in conducting such analyses. Authorizes the Director to establish an index of DNA identification records of persons convicted of crimes, analyses of DNA samples recovered from crime scenes, and analyses of DNA samples recovered from unidentified human remains. Makes the exchange of DNA identification records subject to cancellation if specified quality control and privacy requirements are not met. Requires: (1) FBI personnel who perform DNA analyses to undergo, at regular intervals, external proficiency testing; and (2) the Director to submit an annual report on the results of such tests to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees for five years and to arrange for periodic blind external tests to determine the proficiency of DNA analysis performed at the FBI laboratory. Sets fines of up to $100,000 for individuals: (1) having access to individually identifiable DNA information indexed in a database created or maintained by a Federal law enforcement agency by virtue of employment or official position who willfully disclose such information to any person or agency not entitled to receive it; and (2) who, without authorization, willfully obtain DNA samples or such individually identifiable DNA information. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
