<bill session="103" type="s" number="505" updated="2012-07-17T06:01:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food Stamp Anti-Fraud Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to identify and curtail fraud in the food stamp program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300072"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-06-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1993-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1993-04-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2428)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-12"><committee name="Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Nutrition and Investigations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="Nutrition and Investigations" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Explosives"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Food stamps"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grocery trade"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Welfare fraud"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/4/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Retail Food Stores and Wholesale Food Concerns Title II: Miscellaneous Title III: Effective Dates Food Stamp Anti-Fraud Act of 1993 - Title I: Retail Food Stores and Wholesale Food Concerns - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 with regard to retail food stores participating in the food stamp program (program) to: (1) permit the use of application information by Federal or State enforcement authorities; and (2) repeal the limits on civil money penalties for food stamp trafficking and firearms or controlled substance trading. Amends the Social Security Act to permit the use of social security account numbers by Federal or State enforcement authorities. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit the use of employer identification numbers by Federal or State enforcement authorities. Title II: Miscellaneous - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to permanently disqualify a recipient food store from program participation for trading of firearms, ammunition, explosives, or controlled substances for food stamps. States that penalties collected from retail or wholesale food concerns shall be used for related investigation and enforcement activities. Title III: Effective Dates - Sets forth effective dates for provisions of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
