<bill session="103" type="s" number="513" updated="2012-07-17T06:11:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tobacco Consumption Reduction and Health Improvement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the excise taxes on tobacco products, and to use the resulting revenues to fund a trust fund for health care reform, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401709"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-04-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2436-2438)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Cigarettes"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Free ports and zones"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Medically uninsured"/>
		<term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
		<term name="Smoking"/>
		<term name="State taxation"/>
		<term name="Tax rates"/>
		<term name="Tobacco tax"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/4/1993--Introduced.
Tobacco Consumption Reduction and Health Improvement Act of 1993 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the excise tax on: (1) cigars; (2) cigarettes; (3) cigarette papers and tubes; (4) snuff; and (5) chewing and pipe tobacco. Imposes a tax on the floor stocks of such tobacco products which are removed before January 1, 1994. Makes an exception to the imposition of such tax for floor stocks of such products held on such date at the place intended to be sold at retail. Imposes such tax on such products entered into the United States from foreign trade zones before such date. Establishes in the Treasury the Health Reform Trust Fund composed of the net increases in revenues received by the Treasury as the result of this Act. Directs the Secretary to use: (1) 80 percent of such funds in a fiscal year for the provision of medical care and medical insurance to persons without such insurance; and (2) 20 percent for health education programs, smoking cessation programs, and distribution to States required to reduce State taxes on tobacco products as a result of the increase in the Federal excise tax under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
