<bill session="103" type="s" number="522" updated="2012-07-17T04:11:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enterprise Zone Environmental Restoration Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to award grants to political subdivisions of States for environmental testing and characterization in enterprise zones, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="411818"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2495-2496)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Enterprise zones"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Federal-local relations"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/5/1993--Introduced.
Enterprise Zone Environmental Restoration Act of 1993 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a program to award grants for environmental testing and characterization on land owned by political subdivisions of States to political subdivisions that submit approved applications for such activities on impacted sites. Defines an &quot;impacted site&quot; as an area designated as an enterprise zone pursuant to the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 or that receives a similar designation under other Federal law. Permits the Administrator to authorize State Governors to carry out State grant programs to carry out this Act. Sets forth conditions for the receipt of grants. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
