<bill session="103" type="s" number="525" updated="2012-07-17T04:37:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Educational Flexibility Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Educational Flexibility Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="405212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-03-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2497-2498, S2500-2501)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
		<term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Educational innovations"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
		<term name="Gifted children"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Homeless children"/>
		<term name="Mathematics"/>
		<term name="Scientific education"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/5/1993--Introduced.
Educational Flexibility Act - Amends the General Education Provisions Act to establish a program for flexibility and accountability in education and related services. Directs the Secretary of Education to assist projects for elementary and secondary schools and other service provides to improve achievement of all students and other participants, but particularly disadvantaged individuals, by authorizing waivers for States by which the performance of schools and programs can be improved by increasing their flexibility in use of resources while holding them accountable for achieving educational gains. Authorizes the Secretary to waive a statutory or regulatory requirement only with respect to programs under specified Federal laws relating to elementary, secondary, and vocational education and disadvantaged or homeless students. Authorizes other Federal agency heads, with the Secretary's agreement, to make similar waivers of such requirements applicable to an elementary, secondary, or youth vocational training program they administer. Limits duration of projects and associated waivers. Requires, to the extent possible, project participation by each grade and academic program in a participating school. Prohibits waiver of requirements: (1) in awarding new competitive grants to a service provider within the LEA or other applicant participating in such a project; (2) relating to maintenance of effort, comparability, or equitable participation of private school students; and (3) under specified provisions of certain Federal laws relating to individuals with disabilities.

	</summary>
</bill>
