<bill session="103" type="s" number="541" updated="2012-07-17T06:17:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Foundation for Excellence Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Foundation for Excellence to award scholarships to outstanding students who are committed to careers in teaching in public education and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401604"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2627-2629)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Elementary education"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Foundations"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Secondary education"/>
		<term name="Teacher education"/>
		<term name="Teachers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1993--Introduced.
National Foundation for Excellence Act - Establishes the National Foundation for Excellence as an independent establishment of the executive branch. Authorizes the Foundation to award scholarships for undergraduate and graduate study for outstanding students committed to careers in teaching in public education. Sets forth scholarship conditions, including student agreements to teach in a public elementary or secondary school for a certain period of years based on the total amount of scholarship awarded. Sets forth scholarship repayment requirements for those who do not fulfill such teaching commitments or who otherwise do not comply with the provisions of this Act. Authorizes the Foundation to make grants to States to pay the Federal share (50 percent) of scholarship programs conducted by the States. Establishes in the Treasury the National Foundation for Excellence Trust Fund. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
