<bill session="103" type="s" number="554" updated="2012-07-17T05:09:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Solicitation Enhancement Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to enhance the solicitation process in certain Government contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404598"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1993-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1993-03-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2651-2653)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Evaluation"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Government consultants"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1993--Introduced.
Solicitation Enhancement Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to revise solicitation, evaluation, and award procedures for public contracts. Prohibits the use of appropriated funds to pay for non-Federal employees to evaluate or analyze proposals submitted for an acquisition, unless Federal employees with adequate training and capabilities to perform such activities are not readily available within the agency or any other Federal agency. Sets forth requirements for the delegation of procurement authority for certain acquisitions in special circumstances. Directs the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to provide guidance and promulgate regulations on what actions agencies must take to determine whether expertise is readily available within the Government and how it may be shared before they contract for advisory and technical services to conduct acquisitions.

	</summary>
</bill>
