<bill session="103" type="s" number="580" updated="2012-07-17T04:57:25-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-11">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-11"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Reorganization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Act of 1992</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Technology Administration Act of 1992</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the competitiveness of the United States in the global economy through the establishment of Department of Trade as an executive department of the Government, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400565"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-03-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2824-2827)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-11" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Ambassadors"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Atmospheric research"/>
		<term name="Census"/>
		<term name="Commercialization"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Department of Labor"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Export finance"/>
		<term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Foreign service"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Free enterprise"/>
		<term name="Government corporations"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="International Development Cooperation Agency"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="International monetary system"/>
		<term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
		<term name="Labor statistics"/>
		<term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
		<term name="Oceanographic research"/>
		<term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
		<term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
		<term name="Patents"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Small Business Administration"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology policy"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
		<term name="Trademarks"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/11/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Illegal Immigration Control and Enforcement Title II: Illegal Immigration Incentive Reduction Title III: Enhanced Smuggling Control and Penalties Title IV: Admissions and Document Fraud Control Title V: Border Crossing User Fee Illegal Immigration Control and Enforcement Act of 1995 - Title I: Illegal Immigration Control and Enforcement - Part A: Increased Border Patrol, Support, Training, and Resources - Provides for: (1) increased Border Patrol personnel levels; (2) deployment in areas of high-illegal entry; (3) bilingual hiring preference; (4) improved training; and (5) technology and equipment transfer to the Department of Justice; and (6) land border infrastructure improvements. Part B: Expanded Border Inspection Personnel, Support, and Facilities - Provides for: (1) increased border inspection personnel levels; and (2) deployment in areas of high-illegal entry. Part C: Detention and Deportation - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (Act) to limit collateral attacks on deportation hearings. (Sec. 132) Permits the use of electronic and telephonic media in deportation hearings. (Sec. 133) Amends Federal criminal law to permit deportation as a condition of probation. Part D: Enhanced Criminal Alien Deportation and Transfer - Amends the Act to expand the definition of &quot;aggravated felony.&quot; (Sec. 142) Restricts certain deportation defenses. (Sec. 144) Provides for judicial review of an alien convicted of an aggravated felony. (Sec. 145) Authorizes the Secretary of State, with the Attorney General, to negotiate agreements with foreign countries for home- country incarceration of aliens subject to U.S. deportation. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 147) Amends the Act to permit the use of videotaped witness testimony under specified circumstances in a case of bringing in and harboring certain illegal aliens. Title II: Illegal Immigration Incentive Reduction - Part A: Public Benefits Control - Authorizes States and localities to limit general public assistance to aliens or classes of aliens. (Sec. 212) Increases penalties for forging or counterfeiting the seal of a Federal department of agency to facilitate benefit fraud by an unlawful alien. (Sec. 213) Revises alien sponsorship and related provisions. (Sec. 214) Amends title XIX (Grants to States for Medical Assistance Programs) of the Social Security Act to permit high illegal immigration States to place Medicaid anti-fraud investigators in State, county, and private hospitals. (Sec. 215) Directs the Attorney General to make grants to States for ports-of-entry benefits task force demonstration projects. Authorizes appropriations. Part B: Employer Sanctions Support - Authorizes the hiring of additional Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) investigators and staff to enforce employer sanctions. (Sec. 222) Increases certain penalties for unlawful employment or related extortion of aliens. (Sec. 223) Amends the Internal Revenue Code to 1986 to require a person to have a social security number (and a spouse's number) in order to claim the earned income tax credit. (Sec. 225) Requires the Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and implement a counterfeit- resistant system to verify work and public assistance eligibility. Part C: Enhanced Wage and Hour Laws - Authorizes additional Department of Labor hiring to enforce employer wage and hour law sanctions. (Sec. 232) Authorizes the hiring of additional Assistant United States Attorneys to help preclude illegal immigration. Title III: Enhanced Smuggling Control and Penalties - Amends Federal criminal law to revise alien smuggling penalties. (Sec. 302) Amends the Act to expand INS forfeiture authority for smuggling or harboring illegal aliens. (Sec. 303) Amends Federal criminal law to authorize INS wiretaps for alien smuggling investigations. Title IV: Admissions and Document Fraud Control - Amends Federal criminal law to revise and increase document fraud penalties. Title V: Border Crossing User Fee - Establishes in the Treasury the Immigration Law Enforcement Fund. Imposes a $1 border crossing user fee.

	</summary>
</bill>
