<bill session="103" type="s" number="588" updated="2012-07-17T05:05:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-16">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-16"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Aboveground Storage Tank Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate aboveground storage tanks used to store regulated substances, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400564"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1994-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2925-2926)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-16" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Bankruptcy"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Citizen participation"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Emergency management"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental health"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Farms"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Heating"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Inventories"/>
		<term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
		<term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution"/>
		<term name="Petroleum storage"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Pollution liability insurance"/>
		<term name="Risk assessment"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
		<term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
		<term name="Underground storage"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/16/1993--Introduced.
Safe Aboveground Storage Tank Act of 1993 - Requires owners of aboveground storage tanks used to store regulated substances (as defined under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, including petroleum and excluding hazardous wastes regulated under the Solid Waste Disposal Act) to provide State or local authorities with all relevant particulars about such tanks, including age, size, type, location, and uses. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue notification and performance standards for such tanks. Requires the State to inventory all tanks containing regulated substances. Directs owners or operators of petroleum tanks to notify the Administrator immediately of any petroleum spill exceeding 42 gallons. Requires the Administrator to issue release detection, prevention, and correction regulations, including requirements for leak detection systems, reporting, release prevention, closure, and upgrades, and evidence of financial responsibility. Permits corrective actions by the Administrator or State to protect human health and the environment, but makes owners or operators of tanks liable for costs. Provides for inspections of tanks by the Administrator or a State. Authorizes States to conduct Administrator-approved programs to enforce this Act. Directs the Administrator to provide technical assistance to States, local governments, and owners and operators to assist in compliance with State programs. Sets forth authorized actions when an owner or operator has not complied with or cannot meet financial responsibility requirements. Requires owners or operators to furnish the relevant government employees with all necessary information, including submitting their facilities to inspection and monitoring. Provides for confidentiality of such information and criminal penalties for prohibited disclosure. Authorizes the use of compliance orders to enforce this Act, providing daily penalties for noncompliance. Includes tanks under Federal jurisdiction under this Act, permitting exemptions of up to one year upon the President's specific request. Limits individual liability of Federal employees for civil penalties, but makes them subject to criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Directs the Administrator to study and report to the Congress on tanks used to store petroleum and other regulated substances. Declares that the Comptroller General should study and report to the Congress on whether transportation-related tanks and associated piping are adequately regulated to protect health and the environment and whether they should be regulated by EPA. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
