<bill session="103" type="s" number="59" updated="2012-07-17T06:09:34-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">AIDS Control bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">AIDS Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to control the spread of AIDS, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300154"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="s" number="42" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
		<term name="Africa"/>
		<term name="Africans"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Blood banks"/>
		<term name="Blood donors"/>
		<term name="Condoms"/>
		<term name="Contraceptives"/>
		<term name="Counseling"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
		<term name="Drug abuse"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Gay military personnel"/>
		<term name="Gays"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Haiti"/>
		<term name="Haitians"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Hemophilia"/>
		<term name="Hepatitis"/>
		<term name="Homosexuality"/>
		<term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
		<term name="Immigrants"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marriage"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Medical supplies"/>
		<term name="Medical tests"/>
		<term name="Military personnel"/>
		<term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prostitution"/>
		<term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Syphilis"/>
		<term name="Tuberculosis"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
AIDS Control Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require recordkeeping of cases of individuals infected with the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). Requires: (1) that any entity that collects or distributes blood or blood derivatives test all donors for HIV and allow directed and autologous blood donations; (2) recipients of grants under population research and family planning provisions to provide individuals with HIV infection prevention information; (3) that physicians and medical technicians report to public health authorities the names and addresses of HIV-infected individuals in accordance with State sexually transmitted disease confidentiality laws; (4) notification of the spouse of an AIDS-infected patient; and (5) closure of all bathhouses where a pattern of continuous homosexual sexual activity or continuous illegal intravenous drug use occurs. Prohibits the use of certain funds: (1) to provide hypodermic needles or syringes or distribute bleach for illegal drug use; (2) to promote or provide condoms to prevent the spread of AIDS; (3) to provide AIDS education, information, or prevention materials and activities that promote or encourage, directly or indirectly, homosexual sexual activities; or (4) unless the State requires marriage license applicants to be tested for infection with HIV and both individuals to be notified of each test result. Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for penalties for any individual donating blood, semen, or organs if that individual is knowingly infected with HIV, is a member of certain groups (including African and Haitian immigrants, hemophiliacs, prostitutes, homosexuals, and intravenous drug users), or has engaged in high risk activity. Mandates testing of each person incarcerated in a Federal correctional institution at any appropriate time. Prohibits the induction or retention in the armed forces of a person infected with HIV. Requires testing at induction and at other times as appropriate. Amends the Veterans' Benefits and Services Act of 1988 to mandate testing of each VA patient. Amends Federal law relating to veterans' benefits and confidentiality of medical records to require a physician or counselor to disclose information indicating that a patient or subject is infected with HIV to a spouse or sexual partner. Requires recipients of funds under specified provisions of the Public Health Service Act to routinely test for HIV infection each person receiving treatment for tuberculosis, substance abuse, or a sexually transmitted disease. Directs the President, under specified provisions of the Immigration and Nationality Act, to add infection with HIV and syphilis to the list of dangerous contagious diseases in specified Federal regulations. Prohibits assistance under the Public Health Service Act to a State that fails to protect health care professionals from HIV and hepatitis B during exposure prone invasive procedures. Allows professionals to require HIV testing of patients. Mandates criminal penalties for provision by a health care provider of invasive treatment without prior patient notice of known provider HIV infection.

	</summary>
</bill>
