<bill session="103" type="s" number="605" updated="2012-07-17T04:33:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-17">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-17"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drunk Driving Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Transportation to withhold certain funds from States that fail to deem a person driving with a blood alcohol concentration of 0.08 percent or greater to be driving while intoxicated, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300036"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-06-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3050-3051)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-17" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1386" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Drunk driving"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/17/1993--Introduced.
Drunk Driving Prevention Act of 1993 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to withhold from States failing to provide that a blood alcohol concentration level of 0.08 percent or greater while operating a motor vehicle shall be considered driving while intoxicated the following percentages of funds authorized for such States for Federal aid highway systems: (1) five percent for the first year of such failure; and (2) ten percent for each year after the first year. Allows certain funds released to the States for periods in excess of three years of such failure to be used by such States only to carry out programs approved by the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration that prevent driving while intoxicated. Provides for the release of all funds previously withheld if the State eventually adopts the blood alcohol level requirement of 0.08 percent or greater.

	</summary>
</bill>
