<bill session="103" type="s" number="611" updated="2012-07-17T04:53:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Flight Attendant Duty Time Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to provide for the establishment of limitations on the duty time for flight attendants.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300017" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-03-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1993-03-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3175)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="14" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Airline employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Flight crews"/>
		<term name="Hours of labor"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/18/1993--Introduced.
Flight Attendant Duty Time Act - Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to direct the Secretary of Transportation to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to establish limitations on duty time for flight attendants. Requires the Secretary to issue final regulations by a specified deadline. Prohibits any air carrier from operating an aircraft using a flight attendant who has been on duty in excess of specified hours or who has had less than a specified number of hours of rest if such regulations have not been promulgated by a certain time. Permits modification of the specified hours of duty if the Secretary determines such modification is in the public interest and submits a copy of the modifying regulations to certain congressional committees. Treats a duty period with both domestic and international flight segments as international flying for purposes of calculating duty and rest requirements if the majority of the flight time during such period is on an international or domestic segment.

	</summary>
</bill>
