<bill session="103" type="s" number="619" updated="2012-07-17T06:11:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Bill of Rights</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to provide improved services to beneficiaries under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3187-3188)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Child support"/>
		<term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
		<term name="Disability evaluation"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Emblems"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Employment of the physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Financial statements"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government publications"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Language and languages"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Rehabilitation of the physically handicapped"/>
		<term name="Signs and symbols"/>
		<term name="Social security eligibility"/>
		<term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
		<term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Welfare fraud"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/18/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Service Improvements Title II: Work Incentives for Individuals With Disabilities Subtitle A: Amendment Relating to Benefits Under Title XVI of the Social Security Act Subtitle B: Advisory Committee on Criteria for Determining Disability Title III: Demonstration Projects to Provide for Improved Procedures With Respect to Disability Determinations, Continuing Disability Reviews, and Rehabilitation Services Social Security Bill of Rights - Title I: Service Improvements - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for the: (1) restitution of funds misappropriated by representative payees; and (2) provision of certain information on the OASDI trust fund to individuals receiving OASDI cost-of-living adjustments. Amends SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an ongoing program of outreach to individuals who have attained age 65 and are potentially eligible for SSI benefits by reason of disability or blindness. Amends SSA title XI to direct the Secretary to provide for: (1) the use of Social Security Administration offices to apply for Medicaid (SSA title XIX) and certain other benefits (one stop shopping); (2) training for office employees assisting in the application process for such benefits; and (3) the use of bilingual personnel and printed material in the administration of SSA programs where appropriate. Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to restore telephone access to local offices of the Social Security Administration. Amends title XI of the Social Security Act to: (1) revise the prohibitions and penalties against misleading mailings; and (2) require deposit of penalties relating to misleading mailings in the Federal Old-Age and Survivor's Insurance Trust Fund. Requires annual reports to the Congress with respect to prohibition violations and associated penalties. Title II: Work Incentives for Individuals with Disabilities - Amends SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) to: (1) provide for SSI benefits for individuals who lose social security disability benefits after a trial work period; and (2) revise provisions concerning SSI benefits for individuals who perform substantial gainful activity despite severe medical impairment. Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory committee for the purpose of issuing a report to the Secretary and the Congress concerning the appropiate criteria for determining disability under the OASDI and SSI programs. Title III: Demonstration Projects to Provide for Improved Procedures with Respect to Disability Determinations, Continuing Disability Reviews, and Rehabilitation Services - Directs the Secretary to provide for the establishment of demonstration projects to provide for improved procedures for disability determinations and continuing disability reviews under SSA titles II and XVI and a modified program for providing rehabilitation services to individuals determined under such titles to be under a disability. Directs the Secretary to provide for the establishment of demonstration projects to improve review of disability determinations made under SSA titles II and XVI. Requires the Secretary to evaluate the demonstration projects under this title and report to the Congress on their effectiveness. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
