<bill session="103" type="s" number="639" updated="2012-07-17T04:42:47-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-23">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-23"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Antidrug Assault Weapons Limitation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drive-By Shooting Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make unlawful the possession of certain assault weapons, to establish a Federal penalty for drive-by shootings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="408939" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="406487" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-03-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-23" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3526-3528)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-23" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Committee on Judiciary. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Assault weapons"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conspiracy"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
		<term name="Parole"/>
		<term name="Probation"/>
		<term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
		<term name="Smuggling"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Violence"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/23/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Assault Weapons Title II: Indiscriminate Use of Weapons to Further Drug Conspiracies Title III: Miscellaneous Firearms Offenses Title I: Assault Weapons - Antidrug Assault Weapons Limitation Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the: (1) transfer, importation, transportation, shipment, receipt, or possession of an assault weapon, with exceptions; (2) sale, shipment, or delivery of an assault weapon to a person who does not fill out a form 4473 (prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury) in connection with the purchase; and (3) purchase, possession, or acceptance of delivery of an assault weapon by a person who has not filled out such form. Sets penalties for: (1) the use of an assault weapon during and in relation to any crime of violence or drug trafficking crime; and (2) knowingly violating requirements regarding the filling out of form 4473. Prohibits persons convicted of the latter offense from shipping or transporting firearms or ammunition in interstate or foreign commerce. Directs the Attorney General to investigate the effect of this Act and determine its impact on violent and drug trafficking crime. Title II: Indiscriminate Use of Weapons to Further Drug Conspiracies - Drive-By Shooting Prevention Act of 1993 - Sets penalties for causing grave risk to human life or the death of any person by firing a weapon into a group of two or more persons with intent to intimidate, harass, injure, or maim and in furtherance of, or to escape detection of, a major drug offense. Title III: Miscellaneous Firearms Offenses - Sets penalties for: (1) stealing a firearm that is moving in, or that has moved in, interstate or foreign commerce; and (2) smuggling or knowingly bringing a firearm, into the United States, or attempting to do so, with intent to engage in or promote conduct that is punishable under specified controlled substances Acts, violates a State law relating to a controlled substance, or constitutes a crime of violence. Provides for mandatory revocation of supervised release for possession of a firearm.

	</summary>
</bill>
