<bill session="103" type="s" number="651" updated="2012-07-17T05:09:52-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to provide for expanded participation of historically Black colleges and universities and nonprofit organizations owned and controlled by Black Americans in federally funded research and development activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300073"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1993-10-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="405310" joined="1994-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-09-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3765-3766)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Black businesses"/>
		<term name="Black colleges"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to research"/>
		<term name="General Services Administration"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Research and development contracts"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/25/1993--Introduced.
Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to require the Federal Acquisition Regulation to include regulations to ensure the participation (except in specified circumstances) of at least five historically Black colleges and universities and nonprofit organizations owned and controlled by Black Americans in research and development (R&amp;D) activities conducted for executive agencies. Outlines the requirements to be imposed on executive agencies through such regulations, including the requirement that each such agency reserve a specified percentage of its FY 1995 through 1998 appropriations for R&amp;D activities to be conducted by the Black colleges it must designate under this Act as federally funded R&amp;D centers. Increases such set-aside on a graduated basis for such fiscal years. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to the Congress annually on the activities of executive agencies in carrying out this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
