<bill session="103" type="s" number="670" updated="2012-07-17T04:50:08-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Head Start Quality Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Head Start Act to make quality improvements in Head Start programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406188"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1993-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1993-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="403171" joined="1993-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-04-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4014-4017)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1528" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Child development"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Department of Education"/>
		<term name="Educational accountability"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Parent and child"/>
		<term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Vaccination"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/30/1993--Introduced.
Head Start Quality Improvement Act - Amends the Head Start Act to increase the portions of specified funds which are to be set aside for: (1) quality improvement activities of program grantees; (2) activities under the Head Start Transition Project Act; and (3) program improvement activities (adding monitoring and incentive grants to the current training and technical assistance). Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make program grants to designated Head Start agencies on a seven-year funding cycle (thus requiring existing agency reapplication and recompetition for subsequent grants and designations). Adds continuity of services to selection criteria. Requires an interim evaluation (including a site visit) of each designated agency at least once each year. Authorizes the Secretary to require an agency to correct program deficits, and requires provision of technical assistance for such purpose. Authorizes revocation of the agency's designation and grant if the problem is not corrected in that year, and provides for designation of and grants to another agency to serve the same community. Expands child eligibility criteria for program participation, allowing participation of families that would have been eligible within two years before. Revises notice, hearings, and appeals requirements and procedures. Adds requirements for program outcome measures.

	</summary>
</bill>
