<bill session="103" type="s" number="679" updated="2012-07-17T04:46:05-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-30">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Trade Assurances Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend and enhance the operation of the &quot;Super 301&quot; provisions of the Trade Act of 1974, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409225"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4027-4028)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-30" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5861-5862)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6089-6090)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6309-6314)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Balance of payments"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Economic statistics"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Reciprocity"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Tariff"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/30/1993--Introduced.
Fair Trade Assurances Act of 1993 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to direct the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), in identifying market barriers and certain unfair trade actions, to: (1) identify, if for a calendar year the United States merchandise trade balance (excluding crude petroleum imports) was in deficit, each foreign country that accounted for at least 15 percent of such deficit and had a global current account surplus for such year in an amount not less than such deficit; and (2) specify each act, policy, or practice that was implemented by a foreign country with respect to any goods sector or service sector that accounted for at least ten percent of the merchandise trade and current account deficits between the United States and such foreign country during such calendar year. Makes permanent the program known as &quot;Super 301&quot; which identifies trade liberalization priorities. Applies such program to sectoral priority practices. Requires the President, if the USTR finds violations of trade practices, to: (1) direct the USTR to take certain action to obtain the elimination of the foreign practice; or (2) submit to the Congress an alternative plan for eliminating such practice. Requires the USTR to initiate an investigation under &quot;Super 301&quot; whenever specified congressional committees adopt a resolution stating that in their opinion a particular foreign country is engaging in certain trade practices.

	</summary>
</bill>
