<bill session="103" type="s" number="680" updated="2012-07-17T05:27:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-09">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-11-09" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Safety Protection Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Child Safety Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for toy safety, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400559"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400557" joined="1993-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="1993-03-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4112-4113)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Subcommittee on Consumer. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-29" state="REPORTED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14652-14653)</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-09" ><text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-19"><text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-195.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="322" datetime="1993-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 322.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Measure laid before Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S16885-16892"/></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 965 as an amendment.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 965 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-20"><text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 322.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S16892"/></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S7267"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="Consumer" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="965" />
		<bill relation="superseded" session="103" type="h" number="965" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="965" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Consumer protection"/>
		<term name="Accident prevention"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Balloons"/>
		<term name="Bicycles"/>
		<term name="Child welfare"/>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="English language"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Head injuries"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
		<term name="Industrial standards"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
		<term name="Packaging"/>
		<term name="Product safety"/>
		<term name="Safety appliances"/>
		<term name="Safety measures"/>
		<term name="Signs and symbols"/>
		<term name="Spanish language"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Toys"/>
		<term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Vending machines"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>
		<amendment number="s1233"/>
	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/1994--Indefinitely postponed in Senate. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Toy Labeling Requirements Title II: Children's Bicycle Helmet Safety Title III: Bucket Drowning Prevention Child Safety Protection Act - Title I: Toy Labeling Requirements - Requires warning labels on the packaging of children's toys and games with small parts, balloons, small balls, or marbles. Establishes general labeling requirements, including that any required cautionary statement be displayed in English, in conspicuous and legible type (consistent with specified Federal regulations), and in its entirety on the principal display panel of the product's package, on any descriptive material accompanying the product, in the case of bulk sales of such product when unpackaged, on any bin, any container for retail display, and any vending machine from which the product is dispensed. Sets forth exceptions, including for products manufactured outside the United States. Treats a balloon, ball, marble, toy, or game that is not in compliance with labeling requirements as a misbranded hazardous substance. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) preemption; (2) reporting requirements; and (3) confidentiality. Title II: Children's Bicycle Helmet Safety - Children's Bicycle Helmet Safety Act of 1993 - Authorizes the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to make grants to States and nonprofit organizations for programs that require or encourage individuals under age 16 to wear approved bicycle helmets. Directs the Administrator, in making such grants, to allow grantees wide discretion in designing programs that effectively promote increased bicycle helmet use. (Sec. 203) Includes among permissible grant purposes: (1) enforcing a law that requires individuals under age 16 to wear approved bicycle helmets while riding on bicycles; (2) assisting such individuals to acquire approved helmets; and (3) developing and administering a program to educate such individuals and their families on the importance of wearing helmets. (Sec. 204) Requires bicycle helmets to meet specified interim Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) standards and provides for the setting of a final standard. Considers failure to meet such a standard to be a violation of a consumer product safety standard (safety standard) promulgated under the Consumer Product Safety Act (the Act). (Sec. 205) Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Bucket Drowning Prevention - Establishes a safety standard under the Act to eliminate or reduce the risk of injury or death resulting from infants falling into four- to six-gallon buckets containing liquid. Provides that such standard shall require straight sided or slightly tapered, open head containers with a capacity of between four and six gallons to bear one warning label in English and Spanish which meets specified requirements, including the display of a picture of a child falling into a bucket containing liquid. Exempts buckets manufactured or imported before the effective date of the standard. Directs the CPSC to prohibit a manufacturer, filler, distributor, and retailer from stockpiling such buckets. (Sec. 303) Prohibits intentionally covering, defacing, or removing a label required under this title by any person in the chain of distribution of the bucket. (Sec. 304) Permits the continued use of substantially conforming labels in use on September 1, 1993, until 12 months after enactment of this title, but requires buckets subject to the provisions of this section to bear both an English and Spanish language label after the effective date of such standard. (Sec. 306) Makes the labeling of buckets covered by such standard the responsibility of the manufacturer, unless otherwise specified by contract between the manufacturer and either the filler, distributor, or retailer of such buckets. Prohibits any such bucket from entering the stream of commerce without such label. Specifies that the required label must be on the bucket at the time it is sold or delivered to the end user of the bucket or its contents, or, in the case of a bucket intended to be sold to the public empty, at the time it is shipped to a retailer for sale to the public. (Sec. 307) Directs the CPSC to commence a proceeding under the Act for the issuance of a performance standard for buckets to address the drowning hazard. (Sec. 309) Directs the CPSC to conduct a study to assess the frequency of deaths and injuries arising from drowning accidents in metal buckets, and the frequency and uses of four- to six-gallon metal containers in the home, to determine whether special design and labeling standards are needed.

	</summary>
</bill>
