<bill session="103" type="s" number="681" updated="2012-07-17T05:37:57-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-31">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Paperwork Reduction Reauthorization Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Review Sunshine Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, relating to Government paperwork reduction, to modify the Federal regulatory review process, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="404598"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1993-03-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4114-4115, S4120-4121)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Freedom of information"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Government regulation"/>
		<term name="Information policy"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
		<term name="Information technology"/>
		<term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
		<term name="Productivity in government"/>
		<term name="Records management"/>
		<term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
		<term name="Statistical services"/>
		<term name="Sunset legislation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Paperwork Reduction and Information Resources Management by Federal Departments and Agencies Title II: Review of Federal Regulations Paperwork Reduction Reauthorization Act of 1993 - Title I: Paperwork Reduction and Information Resources Management by Federal Departments and Agencies - Revises, reauthorizes, and extends the Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980. Title II: Review of Federal Regulations: - Regulatory Review Sunshine Act of 1993 - Requires executive branch regulatory review entities to establish procedures for public access to specified information about each agency rulemaking activity under review. Requires a review entity to transmit to the rulemaking agency: (1) copies of any written as well as all oral communications between the entity and any person not employed by the Federal Government concerning the substance of a rulemaking activity of that agency; and (2) written explanation of any significant review action it has taken concerning such an activity. Requires a rulemaking agency: (1) upon request to identify a rulemaking activity, the date it was submitted for review, and any notice of any extensions of review; and (2) explain in its rulemaking notice any significant changes to such rule as a consequence of regulatory review. Requires a review entity, to conclude its review of a rulemaking activity within 60 days after its receipt. Provides for an extension of time in the case of a presidential review. Requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to prepare and make public monthly and annual accountings of regulatory review by all entities. Requires each rulemaking agency to publish in the Federal Register a list of all rulemaking activities undergoing regulatory review during the preceding month. Excludes from coverage under this Act oral communications with the President, Vice President, Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, Director of OMB, and executive department heads.

	</summary>
</bill>
