<bill session="103" type="s" number="686" updated="2012-07-17T04:35:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-31">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf of Mexico Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Gulf of Mexico Commission and a Gulf of Mexico Program Office within the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406487"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="406084" joined="1993-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-03-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4141)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-31" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="103" type="h" number="1566" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Beach erosion"/>
		<term name="Caribbean area"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Marine pollution"/>
		<term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution control"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Presidential commissions"/>
		<term name="Regional economic development"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/1993--Introduced.
Gulf of Mexico Act of 1993 - Requires the President, upon receiving agreement from the Governor of each Gulf State, to establish a Gulf of Mexico Commission to promote the environmental and economic interests of the Gulf by coordinating the public authorities and private organizations that are engaged in evaluating and responding to problems relating to the Gulf. Establishes the Gulf of Mexico Program Office within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Requires the Director of the Program Office to: (1) create an inventory and data base of research on Gulf environmental quality issues; (2) establish a Gulf-wide network to monitor Gulf environmental quality and implement policies to improve environmental quality; and (3) coordinate Federal, State, and local activities to improve environmental quality. Directs the EPA Administrator to publish a Gulf of Mexico Management Plan designed to: (1) summarize existing data on the environmental quality of the Gulf; (2) describe the monitoring network and the Program Office research inventory; (3) describe significant sources of pollution and activities to preserve critical habitats; (4) report on and recommend pollution prevention measures; (5) address the economic impact of such measures on development in the Gulf region; and (6) recommend the Federal, State, and local agencies to be charged with implementing the Plan. Authorizes grants to States for implementing the monitoring network or Plan, subject to cost-sharing requirements. Bars the use of grants for purposes of relieving any person from liability under Federal or State law for damages, response costs, or relief. Permits the Administrator to negotiate memoranda of understanding with other Federal agencies with jurisdiction over the Gulf. Authorizes the Administrator to study the nature and extent of environmental problems in the Gulf and wider Caribbean region. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
