<bill session="103" type="s" number="721" updated="2012-07-17T06:07:20-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Land and Water Conservation Fund Emergency Funding Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="406084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="1993-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4284-4286)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-23"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Agriculture, Department of the Interior, and Office of Management and Budget.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18"><committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings concluded. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-213.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Recreation"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="National parks"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Trails"/>
		<term name="Wild rivers"/>
		<term name="Wilderness areas"/>
		<term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
Land and Water Conservation Fund Emergency Funding Act of 1993 - Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to make available in FY 1994 through 1998 to the Secretaries of the Interior and of Agriculture a specified sum to be deducted from the authorized but unappropriated balance of the Fund to: (1) reduce the significant backlog of unacquired lands within the authorized boundaries of units of the national park, wildlife refuge, wilderness, wild and scenic river, trail, and forest systems; and (2) provide critically needed funding to the States for outdoor recreation, including planning, acquisition of land, waters, or interest in land and water, or development. Earmarks specified sums to be utilized by the Secretaries for Federal and State purposes pursuant to the Act. Requires the Secretary of the Interior (for National Park Service, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and Bureau of Land Management land acquisition projects) and the Secretary of Agriculture (for Forest Service land acquisition projects) as part of the Department of the Interior's annual budget submission to the Congress for FY 1995 through 1998, to transmit to specified congressional committees priority lists of land acquisition projects within each agency or bureau which have been authorized by law. Prohibits any one agency from being allocated more than 50 percent or less than ten percent of the funds made available under this Act for land acquisition needs. States that: (1) funds made available pursuant to this Act shall be allocated to projects in accordance with the transmitted priority lists unless modified by law; and (2) no funds shall be made available for the purpose of this Act until after the enactment of the Appropriations Act for the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies for the appropriate fiscal year.

	</summary>
</bill>
