<bill session="103" type="s" number="722" updated="2012-07-17T05:29:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Aid for Trade Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to reform United States bilateral economic assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="401604"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-04-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4286-4288)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-01-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S280-281)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Capital investments"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Construction industries"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Engineering"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Government service contracts"/>
		<term name="Government vehicles"/>
		<term name="International Development Cooperation Agency"/>
		<term name="Leases"/>
		<term name="OECD countries"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
Aid for Trade Act of 1993 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to earmark foreign assistance funds for Trade and Development Agency projects in developing and middle-income countries. Limits the percentage of Economic Support Fund assistance to be used for cash transfers in FY 1994 through 1998. Declares that it is U.S. policy to give preference to the procurement of U.S. commodities and services in foreign assistance programs. Expands, and revises the authority to make, exceptions to a prohibition on the use of foreign assistance funds to procure motor vehicles that are not manufactured in the United States. (Currently, the President is authorized to waive the prohibition in special circumstances.) Bars the use of foreign assistance funds made available under cash transfers to finance commodity import transactions unless such transactions meet agency requirements for U.S. source, origin, and nationality (or unless such use is officially approved). Designates a Buy-America Advocate within the agency primarily responsible for administering development assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to the Congress on the agreement of the Organization of Economic Cooperation and Development to restrict tied aid practices.

	</summary>
</bill>
