<bill session="103" type="s" number="726" updated="2012-07-17T05:09:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Health Safety Net Infrastructure Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to create a new program to update and maintain the infrastructure requirements of our Nation's essential urban and rural safety net health care facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300031"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-05-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300012" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-05-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="1993-04-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4294, S4298-4299)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-08-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10250-10251)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Capital investments"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
		<term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health planning"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Interest rates"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Revolving funds"/>
		<term name="Rural public health"/>
		<term name="Subsidies"/>
		<term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
National Health Safety Net Infrastructure Act - Title I: Capital Financing Assistance for Safety Net Health Care Facilities Providing Indigent Care - Amends the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make payments for capital financing assistance to eligible health care facilities. Sets forth general eligibility requirements. Imposes certain public service responsibilities on health care facilities accepting capital financing assistance. Creates in the Treasury the Health Safety Net Infrastructure Trust Fund (Fund). Authorizes appropriations. Establishes a loan guarantee program under which the Trust Fund will provide a Federal guarantee of loan repayment to non-Federal lenders making loans to qualified health care facilities for health care facility replacement, modernization and renovation projects, and capital equipment acquisition. Establishes an interest rate subsidy program that provides a partial Federal subsidy of debt service payment where State or local entities demonstrate a significant commitment to financing health care facility replacement, modernization, and renovation projects by undertaking the issuance of bonds. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide direct matching loans to eligible health care facilities unable otherwise to obtain essential financing; and (2) make direct grants to eligible health care facilities with urgent capital needs. Makes direct grants available for three types of projects: (1) emergency certification and licensure grants to facilities threatened with closure or loss of accreditation or certification of a facility or of essential services as a result of life or safety code violations or similar facility or equipment failures; (2) emergency grants for capital renovation, expansion, or replacement necessary to the maintenance or expansion of essential safety and health services; and (3) planning grants to facilities which require pre-approval assistance to meet regulatory requirements related to management and finance in order to apply for loans, loan guarantees, and interest subsidies under this Act. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to give tax-exempt status to bonds guaranteed by the Fund.

	</summary>
</bill>
