<bill session="103" type="s" number="730" updated="2012-07-17T04:59:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Canada Fair Grain Trade Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure fair and free trade of certain agricultural commodities between the United States and Canada, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1993-05-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4227-4228, S4312-4313)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Antidumping"/>
		<term name="Barley"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Countervailing duties"/>
		<term name="Customs administration"/>
		<term name="Export subsidies"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grain"/>
		<term name="Grain trade"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
		<term name="Railroad rates"/>
		<term name="Soybeans"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
		<term name="Wheat"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
United States-Canada Fair Grain Trade Act of 1993 - Title I: Grain Trade Negotiations - Directs the President to negotiate with Canada to: (1) establish a method to determine the price at which the Canadian Wheat Board sells agricultural goods to the United States (as well as the Board's acquisition price) as required under the Statement of Administrative Action of the United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement Implementation Act of 1988; (2) exclude from the transport rates established under Canada's Western Grain Transportation Act Canadian agricultural goods shipped via east coast ports for U.S. consumption; and (3) clarify the meaning of &quot;acquisition price&quot; so that it includes certain subsidy payments to Canadian producers, handlers, grain storers, and transporters. Sets forth sanctions for failure of such negotiations. Requires Federal agencies (other than the United States International Trade Commission) to provide technical assistance to countervailing duty and antidumping duty petitioners with respect to Canadian subsidies on exports of wheat or barley to the United States. Title II: Agricultural Trade Programs - Amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to promote use of a program which permits exporters, users, processors, and foreign purchasers of U.S. grain to compete with exporters, users, processors, and foreign purchasers of Canadian grain and that takes into account: (1) Canadian transportation subsidies to promote grain sales to Mexico; and (2) sale of wheat in foreign markets by the Canadian Wheat Board at a price below its acquisition cost. Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to require an end-use certificate that meets specified requirements to be included in documentation covering the entry of covered foreign commodities (imported wheat, feed grains, or soybeans). Requires a consignee of a covered foreign commodity to report quarterly to the Secretary. Sets forth civil penalties for non-compliance. Requires the Commodity Credit Corporation to provide an opportunity for a hearing before suspending or debarring a person from participation in an agricultural trade program for using a foreign agricultural commodity in violation of the conditions of such program.

	</summary>
</bill>
