<bill session="103" type="s" number="740" updated="2012-07-17T05:21:37-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-02">INTRODUCED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-02"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Expedited Consideration of Proposed Rescissions Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide for the expedited consideration of certain proposed rescissions of budget authority and certain tax expenditure repeals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402727"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4407-4408)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-02"><text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Budget; Governmental Affairs pursuant to the order of August 4, 1977, with instructions that if one Committee reports, the other Committee have thirty days to report or be discharged.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-10-05"><text>Committee on Budget. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
		<term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
		<term name="House rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Legislative amendments"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Presidential messages"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Tax expenditures"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/2/1993--Introduced.
Expedited Consideration of Proposed Recissions Act of 1993 - Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to grant the President an additional method of rescinding budget authority. Allows the President to transmit to both Houses of the Congress, for expedited consideration, one or more special messages proposing to rescind all or part of any item of budget authority provided in an appropriations Act. Requires that such special message be transmitted not later than three days after the President approves the appropriation bill or revenue Act and be accompanied by a draft bill or joint resolution that would, if enacted, rescind the budget authority proposed to be rescinded. Sets forth House and Senate procedures for the expedited consideration of such proposals. Allows the President to transmit to the Congress, for expedited consideration, one or more special messages proposing to repeal any provision in an Act that would result in a tax expenditure.

	</summary>
</bill>
