<bill session="103" type="s" number="75" updated="2012-07-17T05:56:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Sediment Control Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the River and Harbor Act of 1970 to improve Great Lakes Water Pollution Control, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="404598" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-01-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S492-493)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Dredging"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Harbors"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="River regulation"/>
		<term name="Rivers"/>
		<term name="Sediment control"/>
		<term name="Sedimentation"/>
		<term name="Soil erosion"/>
		<term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
		<term name="Water quality"/>
		<term name="Watershed management"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Great Lakes Sediment Control Act of 1993 - Amends the River and Harbor Act of 1970 to make it unlawful, after 1994, to dispose of dredge spoil in Great Lakes waters other than at a confined disposal facility unless the disposal is consistent with guidelines established under this Act. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop guidelines for the disposal of sediment material in the open waters of the Great Lakes. Prescribes civil penalties for violations concerning the disposal of dredge spoil in the Great Lakes. Prohibits the Secretary of the Army from establishing any confined spoil disposal facility in Great Lakes waters unless the facility is consistent with such guidelines. Requires the Administrator to evaluate the integrity of each confined disposal facility in the Great Lakes and assess the environmental consequences of such facilities. Directs the Secretary to submit a remediation plan for each facility that is affecting a surrounding area in a manner inconsistent with guidelines. Provides for termination of the use of facilities for which remediation plans are not undertaken by January 1, 1999. Requires persons who dispose of dredge spoil at confined spoil disposal facilities to obtain permits from the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop tributary sediment transport models for each major river system that flows into a Great Lakes federally authorized commercial harbor, channel maintenance project site, or area of concern; (2) develop an analytical method to project the effectiveness of sediment source reduction approaches and scenarios in reducing upstream sediment loadings; and (3) use such method to conduct sediment load reduction analyses for the models. Requires the Secretary to transfer funds to the EPA for making grants to States for projects to reduce erosion that contributes to the sedimentation of federally authorized commercial harbors, channel maintenance project sites, and areas of concern. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
