<bill session="103" type="s" number="782" updated="2012-07-17T05:24:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-07">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-07"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce spending for agricultural programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-07" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4567-4568)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-07" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-12"><committee name="Committee on Agriculture"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Agricultural Production.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="Agricultural Production and Stabilization of Prices" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Agriculture and food"/>
		<term name="Administrative fees"/>
		<term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
		<term name="Agricultural credit"/>
		<term name="Agricultural economics"/>
		<term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Cotton"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Feed grain program"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Goats"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Grain"/>
		<term name="Grain trade"/>
		<term name="Honey"/>
		<term name="Income"/>
		<term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
		<term name="Meat inspection"/>
		<term name="Milk"/>
		<term name="National forests"/>
		<term name="Oilseeds"/>
		<term name="Overtime"/>
		<term name="Peanuts"/>
		<term name="Poultry inspection"/>
		<term name="Rice"/>
		<term name="Rural electrification"/>
		<term name="Sorghum"/>
		<term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
		<term name="Timber sales"/>
		<term name="Tobacco"/>
		<term name="User charges"/>
		<term name="Wheat"/>
		<term name="Wool"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/7/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Price Support Programs Title II: Other Agricultural Programs Title I: Price Support Programs - (Sec. 101) Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to require that wheat, feed grain, cotton, rice, and oilseed producers repay certain marketing loans in cash rather than through forfeiture of pledged commodities. (Sec. 102) Extends and reduces on a sliding scale deficiency payment rates for wheat, feed grains (including oats and grain sorghums), upland or extra long staple cotton, and rice. (Sec. 103) Eliminates the 0/92 and 50/92 conservation use and acreage reduction programs for wheat, feed grains, cotton, and rice. (Sec. 104) Increases marketing assessments for tobacco, peanuts, oilseeds, and sugar. Extends and increases milk price reduction authority. (Sec. 105) Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to reduce the maximum amount of deficiency payments for wheat, feed grains, upland or extra long staple cotton, or rice. Places income and gross revenue limitations on qualifying producers. (Sec. 106) Repeals the National Wool Act of 1954 (thus eliminating the wool and mohair price support programs). (Sec. 107) Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to eliminate the honey price support program. (Sec. 109) Amends various agricultural Acts to extend specified price support, export, and related programs. Title II: Other Agricultural Programs - (Sec. 201) Repeals the Rural Electrification Act of 1936. (Sec. 202) Imposes Agricultural Marketing Service and Agricultural Cooperative Service user fees. (Sec. 203) Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to require: (1) meat and poultry inspectors to be paid for overtime and services in excess of one eight-hour shift; and (2) the establishments concerned to reimburse the Secretary of Agriculture for such payments. (Sec. 204) Amends the National Forest Management Act of 1976 to prohibit below-cost timber sales from National Forest System Lands.

	</summary>
</bill>
