<bill session="103" type="s" number="79" updated="2012-07-17T06:16:13-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Government Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restore public confidence in the performance and merits of elected officials and Federal employees.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1994-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S498)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-05"><committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/><text>Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-63.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="SSGA-3" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Annuities"/>
		<term name="Civil service pensions"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Ex-presidents"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
		<term name="Financial disclosure"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Lawyers"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Officer personnel"/>
		<term name="Political ethics"/>
		<term name="Retired military personnel"/>
		<term name="Vice Presidents"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Responsible Government Act of 1993 - Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 (FARA) to subject to registration and other FARA requirements foreign agents seeking to influence Federal legislation, executive rulemaking, or the administration of any Federal program or policy through outside contracts with legislative or executive branch officials. Modifies the registration exemption under FARA pertaining to legal representation of disclosed foreign principals. Amends the Federal criminal code to permanently ban former senior executive and legislative branch officials, including former Presidents, Vice Presidents, and Members of Congress, as well as senior military officers, from representing or advising foreign principals. Modifies and extends to : (1) two years the current one-year lobbying ban on representing and advising foreign entities; and (2) five years the current ban on all other lobbying activities (other than those involving the personal and substantial participation of the officer or employee involved, which remain permanently banned) involving former officers and employees of the executive and legislative branches and the District of Columbia, Vice Presidents, and Members of Congress. Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to subject additional executive and legislative branch personnel to financial disclosure requirements under that Act. Provides for forfeiture of Federal retirement benefits for violating requirements for registration as a foreign agent and related financial disclosures.

	</summary>
</bill>
