<bill session="103" type="s" number="806" updated="2012-07-17T04:04:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-China Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend to the People's Republic of China renewal of nondiscriminatory (most-favored-nation) treatment provided certain conditions are met.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407786"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409580" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="404219" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300046" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4825-4828)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6894)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="American investments"/>
		<term name="Arms control"/>
		<term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
		<term name="Biological weapons"/>
		<term name="Chemical weapons"/>
		<term name="China"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Congressional veto"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Dissenters"/>
		<term name="Emigration"/>
		<term name="Forced labor"/>
		<term name="Freedom of association"/>
		<term name="Freedom of speech"/>
		<term name="Great Britain"/>
		<term name="Guided missiles"/>
		<term name="Hong Kong"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Korean War, 1950-1953"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Location of industries"/>
		<term name="Missing in action"/>
		<term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political prisoners"/>
		<term name="Prison labor"/>
		<term name="Prisoners of war"/>
		<term name="Public demonstrations"/>
		<term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
		<term name="Right of assembly"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="Tariff"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Tibet"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Vietnamese Conflict"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
United States-China Act of 1993 - Prohibits the President from recommending for a 12-month period in 1994 continuation of a waiver of human rights and emigration requirements for nondiscriminatory treatment (most-favored-nation treatment) for China under the Trade Act of 1974 unless the President reports to the Congress that China has: (1) taken steps to adhere to the Universal Declaration of Human Rights in China and Tibet and allowed the unrestricted emigration of Chinese citizens who desire to leave for reasons of political or religious persecution; (2) accounted for and released prisoners who dissented in Tiananmen Square on June 4, 1989, and other citizens detained for the nonviolent expression of their political beliefs or the exercise of internationally guaranteed rights of freedom of speech, association, and assembly; and (3) prevented the export to the United States of products manufactured by convict or forced labor. Requires such report to state whether China has made significant progress in: (1) ceasing religious persecution in China and Tibet and releasing religious leaders incarcerated as a result of the expression of their religious beliefs; (2) ceasing financial and other incentives to encourage non-Tibetans to relocate in Tibet; (3) ceasing unfair trade practices which restrict American business; (4) providing U.S. exporters fair access to Chinese markets, including lowering tariffs, removing nontariff barriers, and increasing the purchase of U.S. goods and services; (5) adhering to the Missile Control Technology Regime, the Nuclear Suppliers Group controls and the Australian Group on Chemical and Biological Arms controls; (6) adhering to the Joint Declaration on Hong Kong; (7) accounting for U.S. military personnel listed as prisoners of war or missing in action with respect to the Korean and Vietnam conflicts; (8) ceasing the jamming of Voice of America broadcasts; and (9) providing humanitarian groups access to prisoners and places of detention. Requires the President, if he recommends such extension, to report on the extent of China's compliance with the above-mentioned objectives. Grants nondiscriminatory treatment to products produced by nonstate-owned enterprises in China. Declares that despite China's entry into the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) its most-favored-nation treatment status shall be governed by the Trade Act of 1974. Requires the President, if he decides not to seek such extension, to ensure that members of the GATT take similar action with respect to China.

	</summary>
</bill>
