<bill session="103" type="s" number="808" updated="2012-07-17T05:18:33-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Volunteer Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage the States to enact legislation to grant immunity from personal civil liability, under certain circumstances, to volunteers working on behalf of nonprofit organizations and governmental entities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403346"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="401604" joined="1993-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="407254" joined="1993-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1994-02-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4829-4830)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
		<term name="Block grants"/>
		<term name="Charities"/>
		<term name="Federal-state relations"/>
		<term name="Liability (Law)"/>
		<term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
		<term name="Torts"/>
		<term name="Volunteer workers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
Volunteer Protection Act of 1993 - Prescribes circumstances under which volunteers working for nonprofit organizations or government entities shall be immune from personal financial liability for acts on behalf of the organization or entity. Sets forth exceptions and conditions that a State may impose on the granting of such immunity. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to increase by one percent the fiscal year allotment which would otherwise be made to a State to carry out the Social Services Block Grant Program under title XX of the Social Security Act if such State has, within two years, certified to the Secretary that it has enacted a State law which provides such immunity. Provides for the continuation of such increase based on an annual recertification.

	</summary>
</bill>
