<bill session="103" type="s" number="809" updated="2012-07-17T05:39:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-22">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, relating to open containers of alcoholic beverages and consumption of alcoholic beverages in the passenger area of motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4831-4832)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
		<term name="Drunk driving"/>
		<term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
		<term name="Motor bus lines"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/1993--Introduced.
Requires the Secretary of Transportation, beginning with FY 1997, to withhold five percent of the amount required to be apportioned to a State under specified Federal highway provisions if it is lawful in such State to: (1) possess an open alcoholic beverage container in the passenger area of any motor vehicle on a public highway; or (2) consume any alcoholic beverage in such motor vehicle on a public highway. Exempts from such withholding measures charter buses designed to transport more than ten passengers whose drivers are not permitted by State law to possess open alcoholic beverages in the passenger area. Provides for the release of withheld funds to States which comply with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
