<bill session="103" type="s" number="823" updated="2012-07-17T05:49:32-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-30">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-06-30" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Wildlife Refuge System Management and Policy Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Wildlife Refuge System Management and Policy Act of 1994</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 to improve the management of the National Wildlife Refuge System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300046"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402004" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1994-08-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300031" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1993-04-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-04-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4921-4922)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-09"><committee name="Committee on Environment and Public Works"/><text>Subcommittee on Clean Water, Fisheries. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-172.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-23"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-30"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-08-03"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported to Senate by Senator Baucus with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 103-324. Additional views filed.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="540" datetime="1994-08-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 540.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Clean Water, Fisheries and Wildlife" activity="Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal installations"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Management"/>
		<term name="Military training"/>
		<term name="Nevada"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Water rights"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/1994--Reported to Senate amended. National Wildlife Refuge System Management and Policy Act of 1994 - Amends the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 to set forth the mission and purpose of the National Wildlife Refuge System (System), including units within the System. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to: (1) issue final regulations for determining System use compatibility; and (2) prohibit a new, expanded, or existing refuge use that is not compatible with such regulations. Exempts military use of the airspace at the Cabeza Preta National Wildlife Refuge in Arizona and Desert National Wildlife Range in Nevada from such compatibility requirements. Provides for the transfer of certain lands between the Departments of Defense and Interior. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to issue a comprehensive System conservation plan, including a plan for each refuge or complex of refuges. (Sec. 8) Grants specified emergency authority to the Secretary and to the President with regard to refuge lands. (Sec. 11) States that nothing in this Act shall create a reserved water right in the United States. (Sec. 12) Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
