<bill session="103" type="s" number="826" updated="2012-07-17T04:16:50-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-27">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-27"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit foreign travel by political appointees and Members of Congress during certain post election periods, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4926)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-27" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Federal officials"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections"/>
		<term name="Congressional travel"/>
		<term name="Presidential appointments"/>
		<term name="Presidential elections"/>
		<term name="Travel costs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/27/1993--Introduced.
Prohibits travel by a political appointee (with the exception of the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, or the U.S. Trade Representative) from being paid for under provisions of Federal law, if such travel is outside of the United States and occurs during a post presidential election period in which the incumbent President shall not return for another term of office as President. Waives the provisions of this Act if the President makes a written determination that such travel: (1) cannot reasonably be postponed until after the post presidential election period; and (2) is essential to protect vital national security interests or other vital national interests related to foreign policy, foreign travel, or the economy. Prohibits funds from being expended for travel by a Member of Congress if: (1) such travel is outside of the United States; (2) such travel occurs after the date on which an election for the office held by such Member occurs; and (3) such Member will not serve as a Member of Congress in the session following such election.

	</summary>
</bill>
