<bill session="103" type="s" number="83" updated="2012-07-17T04:59:59-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf of Mexico Preservation Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the preservation of the Gulf of Mexico by establishing within the Environmental Protection Agency a Gulf of Mexico Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300159"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-01-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Beach erosion"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Fishery management"/>
		<term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Oil pollution control"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Water pollution control"/>
		<term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Gulf of Mexico Preservation Act of 1993 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a Gulf of Mexico Program to: (1) report on the assessment of trends in environmental quality in the Gulf; (2) collaborate with specified entities to identify causes of environmental problems; and (3) provide for the development of a management, protection, and restoration plan. Establishes a Gulf of Mexico Program Office within EPA. Authorizes the Administrator to conduct a study of environmental problems in the Gulf. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Secretary of State should enter into international agreements in furtherance of this Act. Directs the Administrator to report on the status of Gulf activities. Requires a report on assessments of Gulf environmental quality and impacts on the economic viability and importance of the Gulf. Directs the Administrator to design a strategy for monitoring the environmental quality of the Gulf. Requires development of a management, protection, and restoration plan for the Gulf. Sets forth Plan requirements, including to: (1) recommend priority schedules for addressing environmental problems in the Gulf; (2) recommend actions by Federal, State, and local agencies to prevent, abate, or remediate pollution in the Gulf or to improve environmental quality and economic viability; and (3) include a summary of the report on assessments and the monitoring strategy. Requires grants to States to further the development and implementation of the Plan. Prohibits grants from being used to relieve any person of liability for environmental damages, response costs, or related relief under Federal or State law. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Administrator to request that funding of the Program Office be included as a separate line item in any annual budget proposal submitted by the President to the Congress.

	</summary>
</bill>
