<bill session="103" type="s" number="840" updated="2012-07-17T04:52:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill for the relief of the estate of Dr. Beatrice Braude.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400563"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1993-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5178-5179)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Private legislation"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Federal employees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Transitional Aid Program Title II: Work and Gainful Employment (Wage) Program Title III: Working Parents Child Care Block Grant Title IV: Child Support Responsibility Subtitle A: Improvements to the Child Support Collection System Subtitle B: Child Support Enforcement and Assurance Demonstration Subtitle C: Demonstration Projects to Provide Services to Certain Noncustodial Parents Subtitle D: Severability Title V: Transitional Medicaid Title VI: Teenage Pregnancy Prevention Title VII: Children's Eligibility for Supplemental Security Income Title VIII: Financing and Food Assistance Reform Subtitle A: Treatment of Aliens Subtitle B: Revenue Provision Subtitle C: Food Assistance Provisions Subtitle D: Supplemental Security Income Title IX: Legislative Proposals; Effective Date Digest will follow.

	</summary>
</bill>
