<bill session="103" type="s" number="844" updated="2012-07-17T04:56:38-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Adopted Children Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a program to fund maternity home expenses and improve programs for the collection and disclosure of adoption information, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400559"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="408252" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5191-5192, S5196)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Adopted children"/>
		<term name="Adoption"/>
		<term name="Childbirth"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disabled"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
		<term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Graduate education"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Parental leave"/>
		<term name="Pension funds"/>
		<term name="Pregnant women"/>
		<term name="Scholarships"/>
		<term name="Social welfare"/>
		<term name="Social work"/>
		<term name="Social workers"/>
		<term name="State laws"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/1993--Introduced.
Fairness for Adopted Children Act - Establishes the National Advisory Council on Adoption (the Council), to be appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS). Authorizes appropriations for FY 1993 through 1995. Terminates such Council after three years. Directs the Secretary of HHS to: (1) report to the Congress, within 30 days, on the status of the implementation of the adoption data collection system required under specified provisions of the Social Security Act; (2) report monthly to the Congress on the progress made in implementing such system; and (3) consult with the Council in developing regulations to carry out such reporting requirements. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to award grants to States to enable them to establish programs to provide maternal health certificates to eligible pregnant women who are residents of a maternity home, or on a waiting list or receiving out-patient services from a maternity home. Limits such women's income to 175 percent of the State poverty level, not including support received from parents, guardians, or the father of the child. Sets forth eligibility requirements for the maternity home, including that it have the capability to serve at least four pregnant women concurrently. Requires the use of certificates to pay the reasonable costs associated with residence in, or services of, the maternity home. Allows the use of certificates to cover expenses incurred during a period that ends not later than one month after the birth of the child. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1993 through 1995. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to establish a program of fellowships for graduate study in social work, in innovative programs concerning the effects of adoption on the adopted children, their adoptive families, and their biological parents who make an adoption plan. Authorizes of appropriations for FY 1993 through 1995. Directs the Secretary of Education, within one year after enactment of this Act, to make grants to States to carry out adoption education programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1993 through 1995. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to prohibit discrimination by insurance companies in the writing or executing of insurance policies on the basis of whether a child is adopted. Makes it an unlawful employment practice for an employer to discriminate against an employee with respect to a term or condition of any leave benefit on the basis of the fact that a child of an employee is not a biological child. Amends the Social Security Act to provide payments to States for expenses incurred in placing a child with special needs in adoptive homes if the child is placed within three months of becoming available for adoption. Expresses the sense of the Congress that each State should adopt and enforce specified types of adoption laws, rules, or regulations.

	</summary>
</bill>
