<bill session="103" type="s" number="85" updated="2012-07-17T04:36:01-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Services Access Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for basic financial services.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S501)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Bank accounts"/>
		<term name="Bank deposits"/>
		<term name="Bank records"/>
		<term name="Checking accounts"/>
		<term name="Checks"/>
		<term name="Congressional investigations"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Consumer education"/>
		<term name="Credit unions"/>
		<term name="Discrimination"/>
		<term name="Federal aid programs"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Identification devices"/>
		<term name="Poor"/>
		<term name="Postal service"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Financial Services Access Act of 1993 - (Secs. 3-4) Prescribes guidelines under which: (1) each depository institution must offer a basic financial services account under which an account holder may obtain either basic transaction account services or government check cashing account services; and (2) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (the Board) must develop a model application form for the use of depository institutions offering such accounts. (Secs. 5-6) Sets forth the criteria for basic transaction services accounts and government check cashing services accounts. (Sec. 7) Requires a depository institution to conspicuously disclose the availability of such accounts in its public areas. (Secs. 8-9) Requires certain credit unions to offer basic financial services accounts. Exempts certain depository institutions from the requirements of this Act. (Secs. 10-11) Prescribes guidelines for fraud prevention and administrative enforcement. (Secs. 13-16) Requires a study and report to the Congress by: (1) the Board on the incidence of fraud in connection with government check cashing services; (2) the Secretary of the Treasury on the feasibility of staggering Federal recurring payments; and (3) the Comptroller General on using the Postal Service as a supplemental provider of government check cashing services and on using direct deposit for Federal recurring payments.

	</summary>
</bill>
