<bill session="103" type="s" number="850" updated="2012-07-17T05:27:21-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Conversion Clearinghouse Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of Economic Conversion Information within the Department of Commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409580" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1993-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="409225" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1993-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="1993-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5219-5224)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="2831" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Commercialization"/>
		<term name="Conversion of industries"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Defense industries"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Military base closures"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Technology policy"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
		<term name="Telephone"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/1993--Introduced.
Economic Conversion Clearinghouse Act - Establishes within the Department of Commerce the Office of Economic Conversion Information to: (1) serve as a central information clearinghouse on matters relating to economic adjustment and defense conversion programs and activities of the Federal and State governments; and (2) aid persons in applying for economic adjustment and defense conversion assistance under Federal, State, and local laws. Outlines further Office functions, including: (1) the development of information data bases for use in identifying and applying for such assistance; (2) the establishment of mechanisms to assure easy access to such information data bases, as well as their user-friendliness (including establishing a toll-free number); and (3) the conduct of a regular review of the various agencies and programs in the Federal system involving economic adjustment and defense conversion. Establishes the Interagency Economic Conversion Information Coordinating Committee to: (1) advise and make appropriate recommendations to the Office; (2) coordinate and facilitate the information gathering and monitoring activities of the Office among Federal departments and agencies; (3) aid the Office in preparing and presenting information in an accessible, user-friendly manner; and (4) assist the Office in making technical assistance personnel available as needed. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
