<bill session="103" type="s" number="857" updated="2012-07-17T06:00:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Commission To Ensure Small Aircraft Safety Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a national commission to ensure small aircraft safety in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408898"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5230-5231)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5801-5802)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5981-5983)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6158-6159)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Aviation safety"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="General aviation aircraft"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/1993--Introduced.
National Commission To Ensure Small Aircraft Safety Act of 1993 - Establishes the National Commission To Ensure Small Aircraft Safety. Requires the Commission to study and report to the President and the Congress on: (1) the current investigatory practices of the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) and the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) with respect to small aircraft safety; (2) the adequacy of such practices; (3) the coordination of NTSB and FAA investigations and enforcement of recommendations; (4) the enforcement of FAA small aircraft safety regulations; and (5) the impediments to full utilization of NTSB and FAA investigatory resources and enforcement. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
