<bill session="103" type="s" number="867" updated="2012-07-17T05:28:07-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Health Care Anti-Fraud and Abuse Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to extend the penalties for fraud and abuse assessed against providers under the medicare program and State health care programs to providers under all health care plans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402727"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-10-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="1993-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-10-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1993-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="403171" joined="1993-10-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5394-5395, S5400-5401)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Communication in medicine"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal investigation"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Data transmission systems"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Embezzlement"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Governmental investigations"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
		<term name="Inspectors general"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
		<term name="Medical ethics"/>
		<term name="Medical personnel"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Medicare fraud"/>
		<term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: All-Payer Fraud and Abuse Control Program Title II: Revisions to Current Sanctions for Fraud and Abuse Title III: Administrative and Miscellaneous Provisions National Health Care Anti-Fraud and Abuse Act of 1993 - Title I: All-Payer Fraud and Abuse Program - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national program to control health care fraud and abuse and facilitate Federal, State, and local enforcement of Medicare and Medicaid (titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act (SSA)) fraud and abuse programs. Creates in the Treasury the Anti-Fraud and Abuse Trust Fund. Authorizes appropriations. Amends SSA title XI to provide for the application of sanctions under the Medicare and Medicaid fraud and abuse programs for specified violations to similar violations by any health benefit plan. Requires the Secretary to establish a program through which Medicare beneficiaries may report allegations of fraud by providers under Medicare. Title II: Revisions to Current Sanctions for Fraud and Abuse - Makes revisions in specified current sanctions for fraud and abuse under Medicare and Medicaid and transfers certain of them for application under the new national program created above. Title III: Administrative and Miscellaneous Provisions - Requires providers to submit claims in a uniform format according to standards prescribed by the Secretary. Amends SSA title XI part A to direct the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register a listing of all final adverse actions taken during during the quarter. Requires the Secretary to establish a national health care fraud and abuse data collection program for the reporting of final adverse actions against health care providers, suppliers, and practitioners.

	</summary>
</bill>
