<bill session="103" type="s" number="869" updated="2012-07-17T06:29:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violence Reduction Training Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for demonstration projects for the identification by health care providers of victims of domestic violence and sexual assault, to provide for the education of the public on the consequences to the public health of such violence and assault, to provide for epidemiological research on such violence and assault, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400566"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1993-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="1993-06-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5403-5404)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Crimes against women"/>
		<term name="Criminal statistics"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Epidemiology"/>
		<term name="Family violence"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Rape victim services"/>
		<term name="Sex crimes"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1993--Introduced.
Violence Reduction Training Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to entities for demonstration projects in which health care providers are trained to: (1) interview and identify victims of domestic violence or sexual assault; and (2) refer such victims to entities providing treatment services. Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to educate health care providers and the public concerning domestic violence and assault. Provides for the conduct of epidemiological research on domestic violence and assault.

	</summary>
</bill>
