<bill session="103" type="s" number="879" updated="2012-07-17T04:30:35-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Work Force Enhancement for Technology Transfer Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide technology implementation through the training of the American work force, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5453-5454)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Manpower training programs"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
		<term name="Teaching materials"/>
		<term name="Technical education"/>
		<term name="Technology assessment"/>
		<term name="Technology policy"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1993--Introduced.
Work Force Enhancement for Technology Transfer Act - Requires the Secretary of Commerce, through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to direct Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology and, when established, Manufacturing Outreach Centers, to assist managers and other workers in U.S. manufacturing firms in using advanced and modern technologies, through needs assessments, information, and training services. Requires the Secretary, through the Director, to assist such managers and other workers in such use by: (1) establishing an information clearinghouse on the best available training material and services; (2) encouraging U.S. providers of such technologies for manufacturing firms to develop training material specifically designed for the managers and other workers responsible; and (3) establishing the availability of such specifically designed training material as an important criterion in assessing such technologies. Authorizes appropriations for a technology training clearinghouse.

	</summary>
</bill>
