<bill session="103" type="s" number="886" updated="2012-07-17T05:00:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-04">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Immunization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve immunization rates among children and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403171"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1993-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1993-05-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="1993-05-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5462)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-04" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
		<term name="Authorization"/>
		<term name="Claims"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Drug industry"/>
		<term name="Excise tax"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health education"/>
		<term name="Hospitals"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Maternal health services"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Public assistance programs"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Vaccination"/>
		<term name="Vaccines"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/1993--Introduced.
National Immunization Act - Amends the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) give States, in order to be eligible for enhanced Federal payments, the option of covering under their Medicaid (SSA title XIX) plans childhood immunization services for children of families with incomes up to 185 percent of the poverty line; (2) require States which exercise such option to implement simplified application and billing procedures for such services; (3) allow States with approved Medicaid plans to contract with manufacturers to supply vaccines for administration to children of Medicaid-eligible families at Federal discounted prices; and (4) give States the option of reducing AFDC (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) payments under SSA title IV part A to families with children who have not received appropriate immunizations. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to reinstate and continue indefinitely the imposition of taxes on certain vaccines under the National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program. Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1989 to reauthorize and extend such Program. Requires a study and report to the Congress by the Secretary of the Treasury on Program funding and payments and whether additional vaccines should be included in the Program. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and disseminate to all hospitals that provide maternity services informational materials on immunization and well-baby care. Requires providers of such services to disseminate such materials to new parents served by them in order to be eligible for funds under SSA titles XVIII (Medicare) or XIX.

	</summary>
</bill>
