<bill session="103" type="s" number="892" updated="2012-07-17T05:10:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health and Safety Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the manufacture, importation, exportation, sale, purchase, transfer, receipt, possession, or transportation of handguns and handgun ammunition, with certain exceptions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402412"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1993-05-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5523-5525)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6921-6923)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7173)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7656-7657)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-24"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8280-8281)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8691-8692)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14040-14042)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-02-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1019-1020)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Ammunition"/>
		<term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Export controls"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Firearms control"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Forfeiture"/>
		<term name="Fraud"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Larceny"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Negligence"/>
		<term name="Private police"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/5/1993--Introduced.
Public Health and Safety Act of 1993 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the manufacture, import, export, sale, purchase, transfer, receipt, ownership, possession, transport, or use (manufacture) of a handgun or handgun ammunition. Makes exceptions with respect to the military, law enforcement agencies, registered security guard services, and licensed handgun clubs and members of such clubs. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to approve such manufacture by licensed manufacturers, importers, and dealers as necessary to meet the lawful requirements of such persons and entities covered by the exceptions. Specifies handgun club licensing requirements. Requires: (1) the Secretary to revoke the license of any such club that does not continue to meet such requirements; and (2) such club to pay to the Secretary an annual license fee of $25. Specifies security guard service registration requirements. Requires: (1) the Secretary to revoke such registration if the service does not continue to meet such requirements; and (2) such service to pay to the Secretary an annual registration fee of $50. Sets forth provisions with respect to: (1) recordkeeping (by licensed manufacturers, importers, dealers, handgun clubs or their members and by registered security guard services that transfer handguns or handgun ammunition); (2) reports of loss or theft; and (3) transfers to handgun clubs. Authorizes the voluntary delivery to any designated Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency of a handgun owned or possessed by a person. Directs the Secretary to: (1) arrange with each such agency to receive handguns for the transfer, destruction, or other disposition of such handguns; and (2) pay to such person $25 or the fair market value of the gun. Authorizes appropriations. Sets penalties for violations of this Act. Specifies that a person who voluntarily delivers a handgun under this Act after 180 days after enactment shall not be subject to criminal prosecution for possession of the handgun, but shall pay to the Secretary a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed $500. Establishes penalties for: (1) failure to report the loss or theft of a handgun; (2) negligent and intentional deliveries to an unauthorized place; (3) false statements or representations; and (4) failure to keep, or permit inspection of, records. Provides for the forfeiture of any handgun or handgun ammunition involved or used in a violation of this Act or of any other criminal law of the United States.

	</summary>
</bill>
