<bill session="103" type="s" number="898" updated="2012-07-17T06:21:10-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">D.C. Statehood bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">New Columbia Admission Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the admission of the State of New Columbia into the Union.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407786" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1993-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300086" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400561" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-05-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5534)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="51" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Building laws"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="District of Columbia"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Statehood (American politics)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/5/1993--Introduced.
New Columbia Admission Act - Declares the State of New Columbia (presently, the District of Columbia) to be a State of the United States of America. Admits New Columbia into the Union on an equal footing with the other States in all respects. Reserves Federal title to certain lands and property in the National Capital Service Area. Directs the Governor to report to the Congress each fiscal year on the effects on the revenues and expenditures of the State because of the presence of the Federal Government's seat within or adjacent to it. Prohibits the State from changing any provision of its Constitution concerning height limitations on buildings without the consent of the Congress. Declares that nothing in this Act or the Constitution or laws of the State may be construed to permit it to refuse to allow an individual to serve as a qualified registered elector of the State solely because the individual resides in the National Capital Service Area. Sets forth election protocol for popular ratification of statehood. Provides for election of one member of the House of Representatives as well as two Senators. Maintains the laws that were territorially in effect. Continues any lawsuits already pending in District of Columbia courts. Establishes a Statehood Transition Commission.

	</summary>
</bill>
