<bill session="103" type="s" number="899" updated="2012-07-17T04:49:06-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-05">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Attorney General to prepare an evaluation and report on potential problem officer early warning programs and to develop a model potential problem officer early warning program, and to express the sense of the Congress that the Attorney General, under existing authorities, should provide assistance to local jurisdictions in establishing procedures to identify and provide guidance to police officers who demonstrate the potentiality of having difficulty dealing with members of the public on a consistent basis.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403171"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1993-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="401709" joined="1993-05-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5537-5538)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-05" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
		<term name="Police training"/>
		<term name="Police-community relations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/5/1993--Introduced.
Directs the Attorney General to: (1) conduct an evaluation of potential problem officer early warning programs utilized by local governments; (2) develop a model early warning system that is effective, capable of adjusting to changing circumstances, and affordable to local governments of jurisdictions with populations of 50,000 or more; and (3) prepare and disseminate findings and recommendations to the law enforcement community for the establishment of such programs. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) reporting requirements; and (2) payment of expenses incurred in conducting the evaluation and developing a model system. Expresses thhe sense of the Congress that: (1) the Attorney General should make seed money grants of up to $25,000 to local governments for assisting in establishing such programs; and (2) local governments should be eligible if they adopt and enforce policies prohibiting unreasonable or unnecessary force by law enforcement officers and procedures for receiving and investigating citizen complaints.

	</summary>
</bill>
