<bill session="103" type="s" number="917" updated="2012-07-17T05:54:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Birth Defects Prevention Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide surveillance, research, and services aimed at prevention of birth defects.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300010"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1993-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-05-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5653-5654)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-06" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="h" number="1296" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Birth defects"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Data banks"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
		<term name="Infant mortality"/>
		<term name="Medical records"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Medical statistics"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Preventive medicine"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Vital statistics"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/6/1993--Introduced.
Birth Defects Prevention Act of 1993 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish birth defects prevention and research programs. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control (CDC), to provide for collection, analysis, and reporting of birth defects statistics from birth certificates, infant death certificates, hospital records, or other sources and to collect and disaggregate such statistics by gender and racial and ethnic group. Directs the Secretary to establish at least five regional birth defects monitoring and research programs to collect and analyze information on the number, incidence, correlation, and causes of birth defects. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC, to award grants or enter into cooperative agreements with specified entities to serve as Centers of Excellence for Birth Defects Prevention Research. Requires one of the Centers to focus on birth defects among ethnic minorities. Requires the CDC to establish a clearinghouse for the collection and storage of data generated from birth defects monitoring programs developed under this Act. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the CDC, to provide for the evaluation, and implementation of prevention strategies designed to reduce the incidence and effects of birth defects. Directs the Secretary to establish an Advisory Committee for Birth Defects Prevention. Requires the Secretary to report biennially to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources regarding birth defects. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
