<bill session="103" type="s" number="938" updated="2012-07-17T06:24:29-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-11">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-11"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Recycling Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to enhance recycling opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5762-5764)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-11" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Apartment houses"/>
		<term name="Automobile industry"/>
		<term name="Automobile parts"/>
		<term name="Automobiles"/>
		<term name="Beverage containers"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Building laws"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Container industry"/>
		<term name="Electric appliances"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Federal preemption"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Imports"/>
		<term name="Industrial standards"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="Labeling"/>
		<term name="Plastics"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Research centers"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Storage"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/11/1993--Introduced.
Recycling Enhancement Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to study and report to the Congress on the opportunities for recycling white goods (defined as major appliances such as refrigerators, washing machines, water heaters, stoves, dryers, and air conditioners) and automobile components and the steps needed to increase such recycling. Requires the Administrator to develop model construction guidelines that provide suitable space for the separation, collection, and temporary storage of material for recycling in construction or major renovation of multifamily or multiunit buildings. Directs the Administrator to encourage organizations involved in establishing national building construction standards and State and local building authorities to adopt such guidelines. Requires the Administrator to establish and make grants to three National Plastics Recycling Research and Development Centers at institutions of higher education. Authorizes appropriations. Requires plastic containers manufactured in or imported into the United States to be coded to identify the principal plastic resin used in such containers. Establishes a symbol and numbers identifying specific types of resins. Makes coding requirements inapplicable to manufacturers with respect to plastic products produced in quantities of fewer than 1,000 annually and that have an expected useful life of at least 15 years. Prohibits States or political subdivisions from enforcing any law applicable to plastic coding unless requirements are the same as requirements under this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
