<bill session="103" type="s" number="939" updated="2012-07-17T05:09:09-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Simplification for Families Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify the definition of dependent, to provide a uniform definition of child, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400563"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1993-05-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5814)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Income tax"/>
		<term name="Adopted children"/>
		<term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
		<term name="Clergy"/>
		<term name="Day care"/>
		<term name="Divorcees"/>
		<term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
		<term name="Families"/>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Health insurance"/>
		<term name="Households"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Housing subsidies"/>
		<term name="Insurance premiums"/>
		<term name="Married people"/>
		<term name="Medical economics"/>
		<term name="Military housing"/>
		<term name="Residence requirements"/>
		<term name="Self-employed"/>
		<term name="Separation (Law)"/>
		<term name="Tax credits"/>
		<term name="Tax deductions"/>
		<term name="Tax exclusion"/>
		<term name="Tax exemption"/>
		<term name="Valuation"/>
		<term name="Widowers"/>
		<term name="Widows"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Definition of Dependent Title II: Definition of Child Tax Simplification for Families Act of 1993 - Title I: Definition of Dependent - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise the definition of &quot;dependent&quot; for purposes of the personal exemption deduction by replacing the present-law support test with a residency test similar to that used in the determination of the earned income tax credit. Redefines a dependent to be a qualifying child or relative (eliminating the requirement that the taxpayer provide over half the dependent's support). Revises provisions concerning divorced or separated parents. Provides an exception for pre-1994 divorce or separation agreements. Modifies the dependent care credit to require a dependent to have the same place of abode as the taxpayer. Modifies the earned income credit to conform its requirements to those for the personal exemption. Makes an exception of the residency test for members of the armed forces stationed outside the United States while serving on extended active duty. Requires employers of members of the armed forces and ministers of the gospel to report to their employees the amount of excludable income received in the form of allowances for housing. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe a simplified valuation method for determining the value of housing allowances of members of the armed forces and the rental value of parsonages. Modifies provisions defining surviving spouse status and head of household status to require that such taxpayers be eligible for a dependency exemption for the one or more individuals. Requires dependents of a surviving spouse or head of household to live with the taxpayer. Repeals the requirement that certain married individuals living apart maintain a household which constitutes the principal place of abode of a child. Repeals the provision which requires a reduction in the medical expense deduction based on the health insurance credit allowable under the earned income credit. Title II: Definition of Child - Establishes a definition of &quot;child&quot; to mean: (1) a son, daughter, stepson, or stepdaughter; (2) an adopted child; and (3) any individual for whom a taxpayer cares as the taxpayer's own child, and who has the same principal place of abode as the taxpayer.

	</summary>
</bill>
