<bill session="103" type="s" number="943" updated="2012-07-17T04:05:30-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-12">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-12"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Television Violence Protection Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect children from the physical and mental harm resulting from violence contained in television programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403669"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1993-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1993-05-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="1993-05-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5821-5825)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-12" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-06-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8259-8260)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8533-8534)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-07-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8598)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-20"><committee name="Committee on Commerce"/><text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 103-852.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Cable television"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Standards"/>
		<term name="Television and children"/>
		<term name="Television broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Television programs"/>
		<term name="Television stations"/>
		<term name="Violence in television"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/12/1993--Introduced.
Children's Television Violence Protection Act of 1993 - Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to prescribe standards requiring television broadcast licensees and cable operators, including cable programmers, to require a video and audio warning with regard to programming that may contain violence or unsafe gun practices, that may adversely affect the mental or physical health of a child, and that may, if the events portrayed in such programming occur in real life, warrant the imposition of criminal penalties. Exempts any programming broadcast between 11:00 P.M. and 6:00 A.M. Authorizes the FCC to exempt, as public interest requires, certain video programming, including news broadcasts, sporting events, educational programming, and documentaries. Directs the FCC to consider, in its review of an application for renewal of a television broadcast license, whether the licensee has complied with this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
