<bill session="103" type="s" number="979" updated="2012-07-17T04:56:24-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Greentech Jobs Initiative Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish an environmental export program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1993-05-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6038-6039)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="Buy American"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Employee training"/>
		<term name="Environmental engineering"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Export finance"/>
		<term name="Export subsidies"/>
		<term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
		<term name="Government and business"/>
		<term name="Information services"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology assessment"/>
		<term name="Trade fairs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/18/1993--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Export Programs of the Environmental Protection Agency Title II: Amendments to the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 Greentech Jobs Initiative Act of 1993 - Title I: Export Programs of the Environmental Protection Agency - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish the Greentech Jobs Initiative to carry out specified activities related to this Act. Requires the Administrator to establish a program to foster the international dissemination of information concerning the performance, costs, and environmental applications of competitive technologies. Directs the Administrator, in carrying out the program, to: (1) conduct field and laboratory testing of new and innovative environmental technologies; (2) establish a demonstration program for environmental technologies; (3) publish monographs of technological approaches to address specific environmental problems; and (4) establish a research and development program. Requires the Administrator to establish an environmental technology financing program to identify projects in foreign countries that could benefit from environmental technologies. Directs the Administrator, acting through the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, to: (1) establish financial mechanisms to increase the participation of domestic business concerns in supplying environmental technologies in developing countries; and (2) use financial assistance authorized by this Act to counterbalance assistance from foreign governments. Requires: (1) at least 50 percent of the cost of any equipment furnished for a project to be attributable to components manufactured in the United States; and (2) the maximum participation of domestic business concerns. Directs the Administrator to establish training programs for: (1) Environmental Export Assistance Officers designated pursuant to the Export Enhancement Act of 1988; and (2) individuals from developing countries concerning the operation and maintenance of environmental technologies. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Amendments to the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 - Amends the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish an advisory committee to advise the Environmental Trade Promotion Working Group on increasing the number of exports of environmental technologies, goods, and services. Directs the Working Group to study the subsidies, incentives, and policies used by foreign countries to promote exports of such technologies, goods, and services and to identify any foreign trade barriers that restrict the import of U.S. technologies, goods, and services. Requires the Secretary to establish an environmental export information center.

	</summary>
</bill>
