<bill session="103" type="s" number="980" updated="2012-07-17T06:07:15-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-18">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-18"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hazardous Pollution Prevention Planning Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce hazardous pollution, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="407663" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-05-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-05-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6042-6044)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-18" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6286-6287)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Actions and defenses"/>
		<term name="Administrative procedure"/>
		<term name="Business intelligence"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
		<term name="Environmental research"/>
		<term name="Executive reorganization"/>
		<term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
		<term name="Industry-university relations"/>
		<term name="Injunctions"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="New products"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
		<term name="Pollution control"/>
		<term name="Product development"/>
		<term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Technology assessment"/>
		<term name="Waste reduction"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/18/1993--Introduced.
Hazardous Pollution Prevention Planning Act of 1993 - Requires owners or operators of facilities subject to toxic chemical release reporting requirements pursuant to the Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986 to periodically prepare pollution prevention plans, summaries, and progress reports. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish criteria pursuant to which owners or operators shall identify targeted production processes on which to focus pollution prevention strategies. Directs the Administrator to establish a small business pollution prevention compliance and technical assistance program. Provides for: (1) grants to States for programs to promote pollution prevention techniques by small businesses; and (2) the establishment of Small Business Pollution Prevention Panels within EPA regional offices. Exempts from plan preparation requirements research and development laboratories and pilot facilities. Permits the Administrator to provide technical assistance in pollution prevention planning to facilities within industrial categories identified as having the highest priority for pollution prevention. Authorizes States to exercise pollution prevention planning authorities, subject to the Administrator's approval. Requires the Administrator to carry out a pollution prevention research, development, and demonstration program in coordination with other Federal agencies. Prescribes civil penalties for failures to submit pollution prevention documents. Permits the Administrator or an authorized State to deny a permit under any environmental law to any owner or operator who fails to submit pollution prevention documents. Directs the Administrator to establish a demonstration program to provide regulatory incentives for achieving pollution prevention. Authorizes the Administrator, as part of such program, to modify requirements of existing permits or agreements. Authorizes appropriations.

	</summary>
</bill>
