<bill session="103" type="s" number="99" updated="2012-07-17T05:18:49-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Fair Competition Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the antitrust laws to provide a cause of action for persons injured in United States commerce by unfair foreign competition.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-01-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S533-534)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Antidumping"/>
		<term name="Antitrust law"/>
		<term name="Dumping"/>
		<term name="International competitiveness"/>
		<term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
International Fair Competition Act of 1993 - Repeals a Federal provision stating that any person who violates or conspires to violate a prohibition against the importation or sale of articles at less than market value or the wholesale price shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, punishable by a fine of up to $5,000, imprisonment for up to one year, or both, at the court's discretion. Revises provisions concerning such importation or sale to prohibit a person who exports a product from a foreign country into the United States, commonly and systematically to export the article into, cause the article to be exported into, or cause the article to be sold within the United States at a price that is less than the average total cost of the article, if: (1) the exportation or sale has the effect of destroying or injuring commerce, preventing the establishment of a line of commerce, or substantially lessening competition or tending to create a monopoly in any part of trade and commerce in the article, in the United States; and (2) the foreign country's market in the article lacks effective price competition or is substantially closed to effective international competition. Specifies that nothing shall prevent a defendant from rebutting a prima facie case made with respect to such circumstances by showing that the circumstances were not a factor in the price charged.

	</summary>
</bill>
