<bill session="103" type="s" number="998" updated="2012-07-17T06:07:53-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-05-20">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Art-in-Architecture Act of 1993</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote social, cultural, and historic awareness of communities that are homes to Federal buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400563" joined="1993-05-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6272)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-05-20" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Architecture"/>
		<term name="Art"/>
		<term name="Art objects"/>
		<term name="Artists"/>
		<term name="Building construction"/>
		<term name="Federal office buildings"/>
		<term name="Government procurement"/>
		<term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
		<term name="Planning"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/1993--Introduced.
Art-in-Architecture Act of 1993 - Requires at least one half of one percent of funds made available for new construction, building purchase, acquisition, or prospectus-level repair and alteration projects to be made available for art projects for each Federal building, except when the Administrator of the General Services Administration or a designee may increase or decrease that percentage under specified conditions. Requires the preliminary planning and design of each new Federal building to include planning for art commissions. Directs the Administrator to commission works of art by living American artists to be placed in Federal buildings. Sets forth requirements for commission amount, selection standards, procedures, artwork maintenance, and registry of portfolios.

	</summary>
</bill>
