<bill session="103" type="sc" number="49" updated="2010-04-19T21:18:40-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-10-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-10-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-10-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of the Congress that the current Canadian quota regime on chicken imports should be removed as part of the Uruguay Round multilateral trade negotiations and that Canada's imposition of quotas on United States processed chicken violates Article XI of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300072"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1993-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1993-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1993-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1993-10-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14709-14710)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-10-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Free trade"/>
		<term name="Import quotas"/>
		<term name="Import restrictions"/>
		<term name="Poultry industry"/>
		<term name="Tariff"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Trade negotiations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/29/1993--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should: (1) as part of the Uruguay Round multilateral trade negotiations, negotiate tariffication of Canada's chicken supply management system and the elimination of processed chicken from Canada's Import Control List; (2) insist under the tariffication that the amount of chicken determined to be within quota be based on the total amount of chicken imported into Canada in 1993 through both global and supplemental import quotas; (3) seek the elimination or, at the minimum, phase-out of new duties imposed by Canada on chicken imports in accordance with the United States-Canada Free Trade Agreement; and (4) oppose any Canadian activity which results in lost sales for U.S. chicken exporters and restricts U.S. access to Canadian markets.

	</summary>
</bill>
