<bill session="103" type="sc" number="64" updated="2010-04-19T21:20:58-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-03-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-03-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the Gautemalan peace process and the need for greater protection of human rights in Guatemala.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300076"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="1994-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1994-08-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="1994-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1994-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="1994-09-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3746-3747)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-03-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Civil war"/>
		<term name="Civil-military relations"/>
		<term name="Colombia"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Diplomacy"/>
		<term name="Dissenters"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Guatemala"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Kidnapping"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Mediation"/>
		<term name="Mexico"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Norway"/>
		<term name="Peace negotiations"/>
		<term name="Peace treaties"/>
		<term name="Prisons"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Repatriation"/>
		<term name="Spain"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Venezuela"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/24/1994--Introduced.
Commends: (1) the President of Guatemala, Ramiro de Leon Carpio, and the leaders of the Guatemalan National Revoluntionary Union for establishing a framework for formal negotiations to bring an end to the internal armed conflict and set Guatemala on the road to democracy; and (2) the leaders of the various segments of civilian society, under the leadership of Bishop Rodolfo Quezada Toruno, for their role in articulating the concerns of all sectors of Guatemalan society and for bringing critical issues onto the agenda of the peace negotiations. Calls on: (1) the Group of Friends of the peace negotiations (Colombia, Mexico, Spain, Venezuela, Norway, and the United States) to continue and intensify their support of such negotiations; (2) President de Leon Carpio to develop a measurable and substantive plan to end human rights abuses and disband the Civil Self-Defense Patrols, to ensure the safety of the returnees, and to recognize the civilian character of the Communities of Populations in Resistance; and (3) the executive branch of the U.S. Government to condition all assistance to Guatemala, except for humanitarian and development assistance, on achieving concrete and significant progress with respect to full compliance with recommended measures of the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights, the continuation of the peace process, substantive improvement in the protection of human rights, the dissolution of the Patrols, the guaranteed safety of refugees, returnees, and the internally displaced, verifiable resolution of the Devine, Ortiz, Harbury, and Mack cases, and the strengthening of the various segments of civilian society.

	</summary>
</bill>
