<bill session="103" type="sc" number="71" updated="2010-04-19T21:22:04-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Capital Improvement Control Resolution</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution to require enactment of a resolution by the appropriate House of Congress for each capital improvement project in the United States Capitol area with an estimated total cost greater than $3,000,000.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7378)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
		<term name="Congressional agencies"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees"/>
		<term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
		<term name="Congressional voting"/>
		<term name="Construction costs"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal office buildings"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Library of Congress"/>
		<term name="Public buildings"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/1994--Introduced.
Capital Improvement Control Resolution - Prohibits funds from being obligated for any capital improvement project with an estimated total cost greater than $3 million in the United States Capitol area (the buildings and grounds of the U.S. Capitol, the Library of Congress, and the congressional offices) unless the House of Congress with jurisdiction over the project has approved it through enactment of a Capital Improvement Resolution (a simple resolution if such project affects only one House or a concurrent resolution if the project affects both Houses). Requires the resolution to be accompanied by a report from a committee with jurisdiction over the capital improvement project which shall include: (1) a description of the project; (2) the justification for making the capital improvement; (3) the alternatives considered, including their costs and the reasons for rejecting them; (4) the total estimated costs for the project; and (5) the maximum amount which may be appropriated for the project. Requires an affirmative vote of three-fifths of Members of the appropriate House of Congress to waive requirements of this Act.

	</summary>
</bill>
