<bill session="103" type="sj" number="3" updated="2010-04-19T21:23:54-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-03">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1993-03-03" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States restoring the right of Americans to pray in public school graduation ceremonies and athletic events.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300154"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S140-142)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-03-03"  state="REPORTED"><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 10.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="hj" number="163" />
		<bill relation="identical" session="103" type="sj" number="16" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Prayer in the public schools"/>
		<term name="Public buildings"/>
		<term name="Religious liberty"/>
		<term name="Student activities"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Declares that nothing in the Constitution shall be construed to prohibit voluntary individual or group prayer in public schools or other public institutions, or to prohibit prayer at public school baccalaureate services, athletic events, or other extracurricular activities. States that no person shall be required by the United States or any State to participate in prayer or be present during any prayer. Provides that neither the United States nor any State shall compose prayers to be said in public schools or other public institutions or at events sponsored by such schools or institutions.

	</summary>
</bill>
