<bill session="103" type="sj" number="6" updated="2012-07-17T04:36:31-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-01-21">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-01-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Balanced Budget Amendment</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to provide for a Balanced Budget Constitutional Amendment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300159"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="403515" joined="1993-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1993-04-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-01-21" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-02-04"><committee name="Committee on Judiciary"/><text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee code="" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Balanced budgets"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Congressional budget"/>
		<term name="Congressional voting"/>
		<term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Deficit financing"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="National income"/>
		<term name="Public debt"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/21/1993--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Requires the Congress prior to each fiscal year to adopt a statement in which total Federal outlays do not exceed total receipts, unless a three-fifths vote of both Houses authorizes a specific excess. Prohibits such total receipts from increasing by a rate greater than the rate of increase in national income in the second prior fiscal year, unless a three-fifths majority of each House of Congress has passed a bill directed solely to approving specific additional receipts and such bill has become law. Directs the President prior to each fiscal year to submit to the Congress a proposed statement of balanced receipts and outlays. Makes the public debt amount on the first day of the second fiscal year after ratification of this amendment a permanent limit on such debt, unless a three-fifths majority of both Houses of Congress have passed a bill approving such increase and the bill has become law.

	</summary>
</bill>
