<bill session="103" type="sj" number="69" updated="2012-07-17T04:53:56-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-24">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-24"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution providing for the United States to assume a strong leadership role in implementing the decisions made at the Earth Summit by developing a national strategy to implement Agenda 21 and other Earth Summit agreements through domestic policy and foreign policy, by cooperating with all countries to identify and initiate further agreements to protect the global environment, and by supporting and participating in the high-level United Nations Sustainable Development Commission.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400566" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-03-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-09-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3661)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-24" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4795-4797)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
		<term name="Debt agreements"/>
		<term name="Defense budgets"/>
		<term name="Developing countries"/>
		<term name="Economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Economic development"/>
		<term name="Economics and public finance"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Foreign loans"/>
		<term name="Government paperwork"/>
		<term name="Government spending reductions"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
		<term name="Subsidies"/>
		<term name="Sustainable development"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/24/1993--Introduced.
Declares that effective follow-up to achieve the goals of the agreements reached at the United Nations Conference on Environment and Development (UNCED) will depend on the following actions by the President and the Congress: (1) adoption of a national strategy for environmentally sustainable development; (2) facilitation of a means for adopting individual Agenda 21 plans of action; (3) establishment of an effective mechanism to plan, initiate, and coordinate U.S. policy for implementing Agenda 21; and (4) formulation of policies to help developing countries to implement Agenda 21. Supports: (1) pursuing the research and policy initiatives urged in Agenda 21; (2) adoption by the Congress of a system to reallocate an appropriate amount of savings from reduced defense spending to achieve its goals of global environmental protection and sustainable development over the next decade; (3) the United Nations Commission on Sustainable Development; and (4) rules of procedure for the Commission which ensure the participation of nongovernmental organizations. Calls on the President to: (1) actively participate in multilateral efforts aimed at creating a more favorable international economic climate for developing countries to practice sustainable development; (2) affirm strong U.S. commitment to the Commission by appointing a high-level representative to the Commission; and (3) submit a national report to the Commission on activities the United States has undertaken to implement Agenda 21 both domestically and internationally, on progress made toward fulfilling other commitments undertaken at UNCED, and on other environmental and developmental activities.

	</summary>
</bill>
