<bill session="103" type="sj" number="70" updated="2012-07-17T06:08:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-25">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to the renewed civil war in Angola.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-03-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-04-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3797-3799)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-25" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Angola"/>
		<term name="Armistices"/>
		<term name="Civil war"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Insurgency"/>
		<term name="Peace negotiations"/>
		<term name="Peace treaties"/>
		<term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/25/1993--Introduced.
Deplores the human rights violations committed by the Government of Angola and the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola (UNITA) during the recently renewed conflict in Angola. Condemns the refusal of UNITA to negotiate and urges the Angolan Government and UNITA to negotiate a cease-fire and set a timetable for full implementation of the Bicesse Peace Accords. Calls upon the President to: (1) extend diplomatic recognition to the Angolan Government to encourage the peace process; (2) appoint a special envoy to support United Nations efforts to facilitate a cease-fire; (3) take actions in the international community to pressure any party in Angola that obstructs the peace process into ceasing such obstruction; and (4) consider dispatching a team to Angola to assess the humanitarian crisis and make recommendations for a U.S. response.

	</summary>
</bill>
