<bill session="103" type="sj" number="74" updated="2012-07-17T05:17:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-26">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-26"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the Government of Malawi's arrest of opponents and suppression of freedoms, and conditioning assistance for Malawi.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="1993-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="403346" joined="1993-04-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="1993-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="1993-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-03-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-26" state="INTRODUCED"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3872)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-26" state="REFERRED"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="American military assistance"/>
		<term name="Arms sales"/>
		<term name="Arrest"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Dissenters"/>
		<term name="Freedom of speech"/>
		<term name="Freedom of the press"/>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Malawi"/>
		<term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
		<term name="Political parties"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Political prisoners"/>
		<term name="Referendum"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Right of assembly"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/26/1993--Introduced.
Condemns: (1) the Malawian Government's continued incarceration and harassment of dissidents; the restriction on freedoms of speech, press, and assembly; and the repeated, short-term arrests of opposition leaders to impede their prodemocracy efforts; and (2) all efforts by such Government to limit the ability of political parties and popular organizations to campaign in relation to the upcoming referendum. Urges: (1) such Government to consider the recommendations of the United Nations (UN) Technical Team on the Conduct of a Free and Fair Referendum on the Issue of a One Party-Multiparty System in Malawi and to release all political prisoners; and (2) the President and the Secretary of State to ensure that the U.S. development assistance program bears relation to such Government's progress toward an open political system and respect for human rights and that the assistance of other governments and multilateral institutions is directed toward these goals. Commends the actions of the United States and UN in support of democratic change in Malawi and freedom of expression and human rights. Encourages the President and the Secretary of State to work closely with other governments to these ends. Sets conditions for the resumption of assistance to the Government of Malawi, including the release of political detainees, establishment and respect for fundamental freedoms, permitting the unimpeded right to participate freely in the selection of government, and establishment of effective institutions for the protection of such rights. Authorizes the President to waive such parts of the restrictions which are necessary to provide assistance to refugees currently residing in Malawi.

	</summary>
</bill>
