<bill session="103" type="sr" number="103" updated="2010-04-19T22:15:27-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-29">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to amend rule XXIV of the Standing Rules of the Senate to limit the length of service of Senators on congressional committees.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300048"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5234)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Senate"/>
		<term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/1993--Introduced.
Amends rule XXIV of the Standing Rules of the Senate to prohibit a Senator who has served as a member of a congressional committee for four consecutive full Congresses from serving again as a member of that committee until the beginning of the third Congress following completion of his or her fourth term on such committee. Exempts the service by a Senator on a congressional committee prior to the 104th Congress. Requires that at least one-half of the Members of the majority and minority parties appointed to serve on a committee during a Congress be Senators who served on that committee during the preceding Congress. Makes it out of order to consider a resolution or take any other action that appoints Senators to serve on a committee in violation of this rule or any other rule of the Senate. Establishes a phase-in formula that rotates membership of Senators among congressional committees.

	</summary>
</bill>
