<bill session="103" type="sr" number="160" updated="2010-04-19T22:24:12-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-11-20">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1993-11-20" where="s" result="pass" how="by Voice Vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-11-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the October 21, 1993, attempted coup d'etat in Burundi, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403669"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409917" joined="1993-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1993-11-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1993-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1993-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1993-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1993-11-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-10-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14163-14164)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14856-14857)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-02"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-11-18"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported to Senate by Senator Pell without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-18"  state="REPORTED"><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 301.</text></calendar>
		<calendar datetime="1993-11-18" ><committee name="Committee on Foreign Relations"/><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1993-11-20" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Voice Vote. (consideration: 11/19/1993 CR S16594)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Burundi"/>
		<term name="Clinton Administration"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Constitution"/>
		<term name="Coups d'etat"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Elections"/>
		<term name="Ethnic relations"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Rwanda"/>
		<term name="Tanzania"/>
		<term name="Zaire"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/2/1993--Introduced.
Condemns the attempted coup d'etat in Burundi and the murder of President Ndadaye. Commends: (1) the people of Burundi for their commitment to democracy; and (2) the Clinton Administration for its prompt condemnation of the October 21, 1993, coup and for the immediate suspension of foreign assistance to Burundi. Urges the people of Burundi to help end ethnic strife. Encourages them to continue their commitment to ethnic reconciliation and democracy. Calls upon: (1) the Organization of African Unity (OAU) to support the continuation of democracy and the end of ethnic strife in Burundi; and (2) the international community to assist the OAU in its efforts to strengthen democracy in Burundi and to address the humanitarian needs of Burundian refugees in Rwanda, Tanzania, and Zaire.

	</summary>
</bill>
