<bill session="103" type="sr" number="207" updated="2010-04-19T22:31:26-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-04-26">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
	<status><vote datetime="1994-04-26" where="s" result="pass" how="by Voice Vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the tragic humanitarian and political catastrophe in Rwanda.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409917"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="411818" joined="1994-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="1994-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="408597" joined="1994-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1994-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300057" joined="1994-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="407992" joined="1994-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1994-04-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-04-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4922-4923)</text></action>
		<vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1994-04-26" where="s" result="pass"  state="PASSED:SIMPLERES"><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Voice Vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4922"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
		<term name="Ambassadors"/>
		<term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
		<term name="Armistices"/>
		<term name="Civil war"/>
		<term name="Clinton Administration"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Diplomacy"/>
		<term name="Diplomats"/>
		<term name="Dispute settlement"/>
		<term name="Ethnic relations"/>
		<term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International relief"/>
		<term name="Murder"/>
		<term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
		<term name="Peace negotiations"/>
		<term name="Peace treaties"/>
		<term name="Political persecution"/>
		<term name="Rwanda"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/1994--Introduced.
Deplores the massacre of civilians and individuals sympathetic to the political opposition in Rwanda by the Rwandan military and associated groups, as well as the Rwandan Patriotic Front. Commends President Clinton for his condemnation of and response to this crisis and the U.S. Ambassador to Rwanda, David Rawson, for his efforts in ensuring the safe and swift evacuation of Americans. Calls on: (1) all parties to exercise restraint and control over their forces, accede to and respect an immediate ceasefire, ensure the safety of innocent civilians, guarantee free passage of humanitarian assistance, and recommit themselves to the principles set forth in the Arusha peace accords; and (2) the United Nations (UN) to consider military and diplomatic options which are consistent with the Arusha accords and will ensure the safety of innocent civilians, assist in monitoring an eventual ceasefire or peace agreement, facilitate the delivery of humanitarian relief, and ensure the viability of these options. Urges: (1) the UN and the Organization of African Unity to continue efforts to gain agreement on a credible ceasefire and to facilitate negotiations between the parties to the conflict based upon such accords; and (2) President Clinton to continue diplomatic efforts to achieve prompt resolution of the crisis in Rwanda.

	</summary>
</bill>
