<bill session="103" type="sr" number="226" updated="2010-04-19T22:34:22-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-15">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate relating to negotiations under the Pacific Salmon Treaty.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400559"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="1994-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="405212" joined="1994-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1994-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300150" joined="1994-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6924)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text></action>
		<action datetime="1994-06-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7084)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Fisheries"/>
		<term name="Alaska"/>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Canada"/>
		<term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Fees"/>
		<term name="Fishery agreements"/>
		<term name="Fishing boats"/>
		<term name="Foreign fishing"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International fishery management"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legislation"/>
		<term name="Licenses"/>
		<term name="Marine resources"/>
		<term name="Maritime law"/>
		<term name="Negotiations"/>
		<term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
		<term name="Salmon fisheries"/>
		<term name="Seizure of vessels and cargoes"/>
		<term name="Territorial waters"/>
		<term name="Transportation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/1994--Introduced.
Declares that: (1) the United States should reimburse the owner of any U.S. fishing vessel forced to pay a transit license fee for Inside Passage off the Pacific coast of Canada, and should seek reimbursement for any such payments from Canada; (2) Congress should amend the Fishermen's Protective Act to authorize such reimbursement for all vessel owners who pay the transit license fee to the extent that such Act does not allow reimbursement for vessels which have not been seized; (3) the United States should prohibit the use of U.S. waters off Alaska, including waters in and near the Dixon entrance, for purposes of anchorage without proper customs clearance by commercial fishing vessels of Canada; (4) the President should direct the Coast Guard to take all steps necessary in accordance with the recognized principles of international law to provide for the safety of U.S. citizens exercising their right of passage in Canadian waters; (5) the President should review all agreements between the United States and Canada to identify other actions that may be taken to convince Canada that continuation of the transit license policy would be against Canada's long term interests, and should immediately implement any such actions which the President deems appropriate until Canada rescinds the policy; (6) the President should immediately convey to Canada in the strongest terms that the United States will not now, nor at any time in the future, tolerate any action by Canada which would impede or otherwise restrict the right of passage of U.S. vessels in violation of customary international law; and (7) the United States should redouble its efforts to seek expeditious agreement with Canada on appropriate fishery conservation and management measures that can be implemented through the Pacific Salmon Treaty to address issues of mutual concern.

	</summary>
</bill>
