<bill session="103" type="sr" number="239" updated="2010-04-19T22:36:23-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-06-29">REPORTED</state>
	<status><calendar datetime="1994-06-29" /></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-07-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding conditions for continued United States participation under the Convention on Biological Diversity.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="408597"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar datetime="1994-06-29"  state="REPORTED"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action datetime="1994-07-11"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Pell. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="513" datetime="1994-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 513.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
		<term name="Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
		<term name="Biotechnology"/>
		<term name="Budget deficits"/>
		<term name="Budgets"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
		<term name="Environmental protection"/>
		<term name="Federal budgets"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International agencies"/>
		<term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
		<term name="International finance"/>
		<term name="Medical care"/>
		<term name="Medicine"/>
		<term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Science policy"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements"/>
		<term name="Treaties"/>
		<term name="Treaty-making power"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/11/1994--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that, in formulating U.S. participation under the Convention on Biological Diversity, the President should ensure that: (1) any proposal for funding includes specific budget offsets to ensure that the deficit is not increased; (2) a restructured Global Environmental Facility is the financing mechanism referred to in the Convention; (3) further decisions under the Convention provide adequate and effective protections for intellectual property and are not weaker than those provided under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), U.S. laws, or the laws of other developed countries; (4) the United States has received a vote in all institutions, organizations, and mechanisms created under the Convention that is commensurate with the level of U.S. assessed contributions under the Convention; (5) the biological safety protocol is submitted to the Senate for its advice and consent to ratification; and (6) U.S. contributions under the Convention are solely dependent upon appropriations by the U.S. Congress and are not bound by assessments of organizations created under the Convention. Calls on the President to report to the Congress annually on the status of U.S. participation under the Convention.

	</summary>
</bill>
