<bill session="103" type="sr" number="274" updated="2010-04-19T22:41:46-04:00">
	<state datetime="1994-10-06">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1994-10-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to amend the Standing Rules of the Senate.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="403515"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400559" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="401874" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="403968" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300159" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300015" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="408420" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300079" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400558" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="406256" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="402675" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="408898" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400565" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="402727" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="402412" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="409923" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="403142" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300154" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300155" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400562" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="403669" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300157" joined="1994-10-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="406188" joined="1994-10-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1994-10-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Senate"/>
		<term name="Charitable contributions"/>
		<term name="Conferences"/>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Congressional employees"/>
		<term name="Congressional officers"/>
		<term name="Foreign agents"/>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Gifts"/>
		<term name="Honoraria"/>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Legal fees"/>
		<term name="Lobbying"/>
		<term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/6/1994--Introduced.
Revises rule XXXV of the Standing Rules of the Senate to prohibit any Member, officer, or employee of the Senate (Member) from accepting a gift, knowing that such gift is provided by a lobbyist, a registered lobbyist under the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act, a lobbying firm, or an agent of a foreign principal. Sets forth provisions regarding what: (1) constitutes a prohibited gift (including anything provided by a lobbyist which is paid for, charged to, or reimbursed by a client or firm of such lobbyist, certain charitable contributions or other payments by a lobbyist relating to a retreat sponsored by or affiliated with an official congressional organization); and (2) does not constitute a gift (including anything for which the recipient pays the market value, anything the recipient does not use and promptly returns to the donor, food or refreshments of nominal value offered other than as part of a meal, and pension and other benefits resulting from continued participation in an employee welfare and benefits plan maintained by a former employer). Sets forth provisions regarding gifts given for a nonbusiness purpose, motivated by family relationship or close personal friendship (generally permitted). Prohibits any Member from knowingly accepting a gift from any other person except as provided in this rule. Lists circumstances where such restrictions shall not apply. Considers a gift to the spouse or dependent of a Member to be a gift to such Member if given with the knowledge and acquiescence of, and with reason to believe the gift was given because of official position as, a Member. Permits Members to accept: (1) offers of free attendance at a widely attended convention, symposium, reception, or similar event, subject to specified requirements; and (2) a sponsor's unsolicited offer of free attendance at a charity event, except for reimbursement for transportation and lodging in connection with the event. Directs the Select Committee on Ethics to provide guidance setting forth reasonable steps that may be taken by Members, with a minimum of paperwork and time, to prevent the acceptance of prohibited gifts from lobbyists.

	</summary>
</bill>
