<bill session="103" type="sr" number="78" updated="2010-04-19T22:11:36-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-03-10">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution encouraging Germany to assume full and active participation in international efforts to maintain and restore international peace and security, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="402727"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2680-2682)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-03-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="Armed forces"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Constitutional law"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Dispute settlement"/>
		<term name="Germany"/>
		<term name="International military forces"/>
		<term name="National socialism"/>
		<term name="Peace"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/1993--Introduced.
Commends the German people for their efforts to: (1) acknowledge the evils perpetrated during the National Socialist period; (2) construct a democratic state deeply rooted in German society; and (3) integrate Germany into international institutions designed to promote democracy and international peace and security. Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) an appropriate response under current circumstances to Germany's past would be for Germany to participate fully in international efforts to maintain or restore international peace and security; and (2) the President should strongly encourage Germany to assume full and active participation in international peacekeeping, peacemaking, and peace-enforcing operations and to take necessary measures with regard to its constitutional law and policy and its military capabilities to enable full and active German participation in such operations.

	</summary>
</bill>
