<bill session="103" type="sr" number="89" updated="2010-04-19T22:13:17-04:00">
	<state datetime="1993-04-01">REFERRED</state>
	<status><introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/></status>

	<introduced datetime="1993-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution relating to restoration of democracy in Haiti.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="407992"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="1993-04-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4331-4332)</text></action>
		<action datetime="1993-04-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign relations"/>
		<term name="American economic assistance"/>
		<term name="Caribbean area"/>
		<term name="Democracy"/>
		<term name="Embargo"/>
		<term name="Energy"/>
		<term name="Energy policy"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid"/>
		<term name="Foreign trade"/>
		<term name="Haiti"/>
		<term name="Haitians"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="International relief"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Petroleum"/>
		<term name="Refugees"/>
		<term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
		<term name="Trade"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/1/1993--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that the highest priority of U.S. policy toward Haiti should be to restore democratic government. Urges the President to: (1) join with the Senate in expressing the outrage of the American people over the Haitian regime's attempt to deny democracy to its people; (2) review the compliance of U.S. persons and corporations with the Organization of American States (OAS)-sponsored embargo of Haiti; (3) implement measures necessary to ensure maximum compliance with the embargo; (4) give special priority to preventing oil from evading the embargo; (5) request that the United Nations (UN) Security Council join with the OAS in sponsoring an embargo against the Haitian regime; (6) assist the UN in expanding the number of its human rights observers in Haiti from 40 to 500; (7) establish as U.S. policy that Haitian refugees be granted the same protection afforded to those fleeing other oppressive regimes; (8) urge other Caribbean nations to share the burden of sheltering and accepting Haitian refugees; (9) offer humanitarian assistance to the Haitian people; and (10) develop a long-term U.S. policy toward Haiti which places a priority on building and supporting democratic institutions.

	</summary>
</bill>
